<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008928" url="http://www.ripoffreport.com/fast-food-restaurants/chipotle/chipotle-more-horrendous-servi-973fy.htm" time="2012-07-13-02:21" support="1" score="0.0015257913173338875" bingtitle="Ripoff Report | Chipotle | Complaint Review: 263817" webtitle="Ripoff Report | Chipotle | Complaint Review: 263817">
			<query id="000942" bing-rank="240"/>
	<description>... their mistreatment which includes throwing my food ... at your terrible location have decided to pick on ... complaint she will continue to go to this fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Ripoff Report | Complaints Reviews Scams Lawsuits Frauds Reported. File your review. Consumers educating consumers.™ 
By consumers, for consumers... allotment 
 Ripoff Report | Complaints Reviews Scams Lawsuits Frauds Reported. File your review. Consumers educating consumers. 
Don&apos;t let them get away with it. ® Let the truth be known! ™ 
 
 Home Help 

 Welcome, Your Profile Your Reports Logout 

 Register to File a Report Login 
 
 File a Report Update a Report Latest Reports Consumer Resources Consumers Say Thank You Legal Directory 
Reputation Management

Corporate Advocacy Program
 
This is the best way to manage and repair your business reputation. Hiding negative complaints is only a Band-Aid. Consumers want to see how a business took care of business.
 
All business will get complaints. How those businesses take care of those complaints is what separates good businesses from bad businesses.

Consumers love to do business with someone that can admit mistakes and state how they made improvements.
 
Corporate Advocacy Business Remediation and Customer Satisfaction Program.

 A program that benefits the consumer, assures them of complete satisfaction and confidence when doing business with a member business. 
 
 Company Name or Report # 
 Review Latest Reports Advanced Search Browse Categories 
   Ripoff Report protects consumers first amendment right to free speech 
 Report: #263817 
 
Report - Rebuttal - Arbitrate
 Arbitrate Remove Reports? 
No! Better yet! Arbitrate to set the record straight! 
 Complaint Review: Chipotle
 
Featured Ripoff Reports
 
 The New &quot;Digital Extortion&quot; Is there a Ripoff Report on you? Reputation Management
SEO WARNING! 
 They might contact you next! NOTICE to Bloggers!
If you write reviews
you want to support this. Help stop junk lawsuits
from killing freedom of
speech on the Internet Anti Slapp laws and why we need them. NOTICE to all consumers! Junk lawsuits targeting free speech are a major threat to the First Amendment and have a chilling effect on consumers first amendment right to speak out. Privacy Invasion WARNING FACEBOOK warns Privacy Invasion. WARNING.. EMPLOYERS SNOOPING YOUR FACEBOOK? Change your Facebook and Twitter privacy settings to only allow friends access to them. Have you been violated by your employer or potential employer by demanding your Facebook or other social media password? If you think you are a victim, file a Ripoff Report, contact Ripoff Report now. Nationwide, Internet 
 
 Past Featured Reports 
 
Ripoff Reports
 
Ripoff Report in the Media
 
 Ripoff Report on CBS 19 Ripoff Report on CBS 19 - Global Marketing Alliance Ripoff Report on ABC 15 - Smart Shopper Ripoff Report - Girls Gone Wild Ripoff Report on Fox 11 - Car Repair 
 
 See more videos 
 
Special Features
 
 Doctored Reviews is designed to help patients, doctors, and websites understand the problems created by Medical Justice, a company trying to restrict online patient reviews, and to offer some ways that let patients freely talk about their healthcare experiences. The government should serve voters, not corporate special interests. Public Citizen works to empower ordinary citizens, reduce the influence of big corporations on government, open the government to public scrutiny, and hold public officials accountable for their misdeeds. WHAT YOU NEED TO KNOW ABOUT THE BBB: NOT a government agency as listed in your local phone book. Instead the BBB is a private non-profit / franchise operation. 20/20 exposes the BBB, Hamas Terror Group Gets &apos;A&apos; Rating - BBB is running a &quot;pay for play&quot; scheme. 
 
 Ripoff Report Legal Directory 
 
 Read how Ripoff Report saves consumers millions.
 
 Submitted: Saturday, July 28, 2007 Last Posting: Monday, March 16, 2009 Reported By: — miami Florida 
 
 Chipotle Alafaya Trail Orlando Florida U.S.A. 
 Phone: Web: Category: Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
Chipotle more horrendous service from the low class psychos that work at chipotle Orlando Florida


 Print this Report Email this Report Tweet 
 5 Author 39 Consumer 0 Employee/Owner 
Rebuttal Box | Respond!

 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 Also a victim? What&apos;s this? 
Are you also a victim of the same company or individual? Want Justice? File a Rip-off Report, help other consumers to be educated and don&apos;t let them get away with it!
 Arbitrate Set The Record Straight! Repair Your Reputation
...the right way! Corporate Advocacy Program 
 after posting several complaints about &apos;chipotle&apos; in orlando just more horrendous service from the sick creeps that work there. Namely in particular a short chubby girl who everytime i go in there, seems to hound me for no particular reason. She walked from the counter ,next to me the last time I was there claiming she &quot;took my order the time before&quot; and couldn&apos;t hear me or something absurd or bizarre. I ignored her. I went to the rsetaurant several days ago, and tried to place an order with her. She claimed she &apos;couldn&apos;t hear me.&apos;

So I talked louder--and louder to where I was yelling almost to try to place an order. This low class *&amp;*&amp;, seemed to be getting off on causing me to yell for fun, while stil claiming she &quot;couldn&apos;t understand or hear me.&apos; she was standing there like an uneducated retarded robot, with a blank look just mumbling &quot;i can&apos;t hear you, i can&apos;t hear you&quot; over and over again while I am literally yelling just to place an order. This is blatant abuse and very sick and disturbing. I have never heard of something so absurd and insane in my life.

She then called another associate to take my order claiming she &apos;couldn&apos;t hear me.&apos; apparently the other associate could hear me just fine, and this psycho witch that works there has some severe issues. I have attmepted contacting chipotle many many times. They have no corporate office, and they have some terribly awful service in their restaurants with the low class jerks and psychos that work there who liek to mess around with customers for fun. what kind of restaurant is this, that they employ such sub-human trailer trash rejects for employees, that think they can get away with doing this to customers.

Almost everytime I go to this nightmare of a rstaurant, i have a horrible experience, am unable to just place a simple order and leave and have to fight, yell, get mistreated, or harassed just for trying to get some food. And nothing is ever done about it--their service doesn&apos;t change, their employees just get worse, and worse.. and hteir management is horrid...

anon
miami, Florida
U.S.A. 
This report was posted on Ripoff Report on 7/28/2007 9:49:20 AM and is a permanent record located here: http://www.ripoffreport.com/fast-food-restaurants/chipotle/chipotle-more-horrendous-servi-973fy.htm . The posting time indicated is Arizona local time. Arizona does not observe daylight savings so the post time may be Mountain or Pacific depending on the time of year.

Ripoff Report has an exclusive license to this report. It may not be copied without the written permission of Ripoff Report.
 
 Click Here to read other Ripoff Reports on Chipotle 


 Search for additional reports 
If you would like to see more Rip-off Reports on this company/individual, search here:
 Search Tips 
In order to assure the best results in your search:

 Keep the name short&amp;simple, and try different variations of the name. Do not include &quot;.com&quot;, &quot;S&quot;, &quot;Inc.&quot;, &quot;Corp&quot;, or &quot;LLC&quot; at the end of the Company name. Use only the first/main part of a name to get best results. Only search one name at a time if Company has many AKA&apos;s. 
 Report&amp;Rebuttal Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 Also a victim? What&apos;s this? 
Are you also a victim of the same company or individual? Want Justice? File a Rip-off Report, help other consumers to be educated and don&apos;t let them get away with it!
 Repair Your Reputation! What&apos;s this? 
Got Reports filed against you? Resolve the issues and rebuild trust through our Corporate Advocacy Program.

Corporate Advocacy Program: The best way to manage and repair your business reputation. Hiding negative complaints is only a Band-Aid. Consumers want to see how businesses take care of business. All businesses will get complaints. How those businesses take care of those complaints is what separates good businesses from bad businesses.
 Arbitrate Remove Reports? 
No! Better yet! Arbitrate to set the record straight! REBUTTALS&amp;REPLIES: 5 Author 39 Consumer 0 Employee/Owner Updates&amp;Rebuttals 
 #1 Update By Author

 they just don&apos;t change... 

AUTHOR: Alice - Miami (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Friday, September 21, 2007
 POSTED: Friday, September 21, 2007 
chipotle employees are still mistreating abusing discriminating against or harassing customesr and women there for no reason. They continue to employ the exact asme people that mistreat others. They dont&apos; train them for good customer service. Upper management dosent&apos; care about their bad treatment, and instead tells people they&apos;re &apos;soft spoken&apos; and the solution to their problem is placing orders online so there&apos;s no interaction.

Though upper managers, do soemthign to attempt to resolve the situation fast, overall the situation isn&apos;t resolved. they comp the customer one burrito which is nonsense for a month or more of continuous mistreatment, and teh corporate never answers any complaint forms or letters. Chipotle employees particularly at the location on university blvd by ucf, are horrendous abusive jerks, that liek to mess with customers. This is a terrible chain of restaurants, their food is good but their service and management is abhorrent..they could care less about customers being given the &apos;special treatment&apos; of discrimination by the low class psycho jerks and employees that work there. it&apos;s almost some knid of joke to them that their employees aer doing this to random customers. Shame on you chipotle...
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #2 Consumer Comment

 Now, I get it 

AUTHOR: Robert - Bowie (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Saturday, September 22, 2007
 POSTED: Saturday, September 22, 2007 You just don&apos;t get along with anyone.

I&apos;ve dealt with low talkers, and mumblers all my life. My brother in law will start talking normally, then peter off midstream into a voice level so low you wouldn&apos;t even know he was still talking. Tell him to speak up, and he will...for a few seconds. Then it&apos;s back to a low mumble. He also wonders why nobody pays him attention.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #3 Consumer Comment

 I think you need help, Alice 

AUTHOR: Tim - Valparaiso (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Thursday, September 27, 2007
 POSTED: Thursday, September 27, 2007 Robert, it took me a few days to understand what you were saying. Once I did, I was definitely amused.

Alice from Miami, Alice from Orlando, or whoever you may be, I think the problem is with YOU, not the multiple businesses that you have complained about.

Believe me (and my cardiologist, my scale, and my wife), I eat a lot of fast food. In fact, I probably eat at least one fast food meal per day. I run into problems maybe one out of every four times. But you seem to run into problems on a MUCH higher frequency.

Having done my high school stint at a drive thru window, I know all about the people who complain every day, but who nonetheless come back every day. And even with a B.A. in sociology, and a law degree, I still don&apos;t understand what motivates these people to continually return to places that they disdain.

My theory is that there is a certain percentage of society that thrives on expressing dissatisfaction or, in simpler terms, complaining about things. I think that these people get some sort of odd thrill out of causing a scene over whatever they can think of. It all comes back to some sort of insecurity, and the belittling of fast food employees, grocery clerks, etc, gives these people a thrill along the lines of what a cleptomaniac feels when he steals something that he has no use for.

At any rate, &quot;Alice&quot; needs some perspective or, possibly, some therapy. No rational person feels screwed over so often and so brutally.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #4 Update By Author

 chipotle employees are low life jerks and creeps that pick on women for fun... 

AUTHOR: Alice - Miami (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Thursday, October 11, 2007
 POSTED: Thursday, October 11, 2007 
what is wrong with teh deranged little pscyhopaths that work at this chipotle location and the hideous manner in which they treat certain csutomesr? i go to this place everyday.. ive been thru harassment, mistreatment by the illiterate uneducated pyschos that work there...contacted management and corporate numerous times with no response or care-- mistreating customers seems to be a huge forte with chipotle .. finally I contacted a regional manager...who the next day decided to meet up with me..at the location...as I went in to place an order, he seemed to &apos;watch&apos; how i was treated, with me not knowing he was sitting nearby.. then met up with me to tell me that i was &apos;soft spoken&apos; adn that he understands how they can&apos;t hear me? soft spoken..not when these jerks are making u &apos;yell&apos; your order after pretending they &apos;can&apos;t hear you&apos;..i have witnessed people whisper and can be understood...

what he&apos;s claiming is soft spoken is a deranged justiifcation for unnecessary mistreatment by the jerks that work there...and allownig them to get away with doing this to a customer for no reason...he comped me &apos;ONE&quot; burrito for weeks of mistreatment...and then said taht my best bet was calling in to palce the order beforehand or placing it online. this is so absurd to me-- taht if someone is not being treated well by the sick people that work there-- that instead of reprimanding the employees for their mistreatment which includes throwing my food away intentionally, rudely telling me to speak up and attempting to treat me as if im stupid or can&apos;t speak english, seemingly mostly b/c im an attractive female and jealousy seems to be a huge issue in this situation, that the manager has decided to say &quot;oh call in beforehand&quot; rather than saying... hey employees.. stop bothering her..

but no chipotle is much different just ike the service of so many places today that seems to be employed with so many jerks who seem to take customer mistreatment as some kidn of joke. the people that work at this chipotle are jerks and sick people.. .

now i wonder if chipotle is reading my reports and continuting to allow this mistreatment with no care...as some kind of joke or something...why would u allow mistreatment of customers like this chipotle? in fact the regional manager told me i was a &apos;special csutomer&apos;.. special customer? excuse me? because the deranged employees at your terrible location have decided to pick on &apos;me&apos; and annoy and bother me and mess with me? that is discrimination....ive had maybe 2-3 bad experiences since that time...but everytime there is a bad experience it&apos;s a BAD experience.. there is no reason for these low lifes at &apos;chipotle&apos; to be doing this to me.. and getting away with it the way they are.. as management has decided to deem customers who aren&apos;t treated well by employees &apos;special customers&apos; who need special attention..

sorry i have a college degree and am highly educated and intelligent and speak perfectly fine english...in no way am i a &apos;special customer&apos; that is a derogatory thing to say to someone based on the pathetic people working there treating them in a bad awy. I have witnessed people speak lower than me and people understand them fine..now as i went to chipotle again...the guy making my food, knows who i am.

I asked him nicely if he could change his gloves since he touched pork and i don&apos;t eat pork. He acted like he jsut couldn&apos;t hear me.. and kept repeating &quot;oh u want SAME ORDERR&quot; as if i was stupid ...i was like &quot;no can u please change your gloves&quot;.. to a ponit where I had to &quot;yell&quot; it.. then he&apos;s liek ohhhh Ohhh and acted like the immature loser he is. He took a while to change his gloves then began making my food. i asked him for some extra black beans.. just a little.. he put some and i said that&apos;s enough-- he didn&apos;t seem to understand that as well and i was lkie no no enough.. again seemingly unable to &apos;hear me&apos; say enough...then...as he knows i usually order a specific type of meat.. as i said &quot;chicken&quot; several times, he said STEAK and was starting to put steak on my food.. to where I had to yell NO CHICKEN really loud because he was abotu to mess my entire order up.

This guy has taken my order many many tiems and knows exactly what I order-- what on earth was the purpose in this jerk doing this? then as I had to yell chicken he and the other employee acted lk e&quot;oh gawd..&quot; as if &quot;I&quot; was the problem there...these people are sick twister /&gt;
&apos;John you do realize you are helping these businesses get away with wrong doing&apos;

&gt;&gt;Again, please post proof of these bullshit accusations. Just because YOU don&apos;t get your way does not mean a business is &apos;bad&apos; and &apos;evil&apos;.

&apos;John you do realize you are helping bad businesses get away with taking advantage of us.&apos;

&gt;&gt;Why are you repeating yourself? It does not make it true just because you do.

&apos;Along with stacy, laurie, cat, sherri, patrick. But you will never keep me quiet.&apos;

&gt;&gt;What&apos;s wrong with these peole? Oh, that&apos;s right, they speak the real truth also. But, we will continue to expose you.

&apos;That Is why you coninue to personally attack me.&apos;

&gt;&gt;Exposing fraud is not an attack. Still waiting 2 months and counting for proof of your lies deadbeat.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #18 Consumer Comment

 John get over It 

AUTHOR: Charles - Phenix City (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Monday, January 05, 2009
 POSTED: Monday, January 05, 2009 I don&apos;t have to leave john&amp;you are the fraud. I don&apos;t really care how many people are agaisnt me.

I am no deadbeat or anything you accuse me of. I will continue to post complaints.

And you can continue to post your lifes about me. Because It doesn&apos;t matter to me what you say or what anyone else says.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #6 Consumer Suggestion

 Alice do you have a challenge going with chuckie from Phenix, AL 

AUTHOR: Chris - Grand Junction (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Friday, October 12, 2007
 POSTED: Friday, October 12, 2007 You must be trying to surpass chuckie in the &quot;dumbest, most repetitive posts&quot; category.

Some things to consider:

Perhaps the people at these food establishments know you by now and, like you, enjoy getting people they dislike upset just for kicks.

You say you are a &quot;pretty woman&quot; and &quot;highly educated&quot; person. Does it lower your inflated opinion of yourself that you are forced to eat in such cheap restaurants? Is that why you treat the employees so poorly?

It appears that you assume you are better than all of the people who are working in food service. Are you upset because unlike you they are content in their lives?

I know you don&apos;t realize it, but you have a filthy mouth. Do you speak to everyone the way you post here? That could be an answer to why people don&apos;t care what you want. They probably just want to see you go away!

As a final note: If you are as &quot;highly educated&quot; as you claim you should know that people tend to judge you on first impressions. On this site people will see how poorly you write and spell - that is their first impression of you. Next time a &quot;highly educated&quot; person as you present yourself to be should use spell check before posting. You also might want to cut the foul language - it does not help your image or voracity.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #7 Update By Author

 and again... 

AUTHOR: Alice - Miami (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Sunday, October 28, 2007
 POSTED: Sunday, October 28, 2007 ok im going to keep posting complaints about chipotle namely because i am so tired of this society, fast food and the way it is run and the knid of sub-human jerks it is run by these days and the things they get away with doing to custtomers.

Despite numerous complaints to this stupid restaurant, it&apos;s horrible customer service repetitive bullying mistreatment picking on of a customer for absolutely no reason nto that there &apos;is&apos; a reason to pick on a customer but nonetheless just blatant abuse and discrimination, not only have the crackheads that work there never been reprimanded for their negative actions towards me or any customer they may do this to, but they continue to employ the &apos;exact&apos; asme people at that particular location.

It&apos;s almost saying hey we&apos;re proud of being jerks to random women or random customers in general. I haven&apos;t had problems here for a while knowing i go there basically almost everyday but the treatment isn&apos;t always great. there is always something going on when I go on with regards to my being there or ordering something.

As I walked in a 2nd time during the day one day, an employee yelled aggravatedly or as if he was annoyed or in a condescendnig manner &quot;HER SECOND TIME IN TODAY&quot; to other employees, like irritated, as if oh gawd. it&apos;s her 2nd time. why do you care how many times I go into the restaurant? why would it matter and who gives you ro anyone the right to make such a stupid statement. shouldn&apos;t restaurants be happy customers are returning. of course not this one and not with the creeps that work there who like to chastise customers and treat them in a derogatory manner.

Then he&apos;s like &quot;you were in earlier&quot; and wasnt saying it in a nice way like oh welcome again. more like. uh u were here earlier so why are u back?? im thinking. ok and? again why would u care? i dont understand what is wrong with the low class idiots and losers that work at this location, but they are always in some way rude to me, derogatory, negative.

Once I asked the girl for a tiny bit of extra black beans. she literally dumped a huge heaping on there basically ruining my entire meal. was rude about it. was acting as if I was making a huge request, and then was rude overall. why? what is the purpose of this demeaning irrational sick behavior?

As I complained to corporate, nothing was done and a regional manager came in the next day to secretly watch me order, then tell me i was soft spoken. instead of reprimandnig his employees for picking on customers or messing with them his solution to my issues at this restaurant was that I &apos;call in and order to avoid interaction.&quot; Hmm so your

You can&apos;t stop them from being jerks to me giving me dirty looks throwing my food away messing my fod up--of course not. i have to &apos;avoid interaction&quot; what kind of stupid sick company is this? people may say-- don&apos;t go. no sorry I love the food and I go there a lot, im not going to deprive myself of something I like because of bad customer service but in no way shape or form does anyone deserve to be treated in this negative terrifying manner consistently or ever without reprimand by upper management.

now i go in recently, and there is a blonde psycho there who &apos;always&apos; gives me the nastiest looks. she makes a sour face at me. just nasty stuff. i try to ignore her this time. she grudgingly shoves this container of cheese near my food--and i knew she was going to spill cheese all over my food, which she did. i cant say it was intentional but whatever occurred did so in a stupid animalistic manner. rude obnoxious etc.

i then asked for it to be removed from my food as she continued giving me not so nice looks. my opinion is that these people that work in this restaurant and in many food service places are basically lke animals-- they have no manners, no restraint, no discipline no morals. they are just pathetic rude sick people..who for some strange reason feel as if they can treat certain customers in a demeaning way and bully them.

i just think this company overall is so pathetic, the people that work at these locations in particular this one, are bullies psychos and deranged animals and creeps who get away with mistreatment and harassment of yougn women. and corporate obviously just doesn&apos;t care and neither does the regional or upper management who blames mistreatment on the customer for being &apos;soft spoken&apos; and continues to allow their low class garbage employees to do this to people for no reason.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #8 Consumer Comment

 Alice you have a problem 

AUTHOR: Stacey - Dallas (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Sunday, October 28, 2007
 POSTED: Monday, October 29, 2007 You make report after report after report!
The issue is not with all the places you frequent it is with you!
Learn to deal with people and stop blaming everyone for your behavior
No one is out to &quot;get&quot; you - you bring these problems on yourself
Get help
Stacey
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #9 Consumer Comment

 Charles&apos; sister? 

AUTHOR: Scott - Laveen (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Friday, December 05, 2008
 POSTED: Friday, December 05, 2008 OMG a female Charles. You have to be siblings!!
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #10 Consumer Comment

 Why must people bring my name In other complaints 

AUTHOR: Charles - Phenix City (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Sunday, January 04, 2009
 POSTED: Sunday, January 04, 2009 People must be obsessive with me. I don&apos;t know why chris would have a problem with me I have never done anything to him.

Why must people bring my name In other complaints.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #11 Consumer Comment

 Why? Find it hard to believe? 

AUTHOR: John - Califon (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Sunday, January 04, 2009
 POSTED: Sunday, January 04, 2009 That there are other lying deadbeat frauds out there like yourself trying to leech off the system for nothing?
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #12 Consumer Suggestion

 works both ways 

AUTHOR: Cat - Hendersonville (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Sunday, January 04, 2009
 POSTED: Sunday, January 04, 2009 Alice, it works both ways. To be treated with respect you have to treat the employees with courtesy and respect. You post these complaints here and if you speak to them they way you write then I wonder how and more importantly WHY do you expect them to treat you any better than YOU treat THEM?

If you go in their as often as you say you do then why don&apos;t you go in speak up and say &quot;please and thank you&quot; and not say one NEGATIVE word at all for a week. If nothing else, you would be setting a good EXAMPLE and who knows, you might even get what you want. Then you would not have anything to complain about right? Or is that what you actually want? Remember, it works both ways. You get what you ASK for.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #13 Consumer Comment

 Cat 

AUTHOR: Stacey - Dallas (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Sunday, January 04, 2009
 POSTED: Sunday, January 04, 2009 Thanks for your response but Alice aka Melissa aka Anon has posted complaint after complaint about every establishment in Orlando
She/He has no grounds for these complaints - they are just as bad as Charles from Alabama 
Grow up Alice aka Melissa aka Anon
Your complaints lack a whollleeee lot or merit
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #14 Consumer Comment

 People like to ruin things for me 

AUTHOR: Charles - Phenix City (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Monday, January 05, 2009
 POSTED: Monday, January 05, 2009 All people like to do stacy, john, cat Is like to blame people for everything. They love to try to ruin things for me or mess up my complaints.

There Is more rude custormer service then ever these days.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #15 Consumer Comment

 John you are nothing but a bully 

AUTHOR: Charles - Phenix City (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Monday, January 05, 2009
 POSTED: Monday, January 05, 2009 John you are nothing but a bully. And you hate It when people stand up to you. All you do Is create more problems for the poster of the complaint like how you are treating me.

But I will not back down, so you can accuse me&amp;call me a liar all you want. It doesn&apos;t get you anywhere. Because I report the truth.

You think you can get away with harassing me or bullying me that Is why you continue to bother me, you are nothing but scum.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #16 Consumer Comment

 John you do realize you are helping these businesses get away with wrong doing 

AUTHOR: Charles - Phenix City (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Monday, January 05, 2009
 POSTED: Monday, January 05, 2009 John you do realize you are helping bad businesses get away with taking advantage of us. Along with stacy, laurie, cat, sherri, patrick.

But you will never keep me quiet.

That Is why you coninue to personally attack me.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #17 Consumer Comment

 No one&apos;s stopping you from leaving....in fact, I have seen several requests that you do. 

AUTHOR: John - Califon (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Monday, January 05, 2009
 POSTED: Monday, January 05, 2009 &apos;John you are nothing but a bully&apos;

&gt;&gt;Just because you are proven wrong and to be a liar, fraud, thief, and deadbeat doesn&apos;t make someone a bully.

&apos;John you are nothing but a bully.&apos;

&gt;&gt;We read this the first time....is it somehow more important now or do you think it will actually make it true just because you say it and repeat it even though you really have nothing to contribute as always?

&apos;And you hate It when people stand up to you.&apos;

&gt;&gt;As always, please post proof to yet another one of your bullsh*t lines. Who actually &apos;stands up to me&apos;? There is no one that needs to.

&apos;All you do Is create more problems for the poster of the complaint like how you are treating me.&apos;

&gt;&gt;Again, post proof of yet another bullsh*t accusation

&apos;But I will not back down, so you can accuse me&amp;call me a liar all you want.&apos;

&gt;&gt;I will and will continue to post the proof tio back it up with your very own words.

&apos;It doesn&apos;t get you anywhere.&apos;

&gt;&gt;I don&apos;t need to go anywhere so there is no &apos;doesn&apos;t get you anywhere&apos;. It does however, show innocent people reading your crap what a fraud you are.

&apos;Because I report the truth.&apos;

&gt;&gt;You just lied right there.

&apos;You think you can get away with harassing me or bullying me that Is why you continue to bother me, you are nothing but scum.&apos;

&gt;&gt;Exposing you for the lying, thieving, fraudulent deadbeat you are is not &apos;harassing&apos; you. Just because you don&apos;t like reading the truth, you are not being &apos;harassed&apos; yet innocent people with real issues are being informed. You are the lazy bag of shit living off the taxes that I and others pay instead of going out to get a job, thus YOU are the true scum.

&apos;John you do realize you are helping these businesses get away with wrong doing&apos;

&gt;&gt;Again, please post proof of these bullshit accusations. Just because YOU don&apos;t get your way does not mean a business is &apos;bad&apos; and &apos;evil&apos;.

&apos;John you do realize you are helping bad businesses get away with taking advantage of us.&apos;

&gt;&gt;Why are you repeating yourself? It does not make it true just because you do.

&apos;Along with stacy, laurie, cat, sherri, patrick. But you will never keep me quiet.&apos;

&gt;&gt;What&apos;s wrong with these peole? Oh, that&apos;s right, they speak the real truth also. But, we will continue to expose you.

&apos;That Is why you coninue to personally attack me.&apos;

&gt;&gt;Exposing fraud is not an attack. Still waiting 2 months and counting for proof of your lies deadbeat.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #18 Consumer Comment

 John get over It 

AUTHOR: Charles - Phenix City (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Monday, January 05, 2009
 POSTED: Monday, January 05, 2009 I don&apos;t have to leave john&amp;you are the fraud. I don&apos;t really care how many people are agaisnt me.

I am no deadbeat or anything you accuse me of. I will continue to post complaints.

And you can continue to post your lifes about me. Because It doesn&apos;t matter to me what you say or what anyone else says.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #19 Consumer Comment

 Yes charles, get over it. 

AUTHOR: John - Califon (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Tuesday, January 06, 2009
 POSTED: Tuesday, January 06, 2009 &apos;I don&apos;t have to leave john&amp;you are the fraud.&apos;

&gt;&gt;Still waiting for the proof....but you can&apos;t because it is a lie.

&apos;I don&apos;t really care how many people are agaisnt me.&apos;

&gt;&gt;Yes you do as you keep responding.

&apos;I am no deadbeat or anything you accuse me of.&apos;

&gt;&gt;Well, yes you are and I have proven it with your own words.

&apos;I will continue to post complaints.&apos;

&gt;&gt;Of course you will instead of going out and getting a job.

&apos;And you can continue to post your lifes about me.&apos;

&gt;&gt;What is &apos;posting your lifes&apos;? I have never posted anything about my life on here. If you are TRYING to say &apos;lies&apos;, well I have provided the proof that my statements are in fact correct....using your very own words while you still have not provided one shred of proof.

&apos;Because It doesn&apos;t matter to me what you say or what anyone else says.&apos;

&gt;&gt;Obviously it doesn&apos;t as you continue to crap in people&apos;s threads and post lies and fraud after being asked repeatedly not to. When are you going to leave like you promised in your fraudulent schneider thread?
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #20 Consumer Comment

 Alice, I think you have a lawsuit. 

AUTHOR: Andy - New York (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Tuesday, January 06, 2009
 POSTED: Tuesday, January 06, 2009 Asking a customer to repeat their order using the flimsy excuse that they didn&apos;t hear her is unreasonable excessive harrassment of a customer. It is unacceptable. I suggest you contact an attorney immediately. Please indicate to them what other types of harrassment to place against you by Chipotle. We must put an end to this intolerable behavior. If you continue to go there please check your food carefully for hockers before eating.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #21 Consumer Comment

 I haven&apos;t done anything wrong 

AUTHOR: Charles - Phenix City (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Tuesday, January 06, 2009
 POSTED: Tuesday, January 06, 2009 I haven&apos;t done anything wrong or lied about anything. Look @ how these business treat custormers like how sprint ripped me off.

Its all right for businesses to steal money from us&amp;take advantage from us, but when we stop letting them do It to us.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #22 Consumer Comment

 I see stacy Is back running her mouth 

AUTHOR: Charles - Phenix City (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Thursday, January 08, 2009
 POSTED: Thursday, January 08, 2009 I see stacy Is back running her big mouth. We all have the right to post comments. But what stacy doesn&apos;t have the right Is to post lies about people she don&apos;t even know.

Like how she Is treating me. Stacy Is nothing but a liar.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #23 Consumer Comment

 I see stacy still running her mouth 

AUTHOR: Charles - Phenix City (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Monday, January 12, 2009
 POSTED: Monday, January 12, 2009 I see stacy still running her mouth. She thinks she can talk to people abusive&amp;hatefil well she can&apos;t.

The reason why she&amp;others continue to bother me cause they think they can get away with It. Well there day Is coming they all reap what they sew. You just don&apos;t make fun of people.

Stacy Is the liar.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #24 Consumer Comment

 Stacey rules and charles drools. 

AUTHOR: John - Califon (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Monday, January 12, 2009
 POSTED: Monday, January 12, 2009 Why are you repeating yourself? It is not making it any more important nor will it ever make it true. When are you going to stop lying? When are you going to leave like you promised in your fraudulent schneider thread?
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #25 Consumer Comment

 John sucks and stacy drools 

AUTHOR: Charles - Phenix City (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Tuesday, January 13, 2009
 POSTED: Tuesday, January 13, 2009 John sucks and stacy drools. John Is just back trying to feed his ego buy putting others down the best thing to do Is ignore john.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #26 Consumer Comment

 To Andy - PLEASE DO NOT ENCOURAGE ALICE, OR WHOMEVER SHE POSTS AS THESE DAYS 

AUTHOR: Laurie - Haslet (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Tuesday, January 13, 2009
 POSTED: Tuesday, January 13, 2009 She is just one person who treats people badly everywhere she goes and then complains that the people she complains about are the ones doing it to her.

She indicated in her response the waiter said &quot;she&apos;s back a 2nd time today&quot;

That is because SHE IS THE PROBLEM - not the businesses that are completely FED UP WITH HER.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #27 Consumer Comment

 I only have ONE gripe with the Chipotle&apos;s here 

AUTHOR: Joe - Austin (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Tuesday, January 13, 2009
 POSTED: Tuesday, January 13, 2009 THE CHIPOTLE&apos;S I atr in is located on Guadalupe Street which is right across the street from the University of texas and the food was mediocre but the PRICE WAS WAY TOO HIGH!

I guess that is because of the OVERHEAD FROM HELL which is way expensive because the sorry real estate developers gouge rent from business owners in Northwest Hills and dear the universities because they figure the well-heeled students are a captive audience and the business should be able to make it back.

I only has 15 minutes for lunch and I managed to grab the burrito in there...It wasn&apos;t really authentically Mexican and I don&apos;t care to eat there anymore but the people were very nice to me.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #28 Consumer Comment

 This Is why businesses get away with there crap 

AUTHOR: Charles - Phenix City (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Wednesday, January 14, 2009
 POSTED: Wednesday, January 14, 2009 This Is why businesses get away with there crap. They get away with being rude to custormers then people on this site blame them also.

We all have rights not to be treated like crap from businesses or have our money stolen from us.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #29 Consumer Comment

 The real problem is 

AUTHOR: John - Califon (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Wednesday, January 14, 2009
 POSTED: Wednesday, January 14, 2009 they didn&apos;t &apos;get away&apos; with anything. This, and all of your fraudulent reports are just that....fraudulent reports. Just because you didn&apos;t get your way, does not mean anyone else did something wrong (except yourself).
When are you going to leave us like you promised in your fraudulent schneider report?
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #30 Consumer Comment

 John sucks&amp;stacy drools 

AUTHOR: Charles - Phenix City (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Wednesday, January 14, 2009
 POSTED: Wednesday, January 14, 2009 There Is nothing fraudulent or made up In my complaints you are just making up things yourself&amp;attacking me.

I don&apos;t care If you or anyone else doesn&apos;t believe me but there Is nothing fraudlent or made up In any of my complaints.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #31 Consumer Comment

 OBVIOUSLY WRITTEN BY TEENAGERS WHO NEED TO GROW UP 

AUTHOR: Joe - Austin (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Wednesday, January 14, 2009
 POSTED: Wednesday, January 14, 2009 stop THE IMMATURE CYBERBULLYING ALREADY AND GIVE US AN HONEST POSTING.

YOU CREEPY LITTLE KIDS NEED TO JOIN THE MILITARY OR GET A LIFE AND STOP HANGING AROUND THIS PLACE.

YOU WEREN&apos;T RIPPED OFF.

YOU JUST DON&apos;T HAVE ENOUGH TO DO BESIDES PURSUE YOUR PETTY ADOLESCENT VENDETTAS ON AN INTERNET SITE THAT IS NOT DESIGNED FOR THIS.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #32 Consumer Comment

 Why do you repeat yourself deadbeat? 

AUTHOR: John - Califon (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Wednesday, January 14, 2009
 POSTED: Wednesday, January 14, 2009 No matter how many times you do, it will never come true.

&apos;There Is nothing fraudulent or made up In my complaints you are just making up things yourself&amp;attacking me.&apos;

&gt;&gt;I have PROVEN WITH YOUR OWN WORDS that you have thus making this statement another of your many, many, many lies. Posting the truth is not an &apos;attack&apos; just because you don;t like being exposed for the lying fraud you are.

&apos;I don&apos;t care If you or anyone else doesn&apos;t believe me but there Is nothing fraudlent or made up In any of my complaints.&apos;

&gt;&gt;Yes you do (yet another of your lies) or else you&apos;d leave like many have asked you to do as well as you promised in your fraudulent schneider report.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #33 Consumer Suggestion

 Watch your language and mind your manners 

AUTHOR: Cat - Hendersonville (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Wednesday, January 14, 2009
 POSTED: Wednesday, January 14, 2009 That is what I was taught growing up. To be treated with RESPECT you have to RESPECT others. I see people telling other people they &quot;suck&quot; . It is no wonder that people who tell strangers this complain that they are not being treated with respect. I have never met Charles yet in another posting above he was all over me and I had not even addressed him. I addressed the issue of respect. So, once again, if you want to be respected , waited on when you go into a resturant then be nice, courteous and respectful! Apparently, a few were not taught this growing up.

End of Story
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #34 Consumer Comment

 How rude 

AUTHOR: Stacey - Dallas (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Wednesday, January 14, 2009
 POSTED: Thursday, January 15, 2009 Grow up Charles
As for Alice aka Melissa aka Fajita girl
Your posts have no merit - you seem to blame every establishment in Orlando for your behavior -
Grow up, get a job and get a life 
your posts are idiotic - many, many people have told you this but you seem to post more complaints - me thinks you are an egomaniac who enjoys all the attention be it positive or negative
SEEK HELP
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #35 Consumer Comment

 Stacy you need to grow up 

AUTHOR: Charles - Phenix City (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Thursday, January 15, 2009
 POSTED: Thursday, January 15, 2009 They are many grown adults on here who need to grow up like you and john. Then ya&apos;ll have the nerve to tell me to grow up.

I am not responding to john anymore sense he continues his hatred cause he doesn&apos;t like the truth&amp;he continues to attack me. Ya&apos;ll are just mad cause I wont let myself get taking advantage again.

So naturally john calls me a liar, I am no longer going to waste my time with this nonsense. The only liar here Is john.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #36 Consumer Comment

 John loves to ruin everyones complaint 

AUTHOR: Charles - Phenix City (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Thursday, January 15, 2009
 POSTED: Thursday, January 15, 2009 John loves to ruin everyone complaints like how he Is trying to ruin my complaints.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #37 Consumer Comment

 To Laurie 

AUTHOR: Andy - New York (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Friday, January 16, 2009
 POSTED: Friday, January 16, 2009 I don&apos;t disagree with anything you wrote. I feel that no matter what comments are written about Alice&apos;s complaint she will continue to go to this fast food restaurant repeatedly every day, and complain about the staff. Nothing will change her routine.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #38 Consumer Comment

 you people need some serious help 

AUTHOR: Anonymous - Miami (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Tuesday, February 17, 2009
 POSTED: Tuesday, February 17, 2009 are you ignorant white trash freaks acting as if, someone who is being mistreated at a rsetaurant should not go back when they like the food?
or it&apos;s &apos;their fault&apos; for going back..... first off most of you are stalkers and nutjobs yourselves...negative mean bitter eople.....youre probably the employees there who are treating peopel badly for no reason.

you low life people have no morals no civility nothing....on top of that u sit around fighting on forums and picking on people posting reports....
that is so scary to me....that people as stupid low class and ignorant as you thinks taht your backwards opinions on basic treatment
customer service and morality even mean something.... I think you&apos;re pests and the lowest form of scum to exist on this planet almost....
and you also don&apos;t seem to go away....just here harping nagging whining arguing such sad lowly pathetic people..... i really wish ROR would get rid of your incessant garbage replies and insults
you are the most pathetic creeps to exist, unfortunately I can&apos;t begin to express in writing what kind of worthelss people you are....
t&apos;s so sad taht society allows your ignorant negativity to be displayed youre bullies and abusers not much else and people who are bullies
are people with no worth morals or decency....just like all the scam and con artists and abusers being reported about on these websites
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #39 Consumer Comment

 Yes, you do need serious help. 

AUTHOR: John - Califon (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Tuesday, February 17, 2009
 POSTED: Tuesday, February 17, 2009 How are you driving out of town-since you have alienated all the restaurants there-with your alleged troubled vehicle from Drive that you filed a fraudulent report on?
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #40 Consumer Comment

 Yep... 

AUTHOR: Edgeman - Chico (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Tuesday, February 17, 2009
 POSTED: Tuesday, February 17, 2009 I think that the post from Melissa (or whatever name she currently uses) on 2/17/09 may be a good example as to why restaurant employees in her area dislike her.
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #41 Update By Author

 bad CSR 

AUTHOR: Anonymous - Miami (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Sunday, March 08, 2009
 POSTED: Sunday, March 08, 2009 most of the pests and low lifes that inhabit this place are obviously very uneducated, uncivil, low adn stupid people. any intelligent person would ignore their white trash menial nonsense. More on chipotle- At first they exhibited horrible treatment for a long time, with the regional manager even telling me that in order to avoid &apos;mistreatment&apos; I would have to order online...which to be is absurd that they cannot stop their employees from mistreating customers or even train them to be decent human beings...yet instead gigglingly tell customers that they should order online and avoid interaction altogether--way to go. afterwards the employees were decent, civil and even nice for a long time with maybe a couple of not so good experiences. Recently, went in to purchase an item, and upon walking in an employee began whispering about me to his co worker. The person took my order, and again tried making me repeat &apos;everything&apos; several times...even after repeating what i said still making me repeat it...then made a semi derogatory comment @ me to her co-worker stating &quot;still can&apos;t hear her&quot; kind of snickering though she heard me fine...if I said peppers she would say &quot;peppers&quot;? And i would say yes...then she&apos;d say &quot;PEPPERS&quot;? and have me say yes again for no reason....and on and off semi rude/hostile treatment from some of the other co-workers. Some of them however are nice... but very rarely....it&apos;s generally condescending or rude service, for no reason at all just because they seem to want to pick on certain custoemrs or people and feel their white or any other race trash right to do so, which they do not have those rights or that place. What has the world come to today---nasty people everywhere almost basically....and for all the psycho/sociopaths trying to complain abuot food service complaints....it&apos;s not jst with me and it&apos;s not just food service it&apos;s everywhere that&apos;s b/c society is now riddled with negative bitter crazy sick and demented people just about everywhere so have fun because most of you negative psycho posters are those very people along with all the bad companies being reported about daily....for all you losers here who sit around and bicker as if your opinions matter... what kind of disgtusting low lifes are you taht you feel as if your negativity and lies and slander are in any way anything other than total garbage and dog sh*t... you&apos;re the sick reason places like this exist because creeps and scumbags like you exist on this planet...
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #42 Consumer Comment

 Yes, you do need serious help. 

AUTHOR: John - Califon (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Sunday, March 08, 2009
 POSTED: Sunday, March 08, 2009 How are you driving out of town-since you have alienated all the restaurants there-with your alleged troubled vehicle from Drive that you filed a fraudulent report on?
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 
 #43 Consumer Comment

 Wow 

AUTHOR: Lvparalegal - Las Vegas (U.S.A.)

SUBMITTED: Monday, March 16, 2009
 POSTED: Monday, March 16, 2009 Not much is more amusing than Charles&apos; posts. Tell me, Charles- how is that &quot;their day will come,&quot; in reference to those who have &quot;bullied&quot; you? You really are delusional.

And as far as the author of this thread... Why, WHY would you continue to frequent a business which, in your eyes, continually harasses you and provides horrible service? I don&apos;t know about the rest of RoR&apos;s members, but when I get bad service more than once, and sometimes just once if it&apos;s severe enough, I don&apos;t return. Maybe it&apos;s just me, but I don&apos;t reward bad service with my time and money.

How is it a rip-off, which is what this board is named for, if you receive other than what you are expecting because you voluntarily return time and time again to engage those who are doing you wrong?
 Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 Report&amp;Rebuttal Respond to this report! What&apos;s this? 
Are you an owner, employee or ex-employee with either negative or positive information about the company or individual, or can you provide &quot;insider information&quot; on this company?
 Also a victim? What&apos;s this? 
Are you also a victim of the same company or individual? Want Justice? File a Rip-off Report, help other consumers to be educated and don&apos;t let them get away with it!
 Repair Your Reputation! What&apos;s this? 
Got Reports filed against you? Resolve the issues and rebuild trust through our Corporate Advocacy Program.

Corporate Advocacy Program: The best way to manage and repair your business reputation. Hiding negative complaints is only a Band-Aid. Consumers want to see how businesses take care of business. All businesses will get complaints. How those businesses take care of those complaints is what separates good businesses from bad businesses.
 Search for additional reports 
If you would like to see more Rip-off Reports on this company/individual, search here:
 Search Tips 
In order to assure the best results in your search:

 Keep the name short&amp;simple, and try different variations of the name. Do not include &quot;.com&quot;, &quot;S&quot;, &quot;Inc.&quot;, &quot;Corp&quot;, or &quot;LLC&quot; at the end of the Company name. Use only the first/main part of a name to get best results. Only search one name at a time if Company has many AKA&apos;s. 
 
 
 
 Advertisers above have met our
 strict standards for business conduct . 


 


 Home File a Report Consumer Resources Search Link to Ripoff Report 

 Privacy Policy Terms of Service FAQ About Us Contact Us Why Ripoff Report will not release author information! 

 Thank You Emails! Corporate Advocacy Program: How to repair your business reputation. Ed Magedson - Ripoff Report Founder 

 Want to sue Ripoff Report? Donate to our Legal Defense Feedback widget provided by WasThis BadBusinessBureau.com 
 
Copyright©1998-2012, Ripoff Report. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
