<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008565" url="http://www.my3cents.com/reviews/burger_king/drivethru" time="2012-07-13-02:02" support="7" score="0.0190512195825408" bingtitle="Burger King - Drive Thru Reviews and Complaints" webtitle="Consumer Reviews on Burger King Drive Thru">
			<query id="001386" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="001197" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000538" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="001196" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000552" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="001481" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="001198" bing-rank="241"/>
	<description>... almost 2o minutes to get my order then got my order and they messed up my husband burger and they didn&apos;t give us a receipt ... to me at any other fast food restaurant. ...</description>
	<body>
		Write a Review  
 
 Consumer News, Tips&amp;Recalls Newsletter 

 Email: 
 
 

 Home &gt; Food Services &gt; Restaurants &gt; Burger King &gt;   

Burger King Drive Thru
 
 
Customer Reviews&amp;Complaints:

 Wrong Order Again?? - Drive-Thru Customer Service - Complaint 
HARRISBURG, PENNSYLVANIA -- I suppose I should have realized something might be amiss when I noticed the drive-thru employee on the phone this morning at ...
 -- Posted by Kris10 on 01/05/2012 
 Keep it to yourself - Simple hamburger drive through order - Complaint 
Well I get regular bad service and food from the Burger King store in my area Mill Run Columbus Ohio (you know who you are). ...
 -- Posted by guyr_cols63 on 09/26/2011 
 
 Waiting To Long In Drive Through - Complaint -- Posted by pnrspatty200245 on 09/18/2011 
 Worst Drive Thru Order Taking Ever! - Tendergrill Chicken Sandwich - Complaint 
SAN BERNARDINO, CALIFORNIA -- If you value your lunch break, never, ever get lunch at San Bernardino Burger King on 205 East Redlands Avenue. I went to the ...
 -- Posted by CarlH on 12/17/2010 
 Insulting, Horrible Service, Attitude - Drive Thru Person-Told Me Not To Come Back, Take My Money Elsewhere - Complaint 
MUNDELEIN, ILLINOIS -- I work at a store almost next to my Burger King Location in Mundelein IL.

I always order the same thing, at least 3 times ...
 -- Posted by shaka915 on 09/27/2010 
 Bad Service!!!! - Drive Through Window - Complaint 
BIRMINGHAM, ALABAMA -- On 9/8/2010, between 11:30pm and 12am, I went through the drive through to get some sandwiches for me and a friend of mine. When ...
 -- Posted by wikkicatfish on 09/09/2010 
 The worst drive thru ever - wrong food - Complaint 
THIS IS THE WORST DRIVE TRUE EVER,, I GO TO THIS BURGER KING NOT MUCH BECAUSE THEY TAKE TO LONG TO SERVE YOU AND THEIR FRIES ...
 -- Posted by sweetness29 on 06/02/2010 
 Fast Food Convenience A Farce - Drive Thru / Hot Chocolate - Complaint 
On a cold January morning while awaiting a prescription to be filled at the local pharmacy, a nice cup of Hot Cocoa sounded soothing. ...
 -- Posted by Mrs. Filippi on 01/24/2010 
 Slowest Service/Nasty Food - Drive-Thru Service - Complaint 
MADISON, MISSISSIPPI -- I waited in the drive-thru line behind 2 cars for 20 minutes. I got my food and the order was wrong.... exactly what I asked ...
 -- Posted by luvtoeatBK on 01/03/2010 
 Burger King drive thru srcew up - Complaint 
A rather large group of us went through the drive thru after celebrating our last final. The driver, being the only sober one, ...
 -- Posted by moldan on 12/16/2009 
 Poor and Untimely Service! - Drive-thru - Complaint 
GALLUP, NEW MEXICO -- Frequently each morning before work, I try to grab a &quot;fast food&quot; meal. Around the corner from my job is a McDonald&apos;s and a Burger ...
 -- Posted by BKLostAnother1 on 12/09/2009 
 Bad Service - Drive Through - Complaint 
CENTRAL FALLS, RHODE ISLAND -- November 12, 09 I went to a Burger King. I went through the drive through. Long story short, I was told to pull aside to wait ...
 -- Posted by bad buisness on 11/12/2009 
 Drive Thru Customers ALERT! - Complaint 
LOS ANGELES -- I was very ill and went to the drive thru for food. I received my order, and as I was driving home, opened the bag to eat something. ...
 -- Posted by Millaydee on 11/09/2009 
 Burger King - Lethbridge, AB - Out of date juice, disgusting food - Drive through lunch order - Complaint 
LETHBRIDGE -- Just went through drive through at the Burger King, Lethbridge (Fairmont) location. Irritated that they do not have kids meal ...
 -- Posted by prairiegal on 10/29/2009 
 Drive thru rudeness - Complaint -- Posted by yvonne51 on 10/22/2009 
 Poor Service - Drive-Thru - Complaint 
LOUISVILLE, KENTUCKY -- McDonalds earned more of my business, today, thanks to my local BK. I ordered a breakfast sandwich and was immediately told ...
 -- Posted by TRUEAMERICAN on 08/20/2009 
 Awful Service By Manager - Drive Thru - Complaint 
PROVIDENCE, RHODE ISLAND -- Burger King Pleasent Valley Parkway in Providence has lost all the the Coca Cola employees as of 2:15pm on July 13 2009..It is ...
 -- Posted by kj0679 on 07/13/2009 
 Who Can I Contact? - Drive-Thru - Question -- Posted by Donella on 03/22/2009 
 Poor Drive-Thru Service - Customer Service At Drive-Thru - Complaint 
CROWLEY, LOUISIANA -- I normally would not complain about it but this is just getting ridiculous. Normally on Saturdays we like to get burgers and ...
 -- Posted by shesprettyodd on 03/14/2009 
 Cle Elum Drive Thru - Long Wait&amp;Poor Customer Service - Drive Through - Cle Elum, WA - Complaint 
CLE ELUM, WASHINGTON -- This review is for Burger King store #12731. We were on our way to a wedding, and decided to stop for a quick bite to eat. ...
 -- Posted by Tagg on 08/17/2008 
 Bad Customer Service! - Drive-Thru Customer Service - Complaint 
APOPKA, FLORIDA -- I just went by Burger King (store #2167 in Apopka, FL) on 07/15/08 at 12:30 p.m. and received the worst attitude from a drive-thru ...
 -- Posted by LRP on 07/15/2008 
 Extremely Rude Drive-Thru Employee - Rude Employee - Complaint 
ALEXANDRIA, MINNESOTA -- My daughter and I recently visited our local Burger King in Alexandria, MN and left absolutely shocked by the rude &quot;service&quot; ...
 -- Posted by unhappy BK customer on 07/03/2008 
 Too Long In The Drive Thru - Drive Thru - Complaint 
CONWAY, ARKANSAS -- I got in line today behind five cars at the drive thru at Burger King on Highway 65 in Conway, AR. I remained in line for approximately ...
 -- Posted by ma rains on 06/15/2008 
 I want a Whopper! - Drive-Thru - Complaint 
ROCKFORD, ILLINOIS -- 1138 E State St

On a couple of occasions I&apos;ve attempted to visit this location, only to drive off before ordering because ...
 -- Posted by LarryDan on 02/27/2008 
 Drive-thru - Drive-thru window - Complaint -- Posted by Mrs J on 01/05/2008 
 Mixed-up order - Drive-thru order - Complaint 
HAZLEHURST -- On December 2, 2007 we ordered 2 #9&apos;s, bacon melt, and a #6, value meals. Our order printed on the order screen reflected this. ...
 -- Posted by leemurr on 12/03/2007 
 BK now has walk up drive thru; No consumer hotline - Walk-up drive thru - Complaint 
VISTA, CALIFORNIA -- I went to Burger King off Melrose in Vista,CA. I frequent the restaurant often but was not happy with what went down tonight. ...
 -- Posted by walk up drive thru at BK Not thrilled on 08/24/2007 
 Terrible Customer Service - Drive Thru Service - Complaint 
HILLIARD, OHIO -- I was with my daughter on a trip to the drive thru at a Burger King in Hilliard, OH. The store is located near the intersection ...
 -- Posted by harleydiva on 07/14/2007 
 Poor Service - Drive thru service - Complaint 
I do have to say, I like burger king food. I don&apos;t eat it often, but I&apos;m a sucker for their chicken sandwich. Anyways, one day ...
 -- Posted by sertasheeplover on 06/12/2007 
 Rude Employees on Drive through Window - Customer Service - Complaint 
FRISCO, TEXAS -- On Wed, May 30 I made a quick stop at the Burger King in Frisco TX (8725 Preston Rd). I proceeded through the drive thru service ...
 -- Posted by PinkLady on 05/30/2007 
 Drive Through Dis-Service - Drive Through Service - Informative 
KINGSTON, PENNSYLVANIA -- You know how when you pull up to a fast food drive through order station such as at Burger King, the order taker seems to jump ...
 -- Posted by HaroldSays on 09/30/2006 
 RUDE SERVICE - DRIVE-THRU - Complaint 
TEMPLE TERRACE, FLORIDA -- I used the Burger-King drive-thru placed my order ,acknowledged the order and amount and pulled forward a few feet to look at ...
 -- Posted by TALON1957 on 05/15/2005 
 Stupid Drive Thru Employee - Drive Thru - Informative 
HAMILTON, OHIO -- My stepfather and I stopped at a Burger King in Hamilton, Ohio, to get my two hamburgers plain only with ketchup, a large order ...
 -- Posted by mjholly on 02/23/2004 
 

 
 

 Consumer Tools | My Account | Write a Review | Compare Company Ratings Businesses: Respond to Consumers HOME | FAQ | Advertise | About Us | Site Rules | Terms and Conditions | Privacy Policy | RSS 


 Copyright 2000-2012 My3cents, LLC  Browse in another language
	</body>
</document>
