<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008868" url="http://jobssearchengine.net/Discussion/Other/Question-I-have-an-interview-with-walgreens-for-a-pharmacy-technician-position-54140.html" time="2012-07-13-02:18" support="5" score="0.011513889510201807" bingtitle="I have an interview with walgreens for a pharmacy technician ..." webtitle="I have an interview with walgreens for a pharmacy technician position? #54140">
			<query id="000125" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000908" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="001505" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000750" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000062" bing-rank="222"/>
	<description>Are there any places to search for legitimate ... In a fast food restaurant; how to get promoted from crew to ... are many different crew positions.....(front counter ...</description>
	<body>
		Jobs Search Engine 
Find a Better Job Today
 
 Home Post a Job Career Discussion Links RSS Feeds Contact us 
 
Find Jobs
   Home &gt; Careers&amp;Employment &gt; Other &gt; I have an interview with walgreens for a pharmacy technician position? 
I have an interview with walgreens for a pharmacy technician position?
 
Category: Other 
 Mexi Taxi 

What should i do to prepare for this because i really want the job. If anyone out their work for Walgreen&apos;s pharmacy and can share some of their wisdom with me it would be greatly appracited.
 
 
 Sabrina 
First of all the word is spelt: appreciate. Second, I hope your math skills are better than your spelling skills. A sample question you may be asked is: To dispense an order calling for: prednisone 5 mg, one t.i.d. X 3 days; one b.i.d. X 3 days; one q.d. X 3 days, the total medication needed is: ___. (Answer is 18) and don&apos;t worry if you don&apos;t know the sig codes (such as b.i.d, t.i.d, etc) that they&apos;ll teach you. But you will have to be able to do simple math&amp;also have good customer service skills. If you get the job then they&apos;ll send you to get state certified. Oh and you have to be 18 or older for pharmacy but that&apos;s really it.
 
 Tony 
Think about what they are likely to want from someone in the job. For this type of role it might include

-good interpersonal skills

-team player

-attention to detail

-great customer service - ie friendly and pleasant

Then consider based on your experience where you have examples of these skills. A great guide for interview success is here

 http://ezinearticles.com/?Interview-Succ 

The key is in the time spent in preparation. This means you can be confident and polished on the day
 

 Share this on your favorite networks 
Career Discussions
 
 Have questions on physician assistant!! anyone out there a PA grad or kno bout it? ( 2 answers)

Sooo i want to become a physician assistant. i am taking my basics at the moment so i jus want to be a step ahead. like i heard that its very difficul ...
 
 Can you answer my UK employment law question? ( 3 answers)

The scenario is this: my girlfriend has been an agency worker for nearly a year (same position). The job has now been advertised for a permanent posit ...
 
 What should I go to college for? Info inside? ( 1 answers)

I really want to travel the world and learn of other cultures and religions! I think it would be really cool to travel the world and take photos of ev ...
 
 Where to find jobs that you can do at home? ( 3 answers)

I am a stay-at-home mom and wish to add a bit to my family&apos;s income. Are there any places to search for legitimate home jobs - doing something s ...
 
 Where can i get a decent job? ( 1 answers)

I live in arlington, virginia. i don&apos;t care if they deduct from my paycheck(like 25%).I need 105 dollars for something. I&apos;ll need it it 2-4 ...
 
 Should I accept my cousin&apos;s job offer? ( 2 answers)

I have a degree in Theatre, but had to move back to a small city with nothing to offer. No agencies, no place to audition, no workshop classes, nothin ...
 
 What a potential employer can/cannot use SSN for? ( 2 answers)

A hiring manager for a local company has used my fiance&apos;s social security number to contact local businesses and the unemployment office to inves ...
 
 Percentages of getting a job ? one out of what ? ? ( 3 answers)

(: just wanna know ! ...
 
 I have an important question about how to get a promotion...? ( 3 answers)

In a fast food restaurant; how to get promoted from crew to supervisor..........There are many different crew positions.....(front counter, drive-thro ...
 
 Which job? Dentist or midwife? ( 3 answers)

I don&apos;t know which to do? Childbirth is very interesting to me, but i don&apos;t know if i want to be a midwife because the pay is bad, hours are ...
 
 

   
   
Jobs Search Engine

Find a better job searching multiple sites! Are you an employer? Create an account today and post your job for free. Thousands of possible candidates can see your job posting!
 
Categories

 Accounting&amp;Finance Advertising&amp;Public Relations Arts&amp;Entertainment&amp;Publishing Banking&amp;Mortgage Clerical&amp;Administrative Construction&amp;Facilities Customer Service Education&amp;Training Engineering&amp;Architecture Government&amp;Military Healthcare Hospitality&amp;Travel Human Resources Insurance Internet&amp;New Media Law Enforcement&amp;Security Legal Management Consulting Manufacturing&amp;Operations Marketing Non-Profit&amp;Volunteer Pharmaceutical&amp;Biotech Real Estate Restaurant&amp;Food Service Retail Sales Technology Telecommunications Transportation&amp;Logistics Other New Jobs 
 
   
Archive: All jobs - Partners - Links - RSS - All RSS Feeds - Privacy Policy 

0.034

Copyright (c) 2009 - 2012 jobssearchengine.net - All rights reserved. Design by Free CSS Templates .
	</body>
</document>
