<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008093" url="http://breadedtenderloin.wordpress.com/2010/12/31/the-pawn-shop-indianapolis/" time="2012-07-13-01:10" support="1" score="0.01153938232994767" bingtitle="The Pawn Shop, Indianapolis. « All tenderloins, all the time." webtitle="The Pawn Shop, Indianapolis.All tenderloins, all the time.">
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="85"/>
	<description>... just West of Keystone, the Pawn Shop is located in an old fast food restaurant ... won’t be disappointed if you order ... Leave a Reply Cancel reply</description>
	<body>
		All tenderloins, all the time. 

The finest food known to man
 
 Home Just who is The Tenderloin Connoisseur? 
 
The Pawn Shop, Indianapolis.

 The Pawn Shop pub has been on my list to try for quite some time now, recommended by friends.  The holiday season has been quite busy for us, but things are slowing down now, and it’s time to get the reviews rolling again!

Those of you who have been around Indy for a while might remember the Pawn Shop from when it was up on College Avenue…I believe it was where Binkley’s is presently located.  I had visited there once or twice, but that’s been 20 or more years ago, and I honestly don’t remember much about it.

Located on 54th, just West of Keystone, the Pawn Shop is located in an old fast food restaurant building, but upon stepping inside, it has the feel of a bar that has been there forever.  They obviously have a lot of regulars, at lunchtime the majority of folks coming in were greeted by name.  Although we had never been there before, the atmosphere was welcoming.

 

 I knew from the start that I wanted to try the tenderloin.  As we perused the menu, the server told us that the special of the day was 1/2 tenderloin and beer cheese soup, which was what Holly elected to try….more about that later.  I chose the full tenderloin.

The sandwich itself?  One word comes to mind…sublime.  This was a darn near perfect tenderloin.  The meat was moist and tasty, and the breading was the perfect compliment to the meat.  Nice and crispy, and it stayed that way for the life of the sandwich….no getting soggy for this one!  The bun was nicely toasted, and the sandwich was dressed exactly as I requested it to be.  This is, from first bite to last, a 5 out of 5 bite tenderloin.  You won’t be disappointed if you order this hand breaded delight!  It sells for $6.75, and, apparently, that includes chips.

I WISH I could say the rest of our experience was just as good….but, it’s time for the other shoe to drop.  I ordered the breaded tenderloin with fries, and I got the tenderloin with chips…and they appeared to be the crumbs out of the bottom of the chip bag.  Anyone who knows me personally knows that I’m not really a picky diner, but I DO expect to get what I ordered.  That lack of attention to detail could cost them a repeat visit from some folks.  On top of that, after we finished our soft drinks, we were never offered a refill.

Holly’s Beer Cheese Soup was mediocre, at best.  It was as if someone took a can of cheez whiz, tossed a couple of potato chunks in, and heated it up.  There was no hint of beer in it…none whatsoever.

To wrap this up, there is no doubt that the tenderloin is a 5 out of 5….certainly worth driving across town for!  And, hopefully….your service experience will be better than ours.

The Pawn Shop is located at 2222 E 54th Street in Indianapolis.  Their website is www.pawnshoppub.com
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
 December 31, 2010 - Posted by thetenderloinconnoisseur | Uncategorized | 5 , Breaded Tenderloin , Breaded Tenderloin Sandwich , Broad Ripple , Indiana State Sandwich , Indianapolis , Pawn Shop , Pawn Shop Pub , Rick Garrett 
 
6 Comments » 

 
You really ought to go try L&amp;M Visions in Ladoga, IN. It’s in Southeastern Montgomery County. They have great tenderloin sandwiches. They have breaded and hand-breaded. The hand-breaded is the best; it really surprised my brother, who was impressed with size and tenderness.

 Comment by Russ C. |
 December 31, 2010| Reply 
 
One of my favorite tenderloins in town. The place itself can get a little rowdy at night, and I prefer to go there when it is warm out so I can sit outside. The fies are mediocre so you didn’t miss much. The fried mushrooms are good.

 Comment by Aaron |
 January 2, 2011| Reply 
 
Thanks for your review. It’s been about a year since I was there but I clearly recall that while the tenderloin was huge, the meat was so thin as to be non-existent. It was just a cripy, fried, hard plank. I’m glad to hear that it can be a good experience and may give it a second try based on your experience. Maybe they’ve changed cooks since I was there!

 Comment by Sam |
 January 3, 2011| Reply 
 
Thanks for your review. It’s been about a year since I was there but I clearly recall that while the tenderloin was huge

 Comment by aoneled |
 February 22, 2011| Reply 
 
Next time you must order the onion rings. Forget the soups, chips and fries. The onion rings may not be bigger than your head, but close.

 Comment by Jeff Indianapolis |
 September 18, 2011| Reply 
 
great post! pulling back my old memories at The Pawn Shop!

 Comment by HappyLEDLight |
 May 30, 2012| Reply 
 
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 «Previous | Next» 
 
Just who is The Tenderloin Connoisseur?
 
Rick Garrett
 
The Tenderloin Connoisseur is Rick Garrett…singer, songwriter, multi instrumentalist who lives in Indianapolis, Indiana.  Over the past 30 years, he’s traveled the Midwest in search of that most perfect of all sandwiches, the Breaded Tenderloin.  From mom and pop diners, to state and county fairs, to some of the finest dining restaurants the Midwest has to offer, he’s always on the lookout for the next breaded tenderloin.  Join us on our journey!
 
 
 Follow me on Twitter! 

 I&apos;m at Jockamo Upper Crust Pizza w/ @ hollyjae 4sq.com/NkFQbI 1 hour ago Patchwork has a show on 07/14/2012 at 01:00 PM @ Woody Guthrie... in Indianapolis, IN reverbnation.com/c./poni/124540… #concert 2 hours ago Patchwork has a show on 07/14/2012 at 12:00 PM @ Woody Guthrie... in Indianapolis, IN reverbnation.com/c./poni/124528… #concert 3 hours ago I&apos;m at Daddy Real&apos;s The Place (Indianapolis, IN) 4sq.com/M53g7F 7 hours ago Cut and paste has become so commonplace, I fear we are quickly losing our ability to think originally and independently. That saddens me. 8 hours ago 
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 
Recent Posts

 Mudsocks Grill, Noblesville, Indiana The Great American Grill at American Legion Post 119, Greenfield, Indiana. Guest Review…The Mill House, Jasper, Indiana Carey Tavern, Westfield, Indiana Barbee Hotel and Restaurant, Warsaw, Indiana 
 
1356

 All tenderloins, all the time. Breakfast in the Valley geonarcissa GrubGrade Lovestoeat\’s Weblog TeamLARS Geoblog TheThirdhouse\’s Weblog 
 
Some general Indianapolis area blogs

 I Eat Around–INDY! Urban Indy 
 
Some of my favorite food blogs

 burgatory Cuisine Connoisseur Culinary Couture Dayton\’s Diners and Dives Diner Hunter EatBufordHighway fletcher place LUNCH ENCOUNTER The Best of Camden County Diners Would I Buy It Again—-my personal favorite food blog! 
 

 
Archives

 June 2012  (3) March 2012  (2) February 2012  (4) January 2012  (1) December 2011  (3) November 2011  (1) October 2011  (5) September 2011  (5) August 2011  (1) July 2011  (2) June 2011  (2) May 2011  (4) 
 
Categories

 Uncategorized 
 
RSS
 Entries RSS 
 Comments RSS 
 
Site info
 All tenderloins, all the time. 
Theme: Andreas04 by Andreas Viklund . Blog at WordPress.com . Follow 
 Follow“All tenderloins, all the time.” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
