<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008633" url="http://news.foodfacts.info/2006/11/outsourcing-drive-thru-window.html" time="2012-07-13-02:05" support="1" score="0.01359793727544953" bingtitle="Fast Food News: Outsourcing the drive-thru window" webtitle="Fast Food News: Outsourcing the drive-thru window">
			<query id="000038" bing-rank="168"/>
	<description>Some fast food restaurants are now relying on remote call-centers to take their drive-thru orders. That means the next time you speak into a drive-thru order box the ...</description>
	<body>
		skip to main | skip to sidebar 
 Fast Food News 
 
 Tracking the latest news on the food, chains, industry and trends of Fast Food.
brought to you by Fast Food Facts - the fast food nutrition database. 
 
 Monday, November 06, 2006 
 
 Outsourcing the drive-thru window 
 Some fast food restaurants are now relying on remote call-centers to take their drive-thru orders. That means the next time you speak into a drive-thru order box the person your talking to on the other end of the wires could be miles away.

Remote call-centers for order taking is just part of a comprehensive order effeciency solution offered to fast food restaurants by a company called Exit41 .

Another part of the plan is a camera that takes a photo of each customer as they speak their order into the drive-thru box. This photo is then used at the drive-thru window to help the fast food employee match the right food order with the right customer (see photo above).

Exit41&apos;s system promises to provide fast food restaurants with increased drive-thru capacity, higher order accuracy and speed, and improve customer satsifaction. Their system is in place in some Wendy&apos;s, Burger King, Panda Express and McDonald&apos;s locations.

There is an animated illustration and explanation of the features and benefits of Exit41&apos;s system on their website . Posted by Ken at 8:36 AM Labels: Wendy&apos;s 
7 comments:
 Anonymous
said... 
It would be &quot;Their&quot; system in the last paragraph. -Wordsmith
 11/06/2006 5:42 PM Ken said... 
Thanks! -fixed-
 11/06/2006 5:55 PM LordJezo said... 
After watching the flash animation on their website it does seem like an interesting idea to allow for multiple simultaneous drive through ordering booths but what about actually getting the food? Most places take a long enough time to get the food ordered to a single car from a single order, now they will need to fill three orders placed at the same time? How could that speed things up?
 11/07/2006 8:03 AM Anonymous
said... 
You know what I just thought? What stops them from taking the natural next step--- outsourcing the order takers to overseas (where cheap labor is abundant)? Exit41 is achieving what was supposed to be impossible- oursourcing SERVICE industry jobs. Seems no type of profession is safe from oursourcing in America!
 11/08/2006 11:45 AM LordJezo said... 
Here&apos;s a news story on it:

 Link to the story 

Once they start porting this kind of thing to India I will be very scared.
 11/09/2006 7:47 AM Anonymous
said... 
Everyone doesn&apos;t even see the BIG picture here. Did anyone think that this booth takes your picture as a data base? Stores your face somewhere for a future purpose? BIG BROTHER is very close to coming into your home, and it starts just like this! I&apos;ll have a number nothing please!
 1/09/2007 9:37 PM Anonymous
said... 
drive thru video gone mad
 1/24/2007 7:31 AM 
 Post a Comment 
 


 
 Newer Post Older Post Home Subscribe to: Post Comments (Atom) Fast Food Facts Nutrition Data Search 

 FastFoodNews on Twitter 
Followers
 
Search This Blog
 Loading... 
Subscribe To
 Posts Atom Posts Comments Atom Comments 
Blog Archive
 
 ►  2012 (3) 
 ►  February (2) 
 Why Is a Big Mac Cheaper Than a Salad? Cannibalistic Chicken McBites TV Ad 
 

 ►  January (1) 
 Burger King Begins Delivery Experiment 
 
 

 ►  2011 (7) 
 ►  December (1) 
 New&quot;Spicy Ketchup&quot;coming to Whataburger 
 

 ►  November (1) 
 Our McRib Photo Featured on Fox News 
 

 ►  February (3) 
 McDonald&apos;s Angus Chipotle BBQ Bacon Hardee&apos;s New Breakfast Platter, 860 calories for $... El Pollo Loco Introduces Fish Tacos 
 

 ►  January (2) 
 Taco Bell Responds to&quot;Ground Beef&quot;Claims Lawsuit Disputes Taco Bell&apos;s&quot;Ground Beef&quot;Claims 
 
 

 ►  2010 (22) 
 ►  August (6) 
 Jim Gaffigan Talks Fast Food on Letterman Taco Bell Intros New Cantina Tacos Jack&apos;s New Breakfast Pita Pocket Whataburger Celebrates 60 Years Today Tip for Volcano Burrito Lovers on a Budget (Taco B... Laredo Wendy&apos;s Accepting Pesos 
 

 ►  July (10) 
 Jamba Juice Making Cheeseburger Smoothies!?!? QSR Drive-Thru Timer iPhone App Fast Food Drive Thru Fun; Video from Funny or Die Blizzard vs. Blizberry: DQ Sues Yogubliz El Pollo Loco&apos;s Queso Crunch Burrito is Back In-N-Out Animal Style Recipe from AHT Carl&apos;s/Hardee&apos;s Testing Foot-Long Hamburger Free Smoothie Samples at McDonald&apos;s *Cancelled* Chipotle Wants Your Junk E-Mail Has the King infiltrated McDonald&apos;s 
 

 ►  March (2) 
 Health Care Law Includes Menu Reform Chipotle Supports Movie About Kids&amp;Food 
 

 ►  February (4) 
 Wendy&apos;s Bacon&amp;Blue Burger Fast Food Solutions for Lent Fast Food Study: Most Trusted Nutritional Claims Anatomy of McDonald&apos;s Mac Snack Wrap 
 
 

 ►  2009 (96) 
 ►  December (1) 
 New Salads from Carl&apos;s Jr. 
 

 ►  October (5) 
 Fast Food Halloween Treats Chipotle&apos;s Kid&apos;s Menu McDonald&apos;s Leaving Iceland Taco Bell Adds New Color... Black Wendy&apos;s NEW Bacon Deluxe 
 

 ►  September (3) 
 Subway To Pass McDonald&apos;s Restaurant Number KFC Expands Value Menu McDonald&apos;s Using Foreign Beef in US Angus Burgers 
 

 ►  August (11) 
 Free Chick-fil-a for Fans on Labor Day Chipotle iPhone App Now Available Breakfast at Chipotle? What is Dublin Dr. Pepper? McDonald&apos;s Japan: The Mega-Egg Esquire: Famous Chefs Fast Food Favs The Onion: Taco Bell Goes Green [Video] KFC Mystery Meat Photos Jack&apos;s Chorizo Sausage Breakfast Burrito 
 

 ►  July (15) 

 ►  June (15) 

 ►  May (22) 

 ►  April (8) 

 ►  March (8) 

 ►  February (4) 

 ►  January (4) 
 

 ►  2008 (167) 
 ►  December (9) 

 ►  November (16) 

 ►  October (39) 

 ►  September (54) 

 ►  August (20) 

 ►  July (22) 

 ►  June (2) 

 ►  May (4) 

 ►  April (1) 
 

 ►  2007 (78) 
 ►  December (4) 

 ►  November (5) 

 ►  October (24) 

 ►  September (16) 

 ►  May (2) 

 ►  April (3) 

 ►  March (6) 

 ►  February (13) 

 ►  January (5) 
 

 ▼  2006 (222) 
 ►  December (9) 

 ▼  November (7) 
 Jack&apos;s holiday shakes and antenna ball Is a burrito a sandwich? Fast food Thanksgiving at Boston Market BK sued over pot-laced burger Jack rolls out&apos;contactless&apos;payments Outsourcing the drive-thru window Chipotle advertising contest videos 
 

 ►  October (20) 

 ►  September (23) 

 ►  August (39) 

 ►  July (34) 

 ►  June (27) 

 ►  April (9) 

 ►  March (18) 

 ►  February (24) 

 ►  January (12) 
 

 ►  2005 (189) 
 ►  December (25) 

 ►  November (6) 

 ►  October (9) 

 ►  September (16) 

 ►  August (13) 

 ►  July (15) 

 ►  June (30) 

 ►  May (50) 

 ►  April (25) 
 
 
Labels
 McDonald&apos;s Wendy&apos;s Burger King burger KFC advertising Taco Bell trans fat breakfast nutritional data video Hardee&apos;s Jack in the Box Chick-fil-a Subway coffee free Arby&apos;s Sonic Drive-In chicken french fries shake Carl&apos;s Jr. gross Chipotle Popeye&apos;s industry Dunkin&apos; Donuts White Castle dessert drink funny t-shirt Panera charity drive-thru El Pollo Loco Starbucks pizza regulation Boston Market Krystal Long John Silver&apos;s Pizza Hut Quizno&apos;s kids technology Dairy Queen Denny&apos;s Domino&apos;s AandW Del Taco HFCS In-N-Out environment ice cream salad Jimmy John&apos;s Papa John&apos;s Steak-n-shake Taco Bueno Taco Del Mar game   Fast Food Facts and Fast Food News are
 ©1999-2009 , Ken Kuhl , All Rights Reserved.
 Terms of Use ¦ Advertising info ¦ Privacy policy 
All trademarks/servicemarks referenced on this site are properties of their respective owners.
Fast Food Facts is not affiliated with any restaurant.
	</body>
</document>
