<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008614" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/article/1818330/lennys_sub_shop_in_knoxville_tennessee.html" time="2012-07-13-02:04" support="1" score="0.0023120667083878304" bingtitle="Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop in Knoxville, Tennessee - Yahoo! Voices - voices ..." webtitle="Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop in Knoxville, Tennessee - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="000788" bing-rank="64"/>
	<description>I-640, Exit Broadway 2901 Tazewell Pike, #G ... A fast food restaurant could not have been quicker. ... The cashier was efficient and friendly without being ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 
 
Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop in Knoxville, Tennessee

Restaurant Review
 Gayle Crabtree , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Jun 10, 2009 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Subs Knoxville Tennessee 
 Flag Close Post a comment Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop Neighborhood: Broadway
Knoxville, TN 37918
United States of America Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop in Knoxville, Tennessee proved to be the perfect place for a quick lunch. The address is as follows:
I-640, Exit Broadway
2901 Tazewell Pike, #G
Knoxville, TN 37918
Phone (865) 688-6177
Sometimes you need something quick but you don&apos;t want fast food. My daughter and I needed lunch. We didn&apos;t want to pay a fortune or wait forever. Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop was nearby. There was a coupon in the Knox County Schools Coupon Book. So, we decided to give it a try.

The street address is Tazewell Pike. Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop faces Broadway. Take I-640, exit Broadway. Turn as though you were going toward the Duck Pond. Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop is on the right between Blockbuster Video and Cingular Wireless.

We were a little early for lunch. Only a few people were in the restaurant. My daughter and I went it and walked right up to the counter with no wait. There was a large menu on the wall. The server gave us a minute to decide and answered our questions.

Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop makes no pretense of being anything but a place to get great subs. There is no fancy coffee. No WI-FI. The seats are the regular tables and hard benches that you would expect. You won&apos;t have soft music playing in the background. And, you won&apos;t be paying for the extra plush that isn&apos;t there. (View the 4 frame slideshow here. )

At Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop many of the sandwiches are served cold. Submarine sandwiches include your choice of ham, roast beef, turkey, homemade chicken salad and toppings. There are classics such as the club sandwich and the Italian sub.

Hot sub choices include the Philly Cheesesteak that they are known for, the meatball sub and the grilled hot dog. If these sandwich are anything like the cold ones they are going to be terrific.

Within minutes the speedy counter staff had our sandwiches finished and we were ready to eat. I was impressed at the speed at which these were done. Despite taking time to answer all our questions they zipped through the sandwich making process. A fast food restaurant could not have been quicker.

My daughter ordered the ham sandwich meal deal with a cookie. This came with chips and a drink. I got the Italian sub and wound up with her chips. She kept the cookie. We both ordered the regular size sub. The monster sandwich is a big 7.5 inches long and comes piled high with both meat and toppings.

Both sandwiches were good. At Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop they claim that there are 8oz. of meat on their subs. If that&apos;s all that was there I will be surprised. There was certainly no shortage of meat. The other toppings were just as generous and the bread tasted as though it was straight from the oven. It was great!

At checkout, there was no problem with the coupon or with making change. The cashier was efficient and friendly without being overly chatty. Our change was correct.

Like the rest of the restaurant that we saw the drink station was clean and well stocked. At the time of this writing the Tennessee Health Department score is a solid 90. You can view their online health score here. A score like that takes teamwork and a commitment to cleanliness.

The cost for our lunch with a coupon deducted was $8.69. Will we back to Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop? You bet.

 My rating: 5 Stars

Sources:
Personal Experience
Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop
Tennessee State Health Department
 
Published by Gayle Crabtree 

Gayle is an expert in budget and family travel. She is a trained mission team leader who has traveled extensively throughout the United States and Canada. Her road trips experiences include traveling with di...  View profile 
 
 Christmas Shopping: Should You Shop Locally? If you are wondering whether you should shop locally or not, you may want to think about the advantages and disadvantages of doing so. Your Cafe Press Shop Can Be a Huge Success Need an extra source of income? A real shop owner tells you how you really can make money on Cafe Press. Corel Paint Shop Photo X1 Script for Synthetic Sumi-E Style Image How to do scripts for Paint Shop Pro X Photo &quot;Olive Garden&quot; is Still an Excellent Italian Restaurant This article reviews the restaurant &quot;Olive Garden.&quot; Lose Weight While You Shop Do you love to shop? Then why not lose weight while you shop? After all, it is the perfect excuse to head out to the mall and pick up that new pair of shoes. 

 Bobcat Asleep in the Crook of a... How To Find Your Nearest KFC Res... Lily Pad Bog at Bays Mountain Pa... 
 
 Lenny&apos;s: Best Denver Sub Shop Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop Gets Two Thumbs Up Guide to Celebrating the Holidays in Knoxville, Tennessee Book and Spy Shop Offers Readers Place for Used and Unique Books Nana&apos;s Consignment Shop Shop-Vac Model 92P350 Review Jesse Jackson Protests at Local Illinois Gun Shop 
 
 
 
 Resources 
 
 www.lennys.com/section.cfm?section=find tn.state.gegov.com/tennessee/search.cfm?i=1131631 local.yahoo.com/info-15025031-lenny-s-sub-shop-knoxville 
 
1 Comments
 Post a Comment 
 Branwen66 6/10/2009 
Sounds like my kind of place: No-nonsense yummy food and good service. Great review!
 
 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Shine and Lifestyles Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
