<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008190" url="http://www.ocregister.com/news/hawks-194690-birds-prey.html" time="2012-07-13-01:40" support="1" score="0.0018703674988347356" bingtitle="Empty nests: Are Orange County&apos;s raptors dying? | hawks, birds ..." webtitle="Empty nests: Are Orange County&apos;s raptors dying? | hawks, birds, prey - News - The Orange County Register">
			<query id="001429" bing-rank="17"/>
	<description>Report: Small firms get worst of credit card deals ... is one of several raptor experts in Orange County ... &quot;It&apos;s a fast-food restaurant for the Cooper&apos;s hawks.</description>
	<body>
		REAL ESTATE JOBS CARS DEALS CLASSIFIEDS PLACE AN AD 
 
 SIGN-IN/SIGN-UP SUBSCRIBE E-REGISTER CUSTOMER SERVICE TODAY&apos;S PAPER 
 Orange County Register 
NEWS
 
 SURF REPORT/CAMS |  WEATHER  | LIVE TRAFFIC 
 
 HOME NEWS SPORTS BUSINESS ENTERTAINMENT LIFE TRAVEL OPINION 
 
 Newsletter RSS Mobile Facebook Twitter 
 Blogs | California | City-by-City News | Columns | Crime and Courts | Data Central | Education | Elections | Immigration | Military | Nation | Obituaries | OC Watchdog | Photos | Politics and Government | Science | Technology | Videos | World Published: July 24, 2008 3:00 a.m. Text: Next Article» 
Empty nests: Are Orange County&apos;s raptors dying?
 Scientists who track birds of prey say adults are dying off, nest sites are vacant, and environmental changes are likely to blame. Tweet    
 Posh Party Box $40 for $100 towards Your Party Box at PoshPartyBox.com ADVERTISEMENT 
More from this story
 SLIDE SHOW: 
Empty nests: Are Orange County&apos;s raptors dying?
9 Photos» 

 
More from Science
 
 Tube wear detailed at San Onofre nuclear plant 1 hour&amp;17 minutes ago 3.9 quake strikes near Yucca Valley Chapman prof: Remembering giant tortoise Lonesome George 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 By PAT BRENNAN / THE ORANGE COUNTY REGISTER 
 
The red-tailed hawk showed no sign of injury, but it was brought, weakened and starving, to veterinarian Scott Weldy for treatment.

&quot;This one is real skinny and debilitated,&quot; Weldy said as he handled the bird, one of nine ailing birds of prey now recovering at his animal hospital in Lake Forest. &quot;There&apos;s competition for eating sites. The restaurants are all closing.&quot;
 RAPTOR: Veterinarian Kristi Fisher shows a male American kestrel at Seranno Animal&amp;Bird Hospital, which cares for raptors. JEBB HARRIS, THE ORANGE COUNTY REGISTER MORE PHOTOS» ADVERTISEMENT 
Weldy, who has treated and rehabilitated raptors for more than 20 years, is one of several raptor experts in Orange County who say they are seeing a disturbing trend: bird of prey numbers plummeting, long-inhabited nest sites empty, and far fewer chicks hatching in the nests that remain.

They say raptors in Orange and San Diego counties, and perhaps across Southern California, appear to be suffering a variety of harmful environmental changes that are happening all at once: reductions in available prey, drought, West Nile virus and continuing loss of habitat because of expanding human presence and large, destructive wildfires.

&quot;What we&apos;re observing here is an advanced degree of ecosystem decay,&quot; said Pete Bloom, who has trapped, tagged and studied Orange County raptors since 1970. &quot;It&apos;s quite alarming. The question is, is this natural? Because in 40 years of monitoring I have not seen it look this bad - not across so many species in the same geographical area.&quot;

The drop in numbers appears to be affecting almost all raptor species, as well as their prey, and the scientists worry that climate change could be helping to drive dramatic changes in habitat that are harming the birds.



 EMPTY NESTS 

Bloom and raptor researcher Scott Thomas, who track success and failure of nesting raptors, say they are increasingly seeing raptor nesting sites that have been occupied for decades turning up empty.

Successful hatching of raptor chicks, and survival of those chicks to adulthood, also appears to be declining at an alarming rate.

&quot;It&apos;s not necessarily because adults are just not having kids,&quot; Thomas said. &quot;We have seen what appears to be a loss of adults, too. We need to look at this further.&quot;

Thomas, Bloom and Weldy say preliminary numbers so far seem to back up their fears, but that much more extensive survey work must be done to determine the true extent of the problem.

The species hit hardest so far include red-tailed and red-shouldered hawks, kestrels, barn owls and white-tailed kites.

 SANCTUARY BIRDS HARD HIT 

At the Starr Ranch Sanctuary in eastern Orange County, a stretch of undisturbed native habitat monitored closely by biologists, 35 to 60 barn owl chicks would be banded in a normal year of nesting.

By three years ago, the number had dropped to about 15. And in the past three years, Thomas said, it was three to 10 birds.

In most years, there would also be four or five active red-tailed hawk nests at Starr Ranch. In the past two years, Thomas has seen only two nests.

He has noted a decline in red-shouldered hawk nests as well.

&quot;That type of trend is what we&apos;ve seen all across Orange County, and into San Diego County, with a few minor exceptions in a few localized areas,&quot; Thomas said.

Weldy, who runs the Orange County Bird of Prey Center in Silverado Canyon, says the numbers of raptors brought there for treatment also has been dropping steadily over the years - and that among those brought to him, more seem to be suffering weakness or starvation with no visible injuries. That &quot;debilitation&quot; is suggestive of a scarcity of prey and of hunting territory for the raptors, he said.

The center released 184 rehabilitated birds in 2005, a banner year. Last year, the center released 64.

The numbers do not include raptors brought to local animal hospitals that are too sick to save and are euthanized.

Birds of prey are routinely trapped and relocated from the wildlife refuge at the Seal Beach Naval Weapons Station, to prevent them from preying excessively on rare and endangered species - least terns, clapper rails, snowy plovers.

But trapping statistics also show a decline, for example, among American kestrels.

&quot;In the late 80s and early 90s, they used to bring 20 to 30 kestrels from the Seal Beach Naval Weapons Station,&quot; Weldy said. &quot;Now it&apos;s 10 to 15.&quot;

The number of kestrels brought to his hospital for treatment also appears to be dropping.

&quot;Definitely, I&apos;ve noticed a big difference,&quot; he said. &quot;My hospital staff has noticed, too.&quot;

 EXCEPTION COULD PROVE RULE 

Even the exceptions to the general decline among raptors seem to tell a tale of humanity&apos;s profound effects on native ecosystems and even the behavior of native animals.

&quot;Cooper&apos;s hawks seem to be doing pretty well,&quot; Bloom said. &quot;They&apos;ve adapted to us humans. They&apos;ve adapted to nesting in urban environments.&quot;

And all three raptor experts give the same reason: Cooper&apos;s hawks, which often feed on smaller birds, have keyed into the bird feeders residents hang from their homes.

&quot;We do know it is the bird feeders that are doing it,&quot; Thomas said. &quot;It&apos;s a fast-food restaurant for the Cooper&apos;s hawks. Where I have a bird feeder in my back yard, a Cooper&apos;s hawk sits in the same place, in the same tree, and grabs birds. And I watch it doing it.&quot;

The Cooper&apos;s hawks&apos; success might be shortlived, however. In the urban environments, Bloom said, while the hawks do well in an &quot;artificial forest&quot; of ornamental trees that is free of most predators, they could ultimately be undone by power lines and windows.

&quot;A lot of Cooper&apos;s hawks pursue avian prey into windows,&quot; he said. &quot;We find a fair number of Cooper&apos;s hawks with broken necks.&quot;

That might lead to a grim result: while the hawks&apos; reproduction benefits from the alterations humans introduce, young birds might not live long enough to breed themselves.

Changes in ecosystems are not only affecting hawks. Scientists have seen declines in many other bird species as well. The numbers of rodents and other prey species also seem to be declining.

Bloom said the ecosystem decay he&apos;s noted in Orange County could lead to permanent loss of native habitat in some natural areas, although far more investigation is needed before such a conclusion could be reached.

 CLIMATE FEARS 

&quot;When you throw in the ominous potential of global warming, I think local ecosystem collapse is plausible, absolutely,&quot; he said. &quot;We are seeing major habitat changes. We are seeing actual conversion of type: habitats are going from what was coastal sage scrub or chaparral to non-native grasslands. And mustard and wild radish burn more frequently than the natural vegetation that was there before.&quot;

But pinning down the cause, or causes, of the raptor declines will take a concerted effort among scientists and conservation agencies, he said. While several environmental factors - drought, West Nile, fire, habitat loss - appear to be involved, detailed study is needed to build a more precise picture.

&quot;We really don&apos;t know what is going on,&quot; he said. &quot;It could be one of those. It could be three in combination. It could be something we&apos;re not really thinking about yet.

&quot;But it&apos;s apparent to those of us who monitor resident breeders that raptor populations, probably for all species, is depressed right now, and has been for a number of years. And it only seems to be getting worse as each year goes by. It&apos;s quite stunning. These are some fairly common species.&quot;



 Contact the writer: 714-796-7865 or pbrennan@ocregister.com .

 
 More from Science» 
 
 COMMENTS | PRINT | EMAIL |   Reader Comments Comments are encouraged, but you must follow our User Agreement .
1. Keep it civil and stay on topic.
2. No profanity, vulgarity, racial slurs or personal attacks.
3. People who harass others or joke about tragedies will be blocked.
 View Article | Article Photos | Article Videos Return to Top 
 home news sports business entertainment life travel opinion Real estate Jobs Cars Deals Classifieds Place an Ad 
 
 
ADVERTISE OPTIONS

 Self Service Place an Online Ad Place a Print Ad Place a Classified Ad Media Kit Advertising Contact Info 
 
CONTACT OCREGISTER

 About Us Careers Contact Us Corrections Customer Service Subscribe Today Subscriber Services Site Help Site Feedback 
 
OCR SERVICES

 Archives Buy Our Photos California Lottery Deals OCRegister Fanshop Orange County Businesses Register Insider Register in Education Obituaries Facebook Comments FAQs 
 
NEWS YOUR WAY

 Blogs E-Mail Newsletters E-Register Mobile RSS Article Map Site Map Video 
 
ADVERTISING

 Classifieds Cars Deals Jobs Real Estate Place a Classified Ad View our Media Kit Interactive 
 
PARTNERS

 KDOC-TV MSNBC OC Excelsior Coast Magazine Preferred Destination OrangeCounty.com FreedomPolitics.com Freedom Printing 
 
 
 Privacy Policy | Site Help | User Agreement | Site Map
	</body>
</document>
