<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008384" url="http://www.coolrunning.com/forums/Forum4/HTML/009789.shtml" time="2012-07-13-01:51" support="1" score="0.0011373826430209756" bingtitle="Cool Running :: Why is West Virginia the 3rd fattest state?" webtitle="Cool Running :: Why is West Virginia the 3rd fattest state?">
			<query id="000851" bing-rank="229"/>
	<description>... always have a fast-food restaurant. ... and says, &quot;You all eat healthy, don&apos;t you?&quot; A second time a different cashier ... they do go out to eat. Its mostly homecooked meals</description>
	<body>
		&gt; home &gt; community &gt; discussion forums &gt; carbo canteen &gt;why is west virginia the 3rd fattest state? (Page 1)
 | &gt; rules | &gt; faq | &gt; e-mail to a friend | moderator:  Leezle 
 
Why is West Virginia the 3rd fattest state?

Topic is 3 pages:
 1 2 3     
 &gt; next newest topic | &gt; next oldest topic 

 Author Topic:  Why is West Virginia the 3rd fattest state? standophish 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-13-2006 06:15 PM               I can see how Mississippi or a few of the other deep south states would top the list, due to their horribly unhealthy food traditions. Plus a huge percentage of African-Americans, who statistically have a much higher incidence of obesity than whites.
West Virginia is predominately white, and it would seem that their food traditions would be closer to northern choices than southern. Also a large portion of the population is very rural, many live much too far away from fast-food restaurants for McD&apos;s to be at fault.
Anyone know?

IP: Logged 
 nscachetti 
 Member posted Dec-13-2006 06:23 PM               I&apos;m sure there are more factors than race, who cares if WV is mostly white, probably a bunch of lazy white fols\ks
IP: Logged 
 dgb2n 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-13-2006 06:28 PM               My vote is for income and education.
It ranks LAST in median household income and pretty close to that in percentage of their population with college degrees.
Its kind of strange that in America, the poorest are the some of our heaviest citizens and healthy food costs more than much of the unhealthy food out there.
It seemed to me that prepared food is cheaper in the US (and fresh vegetables and fruit comparatively more expensive) than Europe and much of the rest of the world.
------------------
 My Running Log 
 My User Profile 
IP: Logged 
 24hrfitnesschick 
 Member posted Dec-13-2006 06:32 PM           I agree....income and education have a lot to do with it. I am from the UK and have lived in Spain and now US and the poorest people have normally the worst eating habits. They buy more processed food IMO - eg. that gross squirty cheese instead of real stuff, soda/nectar instead of 100% juice.
America definitely wins on the processed food stakes but you would be surprised at the obesity problem amongst kids in Spain.
IP: Logged 
 standophish 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-13-2006 06:33 PM               quote: Originally posted by nscachetti:
 I&apos;m sure there are more factors than race, who cares if WV is mostly white, probably a bunch of lazy white fols\ks 
Stating the FACT that AA&apos;s suffer from obesity at a higher rate than whites is not racist. And it IS relevant to the question.

IP: Logged 
 jorgenunes 
 Member posted Dec-13-2006 06:43 PM           because they all have the same DNA
IP: Logged 
 LifeIsAMarathon 
 Member posted Dec-13-2006 07:43 PM           quote: Originally posted by standophish:
 Stating the FACT that AA&apos;s suffer from obesity at a higher rate than whites is not racist. And it IS relevant to the question.
 
Wow. The funny thing is the poster did not call you a racist. All s/he said was race is probably not the only factor. Now that you&apos;ve jumped to your own defense so quickly, without anyone even attacking you, I *am* wondering if you&apos;re a bit racist.
IP: Logged 
 standophish 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-13-2006 08:49 PM               quote: Originally posted by LifeIsAMarathon:
 Wow. The funny thing is the poster did not call you a racist. All s/he said was race is probably not the only factor. Now that you&apos;ve jumped to your own defense so quickly, without anyone even attacking you, I *am* wondering if you&apos;re a bit racist. 
He strongly implied it, then followed it up with a racist comment of his own, that WV is &quot;full of lazy white folks&quot;.
Tell me, what would the &quot;racism meter&quot; peg at if he&apos;d said that Alabama is &quot;full of lazy black folks&quot;?

IP: Logged 
 UncleFred 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-13-2006 09:24 PM           You know ... if they could reunite Germany; you would think they could reunite Virginia.
IP: Logged 
 standophish 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-13-2006 09:33 PM               quote: Originally posted by UncleFred:
 You know ... if they could reunite Germany; you would think they could reunite Virginia. 
And why isn&apos;t there an East Virginia? We have North and South Dakota, same for the Carolinas, what IS the deal?

IP: Logged 
 ljwoodw 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-13-2006 09:41 PM           quote: Originally posted by standophish:
 Also a large portion of the population is very rural, many live much too far away from fast-food restaurants for McD&apos;s to be at fault.
 
I think you&apos;re mixed up a bit on this point. Small towns (with, say, pop&gt;1000) almost always have a fast-food restaurant. In Minnesota, it&apos;s Subway. In WV, it might be something else. More importantly, obesity and urbanization are generally inversely related.
But education and income are probably the deciding factors here.
IP: Logged 
 dubyah 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-13-2006 10:20 PM           My fathers side of the family lives in West Virginia and i have to say that i have never seem a salad at any meal. Its southern food: fried chicken, mashed potatoes, green beans cooked in bacon grease, ect.
i do not think that all people who live in West Virginia eat like that but i was just posting for the person who said they ate northern food.
IP: Logged 
 standophish 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-13-2006 10:24 PM               quote: Originally posted by ljwoodw:
 I think you&apos;re mixed up a bit on this point. Small towns (with, say, pop&gt;1000) almost always have a fast-food restaurant. 
Have you ever been down the backroads of WV? Those places deep down the hollow that are two hours&apos; drive along steep mountain roads from anywhere big enough to even have a Subway?
It just seems to me that with a large percentage of truly rural, remote, subsistence living people, that they would still be eating the same way that past generations ate. These folks aren&apos;t pushing a cart full of Little Debbies down the Wal-mart aisle...

IP: Logged 
 standophish 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-13-2006 10:31 PM               quote: Originally posted by dubyah:
 My fathers side of the family lives in West Virginia and i have to say that i have never seem a salad at any meal. Its southern food: fried chicken, mashed potatoes, green beans cooked in bacon grease, ect.
i do not think that all people who live in West Virginia eat like that but i was just posting for the person who said they ate northern food. 
What general area of WV do they live in? This is interesting...

IP: Logged 
 banananutmuffin 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-14-2006 01:52 AM           I have lived in two areas in WV.
One is northern WV, by the MD line.
The other was VERY southern WV.
Speaking from observation only:
The high rate of obesity in WV is probably linked to culture, education and economics.
Really... the number of fast food restaurants are irrelevant. McDonalds isn&apos;t the only thing that&apos;s responsible for the obesity problem in America. In fact, I&apos;d venture to suggest that fast food is only one small contributing factor.
Although WV residents in the north tend to eat more like northerners, there are plenty of people who still consider themselves southern. (Where I currently live, I can get to northern WV in 30 minutes. And I see plenty of Confederate flags on pickup trucks in this area... leading me to believe that many people around here still consider themselves to be southerners.)
In southern WV the daily diet of most people tends to be even worse than that of northern WV. A standard southern WV meal was fried chicken, mashed potatoes, and maybe corn on the cob. So yes, people don&apos;t dine out as much. But they cook unhealthy, homestyle foods at home.
(One note: While living in southern WV, DH and I were checking out at the supermarket. The checkout girl looks at all our purchases as she rings them out, then looks at me and says, &quot;You all eat healthy, don&apos;t you?&quot; A second time a different cashier said to me, &quot;You must be a vegetarian.&quot; My point: my diet was different enough from the mainstream that it was worthy of note to the cashiers. Since leaving WV, no one has ever commented on my groceries.)
In reality, despite what intuition might suggest, the rural nature of the area actually promotes LESS exercise. Sure, there are the people in the area who like mountain climbing and white water rafting and hiking. But they&apos;re few and far between. People have to drive everywhere, so the average person does very little walking on a daily basis.
Anyway... that&apos;s my two cents, for what it&apos;s worth. Like I said, this is just based on observations. No facts. No stats. And I could be completely wrong. 
------------------
 In Pursuit Of Fitness 
 RefrigeratorRaid.com 
IP: Logged 
 evanflein 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-14-2006 02:21 AM           For what it&apos;s worth: a Northern state post. Alaska has a terrible obesity problem. I don&apos;t know where we &quot;rank&quot; but I&apos;m sure it&apos;s up there. During a recent meeting of department heads at our office, more than half the women are morbidly obese, and that&apos;s just from observation. It&apos;s scary. I know they say it&apos;s too hard to exercise in the winter (but we have a lot of health clubs....), they&apos;re too busy (most of these women are single with very few volunteer obligations), or whatever. Bottom line, it&apos;s just too easy to eat whatever they want and do nothing physically. Today as I was trying to get more exercise by using the restroom on the other end of the building, they were waiting for the elevator to go to lunch (from the 2nd floor!!). Lord help us, I think our underlying problem isn&apos;t economics or education (these women all make good money and have masters degrees or better)... it&apos;s basic laziness!!!!!!
------------------
 My Profile 
IP: Logged 
 sage67 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-14-2006 05:31 PM           quote: Originally posted by banananutmuffin:
 (One note: While living in southern WV, DH and I were checking out at the supermarket. The checkout girl looks at all our purchases as she rings them out, then looks at me and says, &quot;You all eat healthy, don&apos;t you?&quot; A second time a different cashier said to me, &quot;You must be a vegetarian.&quot; My point: my diet was different enough from the mainstream that it was worthy of note to the cashiers. Since leaving WV, no one has ever commented on my groceries.)
 
Lucky. I always get comments about my grocery purchases here in MN when I shop at the muggle stores and not the co-ops. And I am a vegetarian. Usually they&apos;re along the lines of, &quot;You must be a vegetarian. I&apos;ve never had that, how do you make it?&quot; But lots of times they&apos;re of the &quot;ugh, I could never be a vegetarian, I love meat too much&quot; variety, followed by a description of their favorite carnivorous meal.
IP: Logged 
 yellowlamp 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-14-2006 08:35 PM           every state has an obesity problem. the whole world does.
-age
-race
-gender
-socioeconomic status
-education level

If you want to see interesting and factual information, feel free to browse:
 http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/bv.fcgi?rid=healthus05.chapter.trend-tables 
Particularly Tables 72-74
IP: Logged 
 dubyah 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-14-2006 11:11 PM           quote: Originally posted by standophish:
 What general area of WV do they live in? This is interesting...
 

Outside of Summersville. The majority of people there eat very southern dishes. There are also McDonalds, Burger Kings, Pizza Huts, Ect.
My family lives on top of a mountain (basically) so they have to drive 40 minutes to these places but on occasion they do go out to eat. Its mostly homecooked meals

IP: Logged 
 standophish 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-14-2006 11:35 PM               quote: Originally posted by dubyah:
 
Outside of Summersville. The majority of people there eat very southern dishes. There are also McDonalds, Burger Kings, Pizza Huts, Ect.
My family lives on top of a mountain (basically) so they have to drive 40 minutes to these places but on occasion they do go out to eat. Its mostly homecooked meals 
So, WV&apos;ians weren&apos;t obese eating homecooked food 50 years ago. Why now with the exact same food?

IP: Logged 
 banananutmuffin 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-15-2006 02:08 AM           quote: Originally posted by standophish:
 So, WV&apos;ians weren&apos;t obese eating homecooked food 50 years ago. Why now with the exact same food?
 
Portion sizes. Lifestyle. Modern conveniences. Too much TV. More soda, less water. Devices designed to make life easier. Grocery stores instead of gardening. Video games and computers. The list could go on and on...
IP: Logged 
 AA717driver 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-16-2006 10:06 AM               If you want a fight on your hands, declare that WV is not wholly immersed in Southern Culture and may actually have some aspects attributable to &quot;The North&quot;.
(However, you can avoid the fight by using the language I did in the above sentence. They won&apos;t have a clue as to what you said... )
If WV did finish third in the voting, I claim vote fraud. There&apos;s no way they could have beaten out Indiana. We&apos;ve still got them on smoking and divorce, though.
Back on topic: I say it&apos;s education and (as a result) income. You don&apos;t see many runners in low income areas. TC
P.S.--I am qualified to dis WV. The DW is descended from West Virginians. In fact, she&apos;s one of the first to marry outside the family... 
IP: Logged 
 trifecta 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-16-2006 07:11 PM               Check out this animated map of obesity rates by state since 1986. It&apos;s pretty scary how rapidly obesity has increased over very few years. It&apos;s clearly an epidemic. And it&apos;s interesting how New England and the Mountain States have consistently lagged behind as the rest of the country has been swallowed up.
IP: Logged 
 RoyalTay 
 Cool Runner posted Dec-16-2006 08:10 PM               Kids With High IQs Grow Up to Be Vegetarians
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
The smarter they are, the more likely they&apos;ll shun meat as adults, British researchers contend
By Steven Reinberg, HealthDay Reporter

Find More
Helping Grieving Children Through the Holidays
Perception of Who&apos;s Obese Varies by Race
Today&apos;s Health News

FRIDAY, Dec. 15 (HealthDay News) -- As a child&apos;s IQ rises, his taste for meat in adulthood declines, a new study suggests.
British researchers have found that children&apos;s IQ predicts their likelihood of becoming vegetarians as young adults -- lowering their risk for cardiovascular disease in the process. The finding could explain the link between smarts and better health, the investigators say.
&quot;Brighter people tend to have healthier dietary habits,&quot; concluded lead author Catharine Gale, a senior research fellow at the MRC Epidemiology Resource Centre of the University of Southampton and Southampton General Hospital.
Recent studies suggest that vegetarianism may be associated with lower cholesterol, reduced risk of obesity and heart disease. This might explain why children with high IQs tend to have a lower risk of heart disease in later life.
The report is published in the Dec. 15 online edition of the British Medical Journal.
&quot;We know from other studies that brighter children tend to behave in a healthier fashion as adults -- they&apos;re less likely to smoke, less likely to be overweight, less likely to have high blood pressure and more likely to take strenuous exercise,&quot; Gale said. &quot;This study provides further evidence that people with a higher IQ tend to have a healthier lifestyle.&quot;
In the study, Gale&apos;s team collected data on nearly 8,200 men and women aged 30, whose IQ had been tested when they were 10 years of age.
&quot;Children who scored higher on IQ tests at age 10 were more likely than those who got lower scores to report that they were vegetarian at the age of 30,&quot; Gale said.
The researchers found that 4.5 percent of participants were vegetarians. Of these, 2.5 percent were vegan, and 33.6 percent said they were vegetarian but also ate fish or chicken.
There was no difference in IQ score between strict vegetarians and those who said they were vegetarian but who said they ate fish or chicken, the researchers add.
Vegetarians were more likely to be female, of higher social class and better educated, but IQ was still a significant predictor of being vegetarian after adjustment for these factors, Gale said.
&quot;Vegetarian diets are associated with lower cardiovascular disease risk in a number of studies, so these findings suggest that a such a diet may help to explain why children or adolescents with a higher IQ have a lower risk of coronary heart disease as adults,&quot; Gale said.
One expert said the findings aren&apos;t the whole answer, however.
&quot;This study left many unanswered questions such as: Did the vegetarian children grow up in a household with a vegetarian parent? Were meatless meals regularly served in the household? Were the children eating a primarily vegetarian diet at the age of 10?&quot; said Lona Sandon, an assistant professor of clinical nutrition at the University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center at Dallas.
&quot;In addition, we don&apos;t know the beliefs or attitudes of the parents of the children, nor do we know if there was a particular event that led these children to becoming vegetarian in their teens or adulthood,&quot; Sandon said.
As the study showed, more women than men chose a vegetarian diet, Sandon noted. &quot;Other research shows that women in general will focus more on their health than men. So, if they believe that a vegetarian diet will have health benefits, they are more likely to follow it,&quot; she said.
Given these factors, &quot;we cannot draw any solid conclusions from this research,&quot; Sandon added.
Another expert agreed that a vegetarian diet is healthy.
&quot;The evidence linking vegetarianism to good health outcomes is very strong,&quot; said Dr. David L. Katz, the director of the Prevention Research Center and an associate professor of public health at the Yale University School of Medicine.
&quot;Studies, for example, of vegetarian Seventh-Day Adventists in California suggest that they have lower rates of almost all major chronic diseases, and greater longevity, than their omnivorous counterparts,&quot; Katz said. &quot;Evidence is also strong and consistent that greater intelligence, higher education, and loftier social status -- which tend to cluster with one another -- also correlate with good health.&quot;
I am pleased to add I am a vegetarian 
IP: Logged 
 slowshoes 
 Member posted Dec-19-2006 03:22 PM           
QUOTE: &quot;Small towns (with, say, pop&gt;1000) almost always have a fast-food restaurant. In Minnesota, it&apos;s Subway. In WV, it might be something else. &quot;
In WV, it&apos;s called Tudor&apos;s Biscuit World, where they serve 50 kinds of bisquit sandwiches with meat, egg, cheese, and hash browns on one biscuit. There&apos;s Tudors all over West Virginia. Even in the Charleston airport.
Regardless, the geography and socioeconomic isolation probably has a lot more to do with the levels of obesity than biscuits. I eat some pretty terrible stuff too, but I also live in a city where I can walk everywhere I go. Most communities just aren&apos;t set up that way.
IP: Logged 
 

 All times are Eastern Time (US). &gt; next newest topic | &gt; next oldest topic 
Topic is 3 pages:
 1 2 3     
Administrative Options: &gt; Close Topic | &gt; Archive/Move | &gt; Delete Topic 

 Hop to: Select a Forum or Archive List of Forums: Category: New Runners -------------------- Newbie Cafe Category: Training -------------------- Basic Training The Track Multisport Training Ultra&amp;Trail Running Run and Race Reports JeffGalloway Gear Category: Competition -------------------- Mainstream Racing The Competitive Wire Category: Age Groups -------------------- Way Cool Running Boomers and Beyond Category: Fitness -------------------- The Med Tent Carbo Canteen Category: The Lighter Side -------------------- Just Running The Neighborhood Race Together Clubhouse Point of View Category: Feedback -------------------- The Suggestion Box List of Archives: Frequently Asked Questions Best of the Clubhouse Race Report Archive   
 Powered by Infopop www.infopop.com ©2000
Ultimate Bulletin Board 5.47d 
 
 
 
 
 
Follow Coolrunning.com on the social web: Facebook Twitter 
 Subscribe to the Newsletter | Subscribe to the News Feeds 

 About Cool Running | Advertise | Race Directors | Support | Terms of Use | Privacy Policy 
Copyright©2012 The Active Network, Inc. 
 i
	</body>
</document>
