<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008482" url="http://okc.about.com/od/foodanddrink/Food_Restaurants_and_Bars_in_Oklahoma_City.htm" time="2012-07-13-01:56" support="1" score="0.007048621582520476" bingtitle="Food, Restaurants and Bars in Oklahoma City" webtitle="Food, Restaurants and Bars in Oklahoma City">
			<query id="000220" bing-rank="123"/>
	<description>Every level of cuisine from fast food to fine dining are covered with the top ... But if you&apos;re looking for a fun and/or relaxing place to have a drink or watch a ...</description>
	<body>
		Local 
 Oklahoma City Search 
 Oklahoma City Neighborhoods Things to Do Summertime 
 
Food, Restaurants and Bars in Oklahoma City
 The bar/restaurant landscape in the Oklahoma City area is absolutely eclectic with something to satisfy any tastebud. Every level of cuisine from fast food to fine dining are covered with the top choices examined. 
 Grocery/Food Stores (7) Recipes (5) Restaurants (52) 
 
 Oklahoma Liquor Laws 
 The Oklahoma state liquor laws are very specific and limit a number of things that are legal in other states - Here are the Oklahoma liquor laws, the rules governing beer and other alcohol in Oklahoma. 
 Oklahoma Wineries 
 The business of wine producing in the state of Oklahoma has exploded in recent years - Here is a list of all the Oklahoma wineries, the vineyards and companies making local wine across the state of Oklahoma. 
 Oklahoma City Brewing Companies 
 Beer-lovers have plenty of options at bars and pubs across Oklahoma City, but why not support the local brewing companies. You&apos;re sure to find some beers you&apos;ll love. Here is a list of the Oklahoma City area brewing companies, with information on the types of ales offered and where to buy them. 
 Made in Oklahoma Products 
 Originally formed in 2000 the Made in Oklahoma (MIO) Coalition is a consortium of food manufacturers operating in Oklahoma with a primary focus of the marketing and sales of local products - Here is information on the Made in Oklahoma products, where you can buy them, recipes and more. 
 The Best Bars&amp;Restaurants in Oklahoma City that Specialize in Wine 
 Oklahoma City wine bars are the taverns and restaurants that feature the best and largest selection of wines. So if you&apos;re a wine-lover dining out in the metro, here are a few of the top Oklahoma City wine bars, the specialists in wine variety and quality. 
 Top Oklahoma City Gay Bars&amp;Clubs 
 Many are often surprised to learn that Oklahoma City has a number of extremely popular gay bars and clubs, some part of the thriving gay and lesbian scene around the NW 39th Street Enclave at NW 39th and Pennsylvania Avenue. Here is a list of some of the best gay bars&amp;clubs in the Oklahoma City metro area. 
 Top Oklahoma City Sports Bars&amp;Neighborhood Pubs 
 The bar landscape in Oklahoma City is fairly varied. There are a number of boisterous clubs and several quaint lounges. But if you&apos;re looking for a fun and/or relaxing place to have a drink or watch a sports game on television, check out one of the metro&apos;s better sports bars and neighborhood pubs. 
 Oklahoma City&apos;s Taste of Bricktown 
 2006 marked the 1st Taste of Bricktown event in Oklahoma City. A showcase of metro restaurants and entertainment, it takes place in late March at the Coca-Cola Bricktown events center. 
 Oklahoma Restaurant Smoking Ban in Effect 
 Oklahoma restaurants must either be completely smoke-free or offer a separate, ventilated room for smokers. At the very least, supporters say, the new regulations will cut down on complications from second-hand smoke. At best, the added hardship on smokers may encourage more to quit. 
 Cabin Creek Vineyard&amp;Winery 
 Located northeast of Tulsa in Big Cabin, Oklahoma, Cabin Creek Vineyard and Winery has gathered quite a following among Oklahoma City residents. Their website contains information on various events such as their Mother&apos;s Day Brunch as well as recipes and wine-tasting locations. Free Oklahoma City Newsletter! Sign Up 
 Discuss in my forum 
 Explore Oklahoma City Must Reads 
 Where in the Metro Quiz Ten More of OKC&apos;s Best Restaurants Unemployment Benefits Summer Movies in OKC July Event Calendar 
 Most Popular 
 July 4th in Oklahoma City Bricktown Fireworks Extravaganza Top Oklahoma City Restaurants Top Places for Kids in OKC OKC&apos;s Outlet Mall 
 Free Oklahoma City Newsletter! Sign Up By Category 
 Arts and Entertainment Attractions and Events Sports and Recreation Food and Drink Shopping and Services Employment and Jobs Apartments and Real Estate Community and Organizations History and Trivia Education and Learning Travel&amp;Transportation News and Media Image and Photo Galleries Government and Politics 
 Oklahoma City 
 About.com Local Oklahoma City Food and Drink 
 
 Most Popular Latest Articles RSS 
 
 Advertise on About.com Our Story News&amp;Events Work at About SiteMap All Topics Reprints Help 

 Write for About User Agreement Ethics Policy Patent Info. Privacy Policy Your Ad Choices 
 
©2012 About.com. All rights reserved.

A part of The New York Times Company .
	</body>
</document>
