<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008096" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?The-McWedding&amp;id=5223743" time="2012-07-13-01:11" support="1" score="0.0100479407343216" bingtitle="The McWedding - EzineArticles Submission - Submit Your Best ..." webtitle="The McWedding">
			<query id="001198" bing-rank="214"/>
	<description>... around £250 and includes a ceremony and reception ... few years, but this is the first time a fast food restaurant ... it&apos;s time to be a little more creative in order to keep ...</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Relationships » Wedding Heidi L Thompson 
 Expert
 Author |   6 Articles 
 Joined: April 9, 2010 Was this article helpful? 0 0 1 
The McWedding

 By Heidi L Thompson 
 
Only in Hong Kong would you find the introduction of the McWedding. It is exactly as it sounds, a wedding held at a McDonald&apos;s restaurant and apparently it is quite popular. Beginning in January, McDonald&apos;s locations in Hong Kong will be offering wedding packages complete with a wedding cake made of apple pies and Happy Meal toy favours.

The wedding package costs around £250 and includes a ceremony and reception for 100 guests. There are two stipulations to the McWedding: no alcohol and business will carry on as usual so no exclusivity. A few fast food weddings have popped up across the United States over the past few years, but this is the first time a fast food restaurant has actively marketed themselves as a wedding venue.

Surprisingly, there is quite a market for McWeddings. Helen Cheung Yuen-ling, director of corporate communications at McDonald&apos;s Hong Kong, told the South China Morning Post they&apos;ve been flooded with phone calls from fast food fanatics who can&apos;t wait to tie the knot at their favourite fast food restaurant. Perhaps these couples have met or dated at McDonald&apos;s but another proposed reason is the lack of social mobility and falling incomes among young Hong Kongers.

Perhaps these couples are onto something. In a world where many couples have to choose between paying for their wedding and making a down payment on their first home, a £250 wedding for 100 people sounds pretty good. Or maybe your wedding day should be your dream come true....and for these couples it is both. I&apos;m not suggesting we all go get married at our local McDonald&apos;s but maybe it&apos;s time to be a little more creative in order to keep costs from spiraling out of control. I love the challenge of saving couples money on their wedding and often you don&apos;t even have to sacrifice that much. Maybe McDonald&apos;s isn&apos;t for you, but the Chinese are lovin&apos; it!
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=Heidi_L_Thompson 
 Did you find this article helpful? 0 0 1 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Relationships: Wedding 
 Heidi L Thompson 
 Email Address: Subscribe Wedding Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Recent Articles

 Paying Gratitude After Wedding Ceremony Reasons Platinum Rings Are Great Options Choosing An Appropriate Style Of Photography For Your Wedding Choosing the Right Flower Girl Dress for a Summer Wedding The Fact and Fiction of Wedding Day Superstitions Benefits Of Hiring A Professional Wedding Videographer Wedding Stickers for Shoes The Photographer&apos;s Guide to Become a Wedding Photographer Why Torontonians Should Have Their Wedding in Oakville Affairs You Must Carry Out Before You Plan Your Own Wedding 
 
Submitted On October 18, 2010. Viewed 182 times. Word count: 321.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Thompson, Heidi L. &quot;The McWedding.&quot; The McWedding .
 18 Oct. 2010 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?The-­McWedding&amp;id=5223743 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Thompson, H. L. (2010, October 18). The McWedding .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?The-­McWedding&amp;id=5223743 Chicago Style Citation: 
Thompson, Heidi L. &quot;The McWedding.&quot; The McWedding EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?The-­McWedding&amp;id=5223743 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
