<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008872" url="http://www.menuism.com/restaurants/juans-place-berkeley-398565" time="2012-07-13-02:18" support="2" score="0.008653645852645966" bingtitle="Juan&apos;s Place - Reviews &amp; Menu - Southwst Berkeley - 941 Carleton ..." webtitle="Juan&apos;s Place - Reviews&amp;Menu - Southwst Berkeley - Berkeley 94710">
			<query id="000104" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000120" bing-rank="49"/>
	<description>Order online and read reviews from Juan&apos;s Place in Southwst Berkeley Berkeley from ... Description: Juan&apos;s Place is a Mexican and Fast Food restaurant where most Menuism ...</description>
	<body>
		Menuism - Restaurant and dish reviews 
 Explore Restaurant Reviews&amp;Menus 
 Restaurants Near Me Make Online Reservations Order Delivery&amp;Takeout Restaurant Week Directory Popular Cities Popular Chains What&apos;s Menu ism ? Monthly Review Contest 
 Remember Personal Dining Journal 
 My Favorites My Try List My Photos Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 
 Learn Foodie Education Blog 
 Food Primers Exclusive Interviews 
 
 FIND AROUND GO 
 Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 

 Not a member? To save, rate, and share reviews, sign up! Already a member? Log in (OpenID) Connect with Facebook 
 
 larger map / directions 
 
 - Actions - Write a Review Add to Try List Add to Favorites Suggest Corrections Upload Pics 

 - Pages - The Restaurant Map/Directions Dishes/Menu 
 Berkeley Restaurants » Southwst Berkeley » Mexican » Juan&apos;s Place Share | 
Juan&apos;s Place
 
 4.41667 star rating           
  4.4 rating over 6 reviews 
 (510) 845-6904 

 941 Carleton St ( ) 

 Berkeley , CA 94710-2636 

 View Nearby Businesses» 
 Order Online Send to Phone Email Listing Print Listing   
 View Menu Website Read Reviews (6) View Map/Directions 
 
 Information From the Restaurant Offers 
 
 Description:  Juan&apos;s Place is a Mexican and Fast Food restaurant where most Menuism users came for fun with friends and paid between $10 and $25 . Tags: Mexican, Fast Food, Good For Kids, Takeout, Good for groups, Online Ordering, Delivery, and Dinner Stats: 
 2 dishes entered by diners at Juan&apos;s Place 2 users want to eat at Juan&apos;s Place 
 
 
Nothing yet.
 
 Do you own Juan&apos;s Place? Contact us to connect with your diners. 
 
 Suggest Corrections/Menu 
 
Reviews for Juan&apos;s Place
 Write a review 
 6 reviews First reviewed by fattiusthebear 
 
&quot;because a bear&apos;s gotta eat well&quot;

 623 helpful votes over 156 reviews 
 fattiusthebear 
 156 Restaurant Reviews +621 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Juan&apos;s Place fattiusthebear 
 November 21, 2006 
 4.0 
 4.0 star rating           
 +9 1 +9 9 Votes   
tasty mexican
 
Juan’s Place isn’t in the nicest of areas. It is in a fairly ghetto area, next to a warehouse and other unsavory looking places. The restaurant doesn’t look too shady or anything at all, though, with a lighted sign and all.

Anyways, I think this place is pretty authentic, since the atmosphere is has a very Mexican feel and their food was really good. I was weak and ordered their ribs, which they only offer every Tuesday. It didn’t come with a whole rack, so I thought it could have came with more food at first. I was wrong, though, since I was full at the end. The plate also came with beans, rice, and tortilla, to make some sort of fajita thing. I thought that was pretty radical and it was tasty. I may have been full because of all the tortilla chips they offer. You end up eating A LOT of chips since they are there and they are good. Their flour chips are interesting, since they are puffy, soft, yet still crunchy. It is pretty addicting. I also ate some of the steak super burrito (which is pretty damn big) and it was tasty.

Overall, this place is almost guaranteed to make you full since you eat so many chips and the amount of food they serve is pretty big. The prices were fairly reasonable, depending on what you ordered. I would come back here again for Mexican food, granted someone drives me.
 
Dishes I tried:
 
BBQ Ribs
 
 4.0 star rating           
 
Not a full rack of ribs, but they are good and you can make a fajita like thing with it, which is nifty.
 
Super Burrito
 
 4.0 star rating           
 
This is a good dish to get if you plan on filling up. It is huge, tasty, and cheaper than many other dishes.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add/Show Comments (1) 
 
Comments
 
 fattiusthebear (Author)
 03/04/2007 
&quot;because a bear&apos;s gotta eat well&quot;

 623 helpful votes over 156 reviews 
 156 +623 This number is the number of useful votes fattiusthebear has. The more useful votes, the more you can trust the quality of reviews. 
i’d also like to add that the flour tortilla chips are probably the best I’ve ever had. It’s not“pretty addicting.”It’s super addicting and awesome.
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply 
 20 helpful votes over 5 reviews 
 Reine 
 5 Restaurant Reviews +20 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Juan&apos;s Place Reine 
 April 24, 2007 
 5.0 
 5.0 star rating           
 +6 0 +6 6 Votes   
Best Mexican Place in Berkeley
 
Secluded Location
Amazing Chips
Spicy Salsa
Generally Sensationally Good Food
Will make you full for a reasonable price

not necessarily the best location to go to if you just want a quick and good burrito though their burrito is pretty damn good.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply 
 15 helpful votes over 14 reviews 
 CharlieL 
 14 Restaurant Reviews +15 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Juan&apos;s Place CharlieL 
 September 6, 2007 
 4.0 
 4.0 star rating           
 +2 0 +2 2 Votes   
Altogether, this place has pretty darn good...
 
Altogether, this place has pretty darn good Mexican food. It’s an actual sit-down place, and the decor is well done. It’s fun and relaxed- a great place to go for dinner after a Cal victory at Memorial Stadium. The portions are large, and the prices are reasonable, so it’s definitely worth a try!
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply Alon S 
 from Insider Pages 
 
November 5, 2008
 
 4 star rating           
 
Great Local Secret
 
The place is always lively and the service prompt. The food comes quickly and the portions are big - prepare to take half home if you are watching the calories!\r
\r
I am veggie and have no problem finding a variety. The food comes…

 read full review» 
 Maryann S 
 from Insider Pages 
 
October 26, 2008
 
 5 star rating           
 
Love it
 
We eat here often and the service is great. food is also great! They have the biggest super burrito you could ever see and im not kidding. If you are very hungry this is the dish to get. I also love the chips its deep fried tortillas and…

 read full review» 
 BerkeleyFan 
 from Citysearch 
 
June 9, 2008
 
 5 star rating           
 
Awesome Mexican Food
 
I love this place. Great chips, great salsa, great place. Being from California I have had my share of Mexican and this place comes close to the best.

 read full review» 
 Read 22 reviews on Citysearch» 
Best Dishes at Juan&apos;s Place

These dishes from the Juan&apos;s Place menu are contributed by Menuism users directly, 
 as part of a restaurant review, or as part of an image upload.
 
Super Burrito
 
 4.0 star rating           
 
BBQ Ribs ( $9.95 ) 
 
 4.0 star rating           
 View all dishes 
 True Love Tattoos 
 5 reviews 5.0 stars Berkeley Moving Arts Kiss My Ring Yabusaki&apos;s Dwight Way Nursery 
 2 reviews 4.5 stars East Bay Audio Repair Ohmega Salvage 
 2 reviews 4.0 stars Alba&apos;s Glass Orchard Supply Hardware 
 3 reviews 4.0 stars Walgreens Ashby Lumber Company 
 Juan&apos;s Place is located near the cities of Columbus, Regina, Albany, Rockridge, and Kensington. People found this by searching for: Juan&apos;s Place Berkeley, Juans Place Berkeley, Juan&apos;s Place Menu, Juans Restaurant Berkeley, Juan&apos;s Berkeley Menu, Juan&apos;s Place, Juan&apos;s Place Berkeley Menu, Juans Berkeley Menu, and Carleton Berkeley Restaurants. 
Featured in Berkeley
 
 3.875 star rating           
 Kirala 
 3.75 star rating           
 Downtown Restaurant 
 3.5 star rating           
 La Mediterranee 
 3.0 star rating           
 Thai Delight Cuisine 
 4.5 star rating           
 Musical Offering 
 4.25 star rating           
 Picante 
 3.75 star rating           
 King Dong Restaurant 
 5.0 star rating           
 Virginia Bakery 
 4.0 star rating           
 West Coast Pizza 
 3.5 star rating           
 Drunken Boat Restaurant 
 Upload Pics Photos
 
Nearby Restaurants
 K C Barb-Q Westside Bakery Cafe Bubi&apos;s Catering Café Clem Berkeley Food Delivery Restaurants 
Link to Juan&apos;s Place
 
Copy the link below and paste onto your website or blog to display badge.

 Copy 
 
Related Links
 Yelp Reviews Reviews on TripAdvisor 
 Follow Menuism around the web Find us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter Find us on Google+ 
 
 Learn More
 Advertise About
Advertise
FAQ
Privacy
Terms of Use 
 Take Action
 Link to Menuism / Badges and Widgets 
 Browse
 Restaurant Week Restaurant Locations Popular Cities Sitemap 
 
 ©2006 - 2012 Delta Beans, LLC
 Contact Menuism 

Some Images and Data provided by Citysearch .
	</body>
</document>
