<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008863" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/14/1542024/restaurant/Riley-Park-Little-Mountain/Bob-Likes-Thai-Food-Vancouver" time="2012-07-13-02:18" support="5" score="0.005779743923240236" bingtitle="Bob Likes Thai Food - Riley Park/Little Mountain - Vancouver ..." webtitle="Bob Likes Thai Food - Riley Park/Little Mountain - Vancouver | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000060" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="000036" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="000054" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="001534" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000367" bing-rank="246"/>
	<description>... did not ask me if I wanted something else instead, did not take it off the bill. ... environment somewhere else. It felt kind of like a diner or a fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Vancouver » Riley Park&amp;Little Mountain » Bob Likes Thai Food 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Calgary Los Angeles New York Portland Sacramento Seattle SF Bay Area More... 
 
Bob Likes Thai Food
 
(604) 568-8538
 Riley Park/Little Mountain 3755 Main St 
 Vancouver , BC V5V 
 boblikesthaifood.com 

Added by famished foodies 
 See all 49 reviews Cuisine Thai Feature Takes Reservations Menu $$ $10-15 per entree Satay, Pad Thai, Pad Thai, Pork Pad Ka Pow, Cashew Chicken,&amp;Spring Rolld... View menu 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch               Dinner               Late 
   260 people have voted 90 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
Critic reviews

 September 28, 2011 Vancouver Sun/Canada.com The roasted duck curry (coconut based) is lovely and the best of the dishes I tried... More from Vancouver Sun/Canada.com January 28, 2011 The Globe and Mail I’m not too sure about this Bob guy, but I’m really quite smitten with his namesake restaurant, Bob Likes Thai Food. More from The Globe and Mail January 11, 2011 Georgia Straight Bob’s menu is fairly standard for Thai cuisine in Vancouver: green curry chicken, Panang beef curry, tom yum soup... More from Georgia Straight 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews

 July 2, 2012 acfong The tasting plate included: Miang Kham [mîəŋ kʰam] (just a bite) – Piper sarmentosum or chaphlu leaves, Roasted coconut shavings, Lime, Shallot, Peanut and Ginger with Tamarind Palm Sugar... More from acfong May 23, 2012 Likes it Sherman&apos;s Food Adventures Sometimes I wonder if there is ever much thought put into naming a restaurant. There is the&quot;let&apos;s name it after the street&quot;approach such as Kingsway Deli , Slocan Restaurant and The... More from Sherman&apos;s Food Adventures March 21, 2012 Life Bites I love Thai food. On a mellow Saturday night with the sous chef, we were debating on cooking or going out for dinner. We decided to head out and then after reviewing options, the Sous... More from Life Bites February 29, 2012 Senses Inspired The dishes at this little spot hidden along Main Street is decent but found the dishes on the small side for the price. It’s still nice to see a Thai place that slightly steps out of the... More from Senses Inspired January 1, 2012 Follow Me Foodie If it was called Chaiyaanuntchanipornsupaporn Likes Thai Food, I maybe more convinced, but with a name like&quot;Bob Likes Thai Food&quot;it was still pretty good and legit! More from Follow Me Foodie 
 Show 11 more 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 March 22, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Foodie on the Run ( 43 reviews ) I&apos;m a big fan but was disappointed that the beef salad had shrunk by half the portion it use to be ! The price didn&apos;t shrink. 3 out of 3 found this review helpful +1 more review from Foodie on the Run October 2, 2010 Mobile review What a great new Thai restaurant! I ordered the beef salad&amp;fried rice both authentic&amp;very tasty! Highly recommend this new family run restaurant . They only take cash at present 1 out of 1 found this review helpful June 21, 2011 Best Thai food in Vancouver, a change from the usual by main street ( 33 reviews ) Just tried this place and was totally blown away by the delicious, fresh food served at a reasonable price. The restaurant is bright and does not go for the whole dark wood, thai music thing. They play reggae, have a clean and bright decor and a good vibe. We had the fish cakes, they were pretty much the best thing i&apos;ve eaten in a while, the pad thai was amazing and the curry chicken was perfect. Service was good. I am quite fussy and felt that the ingredients were totally fresh. I will definitely go back. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful February 16, 2012 Likes it Fantastic!! by CEB ( 3 reviews ) Delicious&amp;so fresh. Excellent service!!! 1 out of 1 found this review helpful November 1, 2011 meh by deeeelish ( 22 reviews ) Food was okay. Service was extremely quiet, which came off a little rude. FYI, they are not cash only- they do accept credit cards. October 21, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by No Dessert Im Full ( 171 reviews ) Walking in im thinking this seems really&quot;crack in the wall&quot;thats ok i was kind if expecting that. Sawastee was full down the street and bobs seemed like the logical alternative being im in the mood for some thai. The menu looks alittle simplified and modern, went with the kao pow, a thai fried rice dish. A green currey dish, and the usual pad thai. All were good, havent thai in a while so its hard to compare, it was good though. February 4, 2012 Likes it My favorite restaurant in Vancouver by Lindsay Pa ( 4 reviews ) I have eaten at Bob Likes Thai Food 7 times over the last year. I have never once eaten anything that was not delightfully scrumptious. The waiters are also very courteous and speedy. I&apos;ve eaten at just about every Thai restaurant in Vancouver and Burnaby since 2006, and I must say that Bob Likes Thai serves the most authentic Thai food I have ever encountered. I also like the very relaxed setting, not too ritzy which is just my speed. If they ever close I will be very very upset. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful May 30, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Doug Dzzzzzzzz ( 13 reviews ) We live in the area, walk by often, heard good reviews........ It was mediocre at best. I&apos;ll never be back it wasn&apos;t worth it. The person who said it was the best Thai food they&apos;ve ever had? Oh please. 2 out of 4 found this review helpful March 27, 2011 Cute place, but needs some work by migrant ( 30 reviews ) We went here for dinner about a month ago. It opens at around 6pm, I believe. It was quite empty when we were there (I think it was a Friday night). The seating is a little uncomfortable, and there isn&apos;t much privacy (we sometimes felt like we were being watched a little too closely by the staff). My friend had the green curry, and I had some sort of red curry special. We also ordered the spring rolls. Everything was good, but nothing that special. I think I would rather pay a little more for a better environment somewhere else. It felt kind of like a diner or a fast food restaurant. Something to keep in mind: they only take cash. There&apos;s an ATM close by, but it&apos;s still a bit of a pain. January 9, 2011 Really likes it Mobile review by Alan Hoffman ( 5 reviews ) Amazing food, great service! We&apos;ll be back! December 24, 2010 Likes it Pad like no other by imkoonta ( 37 reviews ) I&apos;ve only tried one item, the gauge that I use to see if a restaurant is authentic, ie. pad thai. Bob Likes Thai Food makes pad thai like how it is SUPPOSED to taste like in Thailand. I have lived in Bangkok and Pattaya for a short period and one bite, it took me back. I am rounding up my foodie troop and checking this place out very soon so that I can sample every item on their menu. Service was amazing as well. Warning: cashola only! January 22, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Not great... by lodgecookie ( 41 reviews ) Had dinner here tonight. Looked like a clean restaurant and there were no offensive smells as we walked through the door. Server was friendly enough. Prices seemed a little high for such a basic Thai place. Regardless, willing to pay whatever for good food. $4- Spring Rolls. Acceptable other than line of old oil left behind once each half of the spring roll was picked up off the plate. $4.50- 2 Chicken Satays the size of my pinky. Not kidding. Rubbery, tasteless, even the peanut sauce did not taste of peanuts. $12- Pad Thai. I&apos;ve made better at home. $11?- Beef Curry. Soupy curry with rubbery, tasteless slivers of beef, maybe 1/2 cup. All in all, not such an enjoyable dinner. When I complained to the cashier about the satays she looked at me as if I were some crazy person... Did not apologize, did not ask me if I wanted something else instead, did not take it off the bill. I don&apos;t believe good value for the money paid. I would not recommend this restaurant to anyone. November 23, 2010 Likes it Fantastic Thai Food by Howie K ( 2 reviews ) We went for dinner after hearing about the restaurant from others. The food was excellent. Best Tom Ka Gai soup in the city hands down. Perfectly balanced. Also highly recommend the Penang Beef. But there&apos;s so many great dishes to try and I was too full to try them all. I&apos;ll definitely go back and recommend it to anyone who loves Thai food. The decor is clean and simple with a few nice artistic touches. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful July 9, 2011 Really likes it Mobile review by Chuck ( 11 reviews ) Great Thai food in a low key setting. The owner is suet nice and cooks up auhentic Thai meals. The green papaya salad is a great starter. I&apos;ve been 6+ times and haven&apos;t been disappointed with anything I&apos;ve ordered. The desserts are tasty too. November 5, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it Mediocre thai food by Nom_Food ( 6 reviews ) Had the duck curry and it was mediocre at best but still enjoyed it and satisfied my craving for thai curry. The tom yum soup was the worst I have ever tasted. Completely disgusting I had to throw it away. It tasted like they dumped a bottle of vinegar in there and added some over cooked prawns. Will not return, there are so many other better thai restaurants. May 28, 2011 Too little for too much!!! by Melanie Fahlman Reid ( 2 reviews ) We went for lunch-and I must say the swimming rama was great. But the green papaya salad was miniscule-served on a small saucer; two skinny satay skewers-each with a sliver of meet weighting less than 20 grams, and overpriced small amounts of pad thai left us with a bill of 35 + dollars for a poor lunch. We were even charged double for tea (2 x 1.50) despite having one tea bag and no refills of hot water on offer. About 2:40 the waitress put on her lovely beige ytrench coat and slapped her shoes back and forth in front of us. We did enter after 1:30, and were aware the restaurant closes at 3. So good food but overpriced and rude discourteous service. I don&apos;t recommend the place. Maenan has much better food, service, and prices. Skip this one. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful October 3, 2010 Likes it Excellent authentic Thai finally... by LL ( 5 reviews ) This place brought back fond memories of Thailand-- finally a place in Vancouver who serves up a pad Thai like they do in Thailand, none of this ketchup flavored crap! The papaya salad is made perfectly with just the right amount of heat and the pork kra pow is absolutely fantastic!! The ingredients are so fresh and the flavors are truly authentic. You can tell by talking to the well mannered Thai gentleman who runs the joint that he is very knowledgeable about his ingredients and Thai cooking techniques. This place is a hidden gem at the moment and I&apos;m sure it will stick around the main st hood for a long long time. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful February 17, 2011 Likes it Pretty decent Thai food by Anne ( 6 reviews ) I wish it was easier to find great Thai food in Vancouver, but it just doesn&apos;t seem to be Vancouver&apos;s best ethnic fare. Bob Likes Thai Food is pretty decent, maybe not the best Thai food I have ever had, but worth going back for. Service was great. October 7, 2010 Likes it My favorite new Thai restaurant by Kanongnaj Yimsiri ( 1 review ) I finally found a favorite Thai restaurant in Vancouver. Cute name. Very original taste. My favorite dish is Eggplant Pad Kra Pow. Very...very yummy and the other one is Chicken Satay. Usually, you will find Pork Satay. But you can eat Chicken Satay here, it&apos;s different. Most impressive is the owner very well mannered. I think cos of he&apos;s from Thailand. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful December 19, 2010 No words! by sgtoca ( 1 review ) Granted we&apos;ve only tried the beef curry, tom yum goong and pad thai, it is seriously the best thai food I&apos;ve had in Vancouver! Get their pad thai, it is life changing! August 31, 2011 Mobile review by Tania ( 1 review ) I used to think this place was awesome, but now the portions have shrunk&amp;I&apos;ve noticed if it&apos;s busy the food is not as great. The pad Thai was a bit sour and my eggplant dish was sitting in a pool of oil!!! Dishes shrunk but the price has not. Let me know if prices drop or dishes get bigger, then I&apos;ll try this place again. 
 Show 9 more 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by Greedy Guts Lunch special by eatvancity Bob Likes Thai... 
 All 41 photos View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Coco Et Olive 69% $$ Riley Park/Little Mountain - Bakery, Breakfast/Brunch, French Chocolaterie de la Nouvelle... 95% $ Riley Park/Little Mountain - Desserts/Ice Cream Liberty Bakery 86% $ Riley Park/Little Mountain - Bakery, Coffee/Tea Zipang Sushi 89% $$ Riley Park/Little Mountain - Japanese, Sushi Shaktea 71% $$ Riley Park/Little Mountain - Tea, Desserts/Ice Cream, Sandwiches/Subs 
 More nearby restaurants 
Nearby Places

 Howard Johnson Plaza Hotel -
395 Kingsway Nat Bailey Stadium -
4601 Ontario St Vancouver Olympic/Paralympic... -
4575 Clancy Loranger Way 
 People reached this page by searching for: 
 bob likes thai food bob likes thai food review best thai food vancouver bob likes thai bob likes thai main street 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
