<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008523" url="http://cudacoffee.com/catalog-product.php?p_ref=2018" time="2012-07-13-01:59" support="11" score="0.05367616002729818" bingtitle="Crathco Cold Beverage Dispenser for Premix 1 Bowl (Cold Beverage ..." webtitle="Crathco Cold Beverage Dispenser for Premix 1 Bowl (Cold Beverage Dispenser) - Cuda Coffee">
			<query id="000540" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000317" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000321" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000339" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="001357" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="000524" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000336" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000314" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000337" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000508" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000501" bing-rank="189"/>
	<description>... at your snack bar, buffet, or fast food restaurant. Has plastic side panels and drip tray. ... makes it easier than ever to give your ... How To Order &gt; Site Map &gt; Advertise ...</description>
	<body>
		Toll Free: (866) 411-2832
  Shopping Cart  Secure Shopping 
 
 
 
 Home Contact Shipping Site Map Links  Search July 12, 2012 
 
 Commercial 
 Bar Refrigeration Systems 
 Beverage&amp;Juice Dispensers 
 Coffee / Espresso Parts 
 Coffee Equipment 
 Coffee Grinders 
 Coffee-Espresso Vending Machines 
 Dispensers, Organizers&amp;Accessories 
 Espresso Machines 
 Frozen Drink Machines 
 Hot Drink / Oatmeal / Soup Dispensers 
 Iced Tea Brewers / Dispensers 
 Signs / Displays / Posters 
 Water Boilers&amp;Dispensers 
 Water Dispensers&amp;Coolers 

 Household 
 Coffee&amp;Espresso Machines 
 Coffee Accessories 
 Coffee Grinders / Roasters 
 Cups / Mugs / Saucers / Tumblers 
 Frothers&amp;Hot Chocolate Makers 
 Gift Baskets 
 Gift Packages 
 Storage / Containers / Dispensers 
 Tea Pots&amp;Water Kettles 

 Supplies 
 Coffee Cleaning Supplies 
 Coffee Supplies 
 Gourmet Coffee Blends 
 Sauces / Toppings / BBQ Sauces 
 Tea Blends&amp;Accoutrements 
 Water Filters&amp;Scale Interceptors 

 Let us bring the deals to you... Sign up for our mail list! 
   

 
 

 Online Payments You Are Here: Home &gt; Commercial &gt; Beverage&amp;Juice Dispensers 


 
 images/commercial_equipment/gmc-d15-4.jpg 
Crathco Cold Beverage Dispenser for Premix 1 Bowl

 Product # GMC-D15-4 by GMC 
 List: $ 1,104.00 

Your Price: $577.99

 Savings: $526 

Qty:    
 


 Overview Specifications 

 This Crathco D15-4 single bowl 5 gallon refrigerated beverage dispenser is a simple and effective way to boost impulse sales at your snack bar, buffet, or fast food restaurant. Has plastic side panels and drip tray.
This single bowl premix cold beverage dispenser is as easy to clean as any in the industry! With fewer parts for a fast, easy cleanup, this dispenser makes it easier than ever to give your fruit juice, iced tea, and iced coffee the exposure they deserve.
The D15-4 refrigerated beverage dispenser&apos;s 1/6 hp compressor uses R134A refrigerant that will keep your beverages chilled and ready for consumption for hours at a time. It requires a 120V electrical connection and is UL and NSF Listed.

 Features: 
 Plastic Side Panels and Drip Tray Dimensions: 8.5&quot;H x 14&quot;W x 15.5&quot;D Famous two-piece, stainless steel, dripless pouring valve is sanitary and easy to use and maintain Better design and more stainless steel allow easier cleaning and less maintenance Superior engineering allows full beverage cooling right down to the last drink Large 5 gallon (18.9L) bowl, with easy to read measuring marks Super-strong, virtually unbreakable polycarbonate covers and bowls give lasting durability Unique evaporator and high efficiency pump cools faster and more efficiently for faster start-ups Choice of Regular or Stainless Steel side panels and drain tray Down-to-earth design engineering makes routine servicing easier and simpler Second-to-none quality with &quot;field condition&quot; testing Includes both spray and agitate circulation options packed with every unit 


 We may also suggest...

 
 Zumex Speed Self Service w/Podium 
Only  $10250 
 Qty: 
 Portion Control Grinder with 1 Hopper 9 lbs Analog 
Only  $822.95 
 Qty: 
 La Pavoni Professional 16 cup Lever Espresso Machine (Chrome and Black) 
Only  $959.99 
 Qty: 
 Curtis Round Tea Dispenser 5 Gallon 
Only  $105.99 
 Qty: 
 
 
 
 
 Stella &quot;Galaxy&quot; Stovetop Espresso Maker Additional Sizes Available 
Only  $126.9
	</body>
</document>
