<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008110" url="http://www.phuket-to-krabi.com/Phuket-Airport.html" time="2012-07-13-01:12" support="4" score="0.009358165845431629" bingtitle="car hire phuket airport transfer phuket airport hotels ..." webtitle="car hire phuket airport transfer phuket airport hotels transportation taxi">
			<query id="000696" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="000395" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000712" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="000718" bing-rank="119"/>
	<description>... just the items what you want to order is ... the domestic departure area is also a fast food restaurant from ... only airport parking in an open car park ...</description>
	<body>
		Enter your search terms   
 Web www.phuket-to-krabi.com 
 Submit search form 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 HOME     CONTACT 
 Ao Luk 
 Ao Nang 
 Beach 
 Fossil 
 Shell 
 Beach 
 Karon 
 Phuket 
 Khao Lak 
 Khao Sok 
 Krabi 
 Airport 
 Khao Sok 
 Krabi 
 Airport 
 Krabi 
 Loy Kratong 
 National Parks 
 Patong 
 Phang Nga Bay 
 Phang Nga to Krabi 
 Phi Phi Ko 
 Phuket to Bangkok 
 Phuket to Kuala Lumpur 
 Phuket 
 Town 
 Phuket Airport 
 Phuket 
 Nightlife 
 Railay 
 Beach 
 Tattoo 
 Art 
 Thailand 
 Girls 
 Thai Bar Girls 
 Thai 
 Orchid 
 Thai Video 



 

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
  
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
Phuket 
 Airport 
 Bus Taxi 
 Hotels 
 Transportation 
 to 
 Patong 
 Car 
 Rentals 
 
 
 
 Phuket airport 
hotels, Phuket airport taxi, Phuket airport transfer, Phuket airport, Thailand, Phuket airport bus, Phuket 
airport to Patong, cheap flight to Phuket. 

 

 

 
 
 Airport Phuket Data 

 Airport Code is HKT. 
 Location is at longitude 98 18&apos; 45&quot;and latitude 08 
 06&apos; 38&quot;and 82 feet above sea level, Phuket 
 International Airport is 32 km from downtown Phuket 
 and a few km south of the north end of Phuket Island. 
 The airport can handle 24 flight operations per 
 hour and is open 24 hours. The Runway is 3,000 m long and 45 m wide. 

 Cheap flights to Phuket are a mixture of scheduled flights 
 and charter flights. Sometimes private aircrafts plus helicopters 
 come in, there is even a water airplane or amphibian 
 aircraft operating for short distance flight such as 
 to Phi Phi Island. The airport is 
 reachable via a good 4 lane highway with only 
 moderate traffic. The highway runs almost 
 continuously from the southern end of Phuket at 
 Rawai Beach to the northern end leaving Phuket 
 Island via the Sarasin Bridge. Usually you wont have 
 any traffic problems, but be aware that between 4 pm 
 (school ends) and 7 pm (people drive home from work) 
 sometimes traffic disaster strikes. 

 Phuket Airport Transfer and Phuket Airport Bus 

 I f you are on a Phuket package tour you tour operator will carry 
 you to and from, it is also possible 
 to get airport pick-up service from the Phuket hotel 
 or apartment you will probably stay. If you are not on a Phuket package tour 
 and you have only one light bag you could use a 
 motorbike taxi or a tuk tuk when you are for 
 departure, if the driver wants to 
 go. A Phuket airport taxi you might find if you are 
 lucky, there are several limousine services. A airport bus 
 is available, have a look for they guy who runs 
 around with the big sign where it&apos;s written Phuket 
 Airport Bus at the north end of the arrival zone 
 outside (but try to avoid, its a real pain, they 
 always wait until they are full, which will take 
 quite some time and they never go straight to Phuket 
 city, they just drive around in 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 hope to get some 
 passengers until the bus is real totally overloaded, 
 the last time I took this bus they 
 were circling 5 times within 
 
 Phuket Airport 
 the departure and 
 arrival area, after they went to Nai Yang Beach 
 direction, when I asked them why they don&apos;t drive to Phuket Town 
 they started to smile as usually and took a left 
 turn at the next junction to head for the Phuket 
 International Airport to down town highway. 
 After you arrive 
 maybe via cheap flights to Phuket by Air Asia or 
 Tiger Airways take a minibus, it take some time 
 until they are full but at least there is no funny 
 business around. There are only a handful of taxis 
 on the island, its limited to make sure 
 the tuk tuk operators don&apos;t have competition, you 
 will never find a taxi in Phuket, only outside the 
 arrival hall are about 3-4 taxis waiting, with this 
 taxi&apos;s it&apos;s about Baht 400,- for a ride between the 
 airport and Phuket Town. The minibus service counter at the arrival hall offers shared transportation to 
 almost every location on the island, among them 

 
 to Patong and if 
 there are some passengers even to Khao Lak . If a longer ride is needed e.g. from 
 Phuket to Phang Nga , 
 Takua Pa etc. it needs to take the bus from 
 the terminal at Phuket Town . 

 Low cost air 
 travel started to make inroads into the 
 Thailand bus travel market, although a 
 airline ticket to various destinations in 
 Thailand is still about 3 to 4 times more 
 expensive as a bus ticket, the absolute 
 value don&apos;t indicate such a big difference 
 anymore. For instance the airline ticket for 
 Phuket to Bangkok is always around Baht 
 2200,-, one way, the bus ticket is either 
 Baht 640,- in the 32 seated bus or Baht 
 940,- in the 24 seated bus. On the other 
 hand, air travel is around 3 hours from 
 entering the airport until leaving the 
 airport and bus travel is 12 hours. 
Phuket car 
 rental, cheap flights to Phuket 

 
 
 Cheap flights to Phuket
  
 Aside of 
 flights to Phuket and domestic air 
 travel a excellent option to travel in 
 Thailand is to take a Thailand bus. This 
 probably the best option anyway to travel 
 around, the buses are cheap, comfortable and 
 leave almost hourly to every destination. As 
 you can see at the 
 Thailand Bus not the airport bus 
 picture on right 
 side Thailand buses are colorful and modern, 
 almost all of them follow the construction 
 pattern they started in Germany some decades 
 ago. The same is for minibuses, they are 
 faster than the normal buses but also more 
 expensive. Aside of the before mentioned 
 transfer there is no 
 dedicated airport shuttle. There are no 
 dedicated Phuket airport hotels since there 
 are plenty of hotels near by easily 
 reachable with the car or taxi within a 
 radius of about 15 minutes drive, since 
 this area also has no traffic congestion, 
 its pure rural there is no problem to get in 
 and out from hotels near Phuket airport. 

 
 Hotels near Phuket 
 airport 
 The airport is 
 the second most busy Thailand airport after Bangkok 
 airport. There are only 5 Thailand airports where 
 international flights can land, this is Phuket 
 international airport,  Bangkok airport , Krabi Airport , Hat Yai Airport and Chiang Mai airport . 
 There is always a cheap flight to Phuket available 
 somewhere. With Air Asia a cheap flights to Phuket 
 are available from many destinations in 
 Thailand and on international routes. If you 
 travel to Phuket from or to Singapore 
 probably the best choice is Tiger Airways 
 since most of the time they are on time and 
 ticket fares are low, they also fly to Krabi 
 and Hat Yai out of Singapore Changi.   

 After your Phuket 
 flight arrives the 
 best is probably to take a minibus to almost any 

 
 destination on 
 Phuket Island, it&apos;s between Baht 100,- for a 
 ride to Phuket Town and upwards depending 
 where to go, such as Patong Beach , Rawai Beach , Phuket City , Chalong Beach , Kata Beach , Karon Beach , Nai Harn Beach , Bangtao Beach , Laguna Phuket , Cape Panwa 
 or other Phuket beach areas etc. If 
 you use this minibus service it usually 
 takes about 10 - 15 minutes to wait. The 
 counter for the minibus service is just 
 before you leave the arrival hall, don&apos;t 
 worry you cant miss, there are always some 
 employees screaming taxi . There are no 
 dedicated airport hotels but in the vicinity are plenty of Phuket hotels 
 and Phuket Beach resorts. If someone wants to stay 
 at the airport region the best is to take 
 one of the hotels near at Nai Yang Beach , 
 that&apos;s the second closest beach next to the 
 airport. The closest hotel - beach resort is 
 pictured below. There are counters at the 
 arrival hall for Phuket hotel and Phuket 
 Beach Resort information, if you book a 
 Phuket hotel 
Nai Yang Beach 
 

 
 or Phuket Beach 
 Resort at the Airport be aware 
 that they take commission by asking you for a 
 relatively high price and they get the commission 
 every day you stay in a particular Phuket hotel and 
 Phuket Beach Resort. A way to work around is to book 
 for one night only, check out from the Phuket Hotel 
 or Phuket Beach Resort the next day, negotiate a new 
 and lower price and check in again. Several of the 
 Phuket luxury hotels and resorts have
their own lounge at the airport, check when you 
 book, they will take care 
 
 Phuket Airport Hotels 
 Dewa Resort 
 of you. 
 Airport Hotels got a new member, its the Dewa 
 Phuket Resort only a few minutes drive 
 distance 

 
 from Phuket 
 International Airport. 

 Phuket Airport Car Rental 

 
 There are several 
 Phuket international airport car rental company counter in the arrival 
 hall, those are usually the international car rental 
 companies like avis, hertz etc. but they all are 
 relatively expensive. For Phuket Airport Car Rental , 
 check here, they are located in Phuket Town and will pick you up 
 at and bring you back to the airport. They have 
 excellent new cars, are very friendly and know what 
 they are doing. A family business for many years, 
 they also have a excellent reputation and very 
 important, their prices are around half what the big 
 international guys are charging, for the same 
 service. All cars are fully insure via a&quot;first 
 class insurance&quot;, they also rent small motorbikes 
 for around Baht 150,- per day.

In times of cheap flights to Phuket, as we 
 have, congestion in front of the immigration counter 
 at arrival is inevitable. From time to time the airport gets an upgrade 
 but the worst is probably at arrival when 2 aircraft 
 come in within a few minutes timeframe, usual wait 
 in front of immigration can be up to one hour, there 
 is no problem with going through custom, people are 
 very friendly and tolerant. 
 If you are hungry use this 
 airport restaurant pictured here, it 
 is upstairs, the food is excellent and not 
 expensive. Avoid the fast food counter 
 opposite to the check in counter, their food is lousy, 
 the employees totally ignorant and funny, just the items 
 what you want to order is not available today, this is a&quot;Chester Grill&quot;outlet but when asking for a 
 chicken leg, they usually answer, today not 
 available. Inside the domestic departure area is also a fast food 
 restaurant from Burger King, their food is also quite good, 
 at least they serve real hamburger, about 10 mm thick. Not 
 this flat junk like you get at Macdonald&apos;s downtown where 
 the hamburger is 3 mm thick, actually looks like a small 
 size tortilla between some bread. Everything is very similar to Bangkok&apos;s new airport and Bangkok&apos;s 
 old airport. The real problem is that the 
 whole organization is wrongly as long to 
 handle 1 passenger as their Singapore Changi Airport counterpart, since basically they are just doing 
 the same as the Singaporeans it must be a organization 
 problem since the 
 Thai immigration officers need about 4 times as long as the 
 Singaporean immigration officer. 

 Actually even at the new Yangon or Rangoon airport in 
 Myanmar it 
 
 
 Departure Hall Phuket international airport, cheap flights to Phuket. 
   
Cheap flights to Phuket Thailand 
Cheap flights to Phuket Thailand 
 Airport Restaurant 
 works faster. 
 Airport parking is another strange story at 
 this airport, until beginning of 2009 the 
 fee was Baht 40,- per day which is 
 reasonable since there is only airport 
 parking in an open car park lot, no roof, no 
 cover. At the beginning of 2010 they said a 
 different company took over the car park and 
 the price for one day jumped to Baht 
 400,-this is a tenfold increase within the 
 same environ. 
 
   
 Phuket Transportation, this is from 
 Karon beach but its the same from Patong and other beaches . 
 
 
 
 

 

 
 
 
                                
 Phuket 
 International Airport 
 
 
 
 Phuket car rental , Phuket flight , Phuket 
 hotel , Phuket 
 airport taxi , Phuket airport 
 Thailand , flights to Phuket, cheap flights to Phuket , Phuket Airport hotels . 
 
 
 
 Enter your search terms 
 Web www.phuket-to-krabi.com 
Submit search form 
 
 
 
 
 Copyright phuket-to-krabi.com all rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
