<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008277" url="http://fastfood-statistics.blogspot.com/2011_04_01_archive.html" time="2012-07-13-01:46" support="4" score="0.012441523540940625" bingtitle="FASTFOOD STATISTICS: April 2011" webtitle="FASTFOOD STATISTICS: April 2011">
			<query id="000878" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="001506" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="001035" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000595" bing-rank="180"/>
	<description>My Food Recipes Love to eat and still learning ... If you have to go to a fast food restaurant to meet a friend or something, do your homework first.</description>
	<body>
		skip to main | skip to sidebar 
 FASTFOOD STATISTICS 
 
 ABOUT FAST FOOD STATISTICS 
 
SEARCH ENGINE
 Custom Search 
FAST FOOD PIC
 Loading... 
My Blog List
 
 BREAD MACHINE RECIPES IRON RICH FOODS NORWEGIAN RECIPES MEDICINAL HERBS SWEDISH PANCAKES HOW TO COOK BEETS Edible Mushrooms DETOX DIET KRUMKAKE POTASSIUM RICH FOODS FOODS HIGH IN TRYPTOPHAN BEST GROUND BEEF RECIPES CAN MILK CAUSE HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE ?? HAMBURGER SEASONING RECIPE 2012 APOCALYPSE FOODS HIGH IN URIC ACID GRILL RECIPES FOR STEAK BLANK FOOD PYRAMID EVENING PRIMROSE OIL APPLE CIDER VINEGAR JELLO RECIPES SPANISH DRINKS RECIPES WEBER GRILL RECIPES MARINATED CHICKEN BREAST RECIPES DEVILED EGGS RECIPE CONVECTION OVEN RECIPES TURKEY LEFTOVER RECIPES SIRLOIN STEAK RECIPES MEAT FONDUE RECIPES STUFFED PEPPERS RECIPES ITALIAN CREAM CAKE RECIPE DRY RUB RECIPES KRAFT RECIPES EGG CUSTARD PIE RECIPES RIB EYE STEAK MARINADE RECIPES BAKED HAM RECIPES DENSUS 88 PASUKAN ANTI TEROR CHEESE RENNET RICE KRISPIE TREAT RECIPES CHEDDAR CHEESE FONDUE LOW SODIUM RECIPES ATLANTIS CONTINENT FROZEN STRAWBERRY DAIQUIRI RECIPES HOME MADE HAMBURGER RECIPE HIGH FRUCTOSE CORN SYRUP HOW TO MAKE A MOJITO SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING BRAIN FAST FOOD NUTRITION FACTS CREAM CHEESE WONTONS RECIPES AMERICAN BEEF BURGER RECIPES COCONUT CAKE RECIPES BROCCOLI RECIPE CHEESE FONDUE RECIPES BAKED CHICKEN DRUMSTICK RECIPES BELUGA CAVIAR RECIPES Fruit Salad Recipe SUPERBOWL RECIPES GAS GRILL RECIPES FRENCH PEA SAUCE QUICK COOKING RECIPES SODA BOTTLE BOMB HAMBURGER PATTIE RECIPES HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE SYMPTOMS TERIYAKI SAUCE RECIPE WITCH FINGER RECIPES RUBY TUESDAY RECIPES STEAK AND CHEESE MEATBALLS RECIPE 
 
RECENT VIEWERS
 
About Me
 My Food Recipes Love to eat and still learning to cook great foods. View my complete profile 
ABOUT FAST FOOD STATISTICS
 Loading... 
 Friday, 15 April 2011 
 
 Fast Food Families: Why You Can’t Afford the Drive Thru 
 Fast Food Families: Why You Can’t Afford the Drive Thru 
 Fast Food Statistics 
It’s a question that makes most moms squirm. What’s for dinner? Unfortunately, many times in desperation the answer is found at the nearest drive thru. Today’s average American eats 4 or more meals away from home each week. Fast food is no longer a treat for many families. It’s a habit that comes with a big price tag not listed on any value menu.

Consider the mom who’s trying to lose weight. She should be eating 1,800 calories or less per day. If she orders a hamburger, small French fries and small soda at the neighborhood drive thru, she’s just spent 1000 calories on lunch. Not to mention the terrible nutritional value of those calories. It’s a very high price to pay for convenience.

Here’s a frightening study. Researchers found that every day, nearly one-third of U.S. children aged 4 to 19 eat fast food, which likely packs on about six extra pounds per child every year. Billions of dollars are spent every year on fast food advertising directed at kids. No wonder America’s kids are wrestling with obesity in alarming numbers.

So what can you do to break the cycle of unhealthy fast food consumption for yourself and your kids before it’s too late?

1. Reduce the number of times you eat fast food. If you currently eat fast food once a week, then make it your goal to go for two weeks before hitting the drive thru again. Over time, wean yourself away from fast food restaurants. Reserve trips to McDonald’s or Burger King for occasional meetings with friends.

2. Find other convenient alternatives for meals. Making sandwiches with sliced turkey breast and whole wheat bread with ready-made salad makes an easy meal that’s more nutritious than any value meal. Buy a rotisserie chicken or other ready-to-eat options at a grocery store instead of choosing fast food. If you dread doing the dishes, why not use paper plates?

3. Watch Super Size Me. You will be astounded by this documentary about the fast food industry. Filmmaker Morgan Spurlock eats only McDonald’s for thirty days straight. You’ll see what happens to his body in just one month. Believe me, you won’t look at a cheeseburger and fries in the same way ever again. This captivating Sundance award-winning feature reveals how we as a nation are eating ourselves to death.

4. Check the nutritional facts on the menu items you order. What fast food place do you frequent most often? What do you usually get? Go online and look for &quot;nutritional facts&quot; on that restaurant’s website. You may be shocked to discover the bacon double cheeseburger you love is a whopping 900 calories. If you have to go to a fast food restaurant to meet a friend or something, do your homework first. Order the least caloric and damaging item on the menu. It’s usually a grilled chicken sandwich, chili, salad with dressing on the side, or a fruit cup.

When your kids ask what’s for dinner, don’t automatically make a beeline for the nearest drive thru. There’s nothing convenient about eating fattyScience Articles, unhealthy food that leads to obesity. Get creative and find better food alternatives for you and your loved ones.
 Fast Food Statistics
 fast-food-nutrition-facts 
 Posted by My Food Recipes at 00:07 No comments: Labels: fast food statistics Newer Posts Older Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 
ABOUT FAST FOOD STATISTICS
 
 6-Negative-effects-of-eating-fast-food Can-fast-food-be-healthy Eat-fast-eat-healthy-with-low-carb-fast Effects-of-fast-food Facts-about-fast-food-and-your-weight Fast-food-causes-obesity. Fast-food-danger Fast-food-no-no&apos;s Fast-food-nutrition-facts Fast-food-statistics Fast-food-statistics-and-obesity. Growth-of-Fast-Food-industry. How-many-people-eat-fast-food Marketing-fast-food Spinning-fast-food-statistics 
 
FAST FOOD STAT NEWS
 Loading... 
msnbc.com: Diet and nutrition
 Loading... 
Epicurious.com: New Recipes
 Loading... 
Subscribe To
 Posts Atom Posts All Comments Atom All Comments 
Blog Archive
 
 ▼  2011 (5) 
 ►  August (1) 
 Eat Fast, Eat Healthy With Low Carb Fast Food 
 

 ►  July (1) 
 FAST FOOD NO NO&apos;S 
 

 ►  June (1) 
 6 Negative Effects Of Eating Fast Food 
 

 ►  May (1) 
 Can Fast Food Be Healthy? 
 

 ▼  April (1) 
 Fast Food Families: Why You Can’t Afford the Drive... 
 
 

 ►  2009 (13) 
 ►  November (5) 
 Fast Food causes Obesity? Fast Food Danger Fast Food Nutrition Facts Effects of Fast Food How many people eat fast food 
 

 ►  March (5) 
 Fast food statistics and obesity Marketing Fast Food Growth of the fast food industry Fast Food And Obesity Statistics Fast Food And Obesity Statistics 
 

 ►  January (3) 
 The Facts About Fast Food And Your Weight! Spinning Fast-food Statistics Fast Food Statistics 
 
 
   
 blogger templates | Make Money Online
	</body>
</document>
