<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008539" url="http://www.foxbusiness.com/markets/2010/09/07/analysis-egypts-wheat-bread-riots-unlikely/" time="2012-07-13-02:00" support="1" score="0.00978762067503995" bingtitle="ANALYSIS-Egypt&apos;s wheat bill up, but bread riots unlikely | Fox ..." webtitle="ANALYSIS-Egypts wheat bill up, but bread riots unlikely | Fox Business">
			<query id="001293" bing-rank="148"/>
	<description>The speed at which it has refilled its wheat order ... bigger bill than plannedthis financial year to pay for ... continuingto grow even during the credit crunch at near 5 ...</description>
	<body>
		Fox News Digital Network   Fox News   Fox Business   uReport   Fox News Radio   Fox News Latino   Fox Nation   Fox News Insider 
 Register Login 
 Account 
You&apos;re logged in as Account 

 Edit Profile Logout 
 Search Site 
 Home Video News Investing Technology Personal Finance Business Leaders Travel On Air Small Business 
 
industries

ANALYSIS-Egypt&apos;s wheat bill up, but bread riots unlikely
 
Published September 07, 2010 

 Reuters 
 
   Print   Email   Share   Comments 
 
By Sherine El Madany and Edmund Blair

CAIRO, Sept 7 (Reuters) - Egypt, the world&apos;s biggest wheatimporter, faces a higher bill for bread subsidies in the nextyear but has adequate financial resources and stocks to avoidany rerun of the violent protests of 2008.

Egypt raced to redo orders after drought-hit Russia haltedgrain exports in August, which sent wheat prices surging. Cairohad booked 540,000 tonnes of Russian wheat from July until then.

The speed at which it has refilled its wheat order bookreflects a determination to avoid any shortages of subsidisedbread on which many poor people in the country of 78 milliondepend. The government has repeatedly said supplies are secure.

Shortfalls two years ago, coupled with rising prices ofother commodities, led to clashes between protesters and police.

In Egypt, securing basic staples is politically sensitive atany time, but analysts say the government is particularly warynow because it wants to head off any kind of unrest beforeparliamentary and presidential elections this year and next.

&quot;I do not see the situation escalating to public unrest andriots similar to what happened in 2008, because internationalwheat prices are not rising to 2008 levels,&quot; said Magdy Sobhy atthe Al Ahram Centre for Political and Strategic Studies.

Wheat prices surged in 2008 after several years in whichglobal consumption of wheat had outstripped production.

But a Western industry expert based in Cairo said the latestprice rise followed a couple of record global harvests, withsupplies outpacing demand, so prices are unlikely to rise ashigh as that. &quot;Prices went a lot higher a couple of years ago, and I don&apos;texpect them to continue to climb so much this season or thismarketing year because of the (global) stocks that have built upover the last two years,&quot; he said.

His comments echo those of a U.N. Food and AgricultureOrganisation economist, who said the Russian export ban did notmean a repeat of the 2007/2008 food crisis.

&apos;ENOUGH MONEY&apos;

Egypt has paid about $280-$290 a tonne for wheat fromFrance, Canada and the United States in August and September,while in June it paid around $165 a tonne for some Russianwheat. In early 2008, Egypt paid $450-$480 a tonne for someshipments.

As prices rise, the government is taking no chances and hasbought stocks to last to January, a comfortable cushion.

Egypt consumes some 14 million tonnes of wheat a year, abouthalf of that imported and most of it by state buyer the GeneralAuthority for Supply and Commodities (GASC), which bought some5.5 million tonnes via international tenders in fiscal 2009/10.

The government will have a bigger bill than plannedthis financial year to pay for the small, flat subsidisedloaves, so-called &apos;baladi&apos; bread, which weigh roughly 100-125grammes and each cost 5 piastres (less than 1 U.S. cent).

Cairo has said it expects to spend an extra 2.5 billion to 4billion pounds in 2010/11 to make up the shortfall after theRussian ban. But experts say Egypt can easily cover this.

&quot;We forecast around 3 billion pounds, which constitutesaround 0.2 percent of GDP,&quot; said Mohamed Abu Basha, an economistat EFG-Hermes investment bank. &quot;It is not a significantincrease, and we have enough money to pay the difference.&quot;

Egypt&apos;s economy has defied the global slowdown, continuingto grow even during the credit crunch at near 5 percent. It hasalso built up the central bank&apos;s foreign reserves to recordlevels, now in excess of $35 billion.

&quot;They seem to have the hard currency. It is has not been anissue for them. Definitely wheat is going to be something thatis a top priority for the government and they are going to makesure they have the budget,&quot; said the Western expert.

He also said &apos;baladi&apos; bread can be made with a range ofwheat varieties, giving GASC a wide choice for sourcing. GASCrecently added Argentina to its list of usual suppliers -- theUnited States, France, Germany, Canada and Australia .

But some Cairo traders said Egypt, which bought only fromRussia in July, was too slow to spot the impact of a drought .

&quot;There were signs ahead of time that Russia was facing someproblems in wheat supply, and Egypt should have takenpre-emptive action by diversifying its sources,&quot; said one.

There has been some grumbling and the occasional modestprotest of a few dozen people about price rises in recent weeks.

But analysts say the latest price rises are mainly fuelledby seasonal factors due to Ramadan, a month when Muslim familiesand friends often gather for big meals to break each day&apos;s fast.Inflation has still held fairly steady at just over 10 percent.

No one expects President Hosni Mubarak&apos;s National DemocraticParty to face a significant challenge in either November&apos;sparliamentary poll or the 2011 presidential vote, but thegovernment wants to avoid giving opponents any ammunition.

&quot;We will not see bread queues or riots because thegovernment is well prepared ahead of elections season to avoidany negative impact on the NDP in the elections,&quot; said Sobhy. (Writing by Edmund Blair, editing by Jane Baird)
 
Social Media

   
 
Subscribe
 
Sign up for free e-mail news alerts from FoxNews.com and FoxBusiness.com.
 Subscribe 
 View Article 
 Please enable JavaScript to view the&lt;a href=&quot;http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript=foxnation&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt; 
You must login to comment.
 
 View Article 
 
Follow Fox Business
 
Advertisement
 
More Stories
 
   
 
Advertisement
 
Sections
 
 Home Video News Investing Technology Personal Finance Business Leaders Travel On Air Small Business 
 
Browse
 
 Stock Quotes Video Anchors&amp;Reporters TV Show Schedule Tools Topics Flight Tracker Mobile Apps&amp;Downloads 
 
Shows
 
 After The Bell Cavuto Closing Bell Imus in the Morning Lou Dobbs Tonight Money With Melissa Francis Stossel Tom Sullivan Varney&amp;Company The Willis Report 
 
About
 
 About Fox Business Channel Finder Advertise with Us Jobs at Fox Business Internships Terms of Use Privacy Statement Ad Choices Media Relations 
 
Follow
 
   Facebook   Twitter   YouTube   RSS   Newsletters 
 
 
Quotes delayed at least 15 minutes. Real-time quotes provided by BATS Exchange. Market Data provided by Interactive Data ( Terms&amp;Conditions ). Powered and Implemented by Interactive Data Managed Solutions . Company fundamental data provided by Morningstar . Earnings estimates data provided by Zacks. Mutual fund data provided by Lipper. Economic data provided by Econoday. Dow Jones&amp;Company Terms&amp;Conditions.

This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.©2012 FOX News Network, LLC. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
