<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008226" url="http://www.villa4vacation.com/vacation-rental/USA-Missouri-Lake-Ozark/446681.aspx" time="2012-07-13-01:42" support="1" score="0.0017123885840306888" bingtitle="Lake Ozark vacation Villa rental – Prestigious Waterfront Home ..." webtitle="Lake Ozark vacation Villa rental – Prestigious Waterfront Home  Wooded Lot  P...">
			<query id="000692" bing-rank="56"/>
	<description>We have parking for 6 cars in front of the house, and ... Located near 5 waterfront restaurants, several golf ... Theme Park: Movie Theater: Fishing: Parasailing: Water Skiing</description>
	<body>
		Feedback 
 
 
 Home List Your Home HomeOwner Log In Travelers Guide Travel Agents Contact Us 
 
 
 This badge indicates that this vacation home is managed by an individual homeowner or a property manager who either supplied us with due diligence prove of ownership or his/her listing is advertised on our web site without any complaints for more than 180 days. We still advise to Renters to avoid paying by instant and non-recoverable money transfer services regardless of the Badge. 
 
 
 Translate this page 
 
 
 Bookmark this page 
 
 Email to a Friend 
 
 

 USA Missouri Lake of the Ozarks Lake Ozark Vacation Rentals 

 
Lake Ozark Vacation Rental Prestigious Waterfront Home, Wooded Lot, Private Boat Dock
 
ad # 446681
 

 
 
 7  Bedrooms - 4  Bathrooms - 21  Sleeps 

 Property Type: Villa / House Unit size: 4000 Sq.ft. Daily Rent: $113 - $600 
 
 Owner: Roxann Payne Speaks: English Time zone: US/Central U. S. A. 1 573 819-4438 Show Phone # 
     Security Advise 
 
 
 

 Listed since May, 25, 2010 This ad was viewed 2431 times 


 


 
 Description Photos Location Amenities Rates Availability Contact Owner Related Services Top  
 
Description of the Prestigious Waterfront Home, Wooded Lot, Private Boat Dock Vacation Rental Villa / House


  Title/Quick Description

Located on famous Horseshoe Bend. Home has private dock with cable tv, swim area and patio. This is a 3 story open floor plan with floor to ceiling windows and mirrored walls on main level. Recreation room with air hockey, foosball and wet bar. 3 large decks and bonfire area. 152 ft of natural rock shoreline.

  Specific information about property

 Enjoy the fabulous lake views from our lakeside home. 152 ft of natural rock shoreline. 7 bedrooms with 2 kings, 2 queens, 1 full, 3 twins, 2 sets of bunkbeds, and 2 pull out sofa sleepers. 2 large gas grills, 2 wading pools for little ones, all linens, cook ware, spices, condiments, towels and wash cloths provided. Each Bathroom has a built in hair dryer. Iron and ironing board are provided. Bedrooms are 24 x 24ft. Main floor living room is 30 x 20ft. We have parking for 6 cars in front of the house, and trailer parking at top of the hill. Private setting with no boat traffic around dock. We have 2 wood burning fireplaces and a huge recreation room with wet bar, air hockey and foosball. Large firepit overlooking the lake for all your bonfires! We have added a 21 ft Odessey pontoon that holds 13 passengers--available to rent. Located near 5 waterfront restaurants, several golf courses, the outlet mall and grocery stores. 
 
 


 
 Description Photos Location Amenities Rates Availability Contact Owner Related Services Top  
 
Photos of the Prestigious Waterfront Home, Wooded Lot, Private Boat Dock Vacation Rental Villa / House
	</body>
</document>
