<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008445" url="http://lifewiththegylcemicindexdiet.wordpress.com/eating-out-on-the-glycemic-index-diet/" time="2012-07-13-01:54" support="1" score="0.006622116633968896" bingtitle="Dining Out « Life On The Glycemic Index Diet" webtitle="Dining OutLife On The Glycemic Index Diet">
			<query id="000357" bing-rank="237"/>
	<description>You do get ALOT of rice though, so I usually only eat ... Panera Bread was rated the best fast food restaurant chain ... Texas Farm To Table. Texas Farm To Table focuses on fresh ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About Agave Nectar Dining Out Foodsheds 

 Life On The Glycemic Index Diet 
 
Dining Out

 I’ve sorted some past blog entries and added some new information so there would be a one-stop resource available for glycemic index friendly restaurant information.  I may continue to add information through seperate blog entries, but will also make sure this static page stays updated.  When I first started the GI diet I thought I was stuck with just a couple restaurants, but over time I’ve found lots of great options, and want to help others also find delicious, healthy options.  If you have any great places to share please drop me a line! 

 

 National Chains: 

 Pei Wei Asian Diner 

They have brown rice available as an option which makes any of their rice bowls G.I. friendly. You do get ALOT of rice though, so I usually only eat about half of it. They also have lettuce wraps and other goodies that are South Beach friendly, no matter what stage you are on.

 Panera Bread 

Panera Bread was rated the best fast food restaurant chain in the country by Consumer Reports.  We finally got one in San Antonio less than a year ago and it quickly became the favorite lunch hangout for me and all my coworkers.  They have a bakery section with lots of whole grain goodies, and plenty of GI friendly options on their menu including soups, salads, and sandwiches.  As a side to your meal you can choose whole grain bread or fruit (as well as white bread and chips).  Calling them a fast food restaurant seems technically accurate but awfully unfair.

 The Sandwich Shops 

 Subway , Schlotsky’s , Quizno’s and Firehouse Subs are all national chains that have a whole wheat bread option. I worked at Subway’s all through college and even after college when looking for a real job. They are super clean and the food is always super fresh. Subway also has a healthy option meal where you can get apple slices or raisins instead of chips so I usually go there if I’m hitting a sandwich shop.

 The Salad Chronicles 

I know that when you are trying to stay on a healthy diet everyone tells you“just have the salad!”There is only so much salad one person can eat though, and usually the last thing I want when I eat out.  However, there are two salads I dig. I like the Asian Chicken Salad from Jack In The Box and the Greek Salad from the SuperTarget deli . (Yes the stuffed grape leaf that it comes with is made with white rice, but only about a tbs full.) Generally if I have salad I make my own, but these two I think are worth the price!

 Whole Foods 

Whole Foods is an organic grocery like Sun Harvest or Wild Oats that is a national chain. They have a huge deli/prepared foods section but when I stop there to grab lunch I always get the brown rice sushi that is available in the same varieties the regular sushi is. It falls apart a little faster but stays delicious!

 Regional Chains: 

 FreeB!rd World Burrito 

FreeB!rd is a Texas chain similar to Chipolte Grill except with more options, including wheat tortillas. I get the 1/2 Bird with a wheat tortilla, no rice, whole beans (they have pinto and black), chicken, cheese and guac. They also have beef and lots of veggies. They also have Diet Dr Pepper on fountain so I heart them muchly.

 San Antonio Restaurants: 

 Habaneros Grill 

This is a San Antonio-only build your own burrito bar with two locations in town.  They also have wheat tortillas…and what’s even better is the tortillas are all cooked to order so they are hot and fresh. Go riceless and get the whole beans, just like above, and you can stay G.I. friendly!

 Gourmet Burger Grill 

Here you  have not only a choice of sourdough white bun, but whole wheat or marble rye bun. And a choice of Angus beef, or American Kobe beef, or ahi tuna, or chicken, or turkey or crabcake sandwich! Not to mention any of 13 cheese choices, including boursin, camembert and goat cheese; 13 sauces to choose from including lemon remoulade, pesto mayo and horseradish cream; and 13 interesting other toppings like sun-dried tomatoes, fried egg, and roasted red peppers.

 green 

Is San Antonio’s first and only completely vegetarian restaurant.  To tell you how serious we take our meat in Texas, it took us until 2007 to get a vegetarian option in town!  They have lots of meatless goodies and serve their sandwiches and burgers on whole wheat bread and buns!

 Texas Farm To Table 

Texas Farm To Table focuses on fresh, local, organic, and fair-trade ingredients.  Lots of GI friendly options such as buckwheat pancakes at breakfast and delcious sandwiches served on whole grain breads!  You can also have your sandwich served with fruit instead of potato salad!

 Other Cities: 

Send me your reviews of GI friendly restaurants in your area!
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
1 Response so far » 

 1 
 Tracy said,
 
 October 22, 2008 @ 6:31 pm 

*sigh* How I miss Habanero’s grill. That was one of my fav’s when I was living in SA. Another local (Texas) grocer would be Central Market for whole grain breads. They have 5, 7 and 9 grains that are awesome!
 Reply 
 

 Comment RSS · TrackBack URI 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
Search
 
   
 
Latest

 Salmon Santa Fe Pink Eyed Peas Fried Okra Step By Step Sunday Linky Goodness Freezing Yellow Squash Pasta With Pesto and Grilled Chicken A Note On Pasta Freezing Green Beans Sunday Linky Goodness Pasta With Clams and Criminis 
 
Archives

 January 2010  (1) December 2009  (1) June 2009  (16) May 2009  (23) March 2009  (4) February 2009  (8) December 2008  (1) November 2008  (1) August 2008  (2) July 2008  (27) June 2008  (31) May 2008  (26) October 2007  (1) August 2007  (5) July 2007  (2) June 2007  (18) May 2007  (19) April 2007  (11) 
 
Categories

 Uncategorized (0) Links (67) Product Reviews (22) Book Reviews (3) General Info (69) Recipes—Desserts (21) Recipes—Snacks (19) Recipes—Side Dishes (35) Recipies—Vegetarian (48) Recipes—Drinks (1) Eating Out on G.I. (3) Recipes—Soups (7) Recipes—Appetizers (19) Recipes—Main Dishes (43) Recipes—Breads (12) Recipes—Crockpot (8) Recipies—Sauces&amp;Dressings (17) Glycemic Index 101 (8) 
 
Feeds

 Entries RSS Comments RSS 
 
GI&amp;Diabetic Friendly Blogs

 Diabetes Developments Doable Diabetes GI News Kalyn’s Kitchen 
 
Growing Your Own

 Diggin Food Growing Sprouts The City Chicken You Grow Girl 
 
Locavore Blogs

 100 Mile Diet Blog Cincinnati Locavore Cricket Bread Eating Out Of The Local Box Growers and Grocers Texas Beer Texas Locavore The Sustainable Diet 
 
Recommended Reading

 Animal, Vegetable, Miracle by Barbara Kingsolver Baking With Agave Nectar by Ania Catalano South Beach Diet Dining Guide by Arther Agatston The G.I. Diet: The Easy, Healthy Way To Permanent Weight Loss by Rick Gallup The Good Carb Cookbook by Sandra Woodruff The Omnivore’s Dilemma by Michael Pollan The Vegetable Dishes I Can’t Live Without by Mollie Katzen 
 
Texas Resources

 Austin Farmer’s Market Bastrop Farmer’s Market Go Texan Greenling Leon Springs Farmers Market Pearl Farmer’s Market Pick Texas San Antonio Foodshed Sustainable Food Center Texas Wine Growers Zhi Tea 
 
Your Local Resources

 Find a Co-Op Near You Find a CSA Near You Find A Farmer’s Market Find a Pick-Your-Own Farm Find Good Food 
 
Misc

 Log in 
 
 
 Blog at WordPress.com . | Theme: Greenery by iLemoned .
 Follow 
 Follow“Life On The Glycemic Index Diet” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
