<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008747" url="http://www.scamfound.com/archive/index.php/f-13-p-215.html" time="2012-07-13-02:12" support="1" score="0.0013861820917880309" bingtitle="Complaints Board RSS Feed [Archive] - Page 215 - scams" webtitle="Complaints Board RSS Feed [Archive] - Page 215 - scams">
			<query id="000258" bing-rank="228"/>
	<description>A&amp;W fast food restaurant - Rude staff; Rum &amp; Co - Lost Merchandise... ... Florida Department of Revenue - Child Support ... Ghdoutlet.org - Never received my order; Comcast Cable ...</description>
	<body>
		scams &gt;Complaints Board RSS Feed PDA 
View Full Version : Complaints Board RSS Feed 
 Pages : 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 93 94 95 96 97 98 99 100 101 102 103 104 105 106 107 108 109 110 111 112 113 114 115 116 117 118 119 120 121 122 123 124 125 126 127 128 129 130 131 132 133 134 135 136 137 138 139 140 141 142 143 144 145 146 147 148 149 150 151 152 153 154 155 156 157 158 159 160 161 162 163 164 165 166 167 168 169 170 171 172 173 174 175 176 177 178 179 180 181 182 183 184 185 186 187 188 189 190 191 192 193 194 195 196 197 198 199 200 201 202 203 204 205 206 207 208 209 210 211 212 213 214 [ 215 ] 216 217 218 219 220 221 222 223 224 225 226 227 228 229 230 231 232 233 234 235 236 237 238 239 240 241 242 243 244 245 246 247 248 249 250 251 252 253 254 255 256 257 258 259 260 261 262 263 264 265 266 267 268 269 270 271 272 273 274 275 276 277 278 279 280 281 282 283 284 285 286 287 288 289 290 291 292 293 294 295 296 297 298 299 300 301 302 303 304 305 306 307 308 309 310 311 312 313 314 315 316 317 318 319 320 321 322 323 324 325 326 327 328 329 330 331 332 333 334 335 336 337 338 339 340 341 342 343 344 345 346 347 348 349 350 351 352 353 354 355 356 357 358 359 360 361 362 363 364 365 366 367 368 369 370 371 372 373 374 375 376 377 378 379 380 381 382 383 384 385 386 387 388 389 390 391 392 393 394 395 396 397 398 399 400 401 402 403 404 405 406 407 408 409 410 411 412 413 414 415 416 417 418 419 420 421 422 423 424 425 426 427 428 429 430 431 432 433 434 435 436 437 438 439 440 441 442 443 444 445 446 447 448 449 450 451 452 453 454 455 456 457 458 459 460 461 462 463 464 465 466 467 468 469 470 471 472 473 474 475 476 477 478 479 480 481 482 483 484 485 486 487 488 489 490 491 492 493 494 495 496 497 498 499 500 501 502 503 504 505 506 507 508 509 510 511 512 513 514 515 516 517 518 519 520 521 522 523 524 525 526 527 528 529 530 531 532 533 534 535 536 537 538 539 540 541 542 543 544 545 546 547 548 549 550 551 552 553 554 555 556 557 558 559 560 561 562 563 564 565 566 567 568 569 570 571 572 573 574 575 576 577 578 579 580 581 582 583 584 585 586 587 588 589 590 591 592 593 594 595 596 597 598 599 600 601 602 603 604 605 606 607 608 609 610 611 612 613 614 615 616 617 618 619 620 621 622 623 624 625 626 627 628 629 630 631 632 633 634 635 636 637 638 639 640 641 642 643 644 645 646 647 648 649 650 651 652 653 654 655 656 657 658 659 660 661 662 663 664 665 666 667 668 669 670 671 672 673 674 675 676 677 678 679 680 681 682 683 684 685 686 687 688 689 690 691 692 693 694 695 696 697 698 699 700 701 702 703 704 705 706 707 708 709 710 711 712 713 714 715 716 717 718 719 720 721 722 723 724 725 726 727 728 729 730 731 732 733 734 735 736 737 738 739 740 741 742 743 744 745 746 747 748 749 750 751 752 753 754 755 756 757 758 759 760 761 762 763 764 765 766 767 768 769 770 771 772 773 774 775 776 777 778 779 780 781 782 783 784 785 786 787 788 789 790 791 792 793 794 795 796 797 798 799 800 801 802 803 804 805 806 807 808 809 810 811 812 813 814 815 816 817 818 819 820 821 822 823 824 825 826 827 828 829 830 831 832 833 834 835 836 837 838 839 840 841 842 843 844 845 846 847 848 849 850 851 852 853 854 855 856 857 858 859 860 861 862 863 864 865 866 867 868 869 870 871 872 873 874 875 876 877 878 879 880 881 882 883 884 885 886 887 888 889 890 891 892 893 894 895 896 897 898 899 900 901 902 903 904 905 906 907 908 909 910 911 912 913 914 915 916 917 918 919 920 921 922 923 924 925 926 927 
 Chadwicks of Boston - Stay Away JeffBobbyandSteves - Illegal Deductions from paycheck Randolph AFB Firestone - Don&apos;t make an Appointment Jewelry TV - Receiving orders www.ivetriedthat.com - BEWARe of ivetriedthat.com SCAM Silas - Hi Sallie Mae - They are terrible... go else where!! Heiberger Paving Inc - Causes Damage Accurise - Poor business practices Shoebuy.com - Very poor customer service capitolsupply.com - What a waste of time! Grand Canyon University - Financial Aid Fraud Dish Network - Unauthorized rate changes ZaReason - Terrible company! MONEY 2 INDIA, ICICI BANK - Money Lost in transaction CheapoAir.com - Worst booking ever Association Resources West Hartford - This business sucks Image Display Group - Director is very rude during our interview RMI ENGINES - Don&apos;t use them GENESIS GLASS SPECIALISTS - Do not trust Augustine Automotive - The company destroyed Dr. Sumana Gangi - Very poor service, and care given europa camera&amp;- thief store Target.com - Bad delivery Niteshift Inc. - Didn&apos;t use. Didn&apos;t request. Didn&apos;t provide. No refund. Diageo - Bad company PSE&amp;G - Power outage for days midwestmoving.com - They have stole,scratched, and broken all my stuff Preen Nails Worcester - Dont bother people, unless you like dealing idiots! Braums - meals Turner Veternary Clinic - Filthy place Buffalo Wild Wings - MANAGER LACKS PROFESSIONALISM Hoffman Fuel Co. - Failure to provide service us telecom/long distance - harrassing phonecalls Custom Built Personal Training - Don&apos;t sign with these people. Sharaf DG - No replacement allowed within 1 day even 360Training.com - Absolute Nightmare Dealing with This Company Colothin - Do not want any more orders Coast to Coast dealer services - no coverage Luna Flooring - Lying Thiefs! Attracta SEO - refuses to give refund ipodnano5gsale - fraud Bank of America - Annual enrollment wrong again Direct Buy of Columbia. sc 29229 - Ultimate SCAM Lifestyle Furniture - Money scam Upholstery Cleaning Seattle - They never showed up ADT Home Security - Awful service Wspw inc. - Shame on you! Q.B. Johnson MFG. - Racists LAstop Productions - Stay away Kiev Connections - Discrimination Deceit and Greed Deception Futuresoft - No policy and process Seiko - Faulty watches Tractor Supply - Shes the worst! Art&amp;Logic - Avoid them unless you like spam Bright Star Credit Union - Fraud Maximus - Scammer Money Saving Direct Ltd - Don&apos;t do business with them Odyssey Bookshop - Bad service Bozarts Inc - Bad web designer Adelson Clinic - The staff is unprofessional Blizzard Entertainment - Slow response to problems Minnesota Petroleum Service - Stay away from these people!! Belknap Plumbing - Do not use or work for this company Sansone Auto Mall - Bad service Companynamesucks.com - Bustards Voice Environmental Group - Unprofessional iTrough.com - Order is late BuyWithMe - Do not, under any circumstances, buy anything from this company Design Furnishings - Worst customer service ever! MGA Healthcare Staffing - Company has recruiters that lie to you Banfield - Warning!! brent brown toyota - Horrible dealership Target Corp - Mis-placed product or wrong price Americans / disorders - suicide; failures RegWork - Fraud Software-hq.net - I was stolled!!! E Machines Laptop - Fraud PC-OnTime - Fraud Compuview Microsystems - Don&apos;t be fooled by the low prices Alina Micro - Stay away the BBB - pay to play ranking Connect Computers - This was the worst online purchase experience Overnight Genius - Stay away Bytewize Computers - Store seems unable to deliever really stupid people - false charity RLRSCREENSAVER.COM - They violated my privacy&amp;took money from my bank account unaut Distinctive Collection - Bentley GT - Fraudulent Car Sales Tactics WeBuildPCs - Run forrest RUN! Geenks on Time - I placed numberous calls and e-mail, no dice... Memory Monster - I was only PARTLY SCREWED!! AI Computers - Stay away MP Comp - They are the worst merchants Club Computer - Fraudulant 8ta - Blilling Forest Lake Solutions - Rip off Seagate - Don&apos;t bother ordering from them Marts Oil Service - Deceptive/Dishonest Business Practices 1st Micro - Spooky situation RBS Worldpay - Holding money GDP China WOW gold - Scam Gateway Computers - Money stolen ParetoLogic - Don&apos;t buy it! 3gplaza.com - Scam MbContact.com - Fraud Prosperian Capital - Refund! CHrpay.com - I got nothing for my 49.95 usd HP dv6000 - Never again ! Roxio Media Creator 10 - Buyer beware Ace Wigs - This is actually an extremely POSITIVE REVIEW Prosperian Capital - Refund! usa-battery.org - Stay away InternetIncomeInitiatives.com - Scam Dennis Jordan - Don&apos;t buy from them meyrocorp - Fraudulent behavior Norton - Unauthorized charges Clemcode - Bad service MagicJack Plus - total rip off Promosoft Corporation - Stay away Scribble Software - Stay away Ebay - Cellphone still not replaced Wells Fargo Auto Finance - Harassing calls and reversed payments Belle DVDs - Never received my order Inland Empire Extra Care Inc - Waste of time Sun Search - Ripped off in the land of the Sun CellularTell.com - Unable to change the defect product onlinerepmanagement.com - Their service is a complete fraud Walmart - DOES NOT STAND BEHIND THEIR PRODUCTS Internet-Reputation-Management.com - Worst SEO company HALCO MANAGEMENT - They do not return calls, emails and UPS letters signed for by the Department of Public Social Service - This office is covering up their employee??s a MovieTicketPlusVideo.com - I did not get an email notification about my order and the Craig M. Laverty - After 3 months I was told my request was denied and no refund J. Yesko Roofing - Failed warranty Restaurant.com - Classic Bait and Switch Scam Haband, Inc. - Have not received a credit for this returned merchandise True Credit - Un-authorized monthly billing Sunny Sports, Inc. - defective product / won&apos;t honor warranty American Search Partners - Nick D&apos;uva Straight Talk - Service grc wen by chaz dean - Took unauthorized money from my bank account. McAfee Total Protection 1-Year - wrong email address on account UGG Store CC - Fake UGGs Russian World Forums - Prejudicial Practices and Other Corrupt Activity Dish TV - REGARDING RECHARE San jose mercury news - Won&apos;t stope my subscription and keep sending me bills, and un CyberDefender - Junk MPC Computers - I have not received the monitor ClickInks.com - You will get crappy ink and your money will be lost Last seconds - ATIF MALIK TN Dept of Labor&amp;Workforce Development - Stay away from these guys Reputation Management Consultants - They won&apos;t answer the phone and won&apos;t return my m Reputation Management Kings - Stay away from this one South University Online Education - Stay away from these fraud Verizon Wireless - I gave no authorization for these charges NMX*Franklin Prosperity - UNAUTHORIZED CREDIT CARD CHARGE Pepco Holdings, Inc. - Outrageous electric bills WEN BY CHAZ DEAN - Buyer Beware closeout explosion donny lowy - items not received www.magselect.com - Costs more to activate than promised Chase Bank - Refusal to correct billing errors TifCollections.com - Do not give this company any money A.V. Hospital - I do believe that this Hospital needs to be investigated by the state Reputation Defender - Reputation defender fails to live up to it&apos;s promises Virtual Paradise - Never buy a car from these people Chadwicks Catalog - Cannot stop catalogs Saleeater.com - No customer service and no product Okappa Slim - No product but they have my $$ Daugherty Pump and Drilling - Didn&apos;t provide receipt on payment Saleeater.com - No product and no customer service email despite &apos;shipped&apos; confirmati Baptist Hospital - Avoid this place at all costs US Cash Advance - Bogus loan Financial Education Services - No reimbursement Foxy Lady - Harassment, discrimination, violation of rights Sterling Optical - This man is unprofessional, I believe he is a crook, he is complet Airtel - Unnecessary loading song and cut price from public even me Law Office of Gerald Salerno - He is unethical, incompetent, and unorganized Sears - service Saleeater.com - This business should be stopped Golden Chopsticks - Poor service, rude, over charging, and unsanitary Hockeymonkey.com - The absolute worst customer service you will ever experience Modnique.com - Stay away from this one Travelzoo.com - I will never deal with these crooks again Inkspark.co.uk - 2 weeks after placing an order I&apos;ve still not had anything Goferr - Didn&apos;t give me my money i earned Tidebuy.com - I strongly suggest that you do not deal with this company agoda.com - Pathetic that they can&apos;t even get back within the promised time and that Nicecans.co.uk - Don&apos;t buy from this company sellmyoldcellphone.com - I was supposed to receive $114.40 and they offered a measly Batteryupgrade.co.uk - They were very slow in dealing with the problem Security-cameras-cctv.com - These people lie most of the time Rackspace outsoursing - Be aware of this site Foopile.com - FOOPILE has become terrible Ideeli.com - I ordered two coats on 9/30/11 which was charged to my credit card but u Darntoothysam.com - No response and i definitely feel robbed Akbar Travels - Cargo - Cargo not delivered even after 3 months The o.e. Group - scammers St. Aubyn&apos;s School - Poor Teaching Standards BlueYellowMedia - Fraudulant Charges Airtel Prepaid Connection - Horrible Service Herstyler Classic Zebra Straightening Irons - Faulty item with lifelong warranty Avis - Billing for damage not cause Identity Direct - Frustrated with Customer Service! kel attorneys - Forclosure defense Reliance Big TV - about smart card suspension Advance telecom engineers co llc - co line not working&amp;disturbense in another line NetGrantServices - Money Taken out of Account ANEESHRAJ - Ebay items Not Received ABSA idirect - car insurance Nokia - mobile stolen Nycha - lack of rule and regulation Astrologer G. D.Vashist (Red Book Specialist ) - Wrong Pridictions Randstad - This is how M&amp;G, Randstad and Square-one treat IT contractors Nokia - lost mobile Topups direct.co.uk - Service and product exchangetocash.net - scam GrocerySavers - Free groceries scam Pizza Hut - Asked for a tip after very poor service! LaCie External Harddrive - Faulty LaCie harddrive they wont replace and refund for un City of Tshwane - Added charges to account muscle x-1 - cancel subscription DRI*Electronic Arts eastore.com MN - Unauthorized credit card transaction Relogulf - Extremely bad service puppymatchmaker/carrie sawyer - with held infomation HDFC Bank - salary Eureka Forbes/Water purifier - Poor after sale setvice Indian Railway - INDIAN RAILWAY Mobily - balance deduct Dinodirect - Out of stock DNATA ClockTower Branch Deira - take 1090 more for the eticket. FUJIFILM NP-140 Battery - FUJIFILM NP-140 Battery PANASONIC VW-VBG6 battery - PANASONIC VW-VBG6 battery netspend prepaid cards - money that was deposit to my card Goldstartickets.co.uk - SCAM Agoda - Agoda lies lies lies...... Rackspace outsourcing - my job is not active my account section Samsung - Mobile Theft Whirlpool - poor service srnivasa priya hospital - Signal problem Jagan Enterprise - Cylender not issued Abhijeet Grp - debited account cash not disbursed wp10215acgpeil - washing machine blackberry Redington ltd - damaged handset Golfsmith - No communication / No service / No delivery Al ASDIQA REQUIREMENTS&amp;CONSULTANCY - FRAUD Golfsmith - No communication / No service / No delivery BENZE VACCATION CLUB - service Benze vaccation club - benze vaccation club BENZE VACCATION CLUB - service BENZE VACCATION CLUB - commitments 
 vBulletin®v3.8.3, Copyright©2000-2012, Jelsoft Enterprises Ltd.
	</body>
</document>
