<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008514" url="http://www.oppapers.com/essays/Healthy-Eating-Plan-Comparison/275200" time="2012-07-13-01:58" support="3" score="0.008245141541746584" bingtitle="Healthy Eating Plan Comparison - Essays - Uwillneverkno" webtitle="Healthy Eating Plan Comparison - Essays - Uwillneverkno">
			<query id="000407" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000158" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000721" bing-rank="97"/>
	<description>... my food intake; I am still consuming a lot of fast and junk foods. On most days, I work a 12 hour shift and I usually stop at a fast food restaurant for ... or receive ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Navigation Skip to Content 
 
 OPPapers.com 

 Free Essays and Research Papers 
 
 Join Login Writing Service Resources Help Saved Docs Contact Us 
 
 Search 
 
 Tweet 
 
Get Better Grades Today By Joining OPPapers.com and Accessing Over 650,000 Articles and Essays!
 get better grades 
 Home Page » Health » Nutrition Research Papers 
 
Healthy Eating Plan Comparison
 
Healthy Eating Plan Comparison
Healthy Eating Plan Comparison

SCI 241

My current eating habit has not changed since the last activity. I have not changed my food intake; I am still consuming a lot of fast and junk foods. On most days, I work a 12 hour shift and I usually stop at a fast food restaurant for take-out. My day still doesn’t stop there because I have to clean the house and make sure my homework assignments are completed. I buy my vegetables fresh from a local farmer in our area or receive them from my co-worker. I will normally freeze and can all our vegetables and have farm fresh eggs stocked in the refrigerator. Usually, I purchase meat from a Kosher or Halal store. They provide fresh beef, turkey and poultry items that they raise and butcher themselves. These foods are much better than things that come out of the super market, since they are from land and could be used as fertilizer. I really never had any problem with weight till I became pregnant with my daughter. I used to eat everything in sight and now it seems no matter what I do 
Is this essay helpful? Join OPPapers to read more and access more than 650,000 just like it!
 get better grades the weight will not come off. Losing weight is basically based on my age and physical level and whether I am trying to gain lose or maintain it.
The Number of Calories Needed for my Weight.

I could use a daily allotment of calories on a few high-calorie foods and beverages, but I probably wouldn’t get the nutrients my body needs to be healthy. I need to limit foods and beverages high in calories but low in nutrients, and limit how much saturated fat, Trans fat, cholesterol and sodium I consume. Paying attention to the Nutrition Facts panel will tell keep me informed of how much of those nutrients each food or beverage contain.
   As I make daily food choices, I try to base my eating patterns on the below recommendations:
  • Choose lean meats and poultry without skin and prepare them without added saturated and Trans fat.
  • Select fat-free, l percent, and low fat dairy product.
  • Cut back on foods containing partially... Read Full Essay 
Already a Member? Login Now » 

This essay and over 650,000 other essays are available now on OPPapers.com.
 
 Submitted by: uwillneverkno Date Submitted: 01/21/2010 01:08 PM Category: Nutrition Length: 5 pages (1,180 words) Views: 4793 

 Report this Essay Save Paper 
 
Related Essays

 Healthy Eating Plan Comparison Healthy Eating Plan Comparison Healthy Eating Plan Comparison Healthy Eating Plan Comparison The Healthy Eating Plan... Healthy Eating Plan Comparison Healthy Eating Plan Comparison Healthy Eating Plan Comparison Healthy Eating Plan Comparison Healthy Eating Plan Comparison Healthy Eating Plan Comparison Sci/241 Healthy Eating... Healthy Eating Plan... Healthy Eating Plan Comparison Healthy Eating Plan Comparison Healthy Eating Plan Comparison Assignment: Healthy Eating... Healthy Eating Plan Healthy Eating Plan Healthy Eating Plan Healthy Eating Plan Healthy Eating Plan Healthy Eating Plan Healthy Eating Plan Healthy Eating Plan Healthy Eating Plan Healthy Eating Plan Healthy Eating Plan Healthy Eating Plan Healthy Eating Plan 
 Read Full Essay 
Already a Member? Login Now » 
 Reviews ( 0 ) Grade No grades Be the first person to evaluate the essay!
 Login to grade this document. 
 RSS ©2012 OPPapers.com
 Help 
 About Us Our Blog F.A.Q. Contact Us 
 Other Stuff 
 Terms and Privacy Site Stats Sitemap Advertise With Us 
 Recent Topics 
 Dave Barry Guys Vs Men Mainstream American... Global Concerns Of... Marketing Environment... Compare And Contrast... Why i Want To Be a...
	</body>
</document>
