<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008708" url="http://www.prenhall.com/rm_student/html/careers/restmgr.html" time="2012-07-13-02:10" support="11" score="0.028959730581605826" bingtitle="RESTAURANT AND FOOD SERVICE MANAGERS" webtitle="RESTAURANT AND FOOD SERVICE
MANAGERS">
			<query id="000678" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000178" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000989" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000362" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="001207" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="000167" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="001209" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="001191" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="001216" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000365" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000427" bing-rank="115"/>
	<description>Eating places range from institutional ... and assistant managers to select and ... responsible for depositing the receipts at the bank, or securing them in a safe place.</description>
	<body>
		RESTAURANT AND FOOD SERVICE
MANAGERS 
 NATURE OF THE WORK 
Food is consumed outside the home in a variety of settings. Eating
places range from institutional cafeterias and fast food to elegant
dining establishments. The cuisine, price, and setting where the
meals are consumed vary, but managers of these dining facilities
share many of the same responsibilities. Efficient and profitable
operation of restaurants and institutional food service facilities
requires managers and assistant managers to select and appropriately
price menu items, use food and other supplies efficiently, and
achieve consistent quality in food preparation and service. They
also must attend to the various administrative aspects of business,
which includes recruiting, training, and supervising an adequate
number of workers.
In most restaurants and institutional food service facilities,
the manager is assisted by one or more assistant managers, depending
on the size and operating hours of the establishment. In large
establishments, as well as in many smaller ones, the management
team consists of a general manager ,
one or more assistant managers ,
and an executive chef .
The executive chef is the one responsible for the operation of
the kitchen, while the assistant managers oversee service in the
dining room and other areas of the operation. In smaller restaurants,
the executive chef may be the general manager, and sometimes an
owner. In fast-food restaurants and other facilities open for
long hours or 7 days a week, the manager is aided by several assistant
managers, each of whom supervises a shift of workers.
Many restaurants rarely change their menu, while others make frequent
alterations. Institutional food service facilities and some restaurants
offer a new menu every day. Managers or executive chefs select
menu items, taking into account the likely number of customers,
and the past popularity of dishes. Other issues taken into consideration
when planning a menu include food left over from prior meals that
should not be wasted, the need for variety, and the availability
of foods due to seasonality and other factors. Managers or executive
chefs analyze the recipes of the dishes to determine food, labor,
overhead costs and to assign prices to the various dishes. Menus
must be developed far enough in advance that supplies can be ordered
and received in time.
Ordering supplies and dealing with suppliers are important aspects
of the work of restaurant and food service managers. On a daily
basis, managers estimate food consumption, place orders with suppliers,
and schedule the delivery of fresh food and beverages. They receive
and check the content of deliveries, evaluating the quality of
meats, poultry, fish, fruits, vegetables, and baked goods. Managers
meet with the sales representatives from restaurant suppliers
to place orders replenishing stocks of tableware, linens, paper,
cleaning supplies, cooking utensils, and furniture and fixtures.
They also arrange for equipment maintenance and repairs, and for
various services such as waste removal and pest control.
Managers interview, hire, and, when necessary, fire employees.
They explain the establishment&apos;s policies and practices to newly
hired workers and oversee training. Managers schedule the work
hours of employees, making sure there are enough workers present
to cover peak dining periods.
Restaurant and food service managers supervise the kitchen and
dining room. They oversee food preparation and cooking, examining
quality and portion sizes to ensure that dishes are prepared and
garnished right and in a timely way. They also investigate and
resolve customer complaints about food quality or service. During
busy periods, managers&quot;roll up their sleeves&quot;and help
with the cooking, clearing of tables, or other tasks. They direct
the cleaning of the kitchen and dining areas and the washing of
tableware, kitchen utensils, and equipment to maintain company
and government sanitation standards. They monitor the actions
of employees and patrons on a continual basis to ensure the health
and safety standards and local liquor regulations are obeyed.
Managers have a variety of administrative responsibilities. In
larger establishments, much of this work is delegated to a bookkeeper,
but in others, managers must keep accurate records of the hours
and wages of employees, prepare the payroll, and do paperwork
to comply with licensing laws and reporting requirements of tax,
wage and hour, unemployment compensation, and Social Security
laws. They also maintain the records of supplies and equipment
purchased, and ensure that accounts with suppliers are paid on
a regular basis. In addition, managers record the number, type,
and cost of items sold to exclude dishes that are unpopular or
less profitable.
Many managers ease the burden of record keeping via computers.
Point-of-service-systems (POS) are used in many restaurants to
increase employee productivity and allow managers to track the
sales of specific items. Using a POS system, a server keys in
a customer&apos;s order and the computer immediately sends the order
to the kitchen so preparation can begin. The system totals checks,
acts as a cash register and credit card authorizer, and tracks
sales. To minimize food costs and spoilage, many managers use
inventory-tracking software to compare daily sales with present
inventory. In some establishments, when supplies needed for the
preparation of popular menu items run low, additional inventory
can be ordered directly from the supplier using a PC.
Managers are among the first to arrive and last to leave. At the
end of a day, or sometimes a shift, they tally the cash and charge
receipts received and balance them against the record of sales.
They are responsible for depositing the receipts at the bank,
or securing them in a safe place. Managers are also responsible
for locking up, checking that ovens and lights are off, and turning
on alarms.




 WORKING CONDITIONS 
Evenings and weekends are popular dining periods, making night
and weekend work common. However, many managers of institutional
food service facilities work more conventional hours because factory
and office cafeterias are generally open only on weekdays for
breakfast and lunch. It is common for restaurant and food service
managers to work 50 hours or more per week.
Managers often experience the pressure of simultaneously coordinating
a wide range of activities. When problems occur, it is the responsibility
of the manager to resolve them with minimal disruption to customers.
The job can be hectic during peak dining hours, and dealing with
irate customers or uncooperative employees can be stressful.




 EMPLOYMENT 
Restaurant and food service managers hold about 525,000 U.S. jobs.
Most work in restaurants or for institutional food service firms,
but a small number are also employed by educational institutions,
hospitals, nursing and personal care facilities, and civic, social,
and fraternal groups. Two-fifths are self-employed. Jobs are most
plentiful in large cities and tourist areas.




 TRAINING, OTHER QUALIFICATIONS,
AND ADVANCEMENT 
Many restaurant and food service manager positions are filled
by promoting experienced food and beverage preparation and service
workers. Waiters, waitresses, chefs, and fast-food workers who
have demonstrated their potential for handling increased responsibility
sometimes advance to assistant manager or management trainee jobs
as openings occur. Executive chefs need extensive experience as
chefs, and general managers need experience as assistant managers.
However, most food service management companies and restaurant
chains also recruit management trainees from 2- and 4-year college
hospitality management programs. Food service and restaurant chains
prefer to hire people with degrees in restaurant and institutional
food service management, but they often hire graduates with degrees
in other fields who have demonstrated interest and aptitude.
A bachelor&apos;s degree in restaurant and food service management
provides very strong preparation for a career in this occupation.
More than 160 colleges and universities offer 4-year programs
in restaurant and hotel management or institutional food service
management. For those not wanting to pursue a 4-year degree, a
good option is the more than 800 community and junior colleges,
technical institutes, and other institutions that run programs
in these fields leading to an associate degree or other certification.
Both 2 and 4-year programs involve subjects such as accounting,
business law and management, food planning and preparation, and
nutrition. Some combine classroom and laboratory study with internships
that provide on-the-job experience. In addition, many institutions
offer culinary programs that provide food preparation training
which can lead to a career as a chef and provide a foundation
for advancement to an executive chef position.
Most employers emphasize personal qualities. Restaurant and food
service management can be demanding, so good health and stamina
are important. Self-discipline, initiative, and leadership ability
are essential. Managers must be able to solve problems and concentrate
on details. They need good communication skills to deal with customers
and suppliers, as well as to motivate and direct their subordinates.
A neat and clean appearance is a must.
Most restaurant chains and food service companies have rigorous
training programs for their management positions. Through a combination
of classroom and on-the-job training, trainees receive instruction
and gain work experience in all aspects of the operations of a
restaurant or institutional food service facility-food preparation,
nutrition, sanitation, security, company policies and procedures,
personnel management, record keeping, and preparation of reports.
Usually after 6 months or a year, trainees receive their first
permanent assignment as an assistant manager.
A measure of achievement for restaurant and food service managers
is to earn the designation of certified Foodservice Management
Professional (FMP). Though not required for employment or advancement,
such certification recognizes professional competence, particularly
for those who gain skills largely on the job. The Educational
Foundation of the National Restaurant Association awards the FMP
designation to those who get a qualifying score on a written exam,
complete a series of courses, and meet standards of experience
in the field.
Willingness to relocate may be vital for promotions. Managers
advance to larger establishments, or regional management positions
within restaurant chains. Some even open their own eating and
drinking establishments. Others transfer to hotel management positions,
because their restaurant experience provides a good background
for food and beverage manager jobs at hotels and resorts.




 JOB OUTLOOK 
Employment of restaurant and food service managers is expected
to increase faster than the average for all U.S. occupations through
the year 2005. Opportunities are expected to be best for people
with bachelor&apos;s or associate degrees in restaurant and food service
management.
Employment growth is expected to vary by industry. Eating and
drinking places will provide the most new jobs as the number of
eating and drinking establishments increases and other industries
continue to contract out their food services. Population growth,
rising personal incomes, and increased leisure time will continue
to produce growth in the number of meals consumed outside the
home. To meet the demand for prepared food, more restaurants will
be built, and more managers will be hired to supervise them. In
addition, the number of manager jobs will increase in eating and
drinking places as schools, hospitals, and other businesses contract
out more of their food services to institutional food service
companies located in the eating and drinking industry.
Employment of wage and salary managers in eating and drinking
places is expected to increase more rapidly than self-employed
managers. New restaurants are increasingly affiliated with national
chains rather than being independently owned and operated. As
this continues, fewer owners will manage restaurants themselves
and more managers will be used to run establishments.
Employment in eating and drinking establishments is not very sensitive
to changes in economic conditions, so restaurant and food service
managers are rarely laid off during hard times. However, competition
among restaurants is always intense, and many restaurants do not
survive.
 
 
 ©Prentice-Hall, Inc.
A Simon&amp;Schuster Company
Upper Saddle River, New Jersey 07458 
 
 Legal Statement
	</body>
</document>
