<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008923" url="http://www.coolest-gadgets.com/20081117/microwavable-breakfast-sandwich-maker/" time="2012-07-13-02:21" support="4" score="0.0041521192849506" bingtitle="Microwavable Breakfast Sandwich Maker » Coolest Gadgets" webtitle="Microwavable Breakfast Sandwich MakerCoolest Gadgets">
			<query id="000524" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000775" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000446" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="000779" bing-rank="160"/>
	<description>... which would mean you would have less dishes to clean since you ... tend to get your breakfast sandwiches from a fast food restaurant. You can pick up this microwave tray ...</description>
	<body>
		Coolest Gadgets - the ongoing search for the coolest gadget continues... Signup Via RSS Coolest Gadgets on Facebook Coolest Gadgets on Twitter 
 Home Contact About Advertise 
 
Get email alerts
 « Skyla Memoir digital photo frame scans, too Verizon Wireless USB760 Micro Modem » Home Gadgets , Kitchen Gadgets 
Microwavable Breakfast Sandwich Maker
 by Ally 
 

Cooking for one is always a pain.  I know at least in the US it seems like every meal is created for people cooking for three or more.  So if you want to cook those large meals, usually that means you’re eating leftovers for the next week just off of one meal.  All depending on how much you can eat in one sitting.   Me, I’m a snacker, so it doesn’t take much food at all before I’m full.  The massive sized meals in US restaurants leave plenty of leftovers for me.  Well if you need a little help finding something to eat for just you, this cool little tray would be perfect for a quick breakfast or a late night meal.

 

It has room for two eggs as well as two slices of breakfast meats.  It also has a built-in egg cracker which would mean you would have less dishes to clean since you don’t need an extra bowl.  To make it easier to remove the eggs from the tray it has an egg lifter.  It would also mean you’re saving money if you tend to get your breakfast sandwiches from a fast food restaurant.  You can pick up this microwave tray for $9.99 on Amazon .

Source: RGS 
 
 Email to a friend Leave a comment/review Bookmark or Share 
 
 Join and subscribe to our free daily digest 
 
Related Posts:

 Diablo Sandwich Toaster The Toaster and Egg Cooker Combo The Only Omelet And Waffle Maker Magic Egg Breakfast Set Shake &apos;N Take personal smoothie maker 
 
Write a review or comment
 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 You may use&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt;in your comment. 

 

 

 

 Notify me of followup comments via e-mail 

 
Your browser does not support iframes.
 
 
 Follow @CoolestGadgets 
Get Email Alerts
 
Categories
 
 Apple News (246) Audio/Video Gadgets (3343)
 iPod gadgets (808) 
 Automotive Gadgets (200) Bluetooth (74) CES 2007 (55) CES 2008 (87) CES 2009 (67)
 Showstopers (8) 
 CES 2010 (12) CES 2011 (42) CES 2012 (27) Childrens Gadgets (651) Conceptual Gadgets (1170) Cooking Gadgets (79) Cool Clocks (396) Coolest Gadget of the Week (123) Coolest Mobile News (300) Digital Cameras (356) Digital Picture Frame (80) DIY Gadgets (235) Drinking Gadgets (194) E-book readers (39) Eco Gadgets (560) Electronic Gadgets (3616) Gadget Competitions (114) Gadget Gift Ideas (320) Gadget Humor (32) Gadget Reviews (65) Gadget Thumbs (962) Gaming Gadgets (1056) Gift Guides (47) GPS gadgets (227) Home Gadgets (2845)
 Garden Gadgets (305) Home Automation (108) Kitchen Gadgets (539) 
 Home Theater (172) Medical Gadgets (287) Military Gadgets (60) Miscellaneous Gadgets (2297) Mobile Phones (1186) Office Gadgets (496) PC Gadgets (2983)
 Software (342) USB Gadgets (1193) 
 Pet Gadgets (194) Photography (263) Projectors (97) Remote Control (78) Retro Gadgets (64) Robot Gadgets (345) Site News (85) Solar Powered Gear (236) Sport (479)
 Biking Gadgets (27) Football Gadgets (24) Golf Gadgets (82) 
 Spy Stuff (248) Tablets (140) Tech News (753) Toys (1058)
 Remote Control Toys (272) 
 Vehicle Gadgets (802) Wacky Gadgets (999) 
 
Our Sites
 
 Coolest Gadgets UK 
The UK specific version of Coolest Gadgets for all your UK gadget news Coolest Reviews 
The latest addition to the coolest network, independant hands on reviews of all the latest gadgets and technology. Game Addicts 
Reports on all the latest news in the gaming industry along with reviews on the latest addictive games Say No To Crack 
A cool and funny humor site for all ages Self Made Minds 
A blog about business and making money on the web SoftSift 
News and reviews on the latest software releases 
 
 Cool Gadgets Gadget Gifts Contact Us About Other Interesting Sites Gadget Gifts Privacy Statement Submit News Valentine Gadget Gifts Self Destructing and Healing Robotic Chair How to enter Coolest Gadget of the week Advertise Search Results Privacy 
 Copyright 2005-2012 Coolest-Gadgets.com, all rights reserved Designed by The Floating Frog , powered by Wordpress
	</body>
</document>
