<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008020" url="http://www.prlog.org/10318095-auto-piracy-problems-solutions.html" time="2012-07-13-01:05" support="1" score="0.0006188195850933511" bingtitle="Auto Piracy - Problems &amp; Solutions | PRLog" webtitle="Auto Piracy - Problems&amp;Solutions | PRLog">
			<query id="001462" bing-rank="207"/>
	<description>Auto industry loses $12 billion in annual sales due ... and the consumer pays the price in the end. The ... QA Graphics Creates Nutritional Display for Fast Food Restaurant</description>
	<body>
		Press Release Distribution     
 
 Latest News Submit Press Release 

 PR Home Latest News Feeds Alerts Submit Free Press Release Reporter Account 

 
 Country News Germany 
 Australia 
 Turkey 
 Iran 
 British IOT 
- - -
 More Countries 

 Industry News 


 
 


 July 2012 Th We Tu Mo Su Sa Fr 12 11 10 9 8 7 6 

 
Auto Piracy - Problems&amp;Solutions
 Auto industry loses $12 billion in annual sales due to counterfeiting. China accounts for $9 billion of counterfeit auto parts loses. While the trade of counterfeit parts has dramatically increased, tackling counterfeits is not impossible. 
 FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE 
 PRLog (Press Release) - Aug 22, 2009 -
Introduction: 
When it comes to intellectual property theft and piracy, most people think of moviesand high-end handbags- but what if the brakes on your car were fake? Clearly, the auto parts industry has a piracy problem. The FBI estimates that the auto industry loses $12 billion in annual sales due to counterfeiting. China accounts for $9 billion of counterfeit auto parts loses.

What are fake parts?

Counterfeit Auto Parts is the selling of unauthorized parts to be used in repair and maintenance of an automobile. Virtually every automotive part has turned up in counterfeit trade, including windshield glass, brake fluid, brakes, headlights, taillights, emissions components, tires, belts, hoses, alternators, sheet metal and suspension parts. The extent of it being that an entire car was copied, manufactured and sold not as a Chevy but as a “Chery QQ,” with plans for export.

What’s different now is the sophistication of the industrialization taking place in emerging economies-while manufacturing in these areas has developed, the concept of intellectual property has not.With counterfeit auto parts, the concern goes beyond monetary losses. Fake parts are cheaper for a reason- they cut corners and use poor quality materials, and the consumer pays the price in the end. The physical dangers and risks involved in using these parts, is a grave concern. It is frightening to know, that authorities have found brake linings made of compressed grass, sawdust or cardboard that wear out quickly; spark plugs that overheat and can lead to fires; and gas caps that can leak after rollover accidents.

What should be done?

While the trade of counterfeit parts has dramatically increased, tackling counterfeits is not impossible. Counterfeiting is a problem that needs to be addressed quickly and decisively. Ideally, as a first move, more effective partnerships should be built between law enforcement agencies and the private sector with focus on intelligence sharing, awareness and product identification training. However, the involvement of all segments of the automotive and heavy-duty industries cannot be undermined.

Manufacturers: 

Manufacturers should create a team that focuses on anti-counterfeiting strategy. This should include registration of trademarks and c o p y r i g h t s , a n d s t r a t e g y f o r enforcement of intellectual property rights.Also, anticounterfeiting technology should be employed, to ensure that genuine products are readily identifiable. Use of various markings and anti-theft devices (holograms, RFID tags, etc.) is essential, that would distinguish a genuine product from a fake one. Security features designed for public recognition should be simple, memorable and eye-catching.

For eg. Hyundai Mobis, one of the largest auto parts manufacturers in the country, learned imitated parts are being made and sold in the market. In case of auto parts, the consequence of forgery not only leads to loss of income but also may lead to loss of life if the consumer bought the imitated item unknowingly. Hyundai Mobis after a long contemplation discovered about hologram and decided apply it to protect its buyers from the counterfeits. The company has been using holograms on the inspection certificates since 1993. Holograms for Hyundai Mobis, if forcefully removed from the product, self-destructs and points up the word MOBIS¡ on the product, efficiently demonstrating its level of security.Since theintroduction of hologram, Hyundai Mobis was able to expose the organization responsible for the forgery and distribution of fake parts, and even further, was able to earn even higher customer reliance and increased sales. Enker, a Bosnian manufacturer of sparking plugs, employed De La Rue Holography Company to produce a sophisticated hologram, which is now successfully authenticating its products. Auto industry should work to educate suppliers, distributors and employees on how to detect counterfeit parts.

Distributors, retailers and technicians

Distributors, retailers and technicians in the aftermarket play a slightly different role in the fight against counterfeiting. While they may not be able to stop fake products from being made, they should prevent them from making it in to the supply chain.

Customers

Customers should visually inspect the product and learn to spot fakes If the part looks different from the one being replaced, it is a sure sign that it is a counterfeit. In addition, the packaging should be checked carefully for signals like odd shaped pack, mismatched logos, absence of anti-theft devices like holograms. Anything out of the ordinary should raise a red flag. Counterfeiting has surely exploded in recent years to become a serious threat. The automotive industry needs to stand up and fight this growing economic crime. This fake auto-part trade is like cancer - a problem that nobody can solve quickly- It has to be an effort sustained over many years. 
# # #

 The Hologram Manufacturers Association of India (HOMAI) is a non-profit organisation established in 1998 to represents and promotes the interest of hologram industry in India as well as to fight against counterfeiting. 
--- end --- 
 


 Contact Email : ***@homai.org Source : C S JEENA - HOMAI Phone : 91-11-41617369 Fax : 91-11-41617369 Address : 21-GROUND FLOOR, DEVIKA TOWER 6 : NEHRU PLACE, NEW DELHI Zip : 110019 State/Province : Delhi Country : India Industry : Automotive , Technology Tags : auto piracy solution , hologram , fake auto parts , homai , auto industry , anti-theft devices Last Updated : Aug 22, 2009 Shortcut : http://prlog.org/10318095 
 Disclaimer :  Issuers of the press releases are solely responsible for the content of their press releases. PRLog can&apos;t be held liable for the content posted by others.  Report Abuse 
Latest Press Releases By“ HOMAI ”

 Security Hologram Help Pharmaceutical Companies to Fight Against Counterfeiting HOMAI welcomes new anti-counterfeiting move Hologram Association speaking at Holopack Holoprint Conference Hologram producers met to curb counterfeiting Enterprise Risk Assessment&amp;Management 
 More ...


Upcoming Press Releases...

 Tsai Law Company Expands High Asset Divorce Practice in Seattle with Addition of David W. Kitchell Colorado Mountain Club Hosts Festival in Buena Vista to Celebrate 100th Birthday NO TIME TO WAIT FOR SUPERMAN Educators Prepare to Canvass the Country to Identify What Works in Amer MediaTek Announces Global Partnership to Bring Twitter to &apos;Smart-Feature Phones&apos; Wayand Tourism Department Purchased White Water Raft And Water Tricycles from Navgathi Marine Design 
 
 Similar ? Hologram producers met to curb counterfeiting Elvis Impersonators Cry Out In Terror AVA - the Airport Virtual Assistant Launched at Port Authority of New York&amp;New Jersey Airports Parks Mazda Of High Point, NC Wins Prestigious Mazda North America President’s Club Award The Best and Worst Auto Industry Twitter Accounts of 2011 

 Most Viewed Weekly Black Girls CODE™ Launches IndieGoGo Crowdfunding Campaign to help bridge the digital divide - 2544 views Jewett&apos;s Right Stock Photos offers budget pricing. - 1813 views Axium Healthcare Pharmacy Releases OnePlace™ Patient Therapy Management Web Portal - 1433 views Blacknight Announce New Domain WHOIS Privacy Service - 1067 views Chevrolet 2012 Chevy Confidence Program Information and Announcement - 728 views 

 Daily News! Tudordressing.com Announces Debut of Kids’ Pirate Clothing Mob Wives Star Announced as Cover Model and Launch Party Host of Open Closet Magazine! How to Wordpress Website Design&amp;Themes Training Class Miami Doral Electricity Wizard Supports Australian Government Decision To Insert Brochure On Carbon Tax Component VinSolutions Finalist in National Social Media Contest 

 Aug 22, 2009 News 
 



 SiteMap Privacy Policy Terms of Service Copyright Notice About Advertise 
 Like PRLog ? 3.6K 1.2K 1.7K
	</body>
</document>
