<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008883" url="http://www.shopmyexchange.com/AboutExchange/publicaffairs/restuarants.htm" time="2012-07-13-02:19" support="2" score="0.006149841142475855" bingtitle="The Exchange | About Exchange | Public Affairs | Restaurants, Food ..." webtitle="The Exchange | About Exchange | Public Affairs | Restaurants, Food OperationsTheaters">
			<query id="001286" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000269" bing-rank="201"/>
	<description>Pay Your Bill Online. Login to view your account. ... Exchange Fast Food Restaurant Operations . Fast food continues to dominate the ...</description>
	<body>
		javascript must be enabled for the correct page display
 
javascript must be enabled for the correct page display
 Shop Online Now   THE ALL SERVICES EXCHANGE online store catalog Login Form USERNAME PASSWORD 
Don&apos;t have an account? Create one. 
 Forgot Username or Password? 

To change your log-in information at any time, visit Customer Relations or go to My Account .

Trouble logging in?
 Call 1-(800) 527-2345. 
   Skip navigation 
 Exchange
Stores 
The Exchange

Find the nearest Exchange, view local store ads, get movie schedules and more!
 
Exchange Restaurants

Download coupons and view nutritional information for each restaurant&apos;s menu items.
 
 Exchange Restaurants Military Clothing Store Reel Time Movies Internet, Mobile, TV&amp;Phone Sales Flyers Local Buddy List Our Value Story 

 Authorized Patrons Merchandise Restrictions POG Gift Certificates Germany Fuel Ration Program Netherlands Fuel Ration Program Retail&amp;General FAQs Mobile Online Shopping 
 Community 
Support Your Troops

Gift Certificates&amp;Cards for our troops.
 
Patriot Family

Lets share a connection.
 
 Support Your Troops Salute To Your Service Patriot Family Operation Be Fit Retired Employees Association 

 Military Retiree Connection PCS Headquarters School Lunch Program Homeschooling 
 About
Exchange 
History

For more than 100 years, the Exchange&apos;s mission has been to support the men and women of the Armed Forces around the world during military operations.
 
Exchange Careers

Grow personally and professionally with our: internships, management training courses, tuition reimbursement, and professional and career development.
 
 The Organization Exchange Quick Facts Exchange Careers Strategic Plan Public Affairs Diversity&amp;Inclusion Leadership 

 History Inspector General Military Newcomers Guide Military Exercises&amp;Contingencies Sustainability Skyline Restaurant 
 Credit
Services 
 Military Star® Card

There is a star with your name on it.
 
Credit Products

We understand the many challenges of a military lifestyle and have designed these exclusive benefits with you in mind!
 
Special Offers

Learn more.
 
Pay Your Bill Online

Login to view your account.
 Customer
Relations 
Contact Us

 General Questions (800) 527-6790 DSN 967-2011 

 Catalog Center (800) 527-2345 
 
Customer Feedback

We want to hear from you! Go to Customer Relations and choose an online form to submit your comments.
 
My Account

Check order status and tracking. Get information on returns and exchanges, shipping and more.
 
 Product Recalls/Alerts Price Match Policy Coupon Acceptance Policy 


 Doing Business
With 
The Exchange 
Prospective
Suppliers/Vendors
 
Existing
Suppliers/Vendors
 
Supplier Diversity
 
 Logistics Advertising eCommerce Quality Assurance Frequently Asked Questions 
 
 
 EXCHANGE 
 Enjoy NO SALES TAX&amp;FREE Standard Shipping offers (excludes Online Mall purchases). MILLIONS of items available. 
You save, we give back.
 
About Exchange
 The Organization Exchange Quick Facts Exchange Careers Apply Now! Career Opportunities Military Candidates Benefits Claims: Sunday Pay / Post Allowance Strategic Plan Sustainability Vision Strategic Plan Goals Corporate Social Responsiblity Public Affairs Press Releases Getting Started Diversity and Inclusion Office Associate Careers Training Customer Community Awards Leadership Council Leadership Thomas C. Shull Michael P. Howard Colonel Thomas P. Ockenfels CMSgt. Anthony &quot;Tony&quot; Pearson History Deployees Memorial Preservation Contact Inspector General Fraud, Waste&amp;Abuse Military Newcomers Guide Military Exercises&amp;Contingencies Skyline Restaurant 
 Home About Exchange Public Affairs Restaurants, Food Operations&amp;Theaters 
 
Restaurants, Food Operations&amp;Theaters
 
Exchange Fast Food Restaurant Operations

Fast food continues to dominate the restaurant industry and has proven to be successful with the military customer. Exchange restaurant operations are divided into three categories: Signature Brands, Name-Brand Fast Food (NBFF) Direct, and Concession. Exchange operates over 2,266 restaurants in 18 countries.

Signature Brands:

This group of restaurants has been developed and is supported by the Exchange staff. These highly successful brands offer a variety of fast-food programs competitive with those available in the private sector. All are turn-key and include: image packages, menu specification, employee training, and marketing support.

 Anthony’s Pizza was the first signature brand developed. It features pizza by the slice and whole pizzas with a variety of toppings. Additional standard and optional menu items are available in various restaurant configurations. Currently, there are more than 185 Anthony’s Pizza restaurants open and new delivery programs currently being developed.

 Frank’s Franks is a specialty restaurant serving gourmet all beef franks, polish sausage and baked potatoes. There are currently over 42 restaurants open worldwide serving Frank’s Franks (including carts, kiosks, and mall restaurants).

 Robin Hood Sandwich Shoppes serves a full line of specialty sandwiches, featuring a variety of breads baked on site daily. Over 108 Robin Hood restaurants are in operation.

Exchange also operates American Eatery, ReelTime Express and Specialty Express Products signature brands, in addition to generic snack bars and cafeterias. A principal strategy of the organization is to convert these generic outlets to branded concepts.

Name-Brand Fast Food (NBFF) Direct

 Exchange is satisfying our customers&apos; preference for branded food; operating name-brand fast food restaurants under both license and franchise agreements. In 1974, the Exchange entered into an initial partnership with Baskin Robbins and now operates NBFF restaurants worldwide.

 The first Exchange Burger King opened in Ansbach, Germany, in 1984. Exchange currently operates Burger Kings in nine countries including free standing, modular and in-line units. Louisiana fast is available at Popeye’s Restaurants in the Pacific, Europe, and CONUS. Think outside the bun at Taco Bells open in CONUS, Europe, and the PACRIM. Charley’s Grilled Subs bring that grilled hot sub taste to troops around the world. Looking for that taste of Asia, Exchange offers Manchu Wok Restaurants. Subway Restaurants available in CONUS, Europe, and PACRIM. Church’s Chicken Pizza Hut Einstein Bros Bagels Seattle’s Best Coffee STARBUCKS Godfather’s Pizza Captain D’s Cinnabon Blimpie Dunkin Donuts 

Through branding, Exchange stays on top of industry trends and technology, continuing to offer products that provide a great dining experience and improved quality of life for our customers.

Concession Food

Concession food operations are those where a local business person pays Exchange a fee to operate a food concept on an Army or Air Force installation. They include nearly every type of food offering from espresso coffee carts and neighborhood ice cream carts to mobile food trucks and NBFF operations. Exchange utilizes concession operations with consideration of the following: when the sales potential is questionable or does not warrant an investment by Exchange, is limited in scope to a few installations, or seasonal like the ice cream carts that would be difficult to make money on a year-round basis.

Plant Operations

Exchange currently operates seven food plants overseas that produce American name-brand and American-style products. In Europe, Exchange operates a bakery, ice cream, bagged ice and water bottling plant in Germany. In the Pacific, Exchange operates a bakery in Korea and two in Japan.

The plants support troops of all Forces stationed overseas through exchange retail / food operations, commissaries, MWR facilities, military dining facilities and embassies. The plants also directly support the school meal program by utilizing excess USDA flour commodities.

The plants produce licensed name-brand products that are sold at Express and Commissaries. These include Wonder&amp;Miltons products, Pillsbury bakery items, Baskin Robbins ice cream, and Culligan water. Plants also produce institutional food items to include Burger King and Chili’s hamburger buns, Cinnabon cinnamon rolls and Macaroni Grill peasant bread for restaurants operated by military systems overseas. The plants also produce various snack food products to include tortillas chips and popcorn.

Exchange Theaters

Exchange provides entertainment motion picture service to Army and Air Force installations around the world. The theaters offer current movies at reduced rates.

 Visit ReelTime Theatres Now. 

Many theater snack stands are being remodeled, replacing generic operations with Reel Time Express. This attractive upgrade is now featured in more than 130 theaters. Recent design modifications incorporating modular components have enabled even the smallest theaters the opportunity of implementing this program.

To enhance the movie experience, Dolby Sound Systems have been added to over 100 theaters with more conversions planned. The Exchange First Run Circuit which provides the latest releases to 59 overseas locations has been expanded. This allows theaters in Europe and the Pacific to receive first-run titles earlier. Virtually all of Hollywood mainstream movies wind up on the Exchange film circuits.

Free admission film service, on VHS videocassette, is furnished to military members stationed at over 527 remote locations including 60 OEF / OIF sites.

Although Exchange operates the theaters and is responsible for the projection equipment, the building is assigned to the host command, which is responsible for building and auditorium seating maintenance.

School Lunch Program

School Lunch Program operations provide a nutritious and delicious USDA lunch at 92 schools in 9 countries. The price that parents pay for a school lunch in Okinawa or Europe, despite being thousands of miles away, is the same as a school lunch in Dallas, Texas. In a year, 4.4 million lunches are served overseas. Out of that 4.4 million, 43% are eligible for reduced priced or free lunch.

 Learn More About School Lunch Program Now. 
 
EXCHANGE QUICK FACTS
 
 Printer-friendly Facts Exchange Legal Status Trademarks / Service Marks Facilities Installation Chain of Command Occupational Safety&amp;Health Quality Assurance Pricing Policy Loss Prevention Check Cashing Policies Services&amp;Vending Facts Restaurants, Food Operations&amp;Theaters Sale of Adult Reading Material Environmental Military Star Credit Card 
 

Company Info
 About Exchange Public Affairs Press Releases Diversity History Sustainability 
Employment
 Exchange Careers Claims: Sunday Pay/Post Allowance NO FEAR Act Notice Post Government Employment 


Exchange Locations
 Store Locator Sales Flyers Exchange Restaurants Military Clothing Store Reel Time Movies Mystery Shopper-I want to apply! 
Special Services
 MILITARY STAR® Customer Relations New Car Sales Germany Fuel Ration Program Netherlands Fuel Ration Program 


Community Info
 Support Your Troops Patriot Family Operation Be Fit Retired Employees Association PCS Headquarters School Lunch Program Homeschooling 


Customer Relations
 Contact Us My Account Order Status And Tracking Shipping Information Product Recalls / Alerts Price Match Policy Coupon Acceptance Policy Gift Cards Balance Freedom Of Information Act 


Stay Connected
 Share With Friends Connect On Your Phone Follow Us On Twitter Join Us On Facebook Watch Us On YouTube Check Out Our Blog 
 Need help? We&apos;re available 24/7 at 1-800-527-2345 . Visit Customer Relations for more info. ©2011 The Exchange. All rights reserved.
 Site Terms&amp;Conditions | Privacy Act Statement
	</body>
</document>
