<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008442" url="http://www.allmenus.com/tx/austin/53512-delaware-sub-shop/menu/" time="2012-07-13-01:54" support="2" score="0.004205767671046619" bingtitle="Delaware Sub Shop menu - Austin, TX 78705 - (512) 458-8423" webtitle="Delaware Sub Shop  menu - Austin, TX 78705 - (512) 458-8423">
			<query id="001344" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000229" bing-rank="99"/>
	<description>Large Party tray $53.99. Soft Drinks / Tea $1.65 - $1.95 ... This place is good but not near 5 stars. I like the prices and menu, but find that the sandwiches are a little dry ...</description>
	<body>
		Delaware Sub Shop
 1104 W 34th St , Austin TX 78705 (512) 458-8423 Cuisines and Dishes at Delaware Sub Shop:
 Sandwiches Wraps American 
 
Menu for Delaware Sub Shop
 
Cold Subs

make any sub a salad $1.00, all cold subs include lettuce, onions, tomatoes, pickles, sweet or hot peppers, oil and spices
 
 Delaware Classic $3.95 - $6.55 
genoa salami, Provolone and ham
 Italian $5.25 - $8.25 
genoa salami, Provolone, capicolla ham and ham
 Italian Gourmet $5.85 - $9.65 
genoa salami, Provolone, capicolla ham prosciuttini ham and ham
 Capicolla $4.55 - $7.75 
capicolla ham and Provolone
 Delaware Deluxe $5.70 - $10.95 
honey smoked turkey breast, ham, bacon and Provolone`
 Peppered Turkey Breast $4.95 - $8.45 
sliced turkey and Provolone
 Dell-Sliced Turkey Brest $4.95 - $8.45 
sliced turkey and Provolone
 Honey Smoked Turkey Breast $4.95 - $8.45 
sliced turkey and Provolone
 Roast Beef $4.95 - $8.50 
sliced roast beef and Provolone
 Salami $3.95 - $6.55 
sliced genoa salami and Provolone
 Ham $3.95 - $6.25 
ham and Provolone
 Tuna $3.95 - $6.25 
tuna and Provolone
 Cheese $4.35 - $7.50 
Provolone and white American cheese, add bacon to any sub (per slice) $0.30, add mushrooms to any sub $0.40, $0.60
 
 
Hot Subs


 
 Philly Cheesesteak $5.25 - $8.45 
grilled sliced ribeye steak white American cheese, sauteed mushrooms and onions, sweet or hot peppers and ketchup
 Grilled Chicken Cheesesteak $5.25 - $8.45 
grilled chicken breast white American cheese, sauteed mushrooms, and onions, sweet or hot peppers and oregano
 Eggplant parmesan $4.95 - $8.25 
eggplant, sauteed mushrooms and onions, American, Provolone and parmesan cheeses, marinara sauce, sweet or hot peppers and oregano
 Chicken Parmesan $5.95 - $11.95 
breaded chicken breast, sauteed mushrooms and onions, American, Provolone and parmesan cheese, marinara sauce, sweet or hot peppers and oregano
 Grilled Vegetarian $4.35 - $7.50 
sauteed mushrooms and onions, American and Provolone cheese, marinara sauce, sweet or hot peppers and oregano
 meatball $4.35 - $7.90 
Italian meatballs, Provolone, onions, sweet or hot peppers and oregano
 Italian Sausage (Fridays Only) $3.95 - $7.90 
grilled Italian sausage, Provolone, onions, sweet or hot peppers and oregano
 Lettuce and Tomato on All of the Above $0.25 - $0.50 

 
 
Sandwiches


 
 daily Special $3.95 
sandwich of the day
 Daily Deal $5.50 
sandwich of the day, chips and a 20 oz. drink
 Daily Deal $5.95 
sandwich of the day, chips and a 32 oz. drink
 Kid&apos;s Meal $3.99 
1/4 turkey, ham, meatball or cheese sandwich, chips, one cookie and 20 oz. drink (32 oz, not available)
 Small Party Tray $27.99 

 Large Party tray $53.99 

 Soft Drinks / Tea $1.65 - $1.95 

 Tasty Kakes $1.50 

 Chips $0.99 

 Soup (Nov.-Feb.) $2.20 

 Chef Salad $3.95 
extra salad dressing $0.35, extra meat slice $0.50, extra cheese slice $0.30
 
 
Menu for Delaware Sub Shop provided by Allmenus.com 

 DISCLAIMER : 
 Information shown may not reflect recent changes. Check 
 with this restaurant for current pricing and menu information. 
 A listing on Allmenus.com does not necessarily reflect our 
 affiliation with or endorsement of the listed restaurant, or 
 the listed restaurant&apos;s endorsement of Allmenus.com. Please 
 tell us by clicking here if you know that any of the information shown is incorrect. 
 For more information, please read our Terms and Conditions .
 Recent reviews for Delaware Sub Shop 
Ratings and Reviews for Delaware Sub Shop
 Based on 8 reviews 
 
 

Feb 11 2010

 Stuart B. via Yelp

 This place is good but not near 5 stars. I like the prices and menu, but find that the sandwiches are a little dry and I also find its kind of weird that... read more 
 
 

Nov 20 2009

 Daren C. via Yelp

 Sorry other five reviewers --- I can&apos;t give this place 5 stars. Sorry to be a wet blanket!! Bummer party.

This place aint bad --- but it isn&apos;t 5 stars. Let... read more 
 
 

Nov 17 2009

 John R. via Yelp

 I&apos;ve been walking past this place almost daily for the better part of two months now, each time thinking&quot;hey, I need to yelp that place.&quot;I was very... read more 
 

User reviews powered by 
 
Map of Delaware Sub Shop
 
View larger map and get directions
 Own Delaware Sub Shop? Update your menu online! 

 
 Home ▸ Austin, TX ▸ Delaware Sub Shop 
 
 Contact Us About Advertise with Us Restaurant Owners Chains 

View the mobile version 

Registration on or use of this site constitutes acceptance of the Terms&amp;Conditions and Privacy Policy .©2012 GrubHub, Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
