<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008430" url="http://www.digitalscreenmedia.org/sska-news?category=50" time="2012-07-13-01:54" support="101" score="0.18747430161245884" bingtitle="Digital Screenmedia Association - News Archive" webtitle="Digital Screenmedia Association - News Archive">
			<query id="000913" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000643" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000552" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="001316" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000441" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000986" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="000021" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="000313" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001047" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="001474" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="000076" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000976" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="001128" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000629" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000317" bing-rank="249"/>
			<query id="000125" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000070" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000656" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000219" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001389" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="000958" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000984" bing-rank="201"/>
			<query id="000188" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000318" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000953" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="001384" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="001007" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000940" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="001258" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000750" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000437" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="001442" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="001307" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000067" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="001410" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="001002" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000468" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000521" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000536" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000975" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000161" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000192" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="001393" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="001285" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000282" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000961" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000881" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="000506" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="000256" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="000908" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="001038" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000992" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000724" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="000505" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000980" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000646" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000719" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000989" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000661" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000209" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="001221" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000287" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000688" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000344" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="001387" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000334" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000099" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="001289" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="000206" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="001505" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="000945" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000638" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000693" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="001479" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="001062" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="001408" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000531" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000094" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000625" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001337" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000193" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="001065" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="000062" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="001447" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000971" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000194" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000977" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="001347" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000081" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000615" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000410" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="000598" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000004" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="001290" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="001195" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="001321" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="001299" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000031" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="001415" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="000562" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001033" bing-rank="133"/>
	<description>... of touchscreen ordering kiosks and digital menu board ... and imported gourmet foods, is applying fast-food restaurant ... internal theft and allowed customers to leave ...</description>
	<body>
		about faqs contact site map twitter linkedin privacy policy cart Store advertise 
 
 
 
 Sign up for our Email Newsletter 
 
 
 Home Member Directory Board&amp;Committees Blogs Awards Events Member News Project Help JOIN 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 What is digital signage? 
 What is self-service?
What&apos;s a kiosk? 
 What is mobile?
 What is digital screenmedia? 

 FAQs
 Our Mission 
 Reports Store 
 Industry News 
 Testimonials 
 Speakers Bureau 
 eNewsletter 
 Photo Gallery 
 Glossary
 White Papers 
 Research 
 Contact Us 

Members Only 
 Best Practices 
 ROI Calculator
 Webinar Downloads
 

 
 

 
 
 
 
 REQUEST PROPOSALS  Have DSA members bid for your business.

 Submit RFP 
 
 
 
 Follow DSA on... 
 
 
 
 


 Subscribe to DSA blog feed 

 
 
 
  News Archive  
 
 SSKA Industry News 
 Monday, 16 November 2009 Subway franchisees expanding drive-thru kiosk deployments NEXTEP SYSTEMS and MRI, a digital signage and self-service hardware manufacturer, have launched a new line of touchscreen drive-thru kiosks for the QSR and fast casual foodservice segments.   The companies developed the second-generation line of drive-thru kiosks after several successful pilot deployments with Subway franchises throughout the United States. Subway franchisee Rob Woodward, who operates locations in Colorado and Nebraska, says increased sales helped the store quickly realize an ROI on the kiosk system: Investing in drive-thru self-serve technology has helped us increase our sales and differentiate our customer service from the competition. Customers love the easy-to-use and frustration-free self-service ordering experience. In an industry driven by measurable sales and customer satisfaction, the rapid payback we&apos;ve experience shows that the systems play a significant role in helping out drive-thru operations thrive. NEXTEP says that several Subway locations are scheduled to integrate the new line of drive-thru kiosks. The company says the solutions&apos; features include: 
 A 32-inch, sunlight-readable, interactive touchscreen designed for optimum viewing ability. An ambient light sensor that automatically adjusts the screen’s brightness level, depending on the brightness of the surroundings. A special screen feature called Display Positioning System (DPS) that displays the information right where the driver touches the screen, keeping the interaction at eye level. A proximity sensor that detects an approaching vehicle and displays a welcome screen and voice prompt, so the device is ready to accept orders as soon as the car or truck pulls up. A barcode scanner and credit-card reader that enable payment as soon as food is ordered. A webcam option that allows restaurant staff to view the customer placing the order. A thermal-management system, which can be used in all outdoor environments and operates in temperatures from -4 degrees Fahrenheit to 122 degrees Fahrenheit. 
 POSTED BY: Caroline Cooper AT 10:02 am  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Friday, 30 October 2009 NEXTEP deploys Casino Express self-order kiosk at La. casino NEXTEP SYSTEMS, a provider of touchscreen ordering kiosks and digital menu board solutions, today announced the launch of its Casino Express self-order system at Boomer&apos;s Caféin the Boomtown Casino Hotel in Bossier City, La.   Dan Condon, director of information technology for Boomtown Casino, says the facility chose to work with NEXTEP because of its experience in the casino space: As we sought to adopt technology that would increase our efficiency, the expertise of NEXTEP SYSTEMS and the extent of its work with casino environments convinced us they were the right supplier for us. We believe NEXTEP will have a tremendous positive impact on both our revenue and customer satisfaction. With the system now in place, we expect our average order size to increase, customer wait times to decrease and that we will be able to provide better overall service to our guests during peak periods. Using the Casino Express solution, restaurant customers can order meals directly from the touchscreen and pay for their selections using credit cards, debit cards or casino comp credit. POSTED BY: Caroline Cooper AT 10:38 am  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Thursday, 29 October 2009 NEXTEP deli kiosk makes the news 
 A new deli kiosk from NEXTEP was recently featured on WTWO-TV in Terra Haute. 

 &quot;Once people use this system, they will not order any other way,&quot;said deli manager Cindy Clark&quot;Every one of them just raves about it.&quot; 

 You can watch the video here . 
 POSTED BY: Caroline Cooper AT 10:40 am  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Thursday, 08 October 2009 C-store brand to deploy Blockbuster Express DVD kiosks chain-wide 
 Tedeschi Food Shops, a convenience store chain with nearly 200 locations in the Northeast United States, will deploy Blockbuster Express DVD-rental kiosks chain-wide, according to a report from Convenience Store/Petroleum, a magazine that covers the c-store segment. 

 Tedeschi already has the Blockbuster Express units, developed by NCR Corp. , in 89 of its stores and plans to deploy 27 more by the end of October. The chain says it expects installation to be completed by the end of the year. 
 POSTED BY: Caroline Cooper AT 12:43 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Tuesday, 22 September 2009 NEXTEP announces deployment of Casino Express kiosks at two facilities NEXTEP SYSTEMS has announced the deployment of its Casino Express touchscreen buffet-entry kiosks at Casino Queen, in East St. Louis, Ill., and The Rivers, in Pittsburg.   According to a news release from NEXTEP, casino guests use the kiosks to enter the number of diners in their party and prepay for their buffet meals with cash, credit, debit or casino loyalty credit. The kiosks then issue a receipt the guests use to gain entry to the buffet. The kiosk also offers the casino an optional reservation module to incorporate.   Jeff Breazeale, NEXTEP&apos;s sales director, says casino dining establishments are particularly well-suited to deploy kiosk solutions: Casino foodservice represents an ideal candidate for self-service. Casino dining concepts have high traffic, long hours of operation and relatively high labor costs, resulting in a three- to six-month payback period. NEXTEP says Casino Queen deployed three of the Casino Express kiosks at its Market Street Buffet, while The Rivers installed four of the devices at its Grand View Buffet. POSTED BY: Caroline Cooper AT 01:10 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Monday, 21 September 2009 NYC restaurant launches Incentient&apos;s SmartCellar self-service, touchscreen wine list Incentient, a Jericho, N.Y.-based transaction-services provider, has announced the launch of its SmartCellar touchscreen self-service device at New York City&apos;s SD26 restaurant.    According to a news release from Incentient, the SmartCellar is a wireless, handheld device that gives restaurant patrons access to an establishment&apos;s wine list, allowing them to search for wine by price, grape, year, country, region, characteristics, appellation and more.   SD26&apos;s owner, Tony May, says the restaurant chose the SmartCellar solution to complement its unique wine offerings: At SD26, the electronic wine list will allow our customers to easily and intuitively navigate our expansive collection of more than 10,000 bottles. SD26&apos;s innovative approach to wine selection and SmartCellar&apos;s customizable wine program makes finding the perfect wine for every meal more enjoyable and accessible for all wine lovers. Incentient says the SmartCellar features automatic inventory updates and multilingual capabilities and can be customized to match any operation&apos;s look and feel. POSTED BY: Caroline Cooper AT 01:12 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Monday, 21 September 2009 New England grocery chain pilots NCR self-checkout 
 Quick Chek, a chain of fresh food stores in New England, has announced a pilot installation of self-checkout lanes in one of its Phillipsburg, N.J., locations. The self-checkout terminals, which the store has dubbed the&quot;Quick Chek Fast Lanes,&quot;are manufactured by NCR Corp. and began operating in the store Aug. 26. 

 Maria Fidelibus, vice president of technology for Quick Check, says the brand wanted to expand on its reputation for customer service: 
 
 Along with being held in high regard for our wide array of fresh food products and famed fresh coffee program, Quick Chek customers also know us for the high level of personalized service we offer. Our new&quot;Quick Chek Fast Lane&quot;pilot program is intended as an extension of that solid customer service offering, and we are thrilled to partner with NCR in this industry-pioneering initiative. 
 
 Quick Chek is a family-operated brand and has 120 locations in New Jersey and southern New York. 
 POSTED BY: Caroline Cooper AT 01:12 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Monday, 21 September 2009 Just Enjoy launches mobile menu, ordering appC 
 IRVINE, Calif. —Just Enjoy LLC has announced the launch of its new mobile dining application and service, JUST ENJOY Social Dining. Just Enjoy’s mission is to provide restaurant owners a platform for managing their business, launching targeted promotions and reducing operating costs while being easy to integrate into an existing POS system and giving consumers the opportunity to take control of their dining experience. 

 &quot;People have been using mobile technology to make reservations and online ordering for some time now,&quot;said Juan Guevara, co-founder and president of Just Enjoy.&quot;But all these applications really do is either get you to the door and say goodbye or greet you and take your order —all without ever getting to really know you or your preferences. With JUST ENJOY it’s like having a good friend that knows you, facilitates your visit to the restaurant and more importantly stays with you to ensure you enjoy the occasion.&quot; 

 The JUST ENJOY application remembers user preferences and is continuously learning and categorizing likes and dislikes across restaurants using the JUST ENJOY service.&quot;This helps eliminate typical dining frustrations such as figuring out what to order, comparing prices or even service errors,&quot;said co-founder and CTO Yuriy Kumanov.&quot;Customers will also have the ability to share their dining history, preferences and reviews on JustEnjoy.com, creating a new social media platform for restaurant patrons.&quot; 

 The complete family of JUST ENJOY products is offered to full-service and fast-service restaurants, casinos and resorts as a subscription-based solution to help them enhance their patrons&apos; customer experience and expand the venue offerings via games and other interactive customer entertainment. JUST ENJOY is also a management tool for managers and operators, giving them detailed real-time information on customer preferences and providing a platform for targeted marketing. 
 POSTED BY: AT 01:11 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Thursday, 17 September 2009 Indiana grocery deploys NEXTEP&apos;s deli self-order system Troy, Mich.-based NEXTEP SYSTEMS has announced that Baesler&apos;s Market in Terra Haute, Ind., has deployed NEXTEP&apos;s Deli 1-2-3 touchscreen self-order kiosk system. According to a news release from NEXTEP, the Deli 1-2-3 system incorporates two freestanding self-order kiosks, an order status monitor and order display system.   NEXTEP, which also provides self-order systems for the restaurant industry, has seen more interest in self-order technology from the grocery segment, says president and cofounder Tommy Woycik: These implementations for Baesler&apos;s Market delis reflect a growing demand for NEXTEP SYSTEMS&apos; technology from grocery operations all across America. NEXTEP solutions are enabling grocers to improve productivity, eliminate potential customer walk-aways, and increase revenue and up-sell opportunities within the deli environment. Baesler&apos;s president and owner Bob Baesler says the store has seen increased revenue and more efficiency since the deployment: The size of average orders in our deli has increased, and our customer service in the deli is also growing and improving, thanks to our NEXTEP ordering system. Our deli customers like using the self-order kiosks, and the system allows them to get their shopping done much quicker, which is a real plus. NEXTEP also has deployed its self-service solutions at several metro Detroit retail locations. POSTED BY: Caroline Cooper AT 01:26 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Wednesday, 16 September 2009 Illinois grocery chain deploys ADUSA&apos;s self-order kiosks ADUSA, a Lombard, Ill.-based self-order kiosk provider, has announced the deployment of its S4G Fresh Foods kiosks at Angelo Caputo&apos;s Fresh Market, a small grocery chain also based in Illinois.   Robertino Presta, chief executive of Angelo Caputo&apos;s, says the brand chose to deploy a second round of Fresh Foods kiosks after a positive customer reaction to its initial installation: The response to the kiosk in our Naperville (Illinois) store has been excellent, so we&apos;ve decided to offer the technology to our customers at additional stores. According to a news release from ADUSA, grocery customers can use the Fresh Foods kiosks to order a full range of items in the fresh foods section of Angelo Caputo&apos;s, including meats and cheeses and prepared salads, entrees and side dishes. POSTED BY: Caroline Cooper AT 01:28 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Thursday, 10 September 2009 St. Louis grocery deploys self-order kiosks from ADUSA ADUSA, a self-order kiosk provider, has announced that Schnuck Markets Inc., owner and operators of more than 200 grocery stores and pharmacies, is adding to its fleet of ADUSA&apos;s S4G Fresh Foods kiosks. According to a news release from ADUSA, Schnuck installed the kiosks in its new St. Louis store, Culinaria, which opened last month.   Larry Maggio, director of marketing services for Schnuck Markets, says shoppers have responded positively to the Fresh Foods ordering kiosks deployed in its other stores: A growing number of our customers are using the kiosks to place their orders, and the response continues to be very positive. They are really taking advantage of the added convenience and the easy access to all of the products we offer in the fresh foods and made-to-order areas of our store. POSTED BY: Caroline Cooper AT 01:38 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Monday, 27 July 2009 Virginia university deploys self-order dining kiosks Lynchburg, Va.’s Liberty University has announced the launch of self-order kiosks in three of its campus dining locations, just in time for the start of the school year.

&quot;LU Dining is introducing Webfood, a Web-based ordering service. Complete with touchscreens, card readers and receipt printers, Webfood kiosks take orders and act as cashiers, which will decrease lines for customers. Kiosk orders are transmitted to dining staff, who can begin preparing the meals immediately. The system boasts that a full meal can be ordered in 10 seconds or less.&quot;  
 
The university says students also can use the Webfood kiosk to view nutritional information, meal deals and favorite orders, and that school dining administrators can use the platform to edit menu items and prices and track trends and customer feedback. The university plans to eventually expand the service to include online ordering, so students can order a meal from any computer and pick it up at their convenience. POSTED BY: Caroline Cooper AT 03:04 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Friday, 17 July 2009 Interactive kiosks promote education at Phoenix Zoo TEMPE, Ariz.—Phoenix Kiosk Inc. is pleased to announce the completion of a joint venture with the Arizona Beef Council to create a kiosk solution that focuses on education, nutrition, retail and foodservice promotion at the Pheonix Zoo.

“The Arizona Beef Council project allowed us to demonstrate several areas of expertise, including outdoor technology deployment, software development and interactive marketing content development,”said Alan Work, president and chief executive of Phoenix Kiosk Inc.“Marketing the health benefits of beef products using educational games is another great example of the nearly limitless possibilities of self-service kiosks and their application.”
 
According to a news release, the Arizona Beef Council partnered with Phoenix Kiosk to produce both the hardware and software for the project. The end result was the installation of two Pravannt wall-mounted kiosk units in the Phoenix Zoo Harmony Farm to promote education to children. The kiosks allow children to interactively receive education about the zoo’s animals while navigating through the many different animated games created by Phoenix Kiosk.
“Working hand-in-hand with Phoenix Kiosk enabled us to market creatively and directly to the people we want to reach,”said Anna M. Aja, director of public relations and marketing for the Arizona Beef Council.“This was my first experience with interactive marketing technologies, and Phoenix Kiosk helped to make the process very easy and the final product very effective.” POSTED BY: AT 03:31 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Friday, 05 June 2009 Tulsa Arby&apos;s deploys self-order kiosks from EMN8 SAN DIEGO—EMN8 Inc., a developer of consumer self-service order and payment systems for quick-service restaurants, has installed self-order kiosks at a Tulsa, Okla.-based Arby’s franchise, United States Beef Corp. (U.S. Beef). EMN8’s solution brings an interactive ordering experience to the consumer and integrates with the operator’s POS system for real-time, high-volume order processing.

“One of U.S. Beef’s key strategies is providing a superior customer experience,”said Jeff Turner, U.S. Beef’s senior director of information technology.“The EMN8 kiosk delivers on this strategy through an engaging customer self-service option. An additional technical aspect to our decision is a solution that fully integrates with our existing Radiant POS. EMN8’s experience, technology, and focus on integration ensured success in delivering an exceptional customer self-service experience.&quot; POSTED BY: AT 05:04 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Wednesday, 03 June 2009 Wincor Nixdorf to supply reverse vending systems for German retailer PADERBORN, Germany—Wincor Nixdorf has signed an agreement with NETTO Marken-Discount, a subsidiary of leading German food retailer EDEKA, to equip NETTO’s stores with 1,500 reverse vending machines. The deal makes Wincor Nixdorf NETTO’s primary supplier of reverse vending. According to a news release, the rollout already has begun and should be finished by the end of 2010.
 
“With this contract, the majority of the volume of reverse vending that has been tendered in Germany in recent months has gone to Wincor Nixdorf. This represents a positive development of the business in line with our expectations,&quot;said Dr. Herbert Machill, who is responsible at Wincor Nixdorf for business with retailers worldwide.
 
NETTO has ordered the Revendo 9000 system, which is suitable for all types of empty containers and will be used for the return of bottles and beverage crates. In addition, the Revendo system meets NETTO’s specific requirements, owing to its flexible and customizable background technology. Rigorous use of standard technology makes service work easier and also ensures high availability.
 
NETTO operates solely in Germany with a network of about 3,800 stores, more than 50,000 employees and sales of some 10 billion euros. POSTED BY: AT 05:11 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Wednesday, 29 April 2009 Edeka awards contract to Wincor Nixdorf for 600 reverse vending machines  
 PADERBORN, Germany — Wincor Nixdorf has concluded a framework agreement with leading German food retailer Edeka to equip some of the group’s stores with reverse vending machines. The recently signed contract with Edeka comprises a total of 600 systems to be used for the return of one-way and refillable containers. The contract is due to run for two years. 

 The order also comprises a wide range of technology in the rear section, including compactors, as well as services such as installation, start-up and service packs. The 600 systems will be installed both in subsidiary-based operations associated with Edeka’s regional companies and in the group’s independent retail stores. 

 With some 12,000 stores and expected sales of around 43 billion euros in 2009, the EDEKA Group is the number one food retailer in Germany. Its core business areas include the full product range business conducted by independent EDEKA merchants as well as the discount segment. In total, the company has around 280,000 employees. 
 POSTED BY: AT 07:47 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Thursday, 16 April 2009 TacoTime rolls out touchscreen order kiosks SYLVAN LAKE, Alberta—TacoTime, a Kahala Corp. quick-serve restaurant concept with more than 350 locations around the world, recently installed NEXTEP touchscreen self-order kiosks at its newly-opened Sylvan Lake, Alberta, Canada, location.

The restaurant chain, which specializes in freshly prepared Mexican fare, installed two NEXTEP countertop self order kiosks and immediately witnessed increased revenue, according to a news release.

The countertop kiosks, located at the front of the ordering area, enable customers to easily and quickly order without assistance.

NEXTEP also was able to seamlessly integrate with TacoTime’s Speedline POS solution. POSTED BY: AT 07:15 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Thursday, 02 April 2009 NEXTEP kiosks to deliver at Wow Bao CHICAGO—Wow Bao, a Lettuce Entertain You Enterprises restaurant concept, has selected NEXTEP Systems to provide touchscreen ordering kiosks for its State and Lake location in Chicago. Two self-order kiosks will offer order and payment options at the restaurant. Wow Bao menu offerings include Asian-influenced steamed buns, broths, salads and specialty sodas and teas.
 
&quot;We&apos;re fortunate to be working with the most popular, busiest and (most) innovative top brand,&quot;said Tommy Woycik, president of NEXTEP, in a news release.&quot;Wow Bao&apos;s self-order kiosk implementation demonstrates their commitment to providing excellent customer service using 21st-century technology.&quot; POSTED BY: AT 08:44 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Friday, 20 February 2009 Nextep to provide kiosks, digital menu boards for airports in Mass., Pa. TROY, Mich. -- Two more airports have deployed kiosk and digital menu board technology from NEXTEP SYSTEMS, according to a news release.   Logan International Airport in Boston and Philadelphia International Airport have added NEXTEP solutions.   &quot;Both Boston and Philadelphia airports have moved toward the 21st century standard of providing busy air travelers with less time constraints and innovative visuals, allowing NEXTEP to enlarge our install base,&quot;said Tommy Woycik, president of NEXTEP SYSTEMS.&quot;Not only do the self-order kiosks and digital menu boards increase revenue for the establishments, they offer better customer service.&quot;   Jet Rock Bar and Grill, located within Philadelphia International Airport in Terminals B, D and F, has implemented NEXTEP&apos;s touchscreen self-order kiosks for faster customer service for travelers. The kiosks eliminate long lines and facilitate the rapid fulfillment of food and beverages orders - a must for the demands on today&apos;s traveling public.   Earl of Sandwich, located in Boston Logan International Airport, will install NEXTEP&apos;s solution for digital menu boards at their location within Terminal E. Digital menu boards enable Earl of Sandwich to use dynamic messaging with greater impact, advertise daily specials and target their promotions directly to busy travelers.   NEXTEP was able to provide seamless integration with MICROS 9700 POS. Earl of Sandwich and Jet Rock owners are able to make pricing changes and have them immediately reflect on their digital menu boards and self-order kiosks.   NEXTEP solutions have also been deployed in JFK International Airport, Reagan National and Detroit Metro. POSTED BY: AT 08:20 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Monday, 16 February 2009 Restaurant executives talk self-service benefits Nation&apos;s Restaurant News: Time is money, so the adage goes. That&apos;s especially true when a slow-moving line at the service counter of a quick-service restaurant exacts a toll in customer walk-offs and lost sales. But some operators say they are successfully busting lines and boosting throughput—and increasing average checks to boot—by inviting patrons to use self-service kiosks in the dining room to order their meals. Now, executives from three restaurants are sounding off on the value that self-service technology brings to their bottom lines.   Click to continue POSTED BY: AT 09:31 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Thursday, 05 February 2009 Critic reviews Calif. cafe equipped with self-service ordering The (San Jose, Calif) Mercury News: If there&apos;s one word to describe Specialty&apos;s Cafe&amp;Bakery, the recent addition to downtown San Jose&apos;s casual dining scene, it would be&quot;fresh,&quot;according to one critic. Patrons can step  up to one of the snazzy flat-screen monitors, make their selections from the abundant menu, click on&quot;edit&quot;to add or remove ingredients (more on that in a minute), swipe their credit card, grab their receipt, pocket a pager and—bam!— their order&apos;s up.
   Click to continue POSTED BY: AT 10:00 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Thursday, 22 January 2009 PHOTOS: KFC trials self-service, sees basket sizes jump Silicon.com: Colonal Sanders has tried self-service and, if customer response is any indicator, it&apos;s finger-lickin&apos; good. A KFC franchise in North Wales began trialing self-service kiosks in Aug. 2008. Customers can evade long lines by ordering and paying for their meal at the kiosks. The user interface for the kiosks, provided by YESpay, has boosted the average order size from£5.83 (U.S. $8.01) to£7.93 (U.S. $10.90). Roughly 15 percent of the franchise&apos;s business takes place at the kiosks.   Click to continue POSTED BY: AT 07:27 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Wednesday, 31 December 2008 Upgrade announced for Corporate Safe Specialists kiosk software POSEN, Ill. -- Corporate Safe Specialists is upgrading its MenuSOS kiosk software platform to support more applications, including .net framework 3.05, Windows Presentation and Communication Foundations (WPF and WCF) and SQL Express.   Corporate Safe Specialists kiosk solutions are designed to help small- and medium-sized businesses quickly implement self-service systems with a lower initial investment. MenuSOS is offered as an enhancement to the CSS kiosk platform, which, according to a news release, is the only kiosk system to accept credit/debit cards and cash, validate and count currency, and store it directly to a business rated safe. Notes are deposited directly into a business rated safe and CSS kiosk security can be made ready for armored car pick-up.   MenuSOS offers rapid self-configuration through a scripted, user-friendly process that non-technical users can complete within a few hours. Restaurant and retail establishments would then have a working kiosk platform that would provide benefits to both the business ower and customers.   According to the release, customers will now have the ability to order and pay for products and services through a touchscreen interface. The design objective for the user interface was a superior customer experience that shed associations with order entry via a personal computer.   Business owners are able to service a greater number of customers without hiring additional staff. The MenuSOS will also enable small business owners to offer their customers the self-service options that have become increasingly popular at larger competitors. The MenuSOS module can also be used as a digital chalkboard to communicate daily specials and other information to customers. POSTED BY: AT 11:17 am  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Friday, 21 November 2008 Electronic Art to provide kiosk software for Adplex and Engagement Health CINCINNATI —Electronic Art, an interactive agency specializing in custom kiosk software, kiosk hardware and integrated Web sites, will be providing services for two new clients, Adplex and Engagement Health.   According to a news release, Electronic Art is creating a kiosk for one of Adplex&apos;s retail food clients as part of its customer loyalty program that allows account management and in-store printing of rewards. Based in Houston, Adplex is a strategic marketing solutions company with a focus on customer relationships and communication that drive measurable value.   In addition, Electronic Art has signed Engagement Health, of Westchester, Ill., as a client. Electronic Art will provide kiosk software applications to be used in corporate wellness programs that reduce healthcare costs for both the employee and the corporation. The kiosks incorporate specialty hardware for measurement of blood pressure, weight and other unique data items to help employees monitor their progress towards healthy living. POSTED BY: AT 07:32 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Thursday, 06 November 2008 TableTop Media&apos;s new &apos;Ziosk&apos; tabletop kiosk app offers pay-on-demand for restaurant patrons DALLAS —TableTop Media LLC announced the national availability of Ziosk, the company&apos;s next-generation interactive tabletop device, according to a news release.    Increased labor and food costs, lower check averages, reduced traffic and expensive paper promotions with low success rates are starving the restaurant industry economically, according to some. Ziosk delivers a dynamic, pay-on-demand experience with a menu of financially benefiting capabilities. In addition to Ziosk&apos;s core features (split check, touch tip, email or print receipt capabilities, real-time surveys, movie trailers and ticket purchase), the new product offers increased battery life, order entry, sound, dynamic content scheduling and a 3D graphics capable interface.   The technology was tested at the Cozymel&apos;s Mexican Grill chain in Texas and immediately demonstrated the consumer fascination with media-rich, touchscreen technology and convenience at the table. Leveraging the&quot;pay on-demand&quot;and digital promotional capabilities, Cozymel&apos;s has increased the average check at lunch by seven percent and 14 percent at dinner. Following the successful six-month pilot with more than 20,000 successful check outs, Cozymel&apos;s will begin deploying Ziosk to its other restaurant locations before the holiday season.   By shaving, on average, 10 minutes off the check presenting, processing and closing out process, a casual restaurant like Cozymel&apos;s is also able to increase its lunch and dinner capacity. Additionally, the&quot;pay on-demand&quot;feature has armed servers with the ability to field more tables, reducing labor costs by 16 percent. Those same servers are experiencing a 15 percent lift in tips per shift with the potential of a 30 percent lift thanks to the increase in tables.     Enhanced Product Features include: 
 Increased Battery Life: Ziosk operates with 18-plus hours of battery power, enabling restaurants to operate the complete day without service interruptions. PCI Compliant: Ziosk is fully compliant with all Payment Card Industry Payment Application Data Security Standards (PCI PA-DSS) requirements. Ruggedized and Spill Resistant: Ziosk was designed for the restaurant environment, and is both spill resistant and drop tested for hard surfaces. Customizable Table Configurations: Ziosk offers multiple mounting options, vertical or horizontal in custom designed condiment holders or wall mounts. Dynamic Content Scheduling: This patent-pending feature enables Ziosk to display relevant content at specific periods of the dining cycle by day part. Therefore, lunch specific promotions will be shown just during lunch prior to placing the order or just during the meal. Training and HR: Ziosk offers restaurant employees the opportunity to login to view vacation and paycheck information, training programs, videos from management and other servers, enter internal blog information or participate in internal programs and competitions. 
 &quot;Cozymel&apos;s proved the model across a number of fronts —higher check averages, increased customer frequency and table turns, positive customer feedback, menu up selling and financial comfort in transacting independent of a server,&quot; said Shawn Gentry, chief operating officer and president of TableTop Media. &quot;Despite the current economic environment, we are very pleased with the level of interest among national chains to explore the technology across all category segments. The fact is, Ziosk goes way beyond security and convenience for guests, and it adds dollars to the pockets of restaurateurs and their employees. It&apos;s a win-win.&quot; POSTED BY: AT 04:48 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Wednesday, 08 October 2008 Self-service food ordering tech appearing at Canadian retailers Mediacaster Magazine: Petro-Canada will deploy customer self-service food ordering technology and drive-through point-of-sale kiosk solutions in its c-stores. Working with Radiant Systems, the new platform will provide consumers with high-quality food and coffee as well as traditional fuel and convenience offerings.   Click to continue POSTED BY: AT 02:36 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Friday, 19 September 2008 D.C. site of first self-service wine bar AFP: Ceviche is the first self-service wine bar in Washington and believed to be one of very few in the entire United States. It features wines and food from Latin America or with a Spanish accent. Before Lana Shekim does the week&apos;s shopping, she likes to stop off at the self-service place in her Washington neighborhood for a top-up.&quot;The primary thing for me is, it&apos;s in the neighborhood, across the street from the supermarket, and it&apos;s easy,&quot;she told AFP as she inserted a green card with a microchip into a slot above one of three self-service units, each of which contains eight bottles of wine.   Click to continue POSTED BY: AT 01:05 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Wednesday, 17 September 2008 MICROS: Travelers at JFK International to order food at new touchscreen kiosks James Bickers is the editor of Retail Customer Experience, a sister site of SelfService.org. To submit a comment about this story, e-mail Travis K. Kircher . 
 
ANNAPOLIS, Md.—Fliers departing John F. Kennedy International Airport in October will experience a re-opened terminal featuring 250 touchscreen kiosks and 26 arrival and departure gates.
 
The kiosks from Nextep allow gate-bound travelers to choose food and drink items from multiple vendors and combine them into one order. The buyer swipes a payment card—with an option to add gratuity—and delivery to the gate is scheduled, along with estimated arrival time.
 
The program is part of Terminal 5&apos;s&quot;T5 Experience,&quot;which aims to make dining at the airport something travelers will look forward to. 
 
&quot;The initiative also includes a focus on improved food quality, with local ingredients and a &apos;farmer&apos;s market&apos;-type ambiance,&quot;said Nextep&apos;s Tommy Wojick. POSTED BY: AT 12:57 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Wednesday, 17 September 2008 Kiosk offers choice of 100 wines New York Post: For those who can&apos;t be bothered with blending their own grapes, the new high-tech wine bar Clo offers a novel approach to sipping and swirling. Located on the fourth floor of the Time Warner Center, the walled-in kiosk features a 32-seat communal table with a digital wine list projected onto it. With the touch of a finger —or in the case of one writer, repeated stabs —you can search some 100 wines by color, grape, region and price (half-glass pours start at $3 and quickly go up from there).   Click to continue POSTED BY: AT 12:00 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Wednesday, 10 September 2008 Giant Eagle customers order salami on rye at IBM kiosks Progressive Grocer: Giant Eagle Inc. has deployed more than 30 intelligent self-service ordering systems in more than 30 of its GetGo c-stores that are expected reduce lines and wait times by allowing customers to place orders directly at the sandwich counter. The IBM-powered AnyPlace Kiosk that Giant Eagle is now using relies on NextChoice&apos;s NextWave self-service software suite, which unifies customer ordering and payment with the collection and management of transaction data and preferences.   Click to continue POSTED BY: AT 12:48 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Friday, 05 September 2008 London restaurant offers self-service, computerized tabletops The (Raleigh, N.C.) News&amp;Observer: Inamo, a restaurant in central London&apos;s Soho section, allows diners to order their own food directly from their tables, literally. Using a mouse pad  that turns tables into giant computer screens, diners can order from an illustrated menu, pay their bills, summon taxis, play interactive games with fellow diners, view their food being prepared and even change the look of their tables.   Click to continue POSTED BY: AT 12:36 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Tuesday, 19 August 2008 Self-service Irish coffee chain sees profits The Irish Independent: Tim Hortons, the coffee and doughnut chain with self-service kiosks in Ireland, has reported growth in Canada and the United States. The chain, which is involved in a joint venture with food group IAWS, said second-quarter profit rose as it opened more restaurants and charged higher prices. Internationally, the company said the number of Tim Hortons sites in Ireland and the U.K. has expanded to 213 licensed locations, comprised primarily of self-serve kiosks.   Click to continue POSTED BY: AT 10:39 am  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Friday, 27 June 2008 OPINION: Deli Express kiosk from NEXTEP improves customer service The (Douglas, Ariz.) Daily Dispatch: What kind of effect does NEXTEP Systems&apos; Deli Express kiosk have on the customer experience? Quite a big one, according to Stephanie Nelson, a regular contributor to&quot;Good Morning America.&quot;Nelson recently featured the kiosks in one of her online columns.
 
 Read more POSTED BY: AT 02:42 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Thursday, 19 June 2008 Domino&apos;s may offer movies on demand with pizza deliveries, courtesy MOD Systems Video Business: MOD Systems and Domino’s Pizza are in talks to give consumers the opportunity to have their pizza and movie delivered by the same person, according to participants at Wednesday’s Entertainment Supply Chain Academy. MOD Systems has been testing music manufacturing-on-demand to CD and/or portable device through kiosk installations at Best Buy. But retailers, including pizza chain Domino’s, see value in offering impulse-produced DVDs as a new revenue stream. The idea is that a Domino’s customer could order a pizza plus a movie of their choice and both would be churned out at the storefront for home delivery.   Read more POSTED BY: AT 02:20 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Monday, 16 June 2008 Nino Salvaggio patrons can now preorder at self-service kiosks The Detroit (Mich.) Free Press: Nino Salvaggio, a specialty grocer best known for its fresh produce and imported gourmet foods, is applying fast-food restaurant technology to its deli department to reduce the other thing it&apos;s known for—long lines. The kiosks are at the front of the store so as customers come in they can order their sliced meats and cheeses. They can pick up their order 10 minutes later in the deli. 
 
 Read more 
 POSTED BY: AT 01:57 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Wednesday, 11 June 2008 VIDEO: NEXTEP SYSTEMS deli kiosk featured on cooking show 
 Blip.tv: In a visit to Nino Salvaggio&apos;s grocery in Clinton Township, Michigan, Cathy, host of&quot;Cooking with Cathy,&quot;uses NEXTEP SYSTEMS’Deli Express kiosk. Nino’s store manager, Frank Nicolella, shows Cathy how to order her turkey and cheese, and then pick it up at the deli counter in 10 minutes. 

 Click here to see the video. 
 POSTED BY: AT 12:32 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Wednesday, 04 June 2008 TableTop Media announces touchscreens that let patrons pay-at-the-table DALLAS—TableTop Media LLC has announced a wireless, interactive tabletop device with next-generation pay-on-demand capabilities. The company plans to display the device in the Microsoft Booth at FS/TEC, an international trade show focused on technology for the foodservice industry.   TableTop Media’s device has three main features: split check, touch tip and email or print receipt capabilities.   Using the solution, the company says restaurant operators will receive key benefits.
 
 Dynamic Content Delivery–Increase consumer interaction via digital promotions at relevant times with measurable results. Real-Time Feedback–Boost customer loyalty by empowering guests and alerting managers if certain conditions are met. Infotainment–Engage and entertain guests while enhancing the overall dining experience with information, movie trailers and ticket purchasing. 

 TableTop Media’s solution has been installed at Cozymel’s Mexican Grill in its Grapevine, Texas, location for the past three months. 
 POSTED BY: AT 11:54 am  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Wednesday, 04 June 2008 Starbucks, Coinstar experiment with espresso kiosks The Puget Sound (Seattle, Wash.) Business Journal: Starbucks Corp. is experimenting with selling espresso drinks from a machine, sans barista. The company, through its Seattle&apos;s Best Coffee label, has teamed up with Coinstar Inc. and a small Bellevue company, Concordia Coffee Co. Inc., on automated, self-serve espresso kiosks in grocery stores in eight states. The machines grind their own beans and crank out lattes, mochas, chai teas, hot chocolates and drip coffees. There are 86 machines installed in Albertson&apos;s stores and other groceries in Washington, Oregon, Idaho, Utah, Illinois, Wisconsin, Maryland and Tennessee.   Read more 
 POSTED BY: AT 11:53 am  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Wednesday, 28 May 2008 Japanese consumers pay for Happy meals via mobile tech JAPAN—McDonalds now lets Japanese customers pay for their Big Macs and Happy Meals with their mobile phones. After nearly a year in development, McDonalds Japan has announced the deployment of its e-wallet coupon and payment system, using Felica and NTT DoComo RFID readers.
 
Under the so-called Kazasu Kuupon (no contact coupon) program, DoCoMo subscribers are supposed to download an application and register on McDonalds Japan’s mobile Web site first. They will then receive digital vouchers on their mobile phones, which when tapped against an RFID reader placed at McDonalds counters will redeem the coupons. The McDonald&apos;s tally will show up on the clients’next DoCoMo phone bill.
 
Moreover, customers can also pay food orders via their mobile phones, provided they are enrolled in DoCoMo’s mobile e-wallet system“iD.”
 
The Japan-only technology is currently being tested in 175 McDonalds Tokyo stores as of May 20. The company plans to rapidly expand the program to a total of 3,800 retail shops by 2009. POSTED BY: AT 11:14 am  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Monday, 21 April 2008 TableTop Media announces pay-at-the-table kiosk DALLAS—TableTop Media has unveiled its wireless, interactive tabletop device with pay-on-demand capabilities.   TableTop Media delivers a pay-at-the-table device with three distinct features: split check, touch tip and email or print receipt capabilities. Unlike traditional pay-at-the-table products, the solution places control in the guests’hands to pay at their convenience.     TableTop Media’s solution has been installed at Cozymel’s Mexican Grill in its Grapevine, Texas location for the past three months.   The solution is built upon the Microsoft Windows Embedded CE operating system and the Microsoft .NET Compact Framework and uses additional Microsoft technologies including Microsoft Windows Server 2005, Microsoft SQL Server 2005 and Internet Information Services 6.0. POSTED BY: AT 03:04 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Monday, 07 April 2008 Va. Hardee&apos;s locations test touchscreen kiosks The (Richmond, Va.) Times-Dispatch: Customers at two Richmond-area Hardee&apos;s restaurants can use touchscreen kiosks to order and pay for their food. The kiosks are part of a test for franchise operator Boddie-Noell to see whether customer service improves.&quot;It is really all about speed of service, ordering accurately and giving customers another way to get their order quicker,&quot;said Jerry Allsbrook, senior vice president of marketing for Boddie-Noell, the largest Hardee&apos;s franchisee in the U.S. It operates 346 restaurants in four states, including Virginia.
 
 Read more 
 POSTED BY: AT 02:24 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Tuesday, 01 April 2008 Atlanta bar installs self-service beer taps (Tampa Bay, Fla.) Channel 10: A high-end sports bar in downtown Atlanta has installed beer taps at the table. Stats Sports Bar has built beer taps into some of the tables in the bar, giving patrons the option to serve themselves. The tables have two built-in taps. They still need waitresses to check customers&apos; ID&apos;s. Otherwise, it&apos;s pour your own. Customers are charged 25 cents an ounce for every drop, and that includes the foam. The taps automatically shut off after about 3 pitchers worth.
 
 Read more POSTED BY: AT 01:30 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Tuesday, 18 March 2008 Restaurant touchscreen shows menu in 3-D The Raw Feed: Japan&apos;s TEC has created a restaurant table with a built-in 3-D LCD screen. The table, called the Tobidasu Menu, lets you browse food choices. The piece de resistance is that you can select each item on the touchscreen table for full-size, 3-D view. The table shows what your food will look like sitting in front of you. The table even performs a few wacky tricks—for example, you can place a hamburger bun on the table and when you lift it up again there will be a 3-D digital burger underneath.
 
 Read more POSTED BY: AT 01:13 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Wednesday, 12 March 2008 Largest Hardee&apos;s franchise operator getting kiosks SAN DIEGO, Calif.—Boddie-Noell Enterprises, the largest Hardee’s franchise operator in the United States with 345 restaurants in four states, and EMN8, a provider of self-service systems for quick-service restaurants, has announced the introduction of EMN8 kiosks in BNE Hardee’s locations.
 
According to a news release, a three restaurant pilot is underway that will test the level of guest adoption of the technology and improvement in speed of customer service. EMN8’s self-service software features a user-friendly interface that allows Hardee’s customers to order their food quickly and easily. The menu presents products, suggestions and options in such a manner as to influence customers’decisions at the point of purchase, increasing average ticket and menu awareness. POSTED BY: AT 01:04 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Monday, 10 March 2008 Runtriz, SeePoint partner on wine kiosk LOS ANGELES—Using a new interactive wine-retailing solution from runtriz, and touchscreen technology from SeePoint Technology, wine shops, tasting rooms and bars can expand their offerings. Wine by runtriz, a touchscreen kiosk, allows consumers to learn about different regions, get recommendations, view ratings and order.
 
The interactive system allows consumers to order and checkout without requiring any additional retailer staff or personnel. Not only can customers view wine listings by variety, vintage year or price, the runtriz solution also lets consumers search the world by region. The kiosk uses 3D animated graphics- developed by designers from the National Geographic Channel. Just touch anywhere on the map and the system will take you to that country’s wine regions while pulling retailer’s stock right on the screen. Customers looking for a Bordeaux can simply touch France on the map or scroll through Australia for a new Syrah, for example.
 
Wine by runtriz is certified to run on all of SeePoint’s kiosk systems. The solution can be housed in a free-standing model, on a countertop or the All-in-One VESA mounting kiosk system. All SeePoint systems are secure kiosk systems with integrated processing unit and touchscreen monitor. Their small footprint units can be mounted in various locations, including poles, wall-mounted or desktop. POSTED BY: AT 12:00 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Friday, 07 March 2008 Fingerprint scan kiosk to verify age of pub patrons (Bangkok, Thailand) The Nation: Before gaining entry to a pub, one has to display an identification card. However, the next time just your finger will do. A new technology using a fingerprint scan has been developed to help verify the age of pub patrons. The technology has been launched by Diageo Moet Hennessy, a leading importer and distributor of premium alcoholic beverages, which was formerly known as Riche Monde. The project involved establishing fingerprint scan kiosks at the gates of popular pubs. The kiosk will be used by pubs to verify that their patrons&apos; age is above 20 - the legal requirement to enter a pub in Thailand.
 
 Read more POSTED BY: AT 12:54 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Monday, 18 February 2008 Digital dining is the latest in table-side service The (New Jersey) Star-Ledger: The restaurant industry may soon allow customers to order their food and pay for it without ever needing a waiter. Call it digital dining, self-service, the inevitable confluence of technology and gastronomy that can speed service, reduce ordering errors and better secure your precious credit card information in one of the few remaining environments in which your card leaves your control.
 
 Read more POSTED BY: AT 09:31 am  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Thursday, 24 January 2008 Stew Leonard&apos;s deploys deli kiosk in Yonkers store Progressive Grocer: Stew Leonard&apos;s has rolled out a deli self-order kiosk from Lombard, Ill.-based ADUSA Inc., provider of self-ordering solutions for grocery supermarkets, restaurants and foodservice operations, in its Yonkers, N.Y. store. The kiosks will allow customers to self-order the full range of items available at the service deli, among them meats, cheeses, party trays, and, eventually, sandwiches— reducing, or completely eliminating, the time that a customer has to spend waiting in line.   Read more POSTED BY: AT 09:02 am  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Tuesday, 22 January 2008 uWink restaurants offering service with table touchscreen kiosks CBS 2 HDTV: Ever find yourself unable to get the attention of a waiter? That may be a problem of the past thanks to new tableside touchscreens. The technology is being used at uWink, the latest offering from the founder of Chuck E. Cheese. The company said the new system is providing faster service, fewer mistakes and fewer interruptions.   Read more POSTED BY: AT 03:52 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Monday, 07 January 2008 NCR FastLane extends self-service options 
 Selection 
 Weather Feeds reader Weather Mytempdir upload Imageshack upload Current web scripts SearchMash Google DogPile MultiSearch Delicious Similar webs Email a note Create Note Show/Hide Access Bar Pro Book Burro Babel Mousish Wordreference Diccionario RAE Wikipedia spanish Wikipedia english Youtube videos IMDB AcronymFinder Astalavista Urban Dictionary TinyURL Online mp3Player Open URL Mailinator Bypass banned web ShowMyIp Domains on this ip Whois domain Calculator Make text links clickable Reload Interval Reload Images Clear cookies View cookies Change cookies View web passwords ZOOM IMAGES UNZOOM IMAGES Page Recolorization Remove all images EDIT WEB REDIRECT LINKS ScriptRunner AutoClick WebSwissKnifeToolbar version: 0.0.2d DAYTON, Ohio—Retailers who have deployed NCR Corp .&apos;s FastLane self-checkout kiosks can extend FastLane&apos;s capabilities to shoppers in other parts of the store, thanks to a new solution from NCR called NCR FastLane Order and Pay.   According to a news release, FastLane Order and Pay is designed to address a variety of self-service opportunities within a store —such as a deli or bakery section or an in-store food-service operation. In addition to food stores, it also can be deployed in general merchandise, convenience or other retail formats.   &quot;With this solution, retailers can leverage their NCR FastLane investment by migrating additional transactions to self-service,&quot;said Mike Webster, NCR vice president for self-service solutions. &quot;Because their customers will already be familiar with NCR self-checkout, they can use NCR FastLane Order and Pay with ease and confidence.&quot;   Introduced initially in Europe, NCR FastLane Order and Pay has been deployed in Italy by leading retailer Auchan, which operates supermarkets and hypermarkets across Europe. It also has been installed by one of the largest food and drug retailers in North America.   NCR FastLane Order and Pay features the familiar NCR FastLane interface without the scan and bag functionality. The touchscreen presents shoppers with a pre-set menu appropriate to its location in the store.   After entering choices, a consumer can use NCR FastLane Order and Pay to pay with cash, debit card or credit card and receive a receipt that he hands to a store associate before picking up his purchase.    NCR FastLane Order and Pay makes its North American trade show debut Jan. 13-16 at the National Retail Federation&apos;s Annual Convention&amp;Expo in New York. dummyButton POSTED BY: AT 03:27 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Friday, 04 January 2008 NCR intros contactless, mobile payment solutions for retail, hospitality DAYTON, Ohio—NCR Corp., in partnership with ViVOtech, has introduced a suite of contactless payment terminals for the point of sale. These solutions enable mobile and contactless payment at a variety of customer touch points, including retail checkout, restaurant drive-thru and the diner’s table.   Demonstrations of the new technology will take place Jan. 13-16 during the National Retail Foundation&apos;s Annual Convention&amp;Expo in New York.   “NCR’s unparalleled experience in payment transactions, combined with ViVOtech’s expertise in contactless technology, provides retailers with the latest contactless payment options and a platform for future near field communication applications,”said Greg Egan, NCR vice president for Retail Assisted Service Solutions. “This line of NCR RealPOS contactless readers is designed to help merchants achieve a successful contactless and mobile payments program, and provide a new level of service to their customers.” POSTED BY: AT 03:08 pm  |   Permalink   |   0 Comments   |   E-mail this Tuesday, 18 December 2007 Modiv Media&quot;s DeliVision serves up 7 million self-service orders BOSTON - Modiv Media, a retail interactive media delivery solutions provider, has announced that its Modiv DeliVision, a deli-queue optimization solution that also features self-service ordering and coordinated media, has processed more than 7 million orders since it first was deployed at stores in 2006. The deli kiosk currently is deployed in more than 150 stores and across seven states, including Stop&amp;Shop grocery stores.   Modiv DeliVision combines queue optimization, self-service deli ordering and coordinated, targeted media to enhance the shopper&apos;s deli experience. Modiv DeliVision enables customers to place their deli order, tells the customer when the order will be filled, and offers targeted, relevant offers. This helps retailers reduce line abandonment and&quot;tickets not served,&quot;improve deli operations and increase deli sales.   &quot;Using Modiv DeliVision, Stop&amp;Shop can now provide a new way for customers to shop,&quot;said Christine Dorman, senior vice president, Operational and Strategic Initiatives&amp;Support Services for Stop&amp;Shop.&quot;DeliVision gives us an opportunity to enhance customer satisfaction and increase our efficiency.&quot;   Retailers and manufacturers also use the DeliVision to leverage brand awareness by coordinating their offers and advertisements on the touchscreen self-service kiosk, the deli department&apos;s overhead electronic display monitor, as well as the printed-coupon tickets from the kiosk and the queue ticket dispenser.   &quot;Besides an increase in deli trips, we are also seeing a trend that shoppers purchase more items per trip when they use the Modiv DeliVision kiosk as compared to ordering in person at the deli counter,&quot;� said Robert Wesley, president and CEO of Modiv Media.&quot;Because shoppers do not need to wait to give their deli order, they are more likely to order additional items and can quickly fulfill their own customized orders, including specific brand, weight or cut. Convenience and speed are key elements to Modiv DeliVision&apos;s millions-order success.&quot; POSTED BY: AT 12:20 pm  |   Permalink   |
	</body>
</document>
