<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008921" url="http://restaurants.uptake.com/tennessee.html" time="2012-07-13-02:20" support="5" score="0.02012791095824957" bingtitle="Tennessee Restaurants - Best Food and Dining in Tennessee - Uptake.com" webtitle="Tennessee Restaurants - Best Food and Dining in Tennessee - Uptake.com">
			<query id="001122" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000357" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="001110" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000369" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="001270" bing-rank="239"/>
	<description>Choose from 3000 of the best restaurants in Tennessee - View a restaurant guide for all types of food and cuisine, from Tennessee cafés and fine dining to diners and ...</description>
	<body>
		Uptake 
 Destination   
 United States West 
 Alaska California Colorado Hawaii Idaho Montana Nevada Oregon Utah Washington Wyoming 
 Midwest 
 Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Michigan Minnesota Missouri Nebraska North Dakota Ohio South Dakota Wisconsin 
 Northeast 
 Connecticut Delaware Maine Maryland Massachusetts New Hampshire New Jersey New York Pennsylvania Rhode Island Vermont 
 Southwest 
 Arizona New Mexico Oklahoma Texas 
 South 
 Alabama Arkansas Florida Georgia Kentucky Louisiana Mississippi North Carolina South Carolina Tennessee Virginia 
 Canada Alberta British Columbia Manitoba New Brunswick Newfoundland Nova Scotia Ontario Prince Edward Island Quebec Saskatchewan International Amsterdam Athens Barcelona Berlin Cape Town Edinburgh London Madrid Mexico City Paris Rome Sydney 
 Themes&amp;Activities   
 Family Romantic Cheap/Budget Resorts Golf Courses Campgrounds Nightlife 
 
 Search 
 
 
 Uptake &gt; Restaurants &gt; Tennessee &gt; Tennessee Restaurants &gt; Tennessee Restaurants 
 » 
 Uptake &gt; Restaurants &gt; Tennessee &gt; Tennessee Restaurants &gt; Tennessee Restaurants 
 
Restaurants in Tennessee
 
 

 Tennessee Hotels Facebook Attractions Restaurants 
 
Refine Your Search:
 Cuisine Types 
 American American American South American South Asian Asian Bakery Bakery Breakfast&amp;Brunch Breakfast&amp;Brunch Burgers&amp;Hot Dogs Burgers&amp;Hot Dogs Cafe Cafe Casual Dining Casual Dining Chinese Chinese Delis&amp;Diners Delis&amp;Diners Desserts Desserts European European French French Italian Italian Japanese&amp;Sushi Japanese&amp;Sushi Local&amp;Traditional Local&amp;Traditional Mediterranean Mediterranean Mexican Mexican Misc Misc Pizza Pizza Pubs&amp;Taverns Pubs&amp;Taverns Seafood Seafood Soups&amp;Salads Soups&amp;Salads Steak Steak 
 
Popular Restaurants in Tennessee
 
 1-20 21-40 41-60 61-80 
Popular Cities
 
 Memphis Restaurants Nashville Restaurants Knoxville Restaurants Chattanooga Restaurants Murfreesboro Restaurants Clarksville Restaurants Johnson City Restaurants Franklin Restaurants Kingsport Restaurants Jackson Restaurants Cleveland Restaurants Cookeville Restaurants Sevierville Restaurants Cordova Restaurants Maryville Restaurants Brentwood Restaurants Antioch Restaurants Gatlinburg Restaurants Lebanon Restaurants Columbia Restaurants 

 Pigeon Forge Restaurants Smyrna Restaurants Hendersonville Restaurants Collierville Restaurants Crossville Restaurants Madison Restaurants Bristol Restaurants Greeneville Restaurants Germantown Restaurants Morristown Restaurants Hixson Restaurants Hermitage Restaurants Lenoir City Restaurants Oak Ridge Restaurants Gallatin Restaurants Bartlett Restaurants Athens Restaurants Millington Restaurants Tullahoma Restaurants Dickson Restaurants 

 Shelbyville Restaurants Springfield Restaurants Mount Juliet Restaurants Alcoa Restaurants Elizabethton Restaurants Dyersburg Restaurants Spring Hill Restaurants Manchester Restaurants Goodlettsville Restaurants McMinnville Restaurants Newport Restaurants Paris Restaurants Sparta Restaurants Covington Restaurants Union City Restaurants Clinton Restaurants Arlington Restaurants Lexington Restaurants Ooltewah Restaurants Lewisburg Restaurants 

 Lawrenceburg Restaurants Jonesborough Restaurants Loudon Restaurants Powell Restaurants Savannah Restaurants La Vergne Restaurants Fayetteville Restaurants La Follette Restaurants Dayton Restaurants Sweetwater Restaurants Winchester Restaurants Pulaski Restaurants Martin Restaurants Soddy-Daisy Restaurants Dandridge Restaurants White House Restaurants Rogersville Restaurants Smithville Restaurants Jefferson City Restaurants Seymour Restaurants 
 
 
 Sort by Popularity Avg Rating 

 List View Map View 
 
#1.
 
 Demos&apos; Steak and Spaghetti House 
 
300 Commerce St, Nashville, Tennessee
 Demos&apos; Steak and Spaghetti House 4.5 User Rating (4 sources) × 
 TripAdvisor Yahoo! Travel Restaurantica CitySearch 
 
 Overview Demos&apos; is a great place for a family meal or business lunch. Garden salads and pasta dishes ... more on Yahoo! Travel Overview In Short :Old school decor, hearing your name called over a loudspeaker when your table is r... more on CitySearch 
   
 

 Read Reviews View Map&amp;Directions 
 
#2.
 
 Corky&apos;s Bar-B-Q 
 
5259 Poplar Ave, Memphis, Tennessee
 Corky&apos;s Bar-B-Q 4.5 User Rating (4 sources) × 
 Yahoo! Travel CitySearch Restaurantica TripAdvisor 
 
 Overview Slow-cooked barbecue on ... more on Gayot Overview Corky&apos;s is good-natured and boisterous, with rock-&apos;n&apos;-roll tunes piped both indoors and out... more on Frommers 
   
 

 Read Reviews View Map&amp;Directions 
 
#3.
 
 Pancake Pantry 
 
1796 21st Ave S, Nashville, Tennessee
 Pancake Pantry 4.5 User Rating (4 sources) × 
 TripAdvisor Yahoo! Travel Restaurantica CitySearch 
 
 Overview Monday-Friday 6am-3pm; Saturday-Sunday 6am-4pm. AX, DC, DI, MC, VI. $. Reservations not acce... more on VisitMusicCity.com Overview Fantastic pancakes draw mobs of customers to this favorite Music City eatery. Among the fave... more on RoadFood 
   
 

 Read Reviews View Map&amp;Directions 
 
#4.
 
 Wildhorse Saloon 
 
120 Second Avenue North, Nashville, TN 37201
 Wildhorse Saloon 4.5 User Rating (3 sources) × 
 Yahoo! Travel TripAdvisor CitySearch 
 
 Overview The Wildhorse Saloon showcases the best in contemporary country music. Although this venue i... more on WorldWeb.com Overview Located in the heart of Nashville&apos;s performing district - Enjoy great country music&amp;free d... more on entertainment.com 
   
 

 Read Reviews View Map&amp;Directions 
 
#5.
 
 State Line Bar&amp;Grille 
 
644 State Street, Bristol, TN 37620, United States
 State Line Bar&amp;Grille 4.0 User Rating (3 sources) × 
 CitySearch Restaurantica Yahoo! Travel 
 
 Overview The State Line Bar&amp;Grill offers American food as well as a full service bar and nightly en... more on Virginia.org Overview ![CDATA[ &quot;The corner where great food, awesome times and good friends come together.&quot;]] more on localeats.com 
   
 

 Read Reviews View Map&amp;Directions 
 
#6.
 
 Flying Saucer Draught Emporium 
 
130 Peabody Place, Memphis, Tennessee
 Flying Saucer Draught Emporium 4.0 User Rating (3 sources) × 
 TripAdvisor CitySearch Yahoo! Travel 
 
 The Flying Saucer can get rather busy on certain nights. I know that on pint night (I believe on Thursday),... more on igougo You go here for the beer selection (maybe the schoolgirl waitress attire?) more on TripAdvisor 
   
 

 Read Reviews View Map&amp;Directions 
 
#7.
 
 Brother Juniper&apos;s College Inn 
 
3519 Walker Avenue, Memphis, TN 38111-5917
 Brother Juniper&apos;s College Inn 4.5 User Rating (3 sources) × 
 CitySearch TripAdvisor Yahoo! Travel 
 
 Overview about Brother Juniper&apos;s: Brother Juniper&apos;s dishes up a mean breakfast, from biscuits to crea... more on GoCityKids Overview For four star American, try Brother Juniper&apos;s College Inn in the southern area. Here&apos;s a pla... more on Open List 
   
 

 Read Reviews View Map&amp;Directions 
 
#8.
 
 Texas de Brazil 
 
150 Peabody Place, #103, Memphis, Tennessee
 Texas de Brazil 4.5 User Rating (4 sources) × 
 CitySearch Restaurantica Yahoo! Travel TripAdvisor 
 
 Overview Treat yourself to our sumptuous fifty item salad area including appetizers, soups, salads an... more on OpenTable.com I can&apos;t wait to return again. more on Restaurantica 
   
 

 Read Reviews View Map&amp;Directions 
 
#9.
 
 Big River Grille and Brewing Works 
 
222 Broad St, Chattanooga, TN 37402, United States
 Big River Grille and Brewing Works 4.5 User Rating (4 sources) × 
 Yahoo! Travel CitySearch Restaurantica TripAdvisor 
 
 Overview “Hand crafted and brewed to perfection, Big River goes to great lengths in serving each gues... more on BrewerySearch.com Overview Visit the original location of the Big River Grille and Brewing Works in Chattanooga. This r... more on RealTravel 
   
 

 Read Reviews View Map&amp;Directions 
 
#10.
 
 Southernaire Motel Restaurant 
 
50 Overlook Ln, Stewart, TN 37175, USA
 Southernaire Motel Restaurant 5.0 User Rating (1 sources) × 
 Yahoo! Travel 
 
 The staff is wonderful and very freindly and family oriented. more on Yahoo! Travel Not NEW, but well maintained and clean . more on Yahoo! Travel 
   
 

 Read Reviews View Map&amp;Directions 
 
 Previous 1 2 3 4 5 … 300 Next 
 
Tennessee Lodging
 
Tennessee Things To Do
 
Tennessee Nightlife
 
 Pet Friendly Hotels Hotels Family Hotels Romantic Hotels Campgrounds Bed and B&apos;s Resorts Motels Cheap Hotels More &gt; 
 
 Pet Friendly Things To Do Things To Do Golf Courses Beaches Spas Museums Shopping Zoos and Aquariums Themeparks Family Things To Do Romantic Things To Do Parks Restaurants Cheap Things To Do Breweries More &gt; 
 
 Gay Lesbian Nightlife Bars Wine Bar Nightlife More &gt; 
 Uptake 
 About Uptake Contact Us Jobs The Uptake Blog Press Community Guidelines User Agreement Privacy Policy Site Map 
 
©2006 - 2012 Uptake Networks, Inc.
 × Uptake 
Get the best tips and advice by discovering which of your friends have been
 to Tennessee , and also reach our helpful and experienced Uptake travel
 community. Sign in!
 Login with Facebook or use your email and password New User × 
Quick Survey
 Thanks for helping make Uptake.com better by answering this short survey. 

Did you find what you are looking for?

 Yes

 No


(Optional) Please describe what you were looking for, or offer any other comments you&apos;d like to share. 
 
 Did you know that your Internet Explorer is out of date? 


To get the best possible experience using our website we recommend that you upgrade to a newer version .

 Close
	</body>
</document>
