<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008206" url="http://retailindustry.about.com/od/retailbestpractices/a/2009_best_us_retail_restaurant_chains_zagat_survey.htm" time="2012-07-13-01:41" support="2" score="0.0037476439271283317" bingtitle="Restaurant Diners’ Rankings of Best U.S. Retail Restaurant ..." webtitle="Restaurant DinersRankings of Best U.S. Retail Restaurant Chains and Franchises - 2010 Zagat Fast Food Customer Survey Results">
			<query id="000453" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000167" bing-rank="46"/>
	<description>Find out which U.S. retail restaurant chains and franchises got the best rankings from restaurant diners in the annual 2010 Zagat Fast Food customer survey. This ...</description>
	<body>
		Industry 
 Retail Industry Search 
 Retail Industry Stores&amp;Sales Research Jobs Management Tips 

 Share 
 Free Retail Industry Newsletter! Sign Up 
 Discuss in my forum 
 
 Restaurant Diners’Rankings of Best U.S. Retail Restaurant Chains and Franchises 

2010 Zagat Fast Food Customer Survey Results of Best and Most Popular Fast Food

By Barbara Farfan , About.com Guide
 See More About: 
 best u.s. restaurants american restauant chains zagats survey retail industy awards top restaurants 
 Each year the Zagat organization, publishers of Zagat Survey data for restaurants and hotels, conduct a customer survey of the top, best, biggest, and most popular U.S. retail restaurant chains and franchises. The Zagat Fast Food survey is open to any U.S. resident, and asks restaurant customers to rate fast food, quick service and full service restaurants for their food, service and facilities.

In 2010, the Zagat Fast Food survey was completed by 6,500 U.S. dining customers across the U.S.

What makes the Zagat survey particularly unique and trustworthy is the survey methodology, which is a truly random sampling, not a chosen or targeted study group. While the taste of food is always a matter of individual taste, opinions about what constitutes good and bad restaurant service and high food quality are universal, and therefore, the Zagat survey results are generally considered to be a dependable assessment overall.

Of course, in the case of every restaurant chain and franchise, the individual delivery and execution could vary greatly between locations and are completely dependent on the restaurant management and employee team. The top five restaurant chains and franchises generally manage to achieve their high rankings because of the high standards established and enforced by the company’s headquarters and its management team.

So while it is always possible to have a bad customer experience at any restaurant location, it is less likely that this will occur in the restaurant chains and franchises Zagat’s‘best”rankings. What the Zagat rankings really identify are the U.S. restaurant chains and franchises which have the best consistency and dependability, according to restaurant customers.

What follows are the results of the 2010 Zagat Fast Food survey, arranged alphabetically according to the names of the restaurant chains. The restaurants listed here received a top five ranking in one or more of the following categories that Zagat measures:

The U.S. restaurants and chains not listed in these survey results did not receive the highest ratings from restaurant customers, and therefore, did not achieve a top five ranking in any of the categories measured by Zagat.

 All 2010 Zagat Restaurant Rankings &gt;&gt; 

 More about the U.S. Retail Restaurant Industry: 
 Compare to 2009 Zagat’s Annual Fast Food Customer Survey Ranking Results Emerging U.S. Restaurant Chains Retail Restaurant Performance Index 

 Most Popular Articles | Trending Retail Topics | Follow on Twitter | &quot;Like&quot; on Facebook 
 Previous 
 1 2 3 
 Next Related Articles 
 2010 Rankings of Best U.S. Retail Restaurant Chains and Franchises - Zagat ... ZAGAT Survey Goes Online: New England Restaurant Reviews Now Free on the Ne... QSR 50 List Multi-year Comparison - Domestic Revenue Rankings for the Large... U.S. Retail Customer Satisfaction Survey Trend Is Hot, But Service Recovery... Zagat&apos;s 2009 Seattle Restaurant Winners 
 
 Barbara Farfan 
Retail Industry Guide

 Sign up for My Newsletter 

 Headlines Forum 
 Related Searches restaurant chains u s restaurant random sampling food survey survey methodology restaurant customers Explore Retail Industry Must Reads 
 Back-To-School Free Shipping Options Top 100 Global Franchises Customers: Starbucks Is Best Experience Today&apos;s Grocery&amp;Supermarket Jobs Open Worst U.S. Retail Job-Hunting Cities 
 Most Popular 
 2011 Largest European Retail 2011 World&apos;s Largest Retailers Apple Inc. Mission Statement Is Not Very Innovative and Bare… 2010 World&apos;s Largest Retailers Wal-Mart Stores&apos;Mission Statement - People, Saving Mon… 
 See More About: 
 best u.s. restaurants american restauant chains zagats survey retail industy awards top restaurants 
 By Category 
 Retail Jobs&amp;Careers World&apos;s Largest Retailers Statistics&amp;Sales Numbers Best Practices Glossary of Retail Terms Employee Management Tools Freebies&amp;Coupons Operations Solutions Retail Trendsetters Consultants&amp;Suppliers Global Innovations Trade Associations Merchandising Tips&amp;Trends US Retail History Frequently Asked Questions FAQ 
 Retail Industry 
 About.com Industry Retail Industry World&apos;s Largest Retailers Largest US Retail Companies U.S. Restaurant Industry Restaurant Diners’Rankings of Best U.S. Retail Restaurant Chains and Franchises - 2010 Zagat Fast Food Customer Survey Results 
 
 Most Popular Latest Articles RSS 
 
 Advertise on About.com Our Story News&amp;Events Work at About SiteMap All Topics Reprints Help 

 Write for About User Agreement Ethics Policy Patent Info. Privacy Policy Your Ad Choices 
 
©2012 About.com. All rights reserved.

A part of The New York Times Company .
	</body>
</document>
