<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008356" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Lakeland/Hooters-of-Lakeland-South-Lakeland" time="2012-07-13-01:50" support="2" score="0.002445756206263462" bingtitle="Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland - Fast Food Restaurant Lakeland, FL" webtitle="Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland - Fast Food Restaurant  Lakeland, FL">
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000180" bing-rank="63"/>
	<description>Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland is a Fast Food ... Defending Champion Lake Nona Wins Tavistock Cup Again ... Yes, Sign me up for Hooters Email &amp; Text Club to receive ...</description>
	<body>
		0 Friend Requests Friend Requests 0 Messages Send a New Message Messages 0 Notifications Notifications 
 
 Find Friends Login 
 or login with: User Pages Photos Events Videos Polls Forum Threads Restaurant Search Results For User Search Results For Pages Search Results For Photos Search Results For Events Search Results For Videos Search Results For Polls Search Results For Forum Threads Search Results For Restaurant 
 Places Deals Recipes Photos Members Blog 
 
 Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Hooters of Lakeland South
Lakeland

 
Average User Rating
 
7
 
Exceptional

 1 Reviews 
 
Sponsored Link


 
(863) 644-8461

 http://www.hooters.com/ 
 FL &gt; Lakeland &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Review 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland
 Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland is a Fast Food restaurant located at 3437 S Florida Ave in Lakeland, FL . Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland has been described as an Exceptional Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 7 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food, Take Out, American Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland
 
 
 
All Reviews for Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland

 
 Anonymous 
 


March 27, 2009
 
Food
 
7
 
Decor
 
7
 
Service
 
7
 
Small hideaway but the food is made from scratch. Like your mom would make if she had the time.
 
Overall Rating
 
7
 
&quot;Exceptional&quot;
 
 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   1

 
Comments
 
 
Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland News
 Taking The Kids: Lower Manhattan Offers Much to See and Do We&apos;re talking about Lower Manhattan -- specifically the area south of Chambers ... home to nearly 56,000 New Yorkers, including many families, making the area one of New York&apos;s fastest growing neighborhoods with restaurants and upscale shopping. Fast for Fair Food: Farmworkers Fast so &quot;Our Children Won&apos;t Have To&quot; In a sunlit field in Lakeland, Florida, outside the headquarters of Publix ... Rev. Noelle Damico, a member of the Presbyterian Hunger Program from White Plains, New York, wrote Monday: “It is hot. Searing hot. There isn’t quite enough ... Defending Champion Lake Nona Wins Tavistock Cup Again Beneficiaries include various player charities as well as The First Tee of Lakeland, the Orlando Minority Youth Golf ... financial services, restaurants, commercial properties, private luxury residential properties, resort properties and master-planned ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland Coupons - 3437 S Florida Ave ... Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland is a Fast Food restaurant located at 3437 S Florida Ave in Lakeland, FL . There are 0 places near Hooters of Lakeland South ... Lakeland FL news, sports, weather and classifieds | TheLedger.com ... The Ledger is a Lakeland newspaper covering Lakeland FL news. The Ledger also offers a wide range of information about Lakeland, Florida. Hooters Veterans Day Yes, Sign me up for Hooters Email&amp;Text Club to receive emails and text messages about upcoming Hooters promotions&amp;special events. * Lakeland, Florida - Lakeland City Guide Lakeland City Guide: Discover Lakeland, Florida attractions, restaurants, neighborhoods, and nightlife. Read Lakeland news, meet others in your area, and make travel ... Florida Fried Chicken&amp;Chines Food - Fast Food Restaurant ... Peter Pak, the owner and operator of a novel, fast-casual restaurant in Bellevue called Oma Bap, grew up in Syracuse, New York, about 250 miles ... your choice of ... 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 88° 
Fri
 
 73° - 91° 
Sat
 
 75° - 88° 
Sun
 
 75° - 90° 
 
Address
 
Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland

3437 S Florida Ave

Lakeland, FL 
 

 
Telephone
 (863) 644-8461 
Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland
 
 Rating :  7 out of 10 based on 1 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland Photos
 
 Fast Food Take Out American 
 
 Local Places
 
 Reececliff Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Blimpie Subs&amp;Salads 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Quiznos 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Piccadilly Cafeteria 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Long John Silvers 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Florida Fried Chicken&amp;Chines Food 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Little BBQ House 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Jimmys Pizza 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Burger King 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Steak n Shake 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Checkers Drive-In Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Steak n Shake 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Harrys Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Krystal 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Art Printscom Incorporated 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Arts on the Park Incorporated 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Imperial Art Gallery 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Robert Butler Gallery 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Visual Concepts 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries 
 

See all Lakeland Art Museums Galleries 
See all Lakeland ATMs 
See all Lakeland Bars and Pubs 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland Coupons 

 Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland Lakeland 

 Hooters of Lakeland South Lakeland Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Lakeland Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P Q | R | S | T | V | W | Y | Z 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
