<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009665" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/making-mcchicken-sandwich-home-4563263.html" time="2012-07-13-03:03" support="1" score="0.0008954931879849176" bingtitle="Making the McChicken Sandwich at Home - Yahoo! Voices - voices ..." webtitle="Making the McChicken Sandwich at Home - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="001273" bing-rank="76"/>
	<description>Surely they must be making some type ... This article compares the food selection, taste and calories of two popular fast food restaurant ... How to Book Rental Car Online Th...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 
 
Making the McChicken Sandwich at Home
 Suzie , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Apr 12, 2011 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: McDonald&apos;s Chickens Mayo 
 Flag Close Post a comment There is something special I just love about McDonald&apos;s McChicken sandwich. Whether it&apos;s the texture of the processed chicken, the mayo, or all the refreshing lettuce... I just don&apos;t know. What I do know, however, is that I could eat them for the rest of my life!
And even though they are only a dollar, you have to wonder... isn&apos;t McDonald&apos;s getting away with something, like they do with everything else? Surely they must be making some type of profit from the measly dollar in my wallet!

Well, my friend... you are correct. McDonald&apos;s is making a profit, and even though a simple dollar doesn&apos;t sound like much, it really is. And so I am here to show you how you can have that delicious McDonalds McChicken sandwich and make a profit of your own! Yes, I am going to show you how you can have a McChicken every day, for only around 50 cents or even less!

So right these things down on your grocery list...

1. Store brand 8-pack hamburger buns, right around $1 for the package.
2. Bag of frozen chicken patties, the cheapest is fine, around $4 a bag.
3. Mayo (hopefully you have this at home already)
4. Iceberg lettuce, around $1 for a head, which should last you for some time.

OK, so now that you have everything required to make these tasty treats, go ahead and assemble your own deliciousness - you can either bake or microwave the chicken patty, whichever you prefer. Simply assemble the sandwich in the same way McDonalds does - bottom bun (maybe slightly toasted on the inside), chicken patty, squirt of mayo, shredded lettuce on top, and top bun. Perfect! Enjoy! And if you want to, try wrapping the sandwich up in wax paper and taking with you to work... to be the perfect envy of all your workmates who at the very least spend two quarters more than you did today! Kids love this too... because they can feel like they are enjoying McDonalds everyday, too!
 
Published by Suzie 

European beauty Suzie is a woman of many talents and niches, with a good background in plants and natural remedies, foreign delights and cuisine, relationship advice, and everyday wisdom for life (which she...  View profile 
 
 Low-Calorie Foods at Your Favorite Fast Food Restaurants Here are some low-calorie foods at your favorite fast food restaurants. The Dollar Menu Review : McDonalds Review of the offerings on the dollar menu at your neighborhood Mickey D&apos;s The Spice Rush: How Fast Food is Turning Hot Catch the spice rush in action at a variety of fast food chains that are offering zesty spins on traditional sandwiches and menu items. Learn which bold flavors are best suited for your tastes, and how the trend is mo... McDonald&apos;s Versus Wendy&apos;s Value Fast Food Menu This article compares the food selection, taste and calories of two popular fast food restaurant value menus (Wendy&apos;s and McDonald&apos;s), which offer lunch and dinner choices for 9... A Review of Banquet Fried Chicken Patty Meal A Review Of Banquet Fried Chicken Patty Meal. Read on to see what I discovered about this product. 

 Couple Gets Married at Silver Do... How to Book Rental Car Online Th... Are the things in the Dollar Sto... 
 
 Wendy&apos;s Crispy Chicken Sandwich Versus McDonald&apos;s McChicken Sandwich McDonald&apos;s Menu, My Way McDonalds in India: Where&apos;s the Beef? Guide to Dieting While Eating at Fast Food Restaurants Eating for Cheap: How to Get Lunch for a Buck or Less Breastfeeding and the Dangers of Food Allergies Poisoned ~ All for the Sake of a Dollar 
 
 
 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Shine and Lifestyles Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
