<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009811" url="http://ridgestone.com/" time="2012-07-13-03:12" support="1" score="0.0012326439749229573" bingtitle="Ridgestone Bank - Welcome" webtitle="Ridgestone Bank - Welcome">
			<query id="001468" bing-rank="227"/>
	<description>Success Stories High-end Chocolatier: $1,500,000 SBA Loan $1,000,000 line of ... Success Stories Fast Food Restaurant Operator</description>
	<body>
		Commercial Products Business Momentum Blog Treasury Management SBA Products USDA Lending Personal Banking 
 Checking Accounts Money Market Accounts Savings Accounts Certificates Of Deposit 
 Success Stories About Us Newsroom 
 
 Personal: 
 Ridgestone Connect Commercial: 
 Ridgestone Connect 
 Ridgestone Express 


 Deposit Rate Sheet 


 Important Disclosure Regarding Deposit Insurance on Noninterest-bearing Transaction Accounts 
 Locations | Contact Us | Home 
 We bring the bank to you!

              &quot; Ridgestone Bank helps business owners build their dreams. We are a leader in small business and government-guaranteed lending, and also provide checking account services, remote deposit, money markets, CDs, Home Equity Loans, and other convenience services. As the 27 th largest SBA 7(a) lender and number one USDA lender in the United States for 2009, we are committed to supporting our business customers through access to adequate capital, restructuring long-term debt and creative financial solutions. Our experienced team of commercial lending specialists is ready to assist you. &quot;

 Bruce W. Lammers, CEO



 The Business Journal of Milwaukee reports Ridgestone Bank top rural business lender BizTimes Milwaukee reports on how Ridgestone Bank helps finance Serigraph&apos;s expansion The Business Journal of Milwaukee covers Ridgestone Bank&apos;s Unconventional growth in suburbia . The Chicago Tribune reports on how Ridgestone Tosses a Lifeline of Loans . BizTimes Milwaukee reports Ridgestone Bank Assists Johnson Outdoors with Debt Restructuring . 
 
 Success Stories Manufacturer $2,000,000 SBA Term Loan $1,500,000 Line of Credit with Remote Deposit 
 
 Success Stories Salon&amp;Day Spa $2,000,000 for Debt Refinance, Acquisition of Business Assets, Equipment Purchase, and Working Capital 
 
 Success Stories Candle Company $550,000 Debt Refinance and Recapitalization
$200,000 SBA Express Loan 
 
 Success Stories Distribution Company $2,000,000 SBA Term Loan
$200,000 Conventional Line of Credit 
 
 Success Stories Custom Window and Door Manufacturer $1,687,500 SBA 7(a) Term Loan 
 
 Success Stories High-end Chocolatier $1,500,000 SBA Loan
$1,000,000 line of credit 
 
 Success Stories Outdoor Recreation Company $16 million USDA Guaranteed Term Loan 
 
 Success Stories Asbestos and Lead Abatement Contractor 
$1,200,000 SBA Term Loan
 $200,000 line of credit 
 
 Success Stories Restaurant Franchise Operator $1,175,000 SBA loan 
 
 Success Stories Nursing Home Operator 
$3.8 Million USDA 20 Year Fully Amortized Loan
 
 
 Success Stories Window and Door Manufacturer 
 $10 Million USDA Term Loan–Stimulus Money Funding 

 

 
 
 Success Stories Five Loans for Nursing Homes in Missouri $14.4 million USDA loan
 
 
 Success Stories Auto Dealership 
 $1.95 million SBA 7aTerm Loan 
 
 
 Success Stories Special Event Lighting, Sound and Stage Company 
 $1.34 Million SBA Term Loan and SBA $50K Line of Credit 
 
 
 Success Stories LP Gas Distributor 
 $2,000,000 SBA 7(a) term loan
$850,000 conventional line of credit 

 
 
 Success Stories Fast Food Restaurant Operator 
 $1.17 Million SBA Term Loan 
 
 
 Success Stories Growers and Packers of Fresh Tangerines 
 $7.95 million USDA term loan (AARA Funding) 

 
 
 Success Stories Specialty Printing Company 
 $7,855,000 USDA Term Note 

 
 
 Success Stories Plastic Extruding Company 
 $5,000,000 USDA Term Note 

 
 
 Success Stories Metal Door and Frame Wholesale Provider 
 $1,694,000 million SBA 7a Loan 
 
 
 Success Stories Chicagoland Courier Company $770,000 SBA Term Loan
 
 
 Success Stories Cultural Arts Center $740,000 SBA 7(a) Term Note
 
 
 Success Stories Manufacturing Company $900,000 SBA 7(a) Mortgage&amp;Term Note
 
 
 Success Stories Fast Food Franchise $1.5 Million SBA 7(a) Loan
 
 © 2007 Ridgestone Bank Equal Housing Lender       member FDIC TAG Program     Expenditure Policy     Privacy 
TAG Program

Ridgestone Bank is participating in the FDIC’s Transaction Account Guarantee Program. Under that program, through December 31, 2009, all noninterest-bearing transaction accounts are fully guaranteed by the FDIC for the entire amount in the account. Coverage under the Transaction Account Guarantee Program is in addition to and separate from the coverage available under the FDIC’s general deposit insurance rules.
	</body>
</document>
