<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009270" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/23/778164/restaurant/Pittsburgh/Los-Chiludos-Mexican-Restaurant-and-Catering-Canonsburg" time="2012-07-13-02:39" support="39" score="0.11221685405688187" bingtitle="Los Chiludos Mexican Restaurant and Catering - Canonsburg | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Los Chiludos Mexican Restaurant and Catering - Canonsburg | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="001339" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000811" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000211" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="001129" bing-rank="202"/>
			<query id="001466" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000117" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000806" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000321" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000218" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000156" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000796" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000196" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="001473" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000180" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000201" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="000204" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000149" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000963" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="000798" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="001344" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001158" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000807" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000430" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="000214" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001025" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000341" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="001324" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001346" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000792" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000343" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001332" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000135" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001329" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="001277" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000813" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000329" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000336" bing-rank="45"/>
	<description>I had heard such great things about this place that my fiance and I just had to ... Perhaps the worst insult was the attempt to offer styrofoam cups for our wine.</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Pittsburgh » South » Canonsburg » Los Chiludos Mexican... 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Buffalo Cleveland Columbus Los Angeles New York Toronto Washington DC More... 
 
Los Chiludos Mexican Restaurant and Catering
 
(724) 745-6791
 Canonsburg 325 Southpointe Blvd Ste 300 
 Canonsburg , PA 15317 
 loschiludos.com 
 on facebook.com 
 See all 97 reviews Cuisine Mexican , Tacos Features Gluten-Free Friendly , Kid Friendly , Outdoor Dining , Vegan Friendly Menu $ Under $10 per entree Steak nachos, Beef Chimichanga, Shrimp Taco (special), Mango salsa&amp;homemade... View menu | Add menu photo 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch             Dinner         Late 
   634 people have voted 90 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 Sam&apos;s Pizza Shop 83% $$ Canonsburg - Pizza, Sandwiches/Subs, Salads 525 Adams Ave 
 
 Suzie B&apos;s 93% $ Canonsburg - Sandwiches/Subs, Breakfast/Brunch, Diner 950 S Central Ave 
 
Critic reviews

 August 26, 2010 City Paper ...even assimilated Mexican-American fare can be flavorful, exciting and well worth the long trip. More from City Paper 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews
 Bloggers, have you reviewed this restaurant? Add your review to this page. 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 May 6, 2012 Likes it Cinco De Mayo Buffet by Troy ( 359 reviews ) Yesterday we had the special Cinco De Mayo buffet for dinner, and it was REALLY good! All you can eat Mexican! Mmmmm, there was so much good food, and the carnitas were just melt-in-your-mouth awesome! Mucho Bueno . . . already looking forward to next year!!! 1 out of 1 found this review helpful +5 more review from Troy December 4, 2008 Former Azul chef opens restaurant From the Pittsburgh Tribune Review . . . http://www.pittsburghlive.com/x/pittsburghtrib/living/fooddrink/s_601299.html Chef Jose Lemus, formerly of Azul Bar-Y-Cantina in Edgewood, is operating his own restaurant. Los Chiludos Mexican Restaurant&amp;Catering, 800 First St., in Canonsburg showcases his authentic Mexican dishes. The chef hails from Mexico City. Los Chiludos is open 11 a.m. to 8 p.m. Mondays through Thursdays, 11 a.m. to 9 p.m. Fridays and Saturdays. Details: 724-745-6791 or www.loschiludos.com 1 out of 1 found this review helpful February 14, 2010 Maybe not five star dining, but still pretty good!! If you are looking for a fine dining experience, that is not what you will find at Los Chiludos. What you will find, is a&quot;Mom&amp;Pop&quot;type of Mexican fast food restaurant in a remodeled classic building that feels comfortable, not stuffy, similar to what you might find at a Chipotle or Qdoba, but with a bigger menu and more authentic choices. Yes, the food may be served on disposable plates, cups and silverware, but that has nothing to do with the flavor and quality. Admittedly... more» If you are looking for a fine dining experience, that is not what you will find at Los Chiludos. What you will find, is a&quot;Mom&amp;Pop&quot;type of Mexican fast food restaurant in a remodeled classic building that feels comfortable, not stuffy, similar to what you might find at a Chipotle or Qdoba, but with a bigger menu and more authentic choices. Yes, the food may be served on disposable plates, cups and silverware, but that has nothing to do with the flavor and quality. Admittedly, this isn&apos;t my most favorite place for Mexican food (I don&apos;t like eating with plastic silverware and drinking from Styrofoam cups either), but I will say that what I&apos;ve eaten here on the few occasions I&apos;ve visited, the food was good. By the way, if you want quality chips, salsa and guacamole, go ahead and buy them, you won&apos;t be disappointed. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful May 6, 2010 Went to the Cinco De Mayo Buffet yesterday. Lots of food, all you can eat (no ordering from the regular menu, just the buffet was offered on the 5th of May). There were Tacos (Hard&amp;Soft), Taquitos, Ribs, Chips and 3 kinds of Salsas, Rice, Beans, and even home-made watermelon juice. The only thing missing was guacamole. It was bueno!!! February 5, 2011 New Location . . . Went for dinner to the new location in Southpointe tonight (They are no longer located in Canonsburg). The new location is nice, maybe a little bit larger, and now they actually use real cups, silverware and plates instead of the disposables (which I prefer). I think the old location had maybe a little more charm to it, but this new place is fine. The food was pretty good, as usual. We had a carnitas burrito and the fish tacos. The only things that I was maybe a bit disappointed in was they... more» Went for dinner to the new location in Southpointe tonight (They are no longer located in Canonsburg). The new location is nice, maybe a little bit larger, and now they actually use real cups, silverware and plates instead of the disposables (which I prefer). I think the old location had maybe a little more charm to it, but this new place is fine. The food was pretty good, as usual. We had a carnitas burrito and the fish tacos. The only things that I was maybe a bit disappointed in was they were out of guacamole when we tried ordering chips and guac (ended up getting chips and mango salsa instead), and also, the fish taco had to be eaten with silverware, since the side of beans wasn&apos;t drained properly, and the bean juice made the taco shells mushy on the plate and they fell apart when I tried picking them up. But they still tasted good, just messy. As for the new hours, I guess the breakfast thing didn&apos;t work out for them, since they are discontinuing breakfast on Feb. 10th, but they are also going to start having dinner Wed. thru Saturday instead of just Fridays and Saturdays as they do now. New location, same good food + real plates&amp;silverware!! Bueno y Gracias!!! 2 out of 2 found this review helpful April 19, 2012 Taco Special + Corn on the Cob Yesterday I had their Wednesday special (They&apos;ve been posting the specials each day on their facebook page lately). It was, (3) taco special, chorizo or carnitas (I had the carnitas). Served with onion/cilantro, hot or mild salsa, guacamole and roasted corn on the cob sprinkled with cayenne pepper. The tacos were very good, and the corn was really good also! I wished I had brought my camera, so I could&apos;ve shared a photo with you, the plate presentation was awesome! 1 out of 2 found this review helpful June 1, 2012 Really likes it Good food, generous portions, low cost. Awesome! by Sheila ( 21 reviews ) It&apos;s a casual restaurant, similar in style to a pizza place. These days it&apos;s a challenge to have a nice meal out and not have a high bill. Not here though. The food is delicious but inexpensive. You can enjoy a meal and not feel guilty about the expense of eating out. The portions are so large we brought leftovers home. And it&apos;s byob. What&apos;s not to like? A new favorite. June 4, 2012 Really likes it Mobile review by Matt412 ( 7 reviews ) Great food! Fresh quality ingredients and the burritos are huge! You do have to pay for chips and salsa but I am ok with that because the salsa is great. May 26, 2012 Mobile review by Paul G ( 1 review ) The best authentic Mexican in Pittsburgh! The ingredients are fresh and the portions more than ample for the price. The guacamole is awesome. Currently a BYOB. June 13, 2012 Mobile review by Jackie ( 1 review ) I would rather keep this place a &apos;best kept secret&apos; but they deserve the accolade! Everything you look for in Mexican food but rarely find...great unique fresh flavor. This iisn&apos;t your average refried bean cheese smothered soggy mess. Los Chiludos pays attention to individual flavor and allows the protein to be the star. Beans cheese and toppings are great accents thtat dont over power rather enhance and take the dish to the next level. ...did i mention it&apos;s delicious! Great food for very fair price. May 13, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Mixed Feelings by mtamesg ( 1 review ) Beef Chimichanga -
I am from Mexico City and the food at Los Chiludos did not taste like the real food in Mexico :( I respect everyone&apos;s preferences and I enyoed my dinner but real GOOD mexican food is much better. I am not saying that this place is bad but is not 100% authentic. March 13, 2012 Eh. by Star Destroyer ( 19 reviews ) I had heard such great things about this place that my fiance and I just had to try it. I don&apos;t want to vote&quot;likes it&quot;or&quot;doesn&apos;t like it,&quot;because those aren&apos;t really fair assessments. It&apos;s more like&quot;eh.&quot; First, the girl working at the counter knew nothing about the food. I don&apos;t know if she was new or what, but it was definitely off-putting. We ordered the spinach enchiladas, chips and mango salsa (they didn&apos;t have regular/pico,) and a couple of bottles of Jarritos (Mexican soda.) We had to wait around at the counter to ask for a bottle opener while the girl did some other things and seemed uninterested in why we were standing there. The spinach enchiladas were really bland and tasted mostly like someone stuffed them full of plain frozen chopped spinach. I got the green sauce and my fiance got the red, and while I preferred the green, it was definitely underwhelming. Same with the rice and beans that accompanied them. We were also confused about... more» I had heard such great things about this place that my fiance and I just had to try it. I don&apos;t want to vote&quot;likes it&quot;or&quot;doesn&apos;t like it,&quot;because those aren&apos;t really fair assessments. It&apos;s more like&quot;eh.&quot; First, the girl working at the counter knew nothing about the food. I don&apos;t know if she was new or what, but it was definitely off-putting. We ordered the spinach enchiladas, chips and mango salsa (they didn&apos;t have regular/pico,) and a couple of bottles of Jarritos (Mexican soda.) We had to wait around at the counter to ask for a bottle opener while the girl did some other things and seemed uninterested in why we were standing there. The spinach enchiladas were really bland and tasted mostly like someone stuffed them full of plain frozen chopped spinach. I got the green sauce and my fiance got the red, and while I preferred the green, it was definitely underwhelming. Same with the rice and beans that accompanied them. We were also confused about what to do with our plates when we finished eating. A sign or directions from the staff would have been helpful. The chips and salsa, however, were out of this world! Seriously, the chips were fresh and perfectly crispy, and I had no idea how much I could love mango salsa. The portion size was huge, too. Since this place is a bit off the beaten path, I doubt we&apos;ll return to give it another try. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful May 4, 2012 Really likes it Mobile review by Happy_Chanti ( 5 reviews ) I have worked at Los Chiludos for 3 years now. The owners Jose and Tera are amazing people. Serving fresh foods is always important to them and I have never worked anywhere where the chefs are so particular on freshness and presentation. It makes me proud to be a part of their team. As far as the food, since I started working there I have never craved anything but Los Chiludos so it&apos;s great to be rewarded with my favorite food everyday after a hard day of work. Our customers are amazing. I love working somewhere where everyday you see regulars and it&apos;s exciting when new customers come in to tell them about the food and know that 9 times out of 10 they will love it! If you haven&apos;t been here and love Mexican food come see us and I&apos;m sure you&apos;ll leave here satisfied! I really love working somewhere that I can be confident in the food quality and staff and know that you will like the experience there. Hope to see you soon. Chantelle January 22, 2012 Likes it Some Great Mexican by Effort ( 205 reviews ) High quality Mexican. Order at the counter and receive a number so food can be served to your table. Went on Sat. night and it was crowded and that made it rather noisy since all hard surfaces. Also, had to wait for a table but only a few minutes. Had the carnitas tacos. Some of the best tacos in the Burg. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful September 9, 2011 Likes it Holy Guacamole! by MARK ( 278 reviews ) WARNING: Los Chiludos is NOT a pre-packaged, cookie cutter, straight out of the box Mexican restaurant. From the chips and guac to the enchilada&apos;s and tacos, this is the real deal. I&apos;ll even bet the ranch that, unlike the majority of Mexican spots in and around the city, Los Chiludas has actual prep cooks..... Portions are large, quality is high, surroundings are typical strip mall, however the staff is pleasant, helpful and efficient. If you truly desire good Mexican food then you must go to Los Chiludas. Just remember to BYOB! 3 out of 4 found this review helpful February 13, 2012 Likes it In a League of it&apos;s own by thesuccessor13 ( 1 review ) Hey guys, sorry for my lack of credibility on here...I never really write reviews, I just read ones from others while picking restaurants. I&apos;ve seen some poor comments on here lately, and I must defend this place. Anyways: This IS, by far, one of my favorite restaurants. I&apos;ve been going to this place for a while now, ever since they were located over at First Street in Canonsburg. This place, as I like to call it, is where miracles happen...because the infamous 20 year old hunger that I always have, simply goes away, and stays that way. The quality of the food is a solid 10/10, and as my waiter said,&quot;Everything is prepared fresh daily.&quot;I&apos;ve been there quite a few times (more than 10), and this place is always filled with grade A food that never fails to meet my standards. Further along, the waitresses are extremely helpful, and one of the guy waiters there knows everything from A-Z about Los Chiludos. The owners did not miss one detail when envisioning the... more» Hey guys, sorry for my lack of credibility on here...I never really write reviews, I just read ones from others while picking restaurants. I&apos;ve seen some poor comments on here lately, and I must defend this place. Anyways: This IS, by far, one of my favorite restaurants. I&apos;ve been going to this place for a while now, ever since they were located over at First Street in Canonsburg. This place, as I like to call it, is where miracles happen...because the infamous 20 year old hunger that I always have, simply goes away, and stays that way. The quality of the food is a solid 10/10, and as my waiter said,&quot;Everything is prepared fresh daily.&quot;I&apos;ve been there quite a few times (more than 10), and this place is always filled with grade A food that never fails to meet my standards. Further along, the waitresses are extremely helpful, and one of the guy waiters there knows everything from A-Z about Los Chiludos. The owners did not miss one detail when envisioning the restaurant...the aura of true 100% authentic Mexican resonates from wall to wall: from the handmade portraits, to the music selection and even the staff themselves! Everytime I go, I always see the same Latino cooks, no matter what time of day...and they always produce the best stuff, no matter if it&apos;s 11AM or 6PM. GOD BLESS THEM! As for the negative responses, I really don&apos;t know what you guys are trying to get at...I&apos;m sure that 500+ other people can agree with me. There&apos;s a comment below about an urbanspoon member being disgusted because the food is too big, and because it&apos;s sorta messy. C&apos;mon, now...that&apos;s what North American food is all about. Maybe he should order off the kid&apos;s menu next time...Actually I guess he should look at the menu first, being that it seems like he was surprised when he got his food. Also, don&apos;t really have a problem with self-serve...anyone with eyes can see the silverware and napkins on the back counter, in plain sight. It&apos;s also like 5 steps away from your table.... All-in-all...If I moved away from this area, It would be a very, very sad day because there would be no more Los Chiludos. Will recommend this place, as always! Keep it up guys! Always #1! 2 out of 2 found this review helpful May 30, 2009 Really likes it Awesome! by Brad Kita ( 3 reviews ) Los Chiludos is a nice, small Mexican restaurant in Canonsburg, PA with a great atmosphere, outstanding staff and best of all, amazing food. Knowing full well it is hard to find good, authentic Mexican food in the Pittsburgh area, Los Chiludos is an oasis in a desert. The food is always fresh and always prepared for you, in front of you. The portions are always large and the prices very reasonable. Unless you get the burrito, which is the largest burrito I&apos;ve personally seen before and it is still only $8. The lunch menu looks even better with a handful of specials (including a&quot;make-your-own&quot;style combo), each for under $7. If it is your first time going to Los Chiludos, make sure you have plenty of room, as the meal will fill you up. One dish that everyone should try at Los Chiludos is the carnitas, whether it be in the carnitas platter or in a burrito. The carnitas is phenomenal, a very juicy, extremely well seasoned beef that is cooked for hours and simply falls... more» Los Chiludos is a nice, small Mexican restaurant in Canonsburg, PA with a great atmosphere, outstanding staff and best of all, amazing food. Knowing full well it is hard to find good, authentic Mexican food in the Pittsburgh area, Los Chiludos is an oasis in a desert. The food is always fresh and always prepared for you, in front of you. The portions are always large and the prices very reasonable. Unless you get the burrito, which is the largest burrito I&apos;ve personally seen before and it is still only $8. The lunch menu looks even better with a handful of specials (including a&quot;make-your-own&quot;style combo), each for under $7. If it is your first time going to Los Chiludos, make sure you have plenty of room, as the meal will fill you up. One dish that everyone should try at Los Chiludos is the carnitas, whether it be in the carnitas platter or in a burrito. The carnitas is phenomenal, a very juicy, extremely well seasoned beef that is cooked for hours and simply falls apart in your mouth. I&apos;ve quickly become a regular at Los Chiludos and I tend to stop by on Saturdays and sometimes during the week for lunch. I highly recommend this restaurant to anyone looking for great Mexican food. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful January 7, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by yum ( 36 reviews ) Bummed that they charge for chips and salsa +1 more review from yum December 31, 2011 Mobile review Ok..more hyper than necessary. Old Mexico in Washington trumps chilidos. October 29, 2010 2nd review a little better than the first by shmelvin ( 182 reviews ) I stand by my first review and do not like the physical restaurant, but they are moving to South Pointe in January so that should be an improvement even though 2 restaurants have already failed there. Now to the food, obviously most of the reviewers have never been to Mexico and those that have must have eaten at Senior Frogs or Jose and Tony&apos;s? This is not authentic Mexican food it is not bad for what it is, Amerixican just like all the others, are some of you equating quantity with authenticity? I had the fish tacos, and I liked them..But they were made with Cod (native to Iceland) not the traditional dolphin or grouper, plus they were 4 times the size of a traditional Mexican Taco. Any Taquaria sells a two biter for around 40 cents, easy to handle not these messy monstrosities. The fajitas (which aren&apos;t really Mexican at all) were run of the mill as was the salsa and chips. The best thing was the hot sauce. I voiced my opinion to one of the staff and she agreed they are not very authentic, apparently the owner would like to try serve the real thing but is afraid that the locals will not like it. Too bad as I do think there is potential. 4 out of 7 found this review helpful +1 more review from shmelvin February 13, 2010 When you can&apos;t afford a Taco Bell franchise I finally caved in and decided to give this joint a try, especially after all the positive reviews. I initially did not want to come here when I saw on the menu that they charge $4.50 for chips and salsa, that&apos;s pretty chicken s#*t but never the less off we went. This restaurant is what I picture you would open when you can&apos;t afford a Taco Bell franchise. It&apos;s in an old gas station? or something similar, and be warned this is basically a fast food restaurant, you have to order at the counter... more» I finally caved in and decided to give this joint a try, especially after all the positive reviews. I initially did not want to come here when I saw on the menu that they charge $4.50 for chips and salsa, that&apos;s pretty chicken s#*t but never the less off we went. This restaurant is what I picture you would open when you can&apos;t afford a Taco Bell franchise. It&apos;s in an old gas station? or something similar, and be warned this is basically a fast food restaurant, you have to order at the counter and sit in a very uncomfortable area with a mix of high tops and regular tables that probably came from good will. The second thing that caught my attention was the lack of anybody that seemed remotely Mexican, the staff looked like a bunch of college kids. Now the other attraction was BYOB, unfortunately it was also BYOG (Bring your own Glass) and as we had two bottles of wine and with the only available vessels being Styrofoam cups, you guessed it…we left, so I can&apos;t comment on the food, but I won&apos;t be back as it just isn&apos;t our scene. I&apos;m sure it&apos;s probably good eats for those on a budget and I wish them luck, so be warned this is basically fast food in the back end of Canonsburg. Bon Appetit ! 2 out of 5 found this review helpful March 5, 2010 Really likes it Taqueria Autentica by Greg Kita ( 13 reviews ) I love this place. I lived in some Mexican communities for a couple of years in the Northwest, spoke Spanish every day and ate dinner with Mexican families every night. One thing that I missed when I moved back to the Pittsburgh area is the lack of anything remotely close to Mexican cuisine... Then I was introduced to Los Chiludos. Los Chiludos offers food so authentic that I almost expected to see an abuelita in the kitchen. Everything on the menu is great at affordable prices. If you are looking for real Mexican food, taqueria style, I definitely recommend Los Chiludos. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful February 13, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it A BYOB wanna-be by Luca Loo ( 30 reviews ) This restaurant sounded appealing for several reasons--we love BYOBs, it&apos;s relatively close to us, and the Urban Spoon reviews were great. Well, this was one occasion when the reality wasn&apos;t nearly as good as anticipated. First of all, the atmosphere is nil--it&apos;s essentially a counter-service restaurant with college-age kids working in the kitchen (not sure where the&quot;authentic&quot;Mexican food comes into play). Perhaps the worst insult was the attempt to offer styrofoam cups for our wine. Are you kidding? Needless to say, we didn&apos;t stick around. 2 out of 4 found this review helpful November 29, 2010 Likes it Wet burrito with carnitas. by Ashley ( 15 reviews ) Wet burrito with carnitas. -
Highly recommend. 2 out of 3 found this review helpful September 15, 2010 Likes it Killer Mexican Food by PES ( 12 reviews ) Having lived outside of Charlotte, NC for years and tasting some great authentic Mexican food, I can say without a doubt this is the best in the Pittsburgh area. The tortilla soup is extraordinary, and the chicken quesadilla blew me away. Love this food. 2 out of 3 found this review helpful January 27, 2011 Likes it Catering by Lindsey ( 23 reviews ) I ordered catering for a Mexican themed party and the food was very good. They did free delivery bc I ordered over a certain amount. The appetizer platter came with a ton of sides like salsa and sour cream and guacamole. We had salsa for days! Ask for Tera, she is one of the owners and the easist to work with as she speaks english. January 22, 2011 Really likes it New location - Same Great Food! by SweetThing ( 48 reviews ) We visited the new Southpointe location today for Los Chiludos, and it was just as delicious as we remembered. The new place has about twice the seating as the old Canonsburg location and much more space for food preparation. The set-up is still the same - come to the counter to order your meal and one of their friendly servers will bring it to your table when it is ready. I had the special today - tuna tacos..yum! And my husband got his usual, the excellent pork burrito with salsa verde. The tuna tacos were light and full of flavor with a side of rice and beans. The pork in the burrito is finely shredded and wonderfully seasoned. The hours are different at this new location - breakfast and lunch Mon-Thurs and lunch and dinner Fri-Sat. Now we have an excuse to get there for breakfast too! +1 more review from SweetThing July 24, 2009 Lunching at Los Chiludos Just got back from lunch at Los Chiludos...luckily we got there about 11:45 and beat the noon-time crunch of business people - the place was packed! I had the lunch special mini-chimichanga with shredded chicken and red sauce. It came with sides of pinto beans and rice. My hubby had the lunch platter special and chose a chicken taco that came with pinto beans and rice and a cup of tortilla soup. My chimichanga was great - the chicken was moist, finely shredded with a smoky flavor. The red... more» Just got back from lunch at Los Chiludos...luckily we got there about 11:45 and beat the noon-time crunch of business people - the place was packed! I had the lunch special mini-chimichanga with shredded chicken and red sauce. It came with sides of pinto beans and rice. My hubby had the lunch platter special and chose a chicken taco that came with pinto beans and rice and a cup of tortilla soup. My chimichanga was great - the chicken was moist, finely shredded with a smoky flavor. The red sauce covering it was outstanding. My hubby said the tortilla soup was good, but he was expecting something spicier with tomatoes. He liked his chicken taco, which had the same flavorful chicken used in my dish. We had mango soda from the case to drink. This is a great little place, and I do mean little. Try to get there during off hours so you can grab a table and enjoy your meal. They also were handling alot of take-out orders when we were there. A great local find - we will go back! 
 Show 68 more 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by Gigi Steak nachos... by Kurt Kharouf Enchiladas 
 All 21 photos View larger map Driving directions People reached this page by searching for: 
 los chiludos los chiludos southpointe mexican restaurant southpointe pa los chiludos calgary mexican restaurant canonsburg pa 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
