<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009448" url="http://www.complaintsboard.com/bysubcategory/fast-food-restaurants/?page=2" time="2012-07-13-02:48" support="22" score="0.05491454536063779" bingtitle="Complaints Board - Consumer Complaints, Reviews, Information ..." webtitle="Complaints Board - Consumer Complaints, Reviews, Information | Fast Food Restaurants, Page 2">
			<query id="000226" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000069" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000632" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000068" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000442" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000411" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000692" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000631" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000082" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000412" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000163" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000695" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000258" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000093" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="000975" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000006" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000944" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="000073" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000409" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000349" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="000977" bing-rank="184"/>
	<description>every time i go in this store my order is wrong either i dont get my biscuits my drink is wrong it is ... guess you didn&apos;t!Most of you who come into the fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		The most trusted and popular consumer complaints website 
 
 Everything 
 Everything Complaints Articles News&amp;Stories Recalls Videos Groups Questions 
 Home News&amp;Stories Tips&amp;Tricks Questions Videos Photos Recalls Groups Submit Complaint Connect With: Login Register 
 
 
 
Recently Discussed Complaints
 1. (0 mins ago) 
 Beatrice Marot, so called Psychic Reader 
She Has Stalked&amp;Bullied Me For Two Years! 2. (3 mins ago) 
 Mayan Palace 
Fraud 3. (6 mins ago) 
 StyleZalando.com 
No delivery 4. (13 mins ago) 
 Canadian Pharmacy 
3 e mails a day 5. (19 mins ago) 
 My3Cents.com 
Mistreatment of Members 


Consumer Tips&amp;Tricks
 
 
 
    5 Good Ways to Identify Good Quality 
 
 
 
    Choosing the Water Bottle that&apos;s Right for You 
 
 
 
    What You Need to Know About Prosper.com 
 

 
Latest News&amp;Stories
 
    French Total wins gas drilling tender 
 
    Deceptive Marketing For Prepaid Calling Cards Targeting Immigrants 
 
    Who&apos;s Paying For What? Washington Takes Aim at Secret Political Money 
 


Latest Questions
 transcript sueing cr england not getting my welfare check from govement Neotel SA NO RESPONSE MY MISSING MOBILE PHONE E-MAIL 

 
 
 
Fast Food Restaurants Complaints
 Sort by: Date | Popularity 
 
 Dunkin Donuts 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-20 by    Juliamay 
 
 
 Mean cashier 
 Complaint Rating: Well this morning I came n wanted to buy 2 little donuts, n the cashier told me, u can&apos;t buy two little donuts n the manager came n said there is no key in the register, that was a lie, there is a key to ring a customers like that, why put little ones if u cannot sale individual, u can&apos;t... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 McDonalds 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-18 by    aliciafisk 
 
 
 customer service 
 Complaint Rating: I went to my local mcdonalds drive thu on the 14th of may 2012 I had my two young children with me Iwas due to start work in approx 1hr so I chose the drivethru for convenience, i ordered myself and my children some food i proceded to the payment booth i handed a young man my credit card then... Comments Australian Ext. Territory Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Burger King 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-18 by    Debbie7 
 
 
 COLD temp in BK 
 Complaint Rating: I live in Illinois and the weather has just turned nice and warm--again. Today we had a nice warm day, 81*F. When my friend and I stopped at the BK in Ottawa, IL, for lunch it was freezing inside. I know that not everyone gets cold like I do but even my friend was complaining about the cold... Comments United States , Illinois Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Subway Cocoa Beach&amp;Subway Cape Canaveral 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-17 by    PissedOff3 
 
 
 Dirty, Rude and Insulting 
 Complaint Rating: I went to cocoa beach subway (it is a subway/dairy queen) near state road 520 in Cocoa Beach on north Atlantic avenue. When I walked in my opinion it needed to be cleaner (in my opinion it was a roach motel). I grudgingly ordered a sandwich and had special conditions that they would not adhere... Comments United States , Florida , Cocoa Beach&amp;Cape Canaveral Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 McDonalds 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-16 by    Gefolde 
 
 
 McDonalds employees pulls prank on single mom 
 Complaint Rating: Tonight, after a 13 hour day at work, I stopped by this McDonalds to bring my kids home dinner. I ordered 4 hamburgers and a mcflurry. When my kids opened their hamburgers, there was a single slice of tomato and a pickle. No hamburger, no condiments, nothing but a single slice of tomato and... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Mcdonald’s 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-15 by    Mioduke 
 
 
 Laziness from McDonald’s rude employees 
 Complaint Rating: On Sunday, January 8th, 2012, I went into Radioshack in Houston, Texas, across from Mcdonalds to purchase DVD-r disc but I had questions. When I walked in, I saw 3 employees standing around in conversation and another in normal clothes sitting on the counter. When I asked for assistance, one... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Mcdonald’s 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-13 by    Armeolu 
 
 
 McDonald’s water tasted bad with chlorine 
 Complaint Rating: MCDONALDS HEAD OFFICE: It was a fine day when my girlfriend and I decided to have breakfast in a nearest McDonald’s Branch. We ordered the usual breakfast meal and eat while having conversation. It was my first time to eat in that particular McDonald’s branch. After having meal there... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Burger King 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-10 by    Noumane 
 
 
 Rude Burger King employee at work 
 Complaint Rating: Today, Sunday at 11:30 AM I pulled into the Burger King Blaine Minnesota just S. Of Main St. just E. Of Central Ave. Being handicapped I wanted to park near the door. There was only one slot available In the line of parking slots near the door. That sloth was partially blocked by your car license... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Burger King 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-10 by    Naxie 
 
 
 I was shocked and saddened to receive what Burger King is now calling their mushroom and swiss 
 Complaint Rating: I was so excited to see the mushroom and swiss burger back on the Burger King menu after so long. It has always been my favorite and no other fast food version can touch it. So I was shocked and saddened to receive what Burger King is now calling their mushroom and swiss…2 regular size... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Mcdonald’s 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-10 by    Naive 
 
 
 McDonald’s won&apos;t get a penny from us in the future 
 Complaint Rating: At this point in time, I will for the last time give detailed information to the numerous complaints I have with A SPECIFIC LOCATION. (Lakeside, California, along Hwy 8 EAST, off Los Coches Exit). The franchise nor the Corporate Co. will ever help or remedy. Given numerous chances, having numerous... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 KFC 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-09 by    Namille 
 
 
 Wrong order and waiting at KFC 
 Complaint Rating: Last night (01/11/2011) at approximately 21:00 i went to KFC (Twist&amp;Koch JHB CBD) to buy a street wise 2, Simple right? wrong. Not only was i told i had to wait 8 minutes for my order (because the meat was still cooking), i was not given a receipt when i asked for the receipt i was told i... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Taco Bell 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-09 by    Bdon2933 
 
 
 Bad Service, Worse Management 
 Complaint Rating: On March 16, 2012 at 12:16pm I visited the drive-thru of Taco Bell store# 017984, my order number was: 317560, I spent $14.04.
I ordered my food and drove off only to realize 10 minutes later that I hadn’t gotten half of my order. As I was scheduled for a business meeting I couldn’t... Comments United States , California , Temecula Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Jimmy Jones 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-09 by    Jimmy Jones Bad experience 
 
 
 Horrible experience 
 Complaint Rating: Just want to bring my horrible experience at JJ Grant Street. Since I was getting late for my meeting, I thought let&apos;s go place where I can get something quickly and thought of going to JJ, but I didn&apos;t know instead of my Tuna Club Order, they will hand me another sandwich ( i think... Comments United States , Pennsylvania , Pittsburgh Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Mcdonald’s 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-06 by    Daisukke 
 
 
 Don&apos;t care about the quality of their customer service 
 Complaint Rating: I’m not sure who keeps an eye on the McDonald’s staff but this has been going on for years at the Fremont, Ohio Rt. 53 McDonald’s. The management there has been getting its employees from mainly family members making it impossible for more qualified people to get a job and... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Burger King 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-06 by    Nebrake 
 
 
 Breakfast service and food is the worst in the area 
 Complaint Rating: I just went to Burger King and waited at the drive thru speaker for about 15 minutes behind two cars, who were also waiting. There was one car sitting at the actual window waiting on food. I was looking for a way to exit when the cars started to move forward. I reached the ordering speaker,... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Dunkin Donut 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-05 by    Jordan45 
 
 
 employee cursed the customer 
 Complaint Rating: i was ordering 2 donuts and the guy cannot hear me so i said&quot;I WANT 2 DONUTS&quot;on a loud voice, then he told me to come to the front window when i pulled up i heard the guy cursed at me, my wife heard it too... so i went inside the store and asked for the manager, he said the manager... Comments United States , Illinois , Chicago Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Burger King 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-04 by    flylowguy 
 
 
 bathroom monitoring 
 Complaint Rating: This outfit puts a small nearly unreadable sign on the bathroom doors that tells people they have to show a receipt before using. Then if you don&apos;t have a receipt and try to find someone to show it to, a guy comes out of a door in the hall nearby and rousts you.
Complaint: I am... Comments United States , Arizona , Nogales Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 kfc feltham london 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-01 by    akram islam 
 
 
 manager not serving when he is near the till. 
 Complaint Rating: Dear Sir or Madam,

With reference to the above, this is to inform you that I am a regular customer of kfc feltham london, and whenever the manager is near the tills he never serves me, but keeps on screaming the cashiers names to come and serve me, and the poor cashiers has to... Comments United Kingdom , England|Greater London , feltham Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Burger King 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-01 by    Libanore 
 
 
 Bad food and customer relations 
 Complaint Rating: I go to burger king quite often, because you serve lunch during breakfast. i was at the burger king on robbins road grand haven mi. and i ordered a chicken tender crisp meal. (7.00 almost) the chicken patty was so greasy that when i bit into it grease was running down my chin. i brought the... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 New Burger 
 
 Posted: 2012-05-01 by    Nevaloke 
 
 
 I hate the new Burger King fries 
 Complaint Rating: I used to LOVE burger king BECAUSE of their fries…. and now they’ve changed them and i hate them! they’re disgusting!! bring back the old ones or i won’t come back!!! On Friday, November 4th at 11:25 am I went thru the drive thru of Burger King, located on Middle Country... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 Previous 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 ... 120 Next 
 
    Submit complaint 
Videos
 Credit Report Ripoff? 
 More Videos 

   
 

 
Latest Groups
 Stop underarm sweating MAKING AND SAVING MONEY Diamonds International Fraud seogo Paul J. Hooten&amp;Associates, Debt Co... 

 
Today&apos;s Mess-Up Photo
 Out Of Drama 
 
 More Mess-ups 

 
 
 
   
 Submit Complaint | Consumer Tips&amp;Tricks | News&amp;Stories | Recalls | Groups | View full list of Companies | Updated Complaints | Complaints | Suspicious Companies | Complaints by Countries | Latest Complaints | Terms of Use | Privacy Policy | DMCA Procedures | Investors / Business Offers | Legal Information | Thank you Emails 

©2012 Consumer Complaints Board 
If you have any constructive thoughts, creative ideas, or reasonable offers, please, contact us immediately via E-mail 
 
 
         
 
Login
 
 Email: Password: 
 
 
 Forgot your password?
	</body>
</document>
