<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009722" url="http://www-cs.canisius.edu/~salley/reviews.html" time="2012-07-13-03:06" support="17" score="0.027799341788687926" bingtitle="David&apos;s Restaurant, Winery and Bar Reviews" webtitle="David&apos;s Restaurant, Winery and Bar Reviews">
			<query id="000640" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000286" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="000002" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000627" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="000284" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="001072" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000789" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000695" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="001069" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000784" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000132" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="001289" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000786" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="001067" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="001009" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000806" bing-rank="249"/>
	<description>So, it would be highly unusual for a fast-food restaurant to get ... half-greenhouse, which is probably the best seat ... You pick your starch (lo mein, brown rice or white ...</description>
	<body>
		Bar Reviews
 
Winery Reviews
 
Restaurant Reviews
 41 West Bar and Grill 
 Alaimo&apos;s 
 BJ&apos;s 
 The Caboose 
 Club 35 
 Coughlan&apos;s Pub 
 Coyle&apos;s Pub 
 Down Wind Cafe 
 Ellicottville Brewing Company 
 Heenan&apos;s 
 Lil Magill&apos;s 
 Muldoon&apos;s Irish Pub 
 Old Main 
 Sunny&apos;s 
 Valentine&apos;s 
 Johnson Estate Winery 
 Noble Winery 
 Schloss Doepkin Winery 
 Seven Vines Winery 
 Twenty-One Brix Winery 
 Vetter Vineyards Winery 
 21 East Cafe 
 Aldo&apos;s 
 American Legion Post 
 Aunt Millie&apos;s Family Restaurant and Bakery 
 El Azteca 
 The Brick Room 
 Central Station 
 China King 
 DeJohn&apos;s Italian Restaurant 
 Demetri&apos;s on the Lake 
 Ellicottville Brewing Company 
 East Side Grill 
 Four Seasons 
 Gobbler&apos;s Knob 
 The Golden Griddle 
 The Green Arch 
 Intermezzo Coffee House 
 Lena&apos;s Pizza 
 Liberty Cafe 
 Locovore (Nature&apos;s Network) 
 Mary&apos;s Deli 
 Mongolian Buffet 
 Nomad&apos;s Place 
 Rocco&apos;s 
 Sheridan Diner 
 The Sugar Shack 
 The Sunset Bay Restaurant 
 Tom&apos;s Family Restaurant 
 The Upper Crust 
 The Vineyard 
 The White Horse Inn 
 The White Inn 
 Wing City Grille 
 Zebro&apos;s Harbor House 
 
 
Bar Reviews
 
When I worked at Time Warner, I swore that if I ever got a better job that was 
local, I was going to celebrate by having a drink in every bar in Fredonia. 
I did my bar run on 10/15-16/2010.
 Sunny&apos;s -- 43 Water Street -- permanently closed
Sign on the door says they sold alcohol to minors.
 The Caboose -- 64 West Main Street -- permanently closed
For sale sign on wall. I don&apos;t think I&apos;ve ever seen this place open.
I know people who inspected it with a thought to buying it, said it would
take several thousand to get it up to code.
 Valentine&apos;s (formerly Coyle&apos;s Pub) -- 12 Water Street -- 10/15/2010 8:15PM
$2.50 for a Killian&apos;s draft. The beer was tepid, not cold.
The band was still setting up, live music at 10PM
Drink specials on a huge blackboard, I apparently missed Happy Hour by half 
an hour but there was only one other customer in the place.
Very plain decor, beer signs on the walls, a huge fish tank on the 
bartender&apos;s island. No kitchen!
 Old Main -- 24 Water Street -- 10/15/2010 8:45PM
$3 for a Labatt&apos;s Blue Light, it was cold.
The brick walls and black ceiling provided a suitable background to the random
Halloween decorations. Crowded with college kids. 3 TVs.
The pool table sat unused, but the beer pong table was in full use with a 
line waiting. Dress code for coeds seemed to be tight dresses. 
Jukebox playing. No kitchen!
 Muldoon&apos;s Irish Pub (formerly Alaimo&apos;s) -- 26 Water Street -- 10/15/2010 9:10PM
$2.50 for Killian&apos;s on draft. Five customers in the bar.
Permanent Irish decorations on the bar with halloween decorations over them.
A collection of assorted frogs surrounds the Budweiser sign.
One wall is covered in firefighter patches, another wall is covered in 
customer photos. DJ booth in back currently empty. 2 TVs and a beer pong 
table. No kitchen!
A &apos;second&apos; bar, The Hairy Lemon is upstairs, you have to go through 
Muldoon&apos;s to get to it. I have not seen it open for business.
 Lil Magill&apos;s -- 13 Water Street -- 10/15/2010 9:50PM
5 TVs, an electronic dartboard.
The place is so packed with college students, there&apos;s no room to sit down.
I left without ordering a drink.
 Heenan&apos;s -- 19 East Main Street -- 10/15/2010 10:15PM
No sign on the outside until April 2011.
Not a college hangout, an older crowd.
2 dartboards, a popcorn machine but no bowls available.
3 TVs in bar area, side room has additional TVs
Pool table. Bar decorations mostly license plates and bumper stickers
No kitchen!
 41 West Bar and Grill -- 41 West Main -- 10/16/2010 8:30PM
$2.50 for Killian&apos;s draft, served in a plastic glass!
12 TVs, band still setting up, a few token Halloween decorations here and 
there. No sign of a food menu, but the flash sign is advertising wings and 
fingers, $0.40 each and Friday fish fry. Kitchen open 4:30-8:30PM.
one electric dartboard behind the band stage
Walls decorated with sports memorbilia, mostly Bills, Sabres, and local high 
schools.
One table is painted to look like a basketball court, another painted for 
beer pong games.
 Coughlan&apos;s Pub -- 47 West Main -- 10/16/2010 8:45PM
$2 Killians served in a Killian&apos;s glass!
5TVs, one electronic dartboard, popcorn machine, but the popcorn is heavily 
salted
Wall decorations are photos of bar patrons and sports memorbilia.
One token Irish flag. No stage for a band, no kitchen!
 BJ&apos;s -- 51 West Main Street -- 10/16/2010 9PM
Place is so packed with college students there was nowhere to sit.
I left without ordering a drink
 Ellicottville Brewing Company -- 34 West Main -- 10/16/2010 9:15PM www.ellicottvillebrewing.com 
$2 for an Amber Bock, they brew their own, 15 kinds of draft beer.
4 TVs, no band stage, but their webpage says they have bands come in.
For $20 you can get a Pub Card which is good for a year and entitles you to 
discounts on food and drinks. It was a peaceful bar with quiet music playing
until the college bar hoppers caught up with me. They were wearing
pub crawl t-shirts that they were trying to get autographed in every bar.
 Club 35 -- 35 Water Street -- 10/19/2010 10PM
There&apos;s actually a story behind this. A bar was closed down for selling 
alcohol to minors. A DJ from another bar asked town officials if there 
would be any problem getting a liquor license if he bought the bar. He 
had no previous connection to it. He was told no problem. He bought the bar.
The town officials denied him a liquor license because there were already 
too many bars in Fredonia. Stuck with a mortgage payment and no income, 
he came up with what I thought was a brilliant solution. He boarded over 
all the windows and then opened up Club 35, a non-alcoholic soda and juice 
bar... with nude dancers! When the outraged town officials checked the law, 
they found the same thing he did. Strip clubs and nude bars have to follow 
very narrow regulations or face the loss of their liquor license! He even 
told the newspapers that if he got a liquor license, the girls would be 
packing their bags that evening. After two years of wrestling with the town 
officials, he bought a bar in Dunkirk and sold Club 35... to the girls 
themselves. The bar is owned by the dancers who work there.
I paid a $10 cover charge and $3 for a Sierra Mist, which made this my most 
expensive stop of the night. When I got there at 10PM, no one was dancing 
yet. They started later. The place looks like an old disco, with a DJ booth 
and a stage with two poles. There was a pool table in the corner. And 
bedrooms in back. Yes, bedrooms. Signs advertised a &apos;couch dance&apos; for $22 
and &apos;bed dance&apos; for $49. I thought the prices were rather odd-ball, why not 
just $25 and $50?


My life got busy with one thing and another. However to celebrate my birthday,
I decided to hit the two bars I missed on my original bar run.
 Lil Magill&apos;s -- 13 Water Street -- 4/2/2011 10:30PM
$2 Labatt&apos;s draft. 5 TVs, electronic dartboard,
blasting music, not nearly as crowded as the last time
Male to Female ratio, about 60:40, most of the women wearing tight skirts 
and playing darts
 BJ&apos;s (formerly Down Wind Cafe) -- 51 West Main Street -- 4/2/2011 10:45PM
$2.50 for Labatt&apos;s Blue bottle 
1 TV, 2 electronic dartboards, 1 foosball table
decor is mostly unframed paintings, benches run the length of the side wall
assorted paraphenalia hangs from the ceiling
The bar top is sticky, I don&apos;t think they ever wipe it down.
Food service in back 
Restaurant Reviews
 
A brief word of explanation. My wife&apos;s thesis advisor was Dr. William 
Rappaport. Nearly 20 years ago, he created a small handout of places to eat 
around the University of Buffalo campus for an Association for Computational 
Linguistics conference held at UB in 1988. It now has its own website 
( http://www.cse.buffalo.edu/restaurant.guide ), includes restaurants 
throughout Western New York and is cross-referenced by cuisine, location, 
rating and reviewer. Needless to say, Chautauqua County is not well 
represented. I&apos;ve decided to correct the matter by creating my own restaurant 
review website for Chautauqua County.
A word about my rating system: 1.) It&apos;s subjective, YMMV. How could it be 
anything else? 2.) My ratings are based on expectations for the type of 
restaurant that it is. A &apos;3&apos; is dead average, exactly what I expected when 
I walked in the door. So, if I give a &apos;4&apos; to a sandwich shop and a &apos;3&apos; to a 
romantic restaurant, that doesn&apos;t mean I&apos;m taking my wife to a sandwich shop 
for Valentines Day. It means the romantic restaurant was exactly what I 
expect of a romantic restaurant while the sandwich shop has a really great 
hot pastrami sandwich.
That being said, a fast-food chain follows rigid standards so each restaurant 
in the chain is exactly like every other restaurant in the chain. So, it 
would be highly unusual for a fast-food restaurant to get anything except 
&apos;3 out of 5&apos;.
Landmark references: Main Street is marked as Route 20 as you head out of town. 
Bennett Road is better marked as Route 60. Wendy&apos;s and McDonald&apos;s are 
kitty corner where Route 20 and Route 60 intersect. From there, the 
restaurants are listed in order going north on Route 60. Vineyard Drive 
starts where Thruway Exit 59 meets Route 60. Bob Evan&apos;s and Applebees face 
each other on the corner of Vineyard and Bennett Road. 
 Restaurant: DeJohn&apos;s Italian Spaghetti House 
 Type: Italian 
 Location: 26 West Main Street, Fredonia NY 14063 
 Date: October 28, 2011 
 Rating: *** out of 5 stars 

First of all, the place does not take credit cards. There&apos;s an ATM in bar 
now, but it charges a fee. The bar is in the front of the building, the 
restaurant is in the back. The bar has the shortest ceilings I&apos;ve ever seen 
in a public building. I&apos;m 5&apos;6&quot; and there are points where the ceiling is 
brushing my hair. Typical bar with neon in the windows and bar mirror covered 
in bottles.
The restaurant in back is much nicer. You&apos;re in a greenhouse which overlooks 
the parking lot. The ceiling are much taller, the walls are painted with faded 
murals of Italy which really need to be touched up. The flowers everywhere 
are all plastic, along with most of the statues which gives the place the feel 
of an Italian garden. The tables have red and white checkered tablecloths. 
Fake tiffany lamps hang from the ceiling.
We ordered the appetizer platter ($8), which was mostly deep-fried stuff with 
various dipping sauces; a half carafe of merlot ($13) which was a good wine, 
if not great; my wife ordered the rigatoni with sausage ($8); while I ordered 
ravioli platter ($8.50) which came with cheese, mushroom, and beef filled 
raviolis. Dessert was homemade cannolis ($2.50)

The service was efficient and friendly. The bathrooms are in the bar, and 
should be remodeled as they strike me as older. At the very least, a fresh 
paint job. 
 Restaurant: Tom&apos;s Family Restaurant 
 Type: Family Restaurant 
 Location: 935 Route 5&amp;20, Irving NY 14081 
 Date: March 16, 2012 
 Rating: ***** out of 5 stars 

Tom&apos;s Family Restaurant is on the same intersection with Sunset Bay Restaurant, 
which I&apos;ve already reviewed, and kitty-corner to it. There&apos;s a vaguely 
nautical theme to the place with plastic fish and seascapes and lighthouse 
border wallpaper mounted on the walls, and plastic &apos;stained glass&apos; panels of 
beach scenes dividing the booths. Several aquariums strategically placed as 
well. The front wall of the building is a half-greenhouse, which is probably 
the best seat in the house on sunny days.
We came for a Lenten fish fry. In addition to the regular plastic menu, we 
got a printed handout with the Lenten specials, most of the fish selections 
were a dollar or more off the regular price. We each ordered the fisherman&apos;s 
platter. The haddock was large and quite good, the scallops were delicious, 
the shrimp were quite good. My clams were good, my wife&apos;s were slightly 
overdone. The restaurant does not have an alcohol license, so we had 
lemon-lime and iced tea. Service was fast and efficient, despite the place 
being crowded for Lent.
The dessert menu changes daily. Actually, there is no menu, there&apos;s a large 
refrigerated display case in the front room where you can look over the 
desserts before ordering. The wait staff can also rattle them off for you. 
The portions are generous. Their single cream puff would nearly be a meal in 
itself. The majority of the desserts were various cream or fruit pies, with 
eclaires, cream puffs, cheese cake and carrot cake. We shared a slice of 
cheesecake. Heavenly. Prices very reasonable.
EDITED TO ADD: We went back on March 30th. The waitress not only remembered
us, but our food order as well. This gal is good! 
 Restaurant: Central Station 
 Type: Diner 
 Location: 332 Central Avenue, Dunkirk NY 
 Date: March 3, 2012 
 Rating: *** out of 5 stars 

The place was reviewed in the then-current issue of the Chautauqua Star, so we 
decided to try it out. We were afraid that since it had just been reviewed, 
it would be mobbed, but it was actually empty except for one other table. 
Normally, it&apos;s only open 7AM to 3PM, seven days a week, but they stay open 
until 8PM on Fridays in Lent to serve fish.
There&apos;s a vague train theme to the restaurant but it&apos;s confined to the logos 
on the menu and a wooden version on the back wall, along with historical 
photos of old trains and depots from the area. There&apos;s also a couple of old 
lanterns in the window as props.
It&apos;s a diner, one room with eight tables and a second room with another six 
tables. There&apos;s also stools so you can eat at the counter, but they&apos;re so 
poorly placed, you literally cannot get to them if the table in the back is 
occupied. In addition to the front door, there&apos;s a side door leading to the 
&apos;park&apos;, a widened alleyway with a few planters and benches. I imagine it&apos;s 
convienent for employees at the other businesses that open onto the park.
The menu is the usual slick plastic coated affair, however you also get a 
photocopied menu that is hand-written with all the stuff they now serve since 
the other menus got printed, mostly chicken, subs, sandwiches and wraps. 
There is no alcohol, beer or wine listed. I was mildly amused to see that the 
salt and pepper shakers didn&apos;t match. The salt shakers were the standard 
glass with metal top you expect to see in a diner, the pepper shakers were 
the throwaway plastic ones you buy for your picnic basket.
We ordered bowls of New England Clam Chowder and Fisherman&apos;s Platters. The 
latter were advertised with homemade macaroni salad, potato salad, and 
coleslaw. Apparently the breakfast menu also has homemade hollandaise sauce 
for the eggs benedict.
The waitress was a chubby tattooed goth, reminding me of Paulie Parette from 
NCIS. :D I counted 3 cooks in the kitchen. Considering there was only one 
other table of six, and only one person came in for a pre-ordered &apos;to go&apos; 
order, it should now have taken as long as it did for us to get our food. It 
wasn&apos;t as bad as the American Legion Post last week, but it was still overly 
long. The waitress forgot to bring us our chowder when it was ready and only 
brought it out after the platters which may have compounded the problem. 
Because it had a chance to sit and cool, it was only warm, not hot from the 
stove. It was good, but I would have preferred it to be hotter.
The fried haddock was good and nearly twice the size of what we got at the 
American Legion Post the previous week. The clams were overfried to the point 
of being barely edible. The slaw was a bit sweet, the macaroni salad was good. 
The shrimp were pre-peeled before being dipped and fried so I didn&apos;t have any 
shrimp tails to deal with, a nice touch. The haddock was very good. The 
newspaper review recommended the dessert menu, but the dinner portions were 
generous and we were quite full. The service a bit under par, but the food 
was good and portions generous. Three stars out of five. 
 Restaurant: American Legion Post 
 Type: Lenten Fish Fry 
 Location: 156 E. Main Street, Fredonia NY 14063 
 Date: Friday, February 24th, 2012 
 Rating: 1/2* out of 5 stars 

It&apos;s Lent. It was Friday. We like to go for good Fish Fry. Normally, the 
paper publishes a list of Top Ten Lenten Fish Fry. They didn&apos;t this year. 
The American Legion Post on Main Street serves a Lenten Fish Fry, Fridays 
between 4:30 and 8. We went. NEVER AGAIN. We arrived at 6:30. And waited. 
They had two waitresses, they could have used four. The menu was one page; 
large haddock, small haddock, shrimp, scallops, and fisherman&apos;s platter which 
is a small haddock, shrimp,&amp;scallops. Alcohol is only for members, due to 
their limited liquor license. We ordered scallops and a platter. WE WAITED 
OVER AN HOUR FOR OUR FOOD! Listening in on other tables, we were not the 
worst case. One table waited TWO HOURS. I was getting ready to leave when 
our food finally arrived. It wasn&apos;t bad, but then it&apos;s hard to screw up 
fried fish. When we got our check, I picked it up. The waitress came around 
to my side of the table, and started reading the bill aloud while I was 
trying to calculate a tip. I told her to stop and SHE GOT HUFFY WITH ME. 
We got charged for refills of our pop. Considering we had to wait an hour 
for food, we should have gotten the drinks comped. So, long wait, a much 
belated apology, rude wait staff, mediocre food and the men&apos;s room was out 
of paper towels. HALF A STAR OUT OF FIVE. 
 Restaurant: Sunset Bay Restaurant 
 Type: Diner 
 Location: 954 Main Road, Irving NY 14081 
 Date: Wednesday, July 8th, 2011 
 Rating: ***** out of 5 stars 

Wednesday is All-You-Can-Eat Clam Night and I am in lurve! Big, hot, juicy, 
steamed clams and ice-cold beer! Just $19.50. Yum!
Despite the apparently completely different address, this place is just down 
the street from Aunt Millie&apos;s. It&apos;s on the corner of Main and Alleghany Roads,
kitty corner with Tom&apos;s Family Restaurant. Not to be confused with the Sunset 
Grill directly across the street from Aunt Millie&apos;s.
It&apos;s a plain brick building, one and a half stories, with the upper story in 
siding. You can enter either via the bar on Allegheny, or from the restaurant 
parking lot on Main. There is lots of parking. Inside, it&apos;s a drop panel 
ceiling, white walls, a few black and white paintings for decoration and lots 
of woodwork polished until it gleams. The tables are faux marble and the 
chairs are wooden with padded seats. They also gleam. The bar is just another 
dining room except it has a bar along one wall, it doesn&apos;t have a &apos;tavern&apos; 
look to it.
Our waitress was prompt, polite, friendly and efficient. The first round of 
clams is a platter of 16, with a side-order of french fries. &apos;Refill&apos; platters 
are an even dozen. You get two fresh lemon slices and a little cup of butter 
with each platter. All the condiments you could want for clams and fries are in 
the little rack on each table; ketchup, mustard, salt, pepper, red Tabasco 
sauce, green Tabasco sauce, and malt vinegar. I finished off 4 dozen clams 
(the extra 8 were from my wife&apos;s plate that she couldn&apos;t finish).
I have no idea what the rest of their food tastes like. The rating above is 
strictly for the Clam Special. MMMmmmmm. Clams with butter, clams with salt 
and lemon juice, clams with malt vinegar and red Tabasco, clams with butter 
and lemon juice, clams with... 
 Restaurant: Zebro&apos;s Harbor House 
 Type: Seafood 
 Location: 8254 First Street, Westfield NY 14787 
 Date: June 13, 2011 
 Website: www.zebrosharborhouse.com 
 Rating: ***** out of 5 stars 

Our friend Jim was in NY visiting family. He stopped by to visit us on the 
way back. He wanted someplace to eat that was non-chain, not too pricy, and 
seafood. We took him to Barcelona Harbor House only to discover it&apos;s now 
Zebro&apos;s Harbor House, which is actually owned by the Zimmerman Brothers and 
not by someone named Zebrowski. So, it&apos;s the Z BRO ther &apos;S restaurant.
I don&apos;t know why they have a 4-digit street address. The street itself is 
barely a block long. It&apos;s also just a tad hard to find. Take I-90 to Exit 60 
and go North on Route 394 to Lake Erie. When you get to the stop light on 
Route 5/Lake View Road/Main Street in Barcelona Bay, continue going straight. 
No, really, that&apos;s a road. It ends a block later at First Street which is also 
a block long and has nothing but waterfront restaurants. Zebro&apos;s is the first 
one on the right.
The bar is heavily zebra themed. All the chairs have zebra-print fabric, 
there are zebra paintings in zebra print frames, there&apos;s a light-up reindeer 
lawn ornament that&apos;s had its antlers sawn off and the body decorated with 
black felt stripes to make it into a zebra. The fish tank even has zebra 
colored decorations in it. Fortunately, we were led to tables in the back 
where we could look out over Lake Erie. The restaurant is lightly nautical 
themed with oars and life preservers mounted on the wood-paneled walls. Large 
windows afford a wonderful view of Lake Erie from nearly any table. We got 
one of the corner tables.
Unfortunately for Jim, mid-June is too early for clams or oysters which he has 
a fondness for. I ordered the fried Perch which is local-caught, my wife and 
Jim both ordered the broiled Wall-Eyed Pike which is also local-caught. We 
also ordered a bottle of &quot;green&quot; Sauvignon Blanc, it had been made from organic 
grapes. For appetizers, we all had a cup of New England clam chowder and we 
split an order of Rumaki, chicken livers with water chestnuts and bacon. The 
clam chowder was excellent, thick, chunky and tasty. The Rumaki came with a 
small container of teri-yaki sauce for dipping and was quite good. The dinner 
salad was a nice little salad with red cabbage and carrots and onions and such 
but a bit disappointing, I could have fit the entire salad into a teacup. 
Considering that this is an upscale restaurant and salad greens are cheap, I 
felt we should have had larger servings. The Sauvignon was dry, but then I 
prefer a dry wine.
The perch was generously portioned and not overly greasy. The baked potato 
came with sour cream on the side. The dinner rolls came not only with butter, 
but with honey butter as well. Jim and Karen said the Pike was good, but just 
a little heavy on the lemon-pepper spicing. Most entrees run $15 - $20 
 Restaurant: Ellicottville Brewing Company 
 Type: Family Dining 
 Location: 34 West Main, Fredonia NY 14063 
 Date: May 24, 2011 
 Website: www.ellicottvillebrewing.com 
 Rating: **** out of 5 stars 

I&apos;ve previously reviewed EBC as a bar. This was the upstairs dining room. 
One of the UU committees I&apos;m on held a dinner meeting there. It&apos;s a large 
brick building, a former warehouse. I think there&apos;s an elevator in back. The 
staircase is just a bit steep. The walls have large windows, so everything is 
well-lit and sunny. The tables are well spaced so there&apos;s plenty of room to 
maneuver between them. I ordered their standard Brew-burger for $8, thought 
about a French Onion soup appetizer for $5. They do brew their own beer on 
premises, so I ordered the Black Jack Oatmeal Stout which was quite good. The 
condiments for the burger and fries not only included the standard ketchup and 
mustard but also malt vinegar. I can&apos;t remember the last time I didn&apos;t have 
to specifically request malt vinegar. 
 Restaurant: The Brick Room 
 Type: Fine Dining 
 Location: 49 West Main Street, Fredonia NY 14063 
 Date: April 26, 2011 
 Website: http://www.brickroom.biz 
 Rating: *** out of 5 stars 

There&apos;s a program called &quot;Dining Out for Life&quot; 
( http://www.diningoutforlife.com )
where on one day of the year, restaurants volunteer to donate 25% of their
proceeds for that day to fight AIDS. The Brick Room is normally closed on 
Tuesdays but they opened their doors to participate in this program. It was 
their first year with the program. My wife and I decided to try them out. It 
may have been a mistake.
The building is one long brick room with a drop ceiling. All the tables are 
small wooden tables, the kind you expect to rock and be unsteady, but they were 
all adjusted correctly. The kitchen is all the way in the back. On an 
uncrowded night, you can watch them cook your meal. This was not uncrowded 
night, the place was very crowded and very noisy. In their defense, this 
charity function may have been their busiest night of the year. The front door
was propped wide open to let in the outside air and help keep the heat down.
We were greeted by &apos;AIDS Ambassadors&apos; who welcomed us and thanked us for 
participating in this charity event. They recognized me from my public 
appearance as Bronson Alcott for the Margaret Fuller show, but they thought I 
and my wife were David and Sally! :)
The menus were printed on a single page. I don&apos;t know if this is their 
standard practice or if these were higher-priced menus for the program. 
Selections were limited: 2 kinds of appetizers; 2 kinds of soup; 2 kinds of 
salad, spinach and caesar. Entries started at $20, Wine by the Glass $5 and 
up, a bottle of risling cost us $29. We shared an appetizer of Pan Seared 
Scallops; scallops, tomato, red onion, chorizo, basil and parsley seared in 
olive oil. My wife had the Pork Tenderloin, I selected the Shrimp and Angel
Hair Pasta. The food was quite good, but a bit more expensive than we usually 
spend when we eat out. We&apos;ll have to come back again some other time to see 
if the menu is different during their regular hours.
One small surprise, when I went to the bathroom, I followed the signs down a 
corridor at the back of the building and found myself in the back room of 
Coughlin&apos;s Bar to use their bathrooms. They&apos;re apparently have the same owner 
and the bar was the source of the occasional cheering we heard because the 
Sabres were playing the Flyers in the playoffs. 
 Restaurant: Rocco&apos;s 
 Type: Italian Restaurant 
 Location: 44 Orchard Street, Fredonia NY 14063 
 Date: April 29, 2011 
 Rating: **1/2 out of 5 stars 

We had gotten into the habit of going out for fish frys on Fridays in Lent. 
We were quite fish-fried out, but we still wanted to go out, so we decided to 
try out the neighborhood Italian place I discovered when a road accident forced 
me to detour down a side street. Numberous internet reviews spoke highly of 
it. We were a little disappointed.
It&apos;s in a residential neighborhood between houses. If you&apos;re focused on 
driving, you can actually the neon beer ad in the window and the small sign 
advertising the restaurant itself. An empty lot across the street provides 
adequate parking, but it could be paved.
The front portion of the building is the bar, the middle section restaurant 
seating and the back end of the building is the kitchen. Everything is wood 
paneled, brown for the bar in front, white for the restaurant. Decor is very 
subdued, a few random license plates in the bar along with the owner&apos;s 
honorable discharge from the navy. No decorations in the restaurant. 
Bathrooms between bar and restaurant. The wait staff wears solid black with 
no nametags, I didn&apos;t realize how much I depended on them to remember our 
waitress&apos; name.
We ordered the mussels ($9) as a shared appetizer. They came 24 to the plate 
and were very good. We asked for extra bread to sop up the juices. :) The 
dinner salad was uninspiring, straight lettuce with a few shreds of red cabbage 
and carrot. The specials board is posted near the kitchen, but is behind a 
table of diners and impossible to read unless you stand right up next to a 
table of strangers.
For the main course, I ordered the lasagna ($13) and my wife ordered the 
eggplant parmesian ($13). We also ordered a bottle of Jacob&apos;s Creek Merlot to 
accompany our meal ($26, a 100%+ markup over the liquor store!) The entrees 
were so-so, the pasta was nearly tasteless, tomato sauce was acidic. Parmesian 
cheese has been sprinkled around the edges of each plate. I would have 
preferred a container on the table so we could season our food with it instead.
While we were dining, a couple from my UU church came in. We talked for a few 
minutes. He raved about their fish fry. His lady is a dyed-in-the-wool vegan 
who won&apos;t eat meat, fish, dairy or eggs. We ran into her again the following 
day while grocery shopping and she said she had to make-do with a large salad, 
not much better than our dinner salads.
I&apos;m giving the place a low score because it was a little bit overpriced, 
considering the mediocre quality of the food and the complete lack of 
atmosphere of the restaurant. 
 Restaurant: Mary&apos;s Deli 
 Type: Take out Pizza and Sub shop 
 Location: 100 West Main Street, Fredonia NY 14063 
 Date: Numerous occasions 
 Rating: *** out of 5 stars 

Technically, this is a chain as they also have a location in Dunkirk, but as 
chains go, I don&apos;t consider two to be a very big chain. When we don&apos;t feel 
like cooking, we either order a pizza or a couple of subs from here. It&apos;s 
strictly take out. There are no tables or bathrooms, just one bench which is 
usually half filled with neighborhood newspapers such as the Chautauqua Star 
or the Jamestown Word.
The food is acceptable. We don&apos;t order onions on their pizzas because they 
don&apos;t seem to do it right. The fried mushrooms are good and we always get a 
side order regardless of what else we order. When we get subs, we tell them 
to skip the mayo because they&apos;re stingy with the mayo and you only get a small 
smear. We add mayo and pepper sauce to them when we get home. I really wish 
they would invest in take-out flyers. It&apos;s a pain having to look them up in 
the phone and try to remember what they have available. 
 Restaurant : 21 East Cafe 
 Type: Coffeehouse 
 Location: 21 East 2nd Street, Dunkirk NY 14048 
 Date: Saturday, April 9, 2011 
 Website: http://www.lvoccread.org/21-East-Cafe-and-Bookstore.html 
 Rating: *** out of 5 

For the past several years, the Literacy Volunteers of Chautauqua County have 
been holding a monthly used book sale fundraiser. This spring, they acquired 
space in the historic 1900 Crocker Sprague building and opened a combination 
coffeehouse and used bookstore. It&apos;s a coffeehouse, so while there&apos;s an 
extensive selection of coffees and teas and pastries, the rest of the menu is 
extremely limited. They offer a sandwich of the day ($10) and a soup of the 
day ($3 cup, $5 bowl) and that&apos;s it. The food is from Mustard Seed 
Restaurant in South Dayton NY. http://www.themustardseedrestaurant.com The coffeehouse is staffed by two women volunteers and is only open on 
weekends, Thursdays, Fridays, and Saturdays. They occasionally have musical 
performances in the coffeehouse.
The various coffees, expressos, lattes, and such range from about $2 to $3 
depending on what size, what flavorings, etc. The assorted muffins, pound 
cake slices, sweetrolls, etc. also range from about $2 to $3. My wife and I 
can usually get a coffee, a tea and two pastries for about $10. All proceeds 
go to Literacy Volunteers, which makes us feel good about stopping there 
every Saturday morning. All coffees are Fair Trade.
The bookstore portion of the building is in the back room. You can enter the 
building through the coffeehouse in front, or the bookstore in back, but if 
you want to go from one to the other (or use the bathroom) you have to pass 
through a small middle room where the cafe has its pantry and several of the 
volunteers have their office desks. Given the arrangement of the building 
however, I don&apos;t know any other way you could set it up. Hardcovers are $2, 
paperbacks $1, children&apos;s books $0.50 Certain select books are priced more 
expensively. The stock rotates often enough that its worth the bother of 
dropping in every week. 
 Restaurant: Wing City Grille 
 Type: Sports Bar and Grill 
 Location: 10450 Bennet Road (Route 60),. Fredonia NY 14063 
 Date: Saturday, April 9, 2011 
 Website: http://www.wingcitygrille.com 
 Rating: **1/2 out of 5 

The building is a former Ponderosa. We ate there a few times before it 
closed. Booths along the walls, tables in the center. Wing City advertises 
itself as a sports bar and grill (21 TVs!), but actually they&apos;ve got a fairly 
extensive menu with steak, chicken, fish, sandwiches, salads, burgers, sea 
food, etc. They boast 21 different flavors of chicken wings including mild, 
medium, hot, x-hot, xx-hot and nuclear (must sign release). To check out the 
other flavors, click on the menu on their website.
I ordered a double order of chicken wings in Irish Pub flavor with a tall 
draft. My wife order the veggie wrap with a well-drink. No appetizers. 
Irish Pub is a combination of BBQ, Jack Daniels and just a hint of cajun to 
make them spicy. They made me sweat, but not cry. It&apos;s a sports bar, most 
of the TVs were tuned to various sporting events. If you&apos;re looking for a 
quiet intimate restaurant, this isn&apos;t it. However, that&apos;s not the reason for 
the low rating. With a double order of wings, a wrap, a well drink and a 
draft, the bill came to over $40. We were actually there during Happy Hour, 
which means both drinks should have been half price. The food was typical 
bar food, not horrible but not wonderful either. Far too expensive for what 
we got, hence the slightly lower rating. We won&apos;t be going there too often. 
 Restaurant: Sheridan Diner 
 Type: Diner 
 Location: 2705 Main Street, Sheridan NY 14135 
 Date: Friday, April 8, 2011 
 Rating: ***1/2 out of 5 

The restaurant formerly known as Gobbler&apos;s Knob was sold and is now under new 
management. We decided to try out their Lenten Fish Fry. For $8 you get a 
huge piece of fish, two hush puppies, macaroni salad, potato salad and 
coleslaw. All three salads are obviously out of a commercial package and a 
bit heavy on the mayonnaise. The coleslaw was a little bit on the sweet side 
as well. However, the fish was quite tasty and you get a big piece for your 
money. It was sufficiently filling. The iced tea was pre-sweetened.
We had been here a couple of times when it was Gobbler&apos;s Knob. The turkey 
display case in the corner was gone. Other than that, the decor hasn&apos;t 
changed. The menu is written on a black board on the front wall as well as 
printed on plain paper at each table. The tables are sufficiently small that 
you can span them with your elbows. For two it&apos;s cozy, for more, you have to 
push a couple of tables together. There&apos;s also a counter where you can sit 
on bar stools. The kitchen is in the corner of the room, you can watch them 
cook your dinner and you can smell it! The bathroom is through the kitchen 
into a small side room.
As I said, it&apos;s new management, so no beer license yet and their not yet set 
up to take plastic. Cash only. We&apos;ll go back another time to try a non-fish 
meal.
 Update: There may not be another time. There&apos;s a sign on the building
that says &quot;Public Auction -- Sept 10&quot;. 
 Restaurant: Liberty Cafe 
 Type: Bar and Grill 
 Location: 21 Prospect Street, Fredonia NY 
 Date: Friday, April 1, 2011 
 Rating: **** out of 5 stars 

We first heard about Liberty Cafe in the local paper. It had just been 
re-opened under new management. It also made the paper&apos;s top ten list for 
Lenten Fish Fry in Fredonia, so we decided to give them a try. There&apos;s 
parking behind the building, but it&apos;s an unmarked gravel lot and I think it 
could hold a few more cars than it did if it was paved and had designated 
spaces instead of people parking anywhere they wanted. The place was crowded 
and we had a 20 min wait for a table, but considering we were supposed to 
be in a great place for a fish fry on a Friday during Lent, we decided it 
was worth the wait. We had a drink at the bar. Interestingly, the bar sells
mixed drinks and bottled beer, they don&apos;t have beer on draft yet.
I went with the fish fry, the house special. My wife ordered the broiled 
haddock as she wasn&apos;t in the mood for deep-fried anything. I thought the 
service was fairly fast considering that this was probably their busiest time.
I got a huge piece of fish, fries, coleslaw and macaroni salad. Tartar sauce 
was in a commercial squirt bottle, not unlike ketchup. I don&apos;t think I&apos;ve 
ever seen that in a restaurant before. I found the meal hot, tasty and 
filling. It was not overly greasy the way most deep fried fish are. It was 
also inexpensive at just over $8. 
 Restaurant: Mongolian Buffet 
 Type: Chinese Buffet 
 Location: 3513 McKinley Parkway, Orchard Park NY 14219 
 Date: Saturday, October 9, 2010 
 Rating: ***** out of 5 stars 

I know this isn&apos;t in Chautauqua County, but it was so wonderful, I had to
write it up. :) It&apos;s a slightly overpriced standard Chinese Buffet, $12 per 
person on weekends. The ones in Fredonia are only $10. But, I have to say, 
it&apos;s got the largest variety I&apos;ve ever seen in a Chinese Buffet. The cold 
bar, in addition to the usual boiled shrimp and mussels, had oysters on the 
half shell. Their won-ton and their sweet and sour soups are wonderful. 
There were more varieties of prepared shrimp than I&apos;ve ever since in one 
place. The buffet also had squid, two kinds of octopus and frog legs! For 
a regular dinner, it&apos;s a bit pricey, but for a special occasion, it might be 
worth the price. 
 Restaurant: The Sugar Shack 
 Type: Pancake House 
 Location: 7904 Route 5, Westfield, NY 14787 
 Date: Sunday, August 15, 2010 
 Rating: ***1/2 out of 5 

The Sugar Shack is only open Saturday and Sunday morning during the summer.
The building is half cafe, half gift shop with all items made by local 
artisans. The only item on the menu is the pancake breakfast. Three
pancakes, each larger than the plate they are served on, with 2 bacon strips
or 2 sausage links, and one egg cooked to order. The egg and meat are
served on top of the pancakes. The fruit cup is commercial packed, right
out of the plastic container. The juices are all served in cans.
That being said, it&apos;s a quaint place to have a pancake breakfast. The 
cafe has large windows that look over woodlands with bird books perched
on all the window sills so you can try to identify what you spotted. The
place is famous for the 21 flavors of fruit syrup that you can buy to take
home. They also make their own maple syrup with a state-of-the-art maple
oven and they give tours of it on Maple Syrup weekends 
( www.mapleweekend.com ) 
 Restaurant: The Green Arch 
 Type: Diner 
 Location: 41 West Main Street, Brocton NY 14716 
 Date: Sunday, August 8, 2010 
 Rating: *** of 5 
 Website: http://www.greenarch.us 

One of the last Mullholand Diner Car products known to be in operation. 
The decor has been maintained as an old-fashioned diner car. Numerous 
historical photos on the wall. Breakfast is served around the clock. 
I had the Green Arch special; 2 eggs, toast, bacon, home fries for $6. 
It was okay. My wife had the three egg omelet but didn&apos;t like because they 
used processed cheese in the omelet. There are no vegetarian dishes, all 
the side orders are deep fried, ie onion rings, potato wedges, chicken nuggets, 
etc. Service was fast without the waitress hovering over you. 
They&apos;re only open until lunch hour the first part of the week, 
evening hours from Thurs to Sun. Street parking or you can use the community 
lot half a block down. 
 Restaurant: Nomad&apos;s House 
 Type: Asian 
 Location: 33 Church Street, Fredonia, NY 14063 
 Date: Sunday, June 26, 2010 
 Rating: ***** out of 5 
 Website: http://www.facebook.com/pages/Fredonia-NY/Nomads-House/111222902248855 
Nomad&apos;s is tucked away around the corner from the park in the center of 
Fredonia. Ask someone where the old &quot;Hook and Ladder Restaurant&quot; used to be. 
It&apos;s a small building attached to a historical building in downtown Fredonia 
that used to be a fire hall. H&amp;L;was your stereo-typical greasy spoon. 
I never ate there. Nomad&apos;s remodelled the place completely, it&apos;s much cleaner. 
The decor is vaguely asian, but not in-your-face decor. Officially opened 
May 1st. We went there for a late lunch after our organizational meeting about 
the UU auction. They have exactly one item on the menu, stir fry. 
It&apos;s a sit-down restaurant but you order at the counter like a fast-food place.
You pick your starch (lo mein, brown rice or white rice), your meat (chicken, 
steak, vegetarian), your choice of vegetables (local grown is highlighted in a 
different color) and your sauce and they stir fry it all up for you. The 
kitchen is wide open, there&apos;s no dividing wall. You can watch them prepare 
your meal. They do not skimp on portions and because you pick what you want 
it&apos;s very vegan friendly and locovore friendly. Wifi available. 
Will be eating here more often.
 Edited to Add: It closed on March 5, 2011 
 Restaurant: Locovore (Nature&apos;s Network) 
 Type: Soup and Sandwich Shop 
 Location: 40 E Main St, Fredonia, NY 14063-1821 
 Date: Saturday, January 23, 2010 
 Rating: *** out of 5 

Nature&apos;s Network is a locally owned natural foods store. The owners are 
members of my UU church. &quot;Locovore&quot; is just a couple of tables set-up in 
the back of the store. You can literally reach out and grab a box of 
detergent off the shelf from your table. :) The name comes from the fact that 
all the food served is locally grown from the nearby farms. Because of this, 
there are no printed menus. The day&apos;s selection is written on a chalk board 
at the front of the store. Prices are always the same: $5 for a sandwich, 
$6 for a bowl of soup, $3 for a cup of soup, $1 for a hot beverage, 
$1.50 for a cold beverage.
I went there this weekend with my church group. I can&apos;t fault them for 
serving time because we came in as a group and they were still trying to run 
the natural food store while waiting on us, not to mention they&apos;re also the 
cooks. I had a cup of the broccoli-cheddar soup and an egg-salad sandwich and 
pop. The food was good, and literally everything was homemade. The other 
downside is that there are no bathrooms. Make sure you go somewhere else 
before you come to eat.
 Update: Andrew and Jane sold the natural food store. The new owner
can&apos;t afford a cook yet. So, no more Locovore. 
 Restaurant: Intermezzo Coffee House 
 Type: Coffee house 
 Location: 12 Park Place, Fredonia NY 14063 
 Date: multiple occasions 
 Rating: ****1/2 out of 5 
 Website: http://www.intermezzocoffeehouse.com 

Being a member of a UU church, you&apos;re a member of committees... and you attend 
meetings. Every two weeks, a large number of meetings are held at the church, 
and then we wander across the street to the Intermezzo Coffee House for 
&quot;Tea With Terry&quot; our minister. We used to hold it at the White House Inn, but 
the prices kept rising, so now we meet here instead.
The building is a bit narrow, but extends back a long ways. The coffee bar 
runs along one wall most of the way to the back. The walls have art from 
local artists for sale. Occasionally the coffeehouse has live musicians. See 
their website for schedules.
I usually order coffee and a sandwich. The sandwiches are large and quite good. 
Their hazelnut coffee is some of the best I&apos;ve ever had, and the refills are 
free. I&apos;ve found the service to be a bit slow, but to be utterly fair, there&apos;s 
five or six people there on an early Saturday afternoon when suddenly 15 to 20 
UUs walk in the door and start ordering. One of these days, I&apos;ll go there when 
there isn&apos;t a UU meeting to see how fast they are under normal circumstances.
 Edited to Add: New owners. It&apos;s now The Green Tea Room. New 
review at a later time. 
 Restaurant: El Azteca 
 Type: Mexican 
 Location: 3953 Suite A, Vineyard Drive, Dunkirk NY 14048 
 Date: Tuesday, June 30, 2009 
 Rating: **** out of 5 

The restaurant is actually in the Tops Plaza, hence the &quot;suite&quot; designation. 
This is the second Grand Opening it&apos;s had. It originally opened when the new 
Tops store did, however a few weeks later it was shut down because the entire 
staff was illegal immigrants. My wife and I managed to eat there once before 
it closed, but I misplaced my notebook with the review in it.
The theme, of course, is Aztec. There are back-lit aztec symbols in the tables 
and chairs area and wall paintings in the booths area (Sorry, no human 
sacrifices! :D) We got the customary free chips and salsa. We both found the 
salsa mildly hot and a bit watery. Green and red habenaro hot sauce bottles 
were included along with the usual salt, pepper and ketchup.
My wife ordered the Mushroom Quesadilla, I had the Burrito Deluxe with one 
chicken burrito and one beef. The food arrived quickly and hot. Mexican music 
played quietly in the background. There is a sports TV in the bar, but we 
couldn&apos;t hear it from the restaurant area. My wife found the gualcamole 
disappointing, and the rice and beans only so-so, but said the quesadilla 
itself was quite tasty. My burritos came with shredded lettuce and sour cream. 
A couple of dashes of red sauce made them just hot enough to make me sweat 
without crying, just the way I like it. An experimental drop of green sauce on 
a salsa chip convinced me it was too lethal to play with. :)
There are Mexican and American beers listed on the menu as well as mixed 
drinks, however the State Liquor License Bureau hasn&apos;t finished dotting 
their i&apos;s and crossing their t&apos;s, so only soft drinks are available for the 
time being. Lunch for two, plus all you want chips and pop, $20. 
 Restaurant: East Side Grill 
 Type: Diner 
 Location: 22 Water Street, Fredonia NY 
 Date: Saturday, February 28, 2009 
 Rating: **1/2 out of 5 

First of all, don&apos;t go looking for the diner on Water Street, it isn&apos;t there. 
It&apos;s in &quot;The Alley&quot;. There are businesses that face Main Street in Fredonia. 
The Alley leads to community parking behind Main Street where you can enter 
many of the businesses from the rear. Some businesses actually face The Alley. 
I&apos;ve already reviewed another restaurant there, Lena&apos;s Pizza. The East Side 
Grill is another.
As soon as you walk into the restaurant, you walk downstairs into The Pit. 
Only the bar is at ground level. The decor is wood and brick. Thankfully, 
there&apos;s no sports TV blaring, just a radio. The Quik Draw board is a little 
too prominent for my tastes however.
We were there because the local paper said it had one of the best Lenten fish 
frys in Fredonia. Unfortunately, we were there on a Saturday and they only do 
fish on Fridays. We returned the following Friday for the fish, only to be 
told that they had sold out of fish earlier in the day.
There was nothing decent on draft, so I ordered a Sam Adams Boston Lager. We 
ordered chicken livers as an appetizer. They came breaded and topped with 
bacon. Karen said they were the best she&apos;s had in a long time. She ordered a 
chicken, pepper and eggplant pasta with French Onion soup. I had the honey 
dipped chicken with onion peels instead of fries and a side salad. The soup 
had a good broth, not salty and a generous portion of onions. The salad with 
1000 Island dressing was ok. The dinner rolls and butter were a pre-packaged 
disappointment.
The pasta and the chicken were both decent, but nothing note-worthy. The onion 
peels were mildly spiced, which surprized me. The veg of the day was green 
beans. Meal for two, including tax and tip, just under $45. In summary; 
nothing decent on draft, food acceptable but slightly overpriced, and unable 
to get &apos;one of the best fish frys in town&apos;, Two and a half stars. We may try 
for the fish fry again, but we&apos;re not going to be seeking this place out 
again any time soon. 
 Restaurant: Aunt Millie&apos;s Family Restaurant and Bakery 
 Type: Diner 
 Location: Routes 5&amp;20, Irving NY 
 Date: Thursday, October 2nd, 2008 
 Rating: ***** out of 5 

I couldn&apos;t find an address other than Routes 5&amp;20 in Irving NY. For those 
who are not local to the area, the routes don&apos;t intersect, they merge. 
There&apos;s about a mile or so of road that&apos;s both routes. That&apos;s where the 
restaurant is.
The decor is basic diner without that chain restaurant feel. There&apos;s a 
couple of faux stained glass windows hanging near the windows to catch the 
light. For the holidays, there&apos;s an eclectic mix of halloween ceramics in 
the windowsills. There&apos;s a sunroom extension for sunny days and a back 
patio which is only open in the summer. The place has both booths and tables 
arranged in small rooms for a cozier feel, with a lunchroom counter just 
inside the door.
The menu offers sandwich platters, italian food, salads, and homestyle dinners 
such as turkey, meatloaf, etc . Everything on the menu is homemade! 
Everything! We were there for lunch. My wife ordered the grilled ham and 
cheese sandwich, I ordered the sloppy joe. We had onion rings on the side. 
The sandwiches were delicious, tasting just like homemade comfort food. The 
sloppy joe came without a top bun, and the hamburger was nicely spiced, not 
just burger and tomato sauce. My wife loved her grilled sandwich. The onion 
rings were not prepackaged like you get at the drive-thru, these were cut 
from real onions and deep fried right in the kitchen. I&apos;d almost be willing 
to bet they dill their own pickles!
The &apos;and Bakery&apos; in the name is not just an addition. They have an 
honest-to-goodness bakery on site. All the desserts are homemade. My wife 
ordered the apple pie, I had the daily special; banana-strawberry cream pie. 
Again it was all home-made, no canned pie filling, handmade pie crust. 
Even the whipped cream was real whipped cream and not commercial topping. 
If it had been whipped any more, it would have started becoming butter.
Two lunches, unlimited refills on drinks and two desserts, and everything 
homemade, all for less than $25. We&apos;ll be stopping by there again. 
 Restaurant: Lena&apos;s Pizza 
 Type: Pizzeria 
 Location: 18 Canadaway Street, Fredonia NY 14063 
 Date: Sunday, July 22, 2007 
 Rating: ****1/2 out of 5 

I&apos;d be willing to bet cash money I could find Fredonia natives who couldn&apos;t 
tell you where Canadaway Street is, but they&apos;d be able to give you directions 
to Lena&apos;s without a problem. The storefronts in downtown Fredonia 
(both blocks) face Main Street. Behind them is a large community parking lot. 
There are several entrances to this parking lot. At the back of the lot are 
the backyards of houses that face the next street over. One house is turned 
around so it faces the parking lot. That&apos;s Lena&apos;s. It&apos;s a former house, 
former toy store, now a pizza parlor. According to the map, two of the 
parking lot entrances are the ends of Canadaway Street. There are no street 
signs saying Canadaway, just green signs saying &quot;Parking&quot; with an arrow. 
On the map, it looks like a street, in real life, it looks like a typical 
parking lot. You simply don&apos;t think of it as being a street.
That being said, neither of us felt like cooking after Viking Village, so we 
ordered a pizza. I gotta say, it&apos;s one of the best pizzas I&apos;ve had in years! 
Delicious! We had a 14&quot; pizza with onions, mushrooms, black olives, and sweet 
peppers for $15.20 plus tax. The onions were a little raw for my taste, but I 
realize that this is the way the average person likes onions on their pizza, 
so I can&apos;t complain. They&apos;re one of the few places I know that offers 
anchovies. Pizza hut doesn&apos;t. They also have the traditional side orders, 
subs, wraps, wings, fried mushrooms, etc. but we didn&apos;t order any, so I can&apos;t 
review them.
I&apos;d be willing to give this place a perfect five, except for a few oddities. 
It&apos;s open 11am - midnight Thurs, Fri, Sat. and 4PM - 10PM the rest of the 
week. I guess they&apos;re not interested in non-peak hours. I suspect the vast 
majority of their orders is for take out. There&apos;s a couple of booths if you 
want to eat your pizza there, but go easy on the Pepsi, because there aren&apos;t 
any bathrooms. Finally, they don&apos;t accept checks, credit or debit cards, it&apos;s 
strictly a cash operation. I can understand if they were just starting out, 
but they&apos;ve been there a couple of years now. I&apos;m not used to carrying large 
amounts of cash with me anymore. 
 Restaurant : The Golden Griddle 
 Type : Family 
 Location : 323 Washington Street, Jamestown NY (corner of 4th and Washington) 
 Date : Sunday, April 29, 2007 
 Rating : **** out of 5 

The Heronter herald decided to change the location of the monthly heraldry 
breakfast. We think it was a good decision. To get there, take Main street 
downtown (and down hill!) to 4th Avenue. Turn right on 4th (it&apos;s one-way, so 
you can&apos;t turn left). Drift to the left-most lane and turn left at the traffic 
light onto Washington street. The restaurant is on the corner, next door to it 
is a city parking lot. On Sundays, the lot is empty and you don&apos;t have to 
feed the meters. I have no idea what parking is like during the week.
The Golden Griddle occupies the bottom of a three story building. I have no 
idea what&apos;s on the other two floors. My first guess would be apartments. The 
logo sign for the restaurant is kind of amateurish, but that only lends to the 
charm. They&apos;re only open for breakfast and lunch, seven days a week. New 
hours are posted on flyers taped to the door and windows.
Service was fast and efficient, the waitress was there within seconds of us 
sitting down. The menu was breakfast on one side, lunch on the other. I 
ordered the Western omelet with a side order of sausage links. My wife ordered 
the same with sausage patties. After we handed in our menus, I noticed the 
daily special board on the wall. It might have been nice if there was an 
notice on the menu as well, I might have ordered from it. I&apos;m not asking for 
much, a handwritten sheet of typewriter paper would have been sufficient.
The food came quickly, it was good, it was hot. The links were slightly 
over-done without being burnt, but my wife&apos;s patties were fine, so it may 
have been a matter of a few seconds too long on the grill. The waitress 
brought ketchup and refilled the coffees without being asked. We had to 
take our bills up to the counter to pay them, the waitress doesn&apos;t take them.
It&apos;s not open in the evenings, so we couldn&apos;t use it for after shire 
meetings, not to mention the fact that we&apos;d fill the entire restaurant to 
overflowing, it&apos;s just not that big. But for a heraldry breakfast or a guild 
meeting, it&apos;s just about perfect. The food, the service and the price were 
all better than Friendly&apos;s Restaurant
 Edited to Add: It&apos;s now Lori&apos;s Kountry Kafe, but nothing else has 
changed. 
 Restaurant: Demetri&apos;s on the Lake 
 Type: Greek / Family 
 Location: 6-8 Lake Shore Drive West, Dunkirk NY 
 Date: Tuesday, March 27th, 2007 
 Rating: *** out of five 

The address is slightly deceiving. Central Avenue terminates at Lake Shore 
Drive. Lake Shore Drive East and West addresses extend away from Central 
Avenue. The restaurant is reached by driving up Central Avenue, crossing Lake 
Shore Drive as if you were heading towards the docks and then turning into 
Demetri&apos;s parking lot.
We had been running errands all day and neither of us felt like cooking, so 
we decided to eat out. It&apos;s actually two restaurants. Demetri&apos;s is 
downstairs and is laid out like a typical family restaurant. Katerina&apos;s is a 
upstairs lounge with live Greek music. It&apos;s not open until summer. I&apos;ll 
return then to review it.
You can order the type of meal you can order in a typical family restaurant, 
chicken, pork chops, steaks, burgers, etc. but they call themselves a Greek 
restaurant, so we ordered Greek. I ordered the Greek combo dinner. 
Admittedly, it was exactly what was advertised, beef and chicken souvlaki 
with a gyro slices. I expect something more from something that calls itself 
a combo platter. At the Red Lobster the seafood platter has shrimp, 
scallops, fish and clams. At Towne Restaurant, the Greek platter includes 
moussaka and spanakopita as well as the souvlaki and gyro. Just souvlaki and 
gyro seems kind of plain.
The meal was good and filling. I had two beers with my meal, they ended up 
costing more than the meal itself. It wasn&apos;t a great Greek meal, but it was 
a good one. Platter and two beers: $24. 
 Restaurant: China King 
 Type: Chinese 
 Location: D&amp;F Plaza, Central&amp;Millard Fillmore Avenues, Dunkirk-Fredonia line. 
 Date: Saturday, February 17th, 2007 
 Rating: ***-1/2 out of five 

It&apos;s two restaurants in one! I don&apos;t know the full story behind this place, 
but I&apos;m willing to make a guess. I think China King started out as a take-out 
only place and then when the building next store went out of business, they 
bought it, built a doorway between the two and opened an elegant sit-down 
all-you-can-eat chinese buffet restaurant.
The original building is still a take-out place with a couple of cheap 
plastic booths with linoleum tables. You can walk in and order take-out meals. 
You could probably eat at the booths, but I&apos;ve never seen them in use. The 
menu is overhead of the order desk.
The building next door however, has it&apos;s own separate entrance, with a 
hostess who will seat you in the dining area. The decor has paper lanterns, 
oriental paintings, mirrors and sculptures with flowing water to provide a 
pleasant sound. There&apos;s another banquet hall in back for the occasions when 
they&apos;re busy enough to fill the front area.
The food service area has four long steam tables. The food bins are frequently 
refilled during the day, but we&apos;ve learned not to go during the last hour 
they&apos;re open because they allow the bins to empty out rather than waste food. 
I find the food marginally better than at Best Buffet, another 
all-you-can-eat chinese buffet restaurant literally two blocks away.
Lunch and dinner are basically the same, differing in price by about $2 per 
person. Dinner has crab legs and more varieties of soups. There&apos;s a token 
effort of American food with pans of pizza slices and chicken wings. I&apos;ve 
convinced myself those are for the kids who have to eat with their folks but 
don&apos;t like chinese food. I don&apos;t think they fully understand the concept of 
cheese. One of the offerings is steamed mussels with melted cheese. I&apos;ve 
tried it, I like both items, but combining the two is like putting steak 
sauce on ice cream, it just doesn&apos;t work. Fortunately, they offer regular 
steamed mussels as well.
The back table isn&apos;t a steam table, but a cold table. It has jello, fresh 
fruit, pastries, chocolate, vanilla and rice puddings, and dill pickles. 
I don&apos;t understand the pickles. Best Buffet also offers dill pickles, but 
they have an american grill where you can get hamburgers and hotdogs, so it 
makes slightly more sense there. Best Buffet also has a cold table which is 
a salad bar. I&apos;d like to see a salad bar at China King.
My one complaint is the location of the bathrooms. The only bathrooms are 
back in the take-out section. You have to walk to the back of the rooms and 
down the corridor to the other restaurant. If it had been me, I would have 
added two additional bathrooms to the front of the mostly unused banquet room 
in back. 
 Restaurant: The Upper Crust 
 Location: 27 East Main, Fredonia NY 
 Type: Coffeehouse / Soup and Sandwich Shop 
 Date: Wednesday, January 24th, 2007 
 Rating: **** out of 5 stars 

The Uppercrust, est. 1990 (says so right on the back wall!), has a very 
limited menu. Two or three soups, half a dozen sandwiches, baked goods, and 
the usual varieties of caffeine you find in a coffee shop. Personally, I 
don&apos;t know the difference between an expresso, a latte, or a cappachino, 
nor am I interested in learning. I&apos;m a computer programmer, coffee is hot 
and black and comes in a mug. Period. I&apos;m afraid I can&apos;t judge the quality 
of their coffees.
The baked goods are on display in a bakery display case. It&apos;s the usual 
assortment of muffins, cupcakes and cookies you might order with a coffee or 
a light lunch. If it&apos;s not there, you can&apos;t order it. They do the baking 
during the slow periods of the day. On the plus side, it&apos;s always fresh. 
They also do a good business around Christmas time with pre-ordered cookie 
platters.
The limited sandwich selection might account for their speed. I was there 
with friends from UU and I got my order served within two minutes. I had 
half a club sandwich and an iced tea. I had been pre-warned to order half 
a sandwich unless I was starving because their sandwiches are huge. The 
advice stood me in good stead. I found half a club to be quite good and 
quite filling. Several of my friends raved over their cheese and broccoli 
soup. The bread may have been homemade, it was quite fluffed out like fresh 
bread, not wafer-thin slices like you get from the supermarket. Another 
advantage of the limited menu, is that if you&apos;re in a rush, you can call 
ahead of time and order it and they&apos;ll have it ready for you.
The ambiance is that of a beatnik poet&apos;s coffehouse, especially at night. 
I think that may be intentional. I&apos;d like to see them replace one table with 
a stool and a mike and have open mike night poetry readings. I think they&apos;d 
do a great business. The main table is a huge wooden monster and looks like 
it came right out of a butcher&apos;s warehouse. It&apos;s covered in graffitti. You 
can walk in off the street or park in the community parking lot behind the 
building and come in the back.
It&apos;s just about everything I expect in a soup and sandwich shop, the food is 
hot, filling, delicious and cheap. My meal was five dollars with taxes, 
not including tip. 
 Restaurant: The White Inn 
 Location: 52 East Main Street, Fredonia NY 
 Type: Fine Dining 
 Date: Saturday, January 20th, 2007 
 Rating: ***** out of 5 
 Website: http://www.whiteinn.com 

Last Saturday was &quot;Tea with Terry&quot;, a bi-weekly lunch with our UU minister. 
It turned out that I was the only male who showed up. :)
A brief history of the site (from the menu and their website):
&quot;The property now occupied by The White Inn, once the exclusive domain of 
Indians, came into the hands of Dr. Squire White early in the 19th century. 
He was the first medical doctor to settle and practice in Chautauqua county. 
In 1811 he erected a wood frame house on this site. After a fire destroyed 
the home, Dr. White&apos;s son, Devillo, built a more substantial structure in 1868. 
The University Room and several rooms on the second and third floors are part 
of the original 1868 structure. The wrought iron fence surrounding the 
property dates from this period. The property stayed in the White family until 
1918, when Miss Isabel White, the last remaining White family resident, sold 
the property to Murray Hill Bartley of Westfield, New York. Mr. Bartley 
expanded the property considerably, and in 1919, opened the hotel to the 
traveling public. Located on scenic Route 20, The White Inn flourished and 
became a gathering spot. In the 1930&apos;s, Duncan Hines discovered The White Inn, 
and was so impressed with the restaurant that he included the Inn as one of 
the 50 finest establishments that became his &quot;Family of Fine Restaurants.&quot; 
Over the next four decades, The White Inn went into a period of languishing 
at the hands of several owners. But in 1980, two professors at SUNY College 
at Fredonia bought the property and began a thirteen year project to renovate 
the Inn. Since 1993, Innkeepers Robert Contiguglia and Kathleen Dennison have 
continued the tradition of excellence in outstanding food and lodging.&quot;
It&apos;s a magnificent three story brick mansion, painted white of course. I 
originally thought that was the reason for the name until I read the menu. 
We ate in &quot;The Garden Room&quot;, a dining room with a rose theme. The wallpaper 
is white with red roses, the lace curtains have a white rose design with red 
rose tie-backs. The room dividers are rose printed curtains rather than the 
standard banquet hallplastic fold outs. The rest of the mansion is equally 
furnished in Victorian elegance. There are sitting rooms for informal meetings,
wood paneled conference rooms upstairs for formal meetings, and there&apos;s a 
fireplace in the bar. It&apos;s an utterly gorgeous Victorian mansion. All that 
was missing was a wandering violinist, and I wouldn&apos;t be surprized if they 
have one periodically.
I ordered a Monte Cristo sandwich and iced tea. Since I was the only one at 
the table who ordered a meal that was hot and with meat, I figured I&apos;d be 
served last. My food came out at the same time as everyone else&apos;s. The bread 
wasn&apos;t standard sandwich bread from the supermarket, it was the thick kind 
you associate with homemade. It may have been. The sandwich was huge, hot and 
tasty and it came with homemade hot potato chips, fresh from the fryer! All 
of the meals had very generous portions. They don&apos;t skimp on quantity or 
quality. One woman had ordered hot tea. The waitress brought her a teacup, 
a teapot of hot water and a wooden box. It looked like something a short pool 
cue would come in. When she opened it, it showed off their tea selections for 
the customer to make their own choice.
When we arrived at high noon, we were the only ones in the room. However, the 
place started filling up as we ate and was moderately full by the time we left. 
I was engrossed in personal conversations, so I didn&apos;t make note of how many 
servers were on duty or how well they managed to serve all the tables, but our 
table had no complaints about the service. My meal was $10, not including the 
tip. I intend to come back here during the dinner hour to review them again. 
I also intend to come back when they have a live music night. They also 
co-sponsor &apos;weekend getaways&apos; with the Opera House and various community events. 
 Restaurant: Aldo&apos;s 
 Location: 3rd and Hill Streets, Jamestown 
 Type: Diner 
 Date: Saturday, January 6th, 2007 
 Rating: ***1/2 out of 5 

I&apos;m teaching Chainmail classes at the Scandinavian Studies Group at Jamestown 
Community College. Several other members of the SCA are also teaching Norse 
crafts as well. Classes are the first Saturday of every month, 10AM - Noon. 
After class, we went out to lunch.
Aldo&apos;s is a typical diner. It would fit right in on a Hollywood stage set. 
When we walked in, it took a minute or so before I could see. The lighting 
is a little dim and the blinds were all drawn. Specials are written on a 
&apos;light board&apos;, but it&apos;s directly in front of the door, so everytime someone 
comes in or out, the writing is washed out by sunlight. The carpets are 
well-worn, the wooden paneling well-scraped by chairbacks. The decor is plain. 
The bathrooms were what you&apos;d expect in a greasy spoon.
I ordered iced tea and the gourmet cheeseburger platter. The latter comes 
with onions, fried green peppers and sauteed mushrooms on the burger and 
your choice of french fries, baked potato, home fries or mashed potato on 
the side. I went with french fries.
When the ice tea came, I realized it was fresh brewed, not reconstituted 
from powder. However, the sugar rack was entirely sugar and I used the only 
two sugar substitute packets I could see. A quick glance at other tables 
revealed similar situations.
The food came to the table hot. The burger was done medium well and so good, 
I didn&apos;t even bother with any condiments. The fries got my usual treatment 
of ketchup and salt. I even got a side order of homemade coleslaw. I had 
thought that one of my choices instead of fries, but it comes in addition to 
the fries. It was a generous portion and served in a small glass dish. 
Considering I recently ate in a fancier place and got served slaw in a 
to-go container, I was mildly impressed.
Free refills on the iced tea. Food, not counting tip, was six bucks. 
It was a filling lunch too. At the counter was a certificate. WORD, a 
chautauqua newspaper, recently had a reader&apos;s poll. Aldo&apos;s had been voted 
&quot;Best Local Diner&quot; in Chautauqua County for 2006. 
 Restaurant: The White Horse Inn 
 Location: Route 60, Townline 
 Type: Family Dining 
 Date: Friday, December 29th, 2006 
 Rating: **** out of 5 

The White Horse Inn is on Route 60, literally between the towns of Pomfret and 
Cassadaga. The two town welcome signs face each other across the parking lot. 
They might be able to fit more cars if they pave the gravel parking lot and 
mark spaces in it.
The restaurant was tastefully decorated for the Christmas holidays with a 
large plastic snowflake in each window and a silk white Poinsetta blossom on 
each table. The adjacent bar was slightly less formal in appearance and 
ringed with white icicle lights. Thankfully, there was no Christmas Musak 
blaring at us. There were slight inconsistancies in the presentation, cloth 
napkins, but plastic-coated tablecloths. The coleslaw sides were served in 
plastic to-go containers. The waitresses all wore black slacks with white 
blouses and black aprons. Judging by the variety of cuts and styles, these 
were personal garments rather than an official uniform. There is no clock 
in the dining room, but I could see the time in the clock reflected in the 
bar mirror. :D
Appetizers are in the $7-8 range, most entrees $10-20, all desserts are $5, 
prime rib is only served Thurs thru Sat. Since we were there on a Friday, 
we decided to try two of the Friday fish specials for $8. I ordered the 
sauteed scallops appetizer, a cup of baked French onion soup, the pan-fried 
haddock and a Labatt&apos;s blue. My wife ordered clams casino, New England clam 
chowder, the beer-battered fish and a diet coke because they were out of 
unsweetened ice tea.
The complementary bread loaf came pre-sliced with a small bowl of olive oil 
for dipping rather than the traditional packets of butter. The water glasses 
were cold and had lemon slices. My beer came in a bright blue glass with the 
Labatt&apos;s logo prominently displayed on the side. I don&apos;t know that I&apos;ve ever 
had a drink served to me in a blue glass before.
The clam chowder had carrots and too much celery in it and was very watery 
besides. Karen didn&apos;t care for it. The onion soup on the other hand, was 
excellent and came with a pair of children&apos;s scissors as an eating utensil as 
well as a large soup spoon. Being completely ambidexterous, I had no problem 
holding a spoonful of soup in one hand while using scissors in the other to 
cut it free from the threads of cheese. I can&apos;t help but wonder how less 
dexterous people handle it.
The clams casino were good, but unremarkable. The sauteed scallops were huge, 
requiring that they be quartered before they fit in the mouth. There was a 
half-dozen of them and they were succulent. Two plates of them might 
constitute a meal in and of themselves. They were definitely the big find of 
the night.
Karen&apos;s beer-battered fish came with a side of corn salsa which was probably 
the perfect side dish to counter the slightly greasy taste from frying. 
My pan-fried haddock came with a side dish of pasta salad which included 
tomatoes. Both were cooked well and flaked apart with just a fork. I thought 
it a bit strange that a restaurant that regularly serves a fish fry didn&apos;t 
have malt vinegar as a condiment.
For dessert, we had the Colossol Carrot Cake and the Chocolate Kahlua 
Truffle. The carrot cake had pineapple and walnuts in the batter and was 
iced with a cream cheese topping sprinkled with coconut. Typically good, 
but nothing unique. The truffle was chocolate cake with chocolate Kahlua 
pudding mixed in, served in a sundae glass and topped with whipped cream, 
chocolate syrup and toffee candies. Very rich and very decadent, but it
needs to be washed down with something appropriate. Neither my water nor 
my beer seemed to be the right choice.
We left the restaurant well-stuffed, sated, and satisfied. Appetizers, meal, 
drinks and tip came to less than $70.
We also drove by Four Seasons restaurant. It&apos;s boarded up. I can&apos;t say 
I&apos;m surprized. We tried to eat there once. The booth seats are part of the 
table. Teenagers might be able to fit in those narrow confines, we couldn&apos;t, 
not comfortably. The music was too loud for conversation. The linoleum floor 
was filthy. I could only imagine what the kitchen was like! We left without 
ordering. 
 Restaurant: Four Seasons 
 Type: Family 
 Location: D&amp;F Plaza, Central&amp;Millard Fillmore Avenues 
 Date: Not 
 Rating: ZERO out of five 

The booth seats are part of the table. Teenagers might be able to fit in those 
narrow confines, we couldn&apos;t, not comfortably. The music was too loud for 
conversation. The linoleum floor was filthy. I could only imagine what the 
kitchen was like! We left without ordering.
 Edited to Add: It&apos;s been closed and torn down. We&apos;re hearing
rumors of an Olive Garden at the same location, but so far, just rumor. 
 Restaurant: The Vineyard 
 Type: Family 
 Location: Vineyard Drive 
 Date: Not 
 Rating: ZERO out of five 

The street is named for the restaurant. We never got a chance to eat 
there. It closed within a week of our moving to Fredonia, and was torn
down shortly afterward. There&apos;s now a Dunkin Doughnuts in its place. 
Winery Reviews
 
One of the things we did to celebrate our wedding anniversary was to give ourselves a tour of some of the wineries in the area. We intend to visit all of them eventually, 
 Winery: Schloss Doepkin Winery 
 Location: 9177 Old Route 20, Ripley NY 14775 
 Date: Saturday, October 29th, 2011 
 Website: http://www.sdwines.net p | http://www.lakeeriewinecountry.org/wineries/schloss-doepken-winery 
Old Route 20 is the portion of Route 20 that got cut off when they put the 
thruway in. It&apos;s a long dead-end road with nothing but farms on it. When we 
got to the turnaround at the end of the road, there was a crude sign pointing 
to a dirt road that said Schloss Doepkin on it. When we got to the end of the 
dirt road, we were at a farmhouse. The only indication that this was a winery 
was a well-weathered sign in desperate need of a paint job reading &apos;Wine&apos; and 
a Mastercard/Visa sticker in the window. My wife felt extremely uncomfortable 
with the idea of walking in someone&apos;s house unannounced, so we left.
 Wine sampled: none 
 Winery: Noble Winery 
 Location: 8630 Hardscrabble Road, Westfield NY 14787 
 Date: Saturday, October 29th, 2011 
 Website: www.noblewinery.com | http://www.lakeeriewinecountry.org/wineries/noble-winery 
The highway signs leading you to the winery are bottles on their sides. The 
neck points the way. The unofficial greeter was one of the largest German 
Sheperds I&apos;ve ever seen. The building is an extended pole barn. Inside are 
displays of wine and winery paraphenalia for sale, e.g. fancy stoppers, 
openers, wine racks, T-shirts, sweatshirts, etc. A few tables set up near 
windows. There&apos;s also seating outdoors. The view is spectacular as you&apos;re 
high on an overlook and can see all the way down to Lake Erie. We chose to 
stay at the bar. Cheese platters are available for purchase, crackers are 
free. You can buy 5 tokens for $1. Most wine samples are 1 token, a few are 
2 tokens. The sparkling wines are 5 tokens because the wine will go flat 
shortly after the bottle&apos;s opened. Once the bartender realized that we would 
be buying several bottles, he got a little careless about taking the tokens 
after each serving.

 Wines sampled: (W) Seyval Blanc de Blanc Oaked : Very dry (W) Seyval Blanc de Blanc: Very dry, very little difference in taste (W) Delaware: Sweet (R) Cabernet Sauvignon: Dry (R) Noriet: Spicy (R) Pastavino: Sweet. Literally, &apos;pasta wine&apos; it was designed to go well with tomato sauce dishes. It went very well with pizza! (R) Concord: A dessert wine
 
 Winery: Johnson Estate Winery 
 Location: 8419 US Route 20 West, Westfield NY 14787 
 Date: Saturday, October 29th, 2011 
 Website: www.johnsonwinery.com | http://www.lakeeriewinecountry.org/wineries/johnson-estate-winery 
This was the first place that actually looks like a winery. It&apos;s a rustic 
looking wooden frame building with old farming paraphenalia in the garden area.
The front patio is about the size of someone&apos;s porch with a slate floor, a 
couple of chairs and a milk can for decor. Inside, you can see the copper 
processing tanks. The fruit flies were a little annoying, but I understand 
that a sign of a good winery. Wine samples are free, with baked bread cubes 
to clean the pallet. No chairs inside.

 Wines sampled: (W) Riesling: Much better than Noble&apos;s (R) Cabernet Sauvignon: Karen liked it, David did not (R) Merlot: OK (W) Traminette: Bland (R) Chancellor: Karen liked it, David did not (W) Vidal Blanc: Neither of us liked it (R) Chambourcin: Karen liked it, David did not
 
 Winery: Seven Vines Winery 
 Location: 7580 East Main Road, Westfield NY 14787 
 Date: Saturday, October 29th, 2011 
 Website: http://www.7vineswinery.com | http://www.lakeeriewinecountry.org/wineries/seven-vines-winery 
The building is a former car dealership. And it looks it. The winery is a 
year old this summer. There are a few tables and chairs in the building, but 
you still feel like you&apos;re hanging around a car dealership. We drank standing 
up at the bar in back. The wines are somewhat non-standard, and the names 
are mostly puns.

 Wines sampled: (W) Twilight White: Semi-dry Vidal blend with Cayuga white (W) Cruisin&apos; Cayuga: A light fruity wine, Cayuga grapes were created at Cornell (W) Girls Best Friend: Semi-sweet, fruity. Made from Diamond grapes, hence the name. (W) Ashley Mariesling: Sweet Riesling (R) Moonglow Red: Semi-dry, bland. Server says great for BBQ (W) Fourplay: 40% Riesling, 35% Pinot, 15% Chardonnay, 10% Gewurztraminer hence the name. A good cheese and cracker wine. (R) Madeline Merlot: Bottled that weekend. Okay.
 
 Winery: Vetter Vineyards Winery 
 Location: 8005 Prospect Station Road, Westfield NY 14787 
 Date: Saturday, October 29th, 2011 
 Website: www.vetterwinery.com | http://www.lakeeriewinecountry.org/wineries/vetter-vineyards-winery 
Again, this was someone&apos;s house, however a &apos;store-front&apos; had been built on as 
an addition in back. Another slate patio, but no outdoor furniture. The 
furniture may have been put away in the barn due to the cold weather. A small 
very unfriendly dog runs loose on the property.

 Wines sampled: (W) Gewurztraminer: Spicy fruit taste (W) Victorian Chautauqua: Reisling/Chancellor blend, fruity (W) Dry Riesling: Fruity (R) Pinot Noir: Bland (R) Bell Tower Red: Concord/Chambourcin blend, fruity dessert wine (R) Blueberry: Ugh! (R) Sweet Cherry: Yuck!
 
 Winery: Twenty-One Brix Winery 
 Location: 6634 West Main Road, Portland NY 14769 
 Date: Saturday, October 29th, 2011 
 Website: www.twentyonebrix.com | http://www.lakeeriewinecountry.org/wineries/21-brix-winery 
The winery opened this fall. Our bartender told us the name is a reference 
to the sugar content of the grape. It&apos;s another extended pole barn. The 
porch is a concrete patio that wraps around the building. A sign says &apos;Please 
enjoy our patio&apos; but there are no tables or chairs. The flower garden looks 
like the nursery just made a delivery the day before. There is a display area 
where you can buy souveniers and such.

 Wines sampled: (W) Chardonnay: We liked this one. (R) Noiret: Black pepper, oaky taste, we didn&apos;t like it (R) Cabernet Sauvignon: OK (W) Reisling: We both liked it (R) Brick House Red: Sweet but acceptable (W) Brick House White: Sweet but acceptable (R) Thirsty Elephant: Like drinking strawberry flavored cotton candy, nope.
	</body>
</document>
