<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009554" url="http://www.answerbag.com/q_view/97026" time="2012-07-13-02:56" support="1" score="0.00015009503223503432" bingtitle="You are walking through a field, and you find something to eat. It ..." webtitle="You are walking through a field, and you find something to eat. It doesnt have bones, and it doesnt have meat. You pick it up and put it into your pocket. You take it home and put it on a shelf, but 3 days later it walks away. What is it?  | Answerbag">
			<query id="000400" bing-rank="95"/>
	<description>It was probably the &quot; meat&quot; that they put on your burger @ a fast food restaurant ! ... wash and put away all clothes, pick up dishes and trash, take the trash ...</description>
	<body>
		Ask a Question or Create a Poll 
 Home Categories Questions Forums Blog NEW! 
 
 Arts Autos&amp;Motorcycles Business Computers Diet&amp;Fitness Education Electronics Entertainment Environmentalism Fashion&amp;Beauty Finance Food&amp;Dining Games Health Hobbies Home&amp;Garden Kids Legal Life&amp;Society Pets&amp;Pet Care Real Estate Recreation&amp;Sports Relationship Advice Religion Science Social Sciences Transportation Travel&amp;Places Answerbag Outside the Bag 
 
 Home / Questions / Outside The Bag / Deep Thoughts 
 
by mcclisteraf on December 6th, 2006
 
Question

Help answer this question below.
 
You are walking through a field, and you find something to eat.
It doesn&apos;t have bones, and it doesn&apos;t have meat. You
pick it up and put it into your pocket. You take it home and
put it on a shelf, but 3 day&apos;s later it walks away. What
is it?
 Share your answer here... Want to attach an image to your answer? Click here. 
 
Only upload an image if you have the rights to it,
and ensure that it complies with our terms of use .
 
 Like Report 
 Share: Facebook Twitter Other Sort answers by: Greatness / Likes Date submitted 
Answers. 4 helpful answers below. 
 
 
by babyccat on December 6th, 2006
 
 an egg maybe??? it hatches and the chick walks away???? 
 
Comments

 
that&apos;s correct good job

 Report 
 
by mcclisteraf on December 7th, 2006
 
How warm is your house that an egg will hatch on a shelf!!?

 Report 
 
by WussiePussieHasLetHimselfOutOfTheBag on December 13th, 2006
 
That&apos;s what I was thinking!

 Report 
 
by Anonymous on July 23rd, 2007
 
Awesome!

 Report 
 
by Snooch on July 23rd, 2007
 
It was a good one!

 Report 
 
by Anonymous on July 23rd, 2007
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 5 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by j-man on July 23rd, 2007
 
 It was probably the&quot;meat&quot;that they put on your burger @ a fast food restaurant ! 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by Ruh Roh on January 15th, 2009
 
 an egg. 
 
Comments

 
that was quick. :D

 Report 
 
by ssuess on January 16th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by ssuess on January 17th, 2009
 
 oops, i meant to ask a new question and got stuck in answerville. ;( 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
 Share your answer... Want to attach an image to your answer? Click here. 
 
Only upload an image if you have the rights to it,
and ensure that it complies with our terms of use .
 
Did this answer your question? If not, then ask a new question or create a poll . 
 
More Questions. Additional questions in this category. 

 
 Saw a story about a gal who was born without the ability to see color. She sees black/white/gray. How would you cope if that were you? 
by RosieGHM Jetpacker 11 hours ago
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 how can we ever have world peace if there are men in this World who believes Good&amp;Evil can co exist? 
by andy11-11 11 hours ago
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 The smarter you are the better your sense of humor or is there no correlation between smart and sense of humor? 
by RosieGHM Jetpacker 11 hours ago
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 Is your to and fro/ ebb and flow/ filled with woe or Ho Ho Ho? Happy there or plan to change it? Why? 
by RosieGHM Jetpacker 11 hours ago
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 Do haters age more quickly than those who don&apos;t? Do the constantly angry/upset/perturbed pay a price for it? Do they have more wrinkles? 
by RosieGHM Jetpacker 12 hours ago
 
 | 1 person likes this
 More Deep thoughts See only professionally researched Deep thoughts questions 
 
You&apos;re reading You are walking through a field, and you find something to eat. It doesn&apos;t have bones, and it doesn&apos;t have meat. You pick it up and put it into your pocket. You take it home and put it on a shelf, but 3 day&apos;s later it walks away. What is it? 
 - which can also be phrased in the following ways:

 While walking in a field of wheat, i found something good to eat, it was neither flesh nor bone, yet left it would walk alone. what is it? 
 
Follow us on Facebook!
 
Related Ads
 
Related Questions

 
 How much should i charge to clean single family home 3brm,3bthrm, i wash and put away all clothes, pick up dishes and trash, take the trash out, load and unload the dishwasher, on top of all the dusting,vaccuming, mopping, and whatever else he thinks of! 
 
 Got away with shoplifting 3 times in past week. Seen by clerk 4th time but put object on shelf and runs away in time. If store has CCTV, can they review it and find my face on the cam from few days ago and use my check info to find sum1 and catch them? 
 
 My dog is left inside for part of the day and when I come home is always takes off as soon as the front door is open. I do take him for walks and as he has got older he&apos;s more arthritic. But this running away every time I get home is driving me crazy. 
 
 If you were going to break into a 3 story apartment complex, which floor are you more likely to break into? And are you more likely to pick the apartment closer to the parking lot or furthest away? I need to put my mind at ease. 
 
 The break light turned on in my car and the very next day I take my car and it hardly breaks at all... I&apos;m almost 100% sure it&apos;s the break fluid.... I can&apos;t find where to put the break fluid? Help? Is this something I can do myself? 
 
 
Professionally Researched
 
 
 Why should you put away patio furniture to enhance home security? 
 
 How often does a giraffe eat a day? 
 
 What is the highest memory you can put on an R4 card? 
 
 How do I put up martin houses? 
 
 Do rhinos really put out fires? 
 
 
ANSWERBAG BUZZ
 You are walking through a field and you find something to eat It doesn t have bones and it doesn t have meat You pick it up and put it into your pocket You take it home and put it on a shelf but 3 day s later it walks away What is it You are walking through a field and you find something to eat You are walking through a field and you find something to eat You are walking through a field and you find something to eat It doesn t have bones and it doesn t have meat You pick it up and put it into your pocket You take it home and put it on a shelf but 3 day s later it walks away What is it Can you eat wheat from a field 
 About Us About Answerbag Sitemap Professionally Researched Questions   Legal Privacy Policy Terms of Use Disclaimer Ad Choices   Follow Us on Facebook 
 Answerbag.com 
Your favorite Q&amp;A site is on Facebook! Become a fan to connect with the ever-growing community of Answerbaggers, share your thoughts and find out what Answerbag&apos;s up to next!

 Latest Tweet Are you for or against #spanking #children? http://t.co/cCcsCE1M http://t.co/CbL5MCH4 
 Follow Answerbag on Twitter! 
 
 
Answerbag

 AB4Adults Answerbag UK
	</body>
</document>
