<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009123" url="http://www.bizbuysell.com/Business-Opportunity/Convenience-Store-Nice-Operation/574315/" time="2012-07-13-02:31" support="1" score="0.0006699961983734229" bingtitle="Convenience Store--Nice Operation: Business For Sale in Arizona on ..." webtitle="Convenience Store--Nice Operation: Business For Sale in Arizona on BizBuySell.com">
			<query id="001044" bing-rank="97"/>
	<description>Seller is asking $100,000 as a down payment and will ... Mexican Fast Food Restaurant--Just Reduced. Phoenix, AZ (Maricopa ... Please enter a valid phone number. Please enter ...</description>
	<body>
		Already a BizBuySell Member?

Log In to Continue
 


Invalid log in. Check your user name and password.
 Email Address (Member ID): Password: 
 Verifying... 
 
 Forgot Your Password? 

 Note : The email address you provided matches an existing account. Please log in using this email address and your original password. If you don&apos;t recall your password, click the &apos;Forgot Your Password?&apos; link.
 
 Are you new to BizBuySell? 
 
 
BizBuySell - The Internet&apos;s Largest Business for Sale&amp;Franchise for Sale Marketplace
 
 Welcome! Sign In Register For Brokers 

 My BizBuySell BrokerWorks 
 My Listings My Watch List My Saved Searches My BizAlerts My Ad Responses My Ad Inquiries My Valuation Reports My Community Questions My Community Answers My Profile 
 Sign Out For Brokers 
 
 
 
 
Convenience Store--Nice Operation

 Phoenix, Arizona (Maricopa County) 
   Asking Price: $135,000 
 Gross Income: $385,000 
 Cash Flow: $96,000 
 EBITDA: N/A 
 FF&amp;E;: $50,000.00 * 
 Inventory: $25,000.00 ** 
 Real Estate: N/A 
 Year Established: 2001 
 Employees: N/A 
 Business Types: Convenience Stores 
 Supermarkets 
 
** not included in the asking price

* included in the asking price
 
Business Description

 Seller is asking $100,000 as a down payment and will carry the balance of $35,000 for 3 years at 8 percent interest which would make the buyer&apos;s monthly payment to seller $1,096.78. The financial information was provided by the seller and not verified by the broker. The C-store is currently owner operated with some parttime help. The hours are Monday-Friday 8:30am-10pm, Saturday 10am-10pm, and Sunday 10am-8pm. A #10 liquor license is in place that allows the sale of beer and wine to go. The seller participates in the sale of lottery tickets as well as the sale of phone cards. The store is nicely set up and has large sections of reach-in coolers. This is a good business with excellent lease terms. The surrounding area has a nice mix of businesses, offices, houses, condos, and apartments. A good money maker and a must see!! 

Detailed Information
 Facilities: 1975 square feet. $2392 monthly rent. lease expires january, 2015. there is one 5 year option. Financing: See Listing Summary. Support/Training: Seller will train buyer for one week free. Reason Selling: Other Interests. 
Broker Information
 
 MARY ZORDAN 

 View all of my current business-for-sale listings View my BizBuySell Profile 
 
Similar Listings
 
 

 Bear/wine Store for sale . 

 Mesa/Apache Junction, AZ 
Asking Price: $75,000 

 
 
 

 #6 Neighborhood Bar 

 Phoenix, AZ (Maricopa County) 
Asking Price: $95,000 

 
 
 

 #12 Pizzeria/Sports Bar 

 Mesa, AZ (Maricopa County) 
Asking Price: $120,000 

 
 
 View all businesses for sale in Maricopa County 
 
Contact the Seller

= required
 
 Please enter all required information. Please enter a valid email address. Please enter a valid phone number. Please enter a valid zip code. Please enter a valid invest amount. Please enter a valid decision time frame. Please move the slider to the right to unlock. Your email was not sent. Please try again. 
 Your Name Your Email Your Phone Please send me additional information about this business. If I find the right business, I am able to invest $  (from currently available resources) I plan to make a decision on a business within months Sign up for the Buyer Newsletter Learn how to use your IRA/401K to purchase a business - Guidant Financial (Min. $50k needed in IRA/401K) 
 Business For Sale Listed By

 Mary Zordan 
 JANCO WEST BUSINESS BROKERS 
 602-978-3313 
 
Listing Actions

 Watch this listing You are watching this listing Print this listing 
Your email has been sent! Email this listing 
 Email this listing 
 
Email This Listing

= required
 
 Please enter all required information. Please enter your valid email address. Please enter your friend&apos;s valid email address. Your email was not sent. Please try again. 
 Your Name Your Email Friend&apos;s Email 
Sending...
 
Sharing Actions

 
 

 
Valuation Report

Find the value of similar businesses for sale and recently sold on BizBuySell

 
 
Ad#: 574315 

The information in this listing has been provided by the business seller or representative stated above. BizBuySell has no stake in the sale of this business, has not independently verified any of the information about the business, and assumes no responsibility for its accuracy or completeness. Read BizBuySell&apos;s terms&amp;conditions before responding to any ad.
 
 
 
 
 
 advertise terms&amp;conditions privacy policy about us contact us careers site map mobile 
 
 
 
©1996 - 2012 BizBuySell.com®   |
	</body>
</document>
