<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009718" url="http://reportyourcomplaint.com/what-car-insurance-company-is-the-best-progressive-geico-nationwide-read-on-to-find-out/" time="2012-07-13-03:06" support="1" score="0.000971525628474203" bingtitle="What car insurance company is the best? Progressive? Geico ..." webtitle="What car insurance company is the best? Progressive? Geico? Nationwide? Read on to find out! | Report Your Complaint.com">
			<query id="001462" bing-rank="40"/>
	<description>Who wants a car insurance company that you can’t ... great deal you soon no longer are and then you end ... Customer service disgusting Educational fast food fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In 
 
 RYC (Home) Companies Complaints Reviews Compliments Helpful tips&amp;info Credit repair About us Site Index Blog 
 

 
Random Posts

 iheartradio Application Compliment - Free Radio Station Streaming Straight From Your Smartphone The Pirate Bay, illegal pirated downloads, free software and music and the RIAA Tornado fuel saver review - does it really increase fuel economy or is it just another scam? Queen City Hydroponics review - want to grow some great medical marijuana or just want your own stash to get high with? You need to check out Queen City Hydroponics! Restaurant.com Gift Certificate Website Review - Easy Way to Save Money on Dining Out All Over The United States Cici’s Pizza Buffet Review – Amazing Food, Great Prices, and Awesome Customer Service! FedEx - Kinkos copy center review - very professional and great quality paper copying services. Budget Truck rental review and a bad turn in and truck rental experience! Bin Laden or Bin Laden look alike spotted at Walmart on N. Tryon in Charlotte, NC! Trulia Real Estate Search Application Review - I Was Able To See Real Estate For Sale As I Was Driving On A Live Map! 
 
Recent Comments

 skyday on Great Stuff insulating foam sealant review–this stuff works great for sealing and insulating gaps and cracks SCAM on Childhood leukemia Foundation–a review of a shady charity that uses auto dialers and other shady practices to get donations Mike on HomeVestors home buyers is a shady scam and offers you far less than your home is worth! Chris Brady on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? Lee on Stanley Steemer–fraudulant business practices, abusive telemarketing and a bad rug cleaning experience! Lisa Carroll on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? brenda on Walgreen’s pharmacy–incorrectly filled prescription and they refused to fix it! S.K. Thompson on Virginia State Troopers Complaint–Police officers have too much power and get away with breaking laws! 
 Privacy Policy 
What car insurance company is the best? Progressive? Geico? Nationwide? Read on to find out!
 By Allard T. 
So who really has the best car insurance at the best price with the best customer service? Progressive!
 



If you’re like most people this recession has hit you hard in the pocketbook and seriously cramped your finances. So you’re looking to save money anywhere you can. I don’t blame you. I am doing the exact same thing myself everyday. At one place that we can all save money on is car insurance.

But the first thing you have to ask yourself is this–is the lowest price the best deal? As with many things in life the lowest rate car insurance may not be the best deal out there and it may also not offer you the best coverage or customer service. Customer service with car insurance is a really big deal.

Who wants a car insurance company that you can’t get a hold of when you need them. Or how about one that drops you for no reason and with no warning. Or one that just decides to raise your rates constantly so when you thought your Ridgely getting a great deal you soon no longer are and then you end up paying far more in the end.

Shopping around is the best way to get the best deal on car insurance. Don’t listen to the TV as for Nationwide, Allstate and Geico were they say they save money when you switch to their car insurance from the others. What they are doing is kind of like false advertising because maybe Geico offers a better rate well for a Ford Mustang GT 2000, whereas Allstate offers a better rate for the convertible and Geico has a better rate for the V6 coupe.

You have to actually go and get a quote whether it be through the phone or in person from each of these companies and then compare them. What you will find nine times out of 10 is that usually none of these is the lowest or the best coverage. I have been around for a long time and every year I call all the insurance companies to see who has the best rates and the best coverage for my vehicles.


 Your Ad Here 


The funny thing is that every year I do it I come up with the exact same answer–Progressive always beats out the others by several hundred dollars or even more. Now the next thing you want to look at is customer service. Nationwide, Allstate and State Farm representatives, in my book, have a lot to learn about customer service.

These independent insurance agents think that once you sign with them that you are locked in for life and treat you like dirt. I was insured with Nationwide Insurance for several years until I found that for the same exact vehicle Progressive was $1,600 less per year! That’s a pretty substantial savings in car insurance!

I did not have any points on my record and didn’t have any accidents. I always paid every payment on time and was a great customer.   I have to say was because as soon as I found that out I switched to Progressive.  I then found that progressive actually treated me far better.  If I have to call them about something they don’t put me on hold or treat me like dirt.

I have dealt with Nationwide, All State, State Farm, Geico and Progressive and out of all these car insurance companies the best by far was progressive.  In one instance Geico did offer a slightly better deal that was $150 less per year in insurance.  It apparently just is that they had a lower rate on a van I used to have.  GEICO is not bad either, they just tend to be a tad bit more expensive than Progressive.

But I will say this, both Geico and Progressive have far better customer service than all the other car insurance companies put together.



 
Posts Related to What car insurance company is the best? Progressive? Geico? Nationwide? Read on to find out!

 
 GEICO car insurance review and complaint–I didn’t see any savings like they promise in their TV ads! 

// You&apos;ve seen the TV commercials where GEICO car insurance proclaims that they save customers that switch to them an average of $500. While I ...
 
 Nationwide car insurance–ridiculously high rates–they charged 4 times more than what Progressive does! 

// I used nationwide car insurance because my parents did and I thought that they would be good to me like they were to my ...
 
 GEICO Auto Insurance and Feeling Screwed and Ripped Off! 

// Last summer I was involved in a car wreck where I was rear-ended by a criminal fleeing from the police. I suffered some minor ...
 
 Aetna health insurance–if you are looking for health insurance coverage at a good price be sure and skip right over Aetna especially if you have a pre-existing condition! 

// If you&apos;re shopping around for health insurance are many numerous companies out there that you can look at. From Blue Cross and Blue Shield ...
 
 MVP insurance company could be putting you at risk? 

// I wanted to write about how insurance companies (and in this case MVP Insurance in New York) are taking less interest in their patients ...
 
 
 Tags: Allstate , automotive , car , car insurance , GEICO , GEICO auto insurance , helpful information , insurance , insurance company , Nationwide , Nationwide car insurance , Progressive , Progressive car insurance , review , save money , State Farm , State Farm car insurance 
 
2 Responses to What car insurance company is the best? Progressive? Geico? Nationwide? Read on to find out! 

 Lucy on September 10, 2010 at 10:03 PM 

I read this and I have to say that I am happy with my Nationwide insurance guy. He is really nice to me and I have never had a problem with him or their insurance. However, I am going to call around and see about lower prices for the same coverage. If I can save some money I am all for it!

Like or Dislike: 1   0 
 ZM on October 18, 2010 at 2:24 PM 

Progressive was charging me $95 a month while Farmers is charging me $38 a month. Progressive is a rip off.

Like or Dislike: 1   0 
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
Search Website
 Most Popular
Complaints, Reviews, and Compliments! Want your company&apos;s product or service reviewed?
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 Your Ad Here 
Tags
 automotive Awesome bad customer service car car dealer car dealership chain restaurants Charlotte Charlotte NC complaint compliment Customer service disgusting Educational fast food fast food restaurant food fraud health Helpful helpful information highly recommended honest review Horrible horrible customer service horrible service How to illegal Interesting Not recommended rave recommended restaurant review ripoff rude save money scam sucks Terrible unfair business practices unhealthy untrustworthy Walmart website Copyright©2012 Report Your Complaint.com . All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
