<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009607" url="http://www.menupages.com/restaurants/bread/" time="2012-07-13-03:00" support="3" score="0.007076942623766347" bingtitle="Bread - New York Restaurant - MenuPages Italian, Mediterranean ..." webtitle="Bread - New York Restaurant - MenuPages Italian, Mediterranean, Sandwiches Restaurant Search">
			<query id="001145" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="001156" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000670" bing-rank="60"/>
	<description>Phone: work (212) 334-1015 Fax: fax (212) 334-1019 Place Order: Order From This Restaurant Notes: Delivery Take Out Catering Visa, MC Hours: Sun-Thu: 10:30am-12am Fri ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to MenuPages - Please Select a city:

 New York City San Francisco Los Angeles Philadelphia Boston Chicago Washington, DC South Florida 
 New Menupages Desintations London   Paris 
 hide 
 
 Home Blog My MenuPages Restaurateurs Submit a Menu Change City Food Delivery Login 
 
 MenuPages 

Now Serving: 11183 Menus for New York City Restaurants
 
 Search Advanced Find-A-Food 
 
 Areas Neighborhood All Areas Brooklyn East Village/ LES Midtown East Midtown South / Chelsea Midtown West Murray Hill / Gramercy Soho/Trbca/FinDist Upper East Side Upper West Side Uptown Village/ W Village All Neighborhoods Bath Beach Bay Ridge Bedford-Stuyvesant Bensonhurst Borough Park Brighton Beach / Manhattan Beach Brooklyn Hts / DUMBO Brownsville Bushwick Canarsie Central Village / Noho Chelsea / Midtown South Chinatown / Two Bridges Cobble Hill / Carroll Grdns Coney Island Crown Heights Ditmas Park Dyker Heights East 30&apos;s East 40&apos;s East 50&apos;s East 60&apos;s East 70&apos;s East 80&apos;s East 90&apos;s East Harlem East New York East Village Financial District Flatbush Flatiron / Union Square Flatlands Fort Hamilton Ft. Greene / Clinton Hill Gramercy / Kips Bay Gravesend Harlem Kings Highway / Homecrest Lefferts Gardens Lower East Side Marine Park / Gerritsen Beach Midwood Mill Basin / Bergen Beach Morningside Heights Park Slope / Prospect Hts Prospect Park South / Kensington Sheepshead Bay Soho / Little Italy Sunset Park Tribeca Washington Hts / Inwood West 30&apos;s West 40&apos;s West 50&apos;s West 60&apos;s West 70&apos;s West 80&apos;s West 90&apos;s&amp;100&apos;s West Village Williamsburg / Greenpoint Cuisines All Cusines Afghan African American (New) American (Traditional) Argentinean Asian (other) Asian Fusion Australian Austrian Bagels Bakeries Bar Food Barbecue Belgian Bistro Brazilian British (Modern) British (Traditional) Burgers Burmese Cafes&amp;Coffeehouses Cajun&amp;Creole Californian Caribbean Central American Central Asian Cheesesteaks Chicken Chinese Cocktails Crepes Cuban Delis Desserts Dim Sum Diners&amp;Coffee Shops Dutch Eastern European Eclectic&amp;International Ethiopian Filipino Fish&amp;Chips French Gastropub German Greek Haitian Hawaiian Health Food Hot Dogs Indian Indonesian Irish Italian Jamaican Japanese Korean Kosher Latin American Local/Organic Malaysian Mediterranean Mexican Middle Eastern Moroccan New England Noodle Shops Nuevo Latino Other Pakistani Persian Peruvian Pizza Polish Portuguese Puerto Rican/Dominican Russian Salads Sandwiches Scandinavian Seafood Small Plates/Tapas Smoothies/Juice Bar Soups South American Southern&amp;Soul Southwestern Spanish Sri Lankan Steakhouses Sushi Swiss Teahouses Thai Tibetan Turkish Vegan Vegetarian-Friendly Venezuelan Vietnamese Wild Game Wine Bar Wings Street Zip code Cross street Restaurant name 
 
Hold down Control (PC) or Command (Mac) key + mouseclick to select more than one option
 
 
Bread
 + SHARE 


 $$$ 
 Rating Avg. Dinner Entrée $$$$$ Greater than $25 $$$$ $18.01 - $25 $$$ $12.01 - $18 $$ $7.01 - $12 $ Less than $7 
 Italian, Mediterranean, Sandwiches 20 Spring St , New York   NY 10012 40.7213851 -73.9950759 (Btwn Elizabeth&amp;Mott St) Subway Directions 
 
 Order From This Restaurant› 
 
 
 
 Phone: (212) 334-1015 
 
 Profile&amp;Reviews Menu http://www.menupages.com/restaurants/bread/menu Report Errors Add to
My MenuPages Email 
 Facebook Twitter + MORE 
 
 
 Reviews + Photos from nymag.com
 
User Ratings (Based on 64 reviews) 
 3.49 5 
 Food 3.7 Value 3.5 Service 2.9 Atmosphere 3.8 
 
 Rate and Review this restaurant 
 
Other Restaurant Info
 Phone: work (212) 334-1015 Fax: fax (212) 334-1019 Place Order: Order From This Restaurant Notes: Delivery Take Out Catering Visa, MC Hours: Sun-Thu: 10:30am-12am Fri-Sat: 10:30am-1am Brunch Sat-Sun: 10:30am-5pm Serves: Lunch,
 
 Dinner,
 
 Brunch Features: Open Late,
 
 Outdoor Dining,
 
 People Watching,
 
 Trendy,
 
 Gluten Free Items,
 
 Delivery,
 
 Online Ordering,
 
 Accepts Credit Cards,
 
 Lunch Special,
 
 Take Out,
 
 Catering,
 
 Private Parties Min Delivery: 20.00 Delivery Area: 4th to Canal St; Hudson to Pitt St 
User Reviews
 
 Bread 
 Posted by SNCS on 05/28/2012 
 
Great find
 
We were looking for a quick bite early on Saturday and came across&quot;BREAD&quot;. We were promptly served and the food and atmosphere were excellent. Had breaded baked eggplant for a starter, an aged salami bread, my wife fresh linguini with asparagus and pesto, and the kids split spinach ravioli. We all enjoyed our food, the bread and olive oil was good too!
 Bread 
 Posted by zooey on 10/03/2011 
 
waited forever - food disappointing
 
was looking for a new place and ordered dinner from bread on a whim - delivery took over an hour and the food was a huge disappointment. my boyfriend had a chicken sandwich . . . which didn&apos;t have much chicken in it at all. was pressed within an in of its life and looked like cardboard. I had a salad which was OK, but not worth an hour. won&apos;t be ordering from here again.
 Bread 
 Posted by giovanni on 05/12/2011 
 
I love this place
 
I just got here from Italy and I been having a hard time finding a good Italian place. There are many Italian restaurant and some are good but usually overpriced. Bread made me feel at home, simple food ( the pesto is great!) and the stuff was friendly and full of smiles. I dont miss Rome now.
 Bread 
 Posted by alexiscollidge on 04/01/2011 
 
Great Meatballs!
 
I ordered from Bread tonight with my girlfriend. The meatballs were so delicious! WE loved it.
 Bread 
 Posted by amanda on 03/20/2011 
 
Not the best experience
 
This place had a nice atmosphere and decent menu with decent prices. We waited at the back bar for our table and drank watery sangria. It was so busy that the servers and hostess seemed confused and inattentive. I was told that the kitchen was too busy to make my omelet with egg whites instead of eggs. While I was irritated by that, the food came quickly and was not bad.
 Bread 
 Posted by nolitaeater on 01/29/2011 
 
I love bread!
 
I eat here or order delivery at least once a week. the salads and soup are delicious and fresh. the staff is always super nice. im a big fan and supporter!
 Bread 
 Posted by maximiliano on 01/18/2011 
 
falso cibo italiano
 
i ordered from bread earlier tonight with my girlfriend...it take over an hour..i had 2 pastas and a sanwich for 38 $...opened the brown paper bag..ready to eat my meal...which was cold...the pesto sauce in the pasta was the worst creamy pesto i ever had..im a native italian so i know. over priced, smalll portians....bad service. ciao
 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 › » 
 
 Rate and Review this restaurant 
 
Advertising
 
Movies near Bread
 Angelika Film Center 
18 W. Houston St.

NEW YORK
 To Rome With Love  (R) Dark Horse  (NR) A Cat in Paris  (PG) The Intouchables  (R) More Nearby theaters» 
 Ticketing provided by
 
Hot and Fresh Restaurant News Delivered Weekly
 You are signing up to receive: Weekly updates delivered straight to your inbox covering the latest restaurant news, menus, openings, closings, and food events Menupages NYC Newsletter You may also be interested in: Hear about special offers from MenuPages or its partners about future events, promotions and features. Offers&amp;Promotions Sign Up 
Thanks for subscribing!

You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you selected.

To enjoy more benefits and personalization available on MenuPages.com, register now! 
 Checkbox is required 
Advertising
 
 About Us Careers Contact Us Advertise With Us Restaurateurs Privacy Policy Legal Notices Copyright Notice 

©2002-2012 Slick City Media, Inc. All Rights Reserved. MenuPages®is a trademark of Slick City Media, Inc. Disclaimer
	</body>
</document>
