<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009528" url="http://www.franchiseadvantage.com/Franchises/4-Food_Service_Retail_Franchises.aspx" time="2012-07-13-02:55" support="1" score="0.008677794605678907" bingtitle="Food Franchise for Sale, Restaurant Franchise Opportunities for ..." webtitle="Food Franchise for Sale, Restaurant Franchise Opportunities for Sale on FranchiseAdvantage.com">
			<query id="001254" bing-rank="77"/>
	<description>Great Food Franchises for Sale - Pizza, Fast-Food ... You get to choose where you work, when you work, and who ... sive support from initial contact through site selection ...</description>
	<body>
		FranchiseAdvantage.com Your Request Basket (0 Items) 
 Home Franchise Search Businesses for Sale Resource Center Contact Us 
 Follow us: 
Food Franchises
 
Franchise Advantage&apos;s Restaurant&amp;Food Franchise and Business Opportunities Directory provides in-depth profiles of pizza, coffee, restaurant, sub shop, food, and other related restaurant and fast food franchises and business opportunities. If you have a passion for food, then owning a food franchise could be perfect for you!
   Request more information by checking the box next to each franchise you are interested in, then click the &quot;Add Selected Franchises to Request Basket&quot; button at the top or bottom of the page. 
 Kona-Ice 
   Explosive 400% Growth, Amazing Margins, and Unbeatable Support all make Kona Ice a No Brainer! Still Available In Every Major Market! Capital Required: $20,000   
 Dickey&apos;s Barbecue 
   Spreading faster than a brush-fire in July with locations around the country, Dickey&apos;s BBQ offers Texas-Sized profits! Capital Required: $50,000   
 Naturals To Go 
   Enjoy the freedom that comes with owning a vending business. You get to choose where you work, when you work, and who you work with. A career in vending is all about maximizing your income while minimizing time spent working. Capital Required: $25,000   
 Healthy Vending by HUMAN 
   HUMAN stands for &quot;Helping Unite Mankind And Nutrition&quot; and we started the Healthy Vending Industry back in 2003. We&apos;re looking for top 10% entrepreneurs to &quot;crush it&quot; with their own quickly growing, ridiculously fun, incredibly fulfilling, health&amp;nutrition franchise. In short, we help entrepreneurs launch and grow their own healthy vending businesses so they can make money, help people, and become truly fulfilled. Capital Required: $70,000   
 Quiznos Sub 
   Here at Quiznos we believe in giving every entrepreneur the head-start they deserve. In other words, we&apos;ve just made it faster, easier, and more affordable than ever to own a Quiznos! Capital Required: $70,000   
 Beef &apos;O&apos; Brady&apos;s Family Sports Pub 
   With 216 neighborhood sports pub franchise locations in the U.S.&amp;over 50 opening in 2007, Beef O Brady&apos;s sports-themed restaurant concept is expanding! Capital Required: $125,000   
 Checkers Drive In Restaurants 
   Checkers Drive-In Restaurants, Inc. is the largest double drive-thru restaurant chain in the United States. The Company develops, owns, operates and franchises quick-service Checkers® and Rally&apos;s® double drive-thru restaurants. Capital Required: $200,000   
 GNC Live Well 
   The leading specialty retailer of nutritional products, GNC has dominated franchising for over 22 years. Capital Required: $85,000   
 The Hungry Greek 
   Our loyal customers know firsthand that The Hungry Greek is the place to be if you?re looking for authentic, great tasting Greek food! Capital Required: $150,000   
 Woody&apos;s Bar-B-Q Canada 
   Woody&apos;s has a lower start-up entry cost and outstanding franchisee support and is a great opportunity within the fast-growing casual dining segment. Capital Required: $50,000   
 The Brass Tap 
   The Brass Tap is an upscale beer bar that offers 60 different craft beers on tap, more than 300 varieties of imports, local craft beers, and a large selection of premium wines and cigars. We constantly are searching for the best beers from all regions around the world, and rotate our taps to ensure that you can always expect to find a new favorite. Capital Required: $100,000   
 Rosati&apos;s Pizza Franchising 
   Our Rosatiʼs Brand products are created from family recipes that have been handed down from generation to generation for more than 40 years. They have been blended exclusively for us by the highest quality manufacturers in the industry. Products are delivered to our stores by national distributors on a weekly basis. Capital Required: $70,000   
 BGR The Burger Joint 
   BGR The Burger Joint--We are looking for just the right people to be part of a exclusive and limited opportunity, within an exploding industry. Provide the highest quality burger, in an upscale atmosphere, for a reasonable price. It&apos;s no wonder our customers love us and come back for more! Capital Required: $200,000   
 Goodcents Deli Fresh Subs 
   Goodcents opened the first franchised restaurant on May 31, 1990 in Overland Park, Kansas. There are over 122 Restaurant franchises in operation today! Capital Required: $50,000   
 Scooter&apos;s Coffee&amp;Yogurt 
   Scooter&apos;s recipe for greatness equals uncompromised product quality, proven and successful financial business models, and uncompromised quality of franchise support, coupled with a select group of excellent and compatible franchisees. Capital Required: $100,000   
 Bruster&apos;s Real Ice Cream 
   Bruster&apos;s Real Ice Cream is the fresh opportunity you&apos;ve been looking for. Consistently ranked among the nation&apos;s top franchises by Entrepreneur Magazine. We&apos;re one of the fastest growing ice cream franchises. Capital Required: $75,000   
 America&apos;s Taco Shop® 
   At America&apos;s Taco Shop, we offer a dining experience unlike that of your typical quick-service restaurant. To put it simply, we&apos;re passionate about good food. You&apos;re not going to find our recipes in a cookbook - we use the same recipes that America&apos;s family has perfected in their kitchens for generations. Capital Required: $90,000   
 Woody&apos;s Bar-B-Q 
   Woody&apos;s has a lower start-up entry cost and outstanding franchisee support and is a great opportunity within the fast-growing casual dining segment. Capital Required: $80,000   
 Papa Murphy&apos;s Pizza 
   Personal and professional success can come in many delicious varieties. But you&apos;ve not made it until you&apos;ve made a fresh Papa Murphy&apos;s pizza. Our franchise owner/operators - entrepreneurs just like you - have made us the world&apos;s largest, fastest growing Take &apos;N&apos; Bake pizza franchise and America&apos;s best pizza chain seven years in a row.* So if you&apos;re interested in joining a franchise family that&apos;s really going places, Papa Murphy&apos;s is the opportunity for you. Capital Required: $80,000   
 It&apos;s A Grind Coffee House 
   As a neighborhood coffee house with a blues and jazz motif, It&apos;s A Grind Coffee House features the highest quality espresso and iced blended coffee drinks, bagels, muffins, scones and assorted bakery items. Capital Required: $200,000   
 Patrice&amp;Associates Hospitality Recruiting 
   Patrice&amp;Associates is one of the largest recruiting firms in the U.S., specializing in the hospitality industry. Turnkey Work from Home Opportunity! Capital Required: $30,000   
 My Favorite Muffin 
   BAB, Inc. is a growing, publicly traded franchisor of its bagel, muffin, and coffee cafe concepts. Over 250 locations in the U.S. and overseas. Capital Required: $80,000   
 Cousins Subs 
   Cousins Subs is a Midwest-based franchise chain in the fast growing sub sandwich segment. Our guests love our food, and our franchisees respect our organization. Our vision of excellence keeps us growing and our guests coming back. Capital Required: $80,000   
 Marble Slab Creamery 
   Marble Slab Creamery has built its reputation by specializing in super-premium ice cream with the finest ingredients since 1983. Capital Required: $90,000   
 Farr&apos;s Fresh 
   Is it the right time for you to invest in yourself and start your own business? Are you looking for a unique concept that can be run as a full-time venture or as an absentee owner? Farr&apos;s Fresh is &quot;Your Happy Place&quot;. If you are interested in low labor cost, great margins, a strong ROI and an exciting business to own, then a Farr&apos;s Fresh franchise could be right for you. Capital Required: $70,000   
 Great American Cookies 
   Founded on the strength of an old family chocolate chip cookie recipe, the Great American Cookie franchise has set the standard for gourmet cookies. Capital Required: $95,000   
 The Fuzzy Peach 
   The Fuzzy Peach is a rapidly expanding frozen yogurt concept whose vision is to become synonymous with dessert nationwide. The Fuzzy Peach will accomplish this by offering the Best Products with World-Class Customer Service in a Clean and Inviting Atmosphere. Capital Required: $70,000   
 Doc Popcorn 
   The Doc Popcorn Franchise concept is fun, will make you smile, and is certainly no joke. In its first year of franchising, Doc Popcorn awarded 22 agreements. This makes Doc Popcorn one of the fastest growing snack franchises on the planet. Capital Required: $70,000   
 Figaro&apos;s Pizza 
   Figaro&apos;s Pizza is one of the country&apos;s fastest-growing, most respected pizza franchises. Consumers love the food and 
you&apos;ll love the system. Capital Required: $150,000   
 Toppers Pizza 
   People are fanatical about Toppers Pizza! We can&apos;t say exactly how it happened, but somewhere along the way we got very popular. Our customers are fanatics, really beyond what&apos;s reasonable based simply on our great service. Capital Required: $100,000   
 Wings Etc. 
   In today&apos;s competitive food service environment, having the right system, the right team, and the right training makes all the difference. Wings Etc. provides comprehen­sive support from initial contact through site selection, buildout, pre-opening, grand opening and beyond. Capital Required: $100,000   
 Ritter&apos;s Frozen Custard 
   Ritter&apos;s Frozen Custard is an award winning ice cream franchise. We offer a proprietary, super-premium ice cream menu Capital Required: $200,000   
 Wall Street Deli 
   With locations in 14 markets in 12 different states, we are an upscale, big city style deli with a down home charm. Capital Required: $200,000   
 Carl&apos;s Jr. 
   At Carl´s Jr.®, we are known for our best-in-class menu that consistently out-delivers the competition. With years of remarkable growth and performance, Carl´s Jr.® has become the greatest franchise story of our time. Capital Required: $500,000   
 VOM FASS 
   VOM FASS, recent winner of the prestigious German Franchise of the Year is now available in the United States! Offering the best culinary oils, fruit and balsamic vinegars, and the finest rare spirits and liqueurs the world offers. Capital Required: $80,000   
 Gloria Jean&apos;s Coffees 
   With over 900 locations worldwide and more than 20 years of experience in franchising, at Gloria Jean&apos;s Coffees you&apos;re teaming up with one of the 2nd largest, most experienced franchise coffee companies around. We believe we have the organization, experience and support that leads to success. Our system is established and has passed the test of time. Capital Required: $200,000   
 House of Bread 
   House of Bread is a bakery cafe concept. We focus on using the finest ingredients. Capital Required: $100,000   
 Brixx Franchise Systems 
   Get fired up! Everybody goes home happy. Customers get great food; owners get streamlined operations designed to give them a better lifestyle. Capital Required: $200,000   
 Hardee&apos;s 
   At Hardee´s®, we are known for our best-in-class menu that consistently out-delivers the competition. Multi-unit franchise territories are available for highly-qualified, experienced candidates in the Midwestern and Eastern United States and in select international markets. Capital Required: $500,000   
 Coffee Beanery 
   Coffee Beanery continues to build its brand and franchise on the principles of time-tested and honored traditions and values. Exceptional coffee, a warm relaxing environment, and a corporate culture that embraces its franchisees with every opportunity to succeed exemplify these values. Capital Required: $150,000   
 Pretzelmaker 
   With our delicious line of hot, fresh soft pretzels, Pretzel Maker is redefining the &apos;&apos;Snack Food of the new Millennia.&apos;&apos; Capital Required: $95,000   
 ARCO-ampm 
   ARCO and ampm are iconic industry brands within the gas station and convenience store franchise industries. With over 25 years of operating experience, advanced systems and training solutions, we set the standard for quality, brand recognition and leadership. Capital Required: $750,000   
 Maui Wowi Hawaiian Coffees&amp;Smoothies 
   Maui Wowi Hawaiian Coffees&amp;Smoothies franchise is the number one largest coffee/smoothie franchise in the world, with nearly 600 locations. Capital Required: $65,000   
 Tin Drum Asiacafe&apos; 
   Tin Drum Asiacafé creates new standards for fast-casual pan-Asian dining in the Southeast. In our words, Tin Drum puts the STREETS OF ASIA IN YOUR BOWL! Capital Required: $100,000   
 Pudgie&apos;s Famous Chicken 
   As our business partners, Pudgie&apos;s Famous Chicken franchisees bring classic food brands into the neighborhoods they serve. Capital Required: $200,000   
 Forever Yogurt 
   Forever Yogurt is a Self Serve Frozen Yogurt chain that has one of the highest per store sales averages in the industry. Each store is custom designed to best fit the area you&apos;ll serve, creating a unique look and feel for each Forever Yogurt a customer visits. Capital Required: $100,000   
 Taco John&apos;s 
   A HOT franchise that&apos;s fanning out across America like wildfire! Get your Taco John&apos;s Mexican Restaurant Franchise Today! Capital Required: $200,000   
 Manny&amp;Olga&apos;s Pizza 
   Manny&amp;Olga&apos;s has been serving their tempting selection of pizzas at prices for more than a decade - so great that customers return again and again. Capital Required: $100,000   
 Milio&apos;s Sandwiches 
   Milio&apos;s Sandwich Franchise is Hot! It might be cold-cuts, but our industry is hot. Sandwiches are the fastest growing category, with sales of quick se Capital Required: $150,000   Request more information by checking the box next to each franchise you are interested in, then click the &quot;Add Selected Franchises to Request Basket&quot; button at the top or bottom of the page. Discover More Opportunities! Search our Level 2 Industry Specific pages for 1,000&apos;s of established businesses and franchises: Industry Specific   »    Canadian Food Franchises   »    Coffee Franchise   »    Convenience Stores   »    Distribution   »    Espresso Franchise   »    Fast Food Franchise   »    Fried Chicken Franchises   »    Health-Nutrition Food Franchises   »    Ice Cream&amp;Dessert   »    Pizza Franchise   »    Restaurant Franchise   »    Vending Opportunity 
Franchise Category
 Advertising, Marketing Automotive Business Consulting Business Opportunities Business Services Canadian Child Products, Services Cleaning, Maintenance Computer, Technology Copying, Shipping, Signs Financial Services Fitness&amp;Gyms Food: Service, Retail Canadian Food Franchises Coffee Franchise Convenience Stores Distribution Espresso Franchise Fast Food Franchise Fried Chicken Franchises Health-Nutrition Food Franchises Ice Cream&amp;Dessert Pizza Franchise Restaurant Franchise Vending Opportunity Health, Beauty, Nutrition Home Based Businesses Home Services Low Cost Mobile Businesses Onsite Services Pet Related Recreation, Sport, Travel Retail Senior Living&amp;Care Unique Opportunities Vending   Franchise Search 
 Search By Industry Listed Alphabetically Established Franchises 
 About Us Advertise Your Franchise Contact Us Sign Up for Free Newsletter Site Map Disclaimer Press Releases Sell a Business-Post Ad Finance Center Follow us:
	</body>
</document>
