<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009772" url="http://gothamist.com/2011/12/08/mcdonalds_beating_customers_indicte.php" time="2012-07-13-03:09" support="1" score="0.0016093396452118176" bingtitle="Victims In McDonald&apos;s Beating Indicted On Burglary Charges: Gothamist" webtitle="Victims In McDonald&apos;s Beating Indicted On Burglary Charges: Gothamist">
			<query id="001292" bing-rank="101"/>
	<description>... that they allegedly entered the fast food restaurant ... fight started when Darbeau tried to pay for their food with a $50 bill ... br in a diner having someone take my order ...</description>
	<body>
		79° 
 our cities:
 Austin Chicago London Los Angeles New York City San Francisco Shanghai Toronto Washington DC 
 
 NYC Starts Offering Free, Unlimited WiFi Via Payphone Kiosks featured Oops? DNA From 2004 Murder&amp;2012 OWS Incident Might Be Lab Tech&apos;s Photos: Bus Passengers Hike To Port Authority After Lincoln Tunnel Accident 
 
Victims In McDonald&apos;s Beating Indicted On Burglary Charges
 
 
 Denise Darbeau (left) and Rachel Edwards ( via DNAInfo ) 

Last week, a jury voted to dismiss all charges against the McDonald&apos;s cashier who used a metal rod to beat up two customers who slapped him and then jumped over the counter at the West Village location in October. While 31-year-old Rayon McIntosh is off the hook , a jury has now voted to indict Denise Darbeau and Rachel Edwards, the two women who jumped over the counter, on burglary charges.

The 24-year-old women were initially charged with misdemeanor trespass in the West 3rd Street McDonald&apos;s altercation which took place on October 13. Those charges were increased to burglary, which meant that they allegedly entered the fast food restaurant with intent to commit a crime.“The person who committed a crime got away with a vicious assault,”said defense attorney Harold Baker.“It seems backwards to me...The people who were hurt are now charged with a crime.”Darbeau suffered a fractured skull and a broken right arm in the incident, while Edwards received a gash on her face.

The fight started when Darbeau tried to pay for their food with a $50 bill; that worker wanted to check the authenticity, as was store policy. The two women allegedly taunted McIntosh , who brought the order to the counter, calling him a &quot;bitch ass n--ga,&quot; and saying &quot;your mother&apos;s a bitch.&quot; McIntosh said in an interview that Darbeau spat at him, threatened to &quot;cut me up,&quot; came across the counter and slapped him. When Edwards jumped across to join in, McIntosh says instinct kicked in: &quot;I was being attacked by aggressive people I didn&apos;t know,&quot; said McIntosh. &quot;I was just defending myself. They came in and went crazy on me.&quot; You can see the rest of the incident play out in the video below:

 
 Contact the author of this article or email tips@gothamist.com with further questions, comments or tips. By Ben Yakas in News on December 8, 2011 3:33 PM View 
 assault beating burglary cashier indictment manhattan mcdonald&apos;s metal rod rayon mcintosh 
 
Other Interesting Stories
 
Comments [ rss ] 
 
 TishTash 
I don&apos;t think think these two are college material.
 Guest 
thank mom.

sent from prison phone
 Gadea 
The two young ladies, Miss Denise Darbeau and Rachel Edwards, have suffered enough.
Give them a break, so that they can get on with their lives.
Mr.  Rayon McIntosh was excessive in beating Ms. Darbeau and Ms. Edwards.
Mr. McIntosh went far beyond stopping a threat.
Enough is enough, give the young ladies a break, so that they can heal physically as well
as emotionally.
They will soon be in college pursing worthwhile careers.
 ardentsocialist 
Or, we can laugh as they go off to prison where they belong.
 ardentsocialist 
Or, we can laugh as they go off to prison where they belong.
 robingee 
“It seems backwards to me...The people who were hurt are now charged with a crime.”
Defense attorney logic seems backwards to me.
 zombiebob 
how very very prejudiced of you, stating such a fact. O wait, I forgot, snark is ok when YOU aim it anything not connected with overly-liberal-loved targets. Proceed. Of course I love this particular comment as much as I find ridiculous and funny your constant oblivious hypocrisy. The former is funny and the later is cute/adorable!
 robingee 
Dunno what you are on about, but you picked a fight over what I posted so I assume you are in agreement with the defense lawyer and on the side of those 2 women, which means you&apos;re a dick and we don&apos;t need to talk.
 bobbyjfromtheuk12 
I&apos;m guessing English is maybe your second or third language, right?

 zombiebob 
you so FUNNY!!!!!!
 robingee 
Try making sentences that mean things. Little advice.
 zombiebob 
Try being a little less of a douche
 robingee 
You not making any sense doesn&apos;t make others the douche.
 TheOtherBob 
Tha&apos;fuck you talkin&apos;about?
 Yishai 
For once the system isn&apos;t flawed.
 JacksBack72 
 Why does Gothamist refer to the two agressive crazies as&apos;Victims&apos;in the headline of this news item?!  Rayon IS the actual VICTIM in this incident!

AND-&gt;Was the $50. bill ever examined to see if it was real or not?!? 
 
 BTW-&gt;WTF is a&apos;n--ga&apos;?? And shouldn&apos;t the&apos;n&apos;be capitalized-&apos;N&apos;?? 
 Mr Mel 
&quot;AND-&gt;Was the $50. bill ever examined to see if it was real or not?!?&quot;
Yes it was, one side appeared to be ok, the back, however, read &quot;Good only at Larry Flynt&apos;s Hustler Club&quot;.
 JacksBack72 
 THIS- is a very funny comment!! Congrats-
 and welcome to the&apos;we-don&apos;t-take-ourselves-too-seriously-club&apos;!! 
 bawlsdeep 
We were warned that upon the return of the McRib, chaos and terror would follow. We just
didn&apos;t
listen.
 Jimmy 
savages.  ooops i sank to the level of a nypd pig
 
 blog comments powered by Disqus «Previous Home 
best of gothamist
	</body>
</document>
