<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009464" url="http://www.usedpos.net/restaurant-pos-system-for-sale/" time="2012-07-13-02:50" support="8" score="0.009043979568543775" bingtitle="Restaurant POS System for Sale!" webtitle="Restaurant POS System for Sale!">
			<query id="001207" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="000303" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001218" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="000615" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000612" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001398" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="001020" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="001209" bing-rank="240"/>
	<description>Revention Restaurant POS System for sale. Approx. 2 yrs ... • Purchase orders with item level posting at receipt ... Revention POS provides you with tools to keep track ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome, visitor! [ Register | Login ]  
 Post an Ad 
 Home Categories About Dashboard Edit Ad Profile Page Privacy FAQs 
 
 Cash Registers (8) New Cash Registers (1) Refubished Cash Registers (1) Used Cash Registers (6) 

 Credit Card Terminals (8) New Credit Card Terminals (2) Refurbished Credit Card Terminals (1) Used Credit Card Terminals (7) 

 Misc (38) Coin Dispensers (1) Digital Signage (1) Guest Pagers (1) Kiosks (4) Security Cameras (1) 
 
 Poll Displays (5) New Poll Displays (1) Used Poll Displays (4) 

 POS Monitors (16) New POS Monitors (2) Refurbished POS Monitors (1) Used POS Monitors (15) 

 POS Printers (41) New POS Printers (10) Refurbished POS Printers (1) Used POS Printers (29) 
 
 POS Systems (159) New POS Systems (13) Refurbished POS Systems (26) Used POS Sytems (108) 

 Wanted (11) Jobs (2) Pos Services (4) 
 Home » POS Systems » Used POS Sytems » Restaurant POS System for Sale! 
$Best offer

 Restaurant POS System for Sale! 
 
 State: Texas Country: United States Listed: August 6, 2010 12:16 pm Expires: This ad has expired 
 
Description

Revention Restaurant POS System for sale. Approx. 2 yrs old, but kept in almost brand new condition! Original boxes included.

Complete system with:
- 3 touchscreen Dell monitors
- 1 Dell monitor
-4 Dell computers
-2 cash drawers
-Fingerprint technology
-Mapping/ delivery system and much more.

For more information, please call us at (713) 419-1569

Detailed info about Revention system from Revention website:

Point-of-Sale Features
• User-configurable Order Screen Flow
• Multiple Customer Categories i.e. Hotel, Apartment, School
• Define Required Customer Fields
• Smart Coupon Builder
• Automatically Applied Coupons
• Meal Deal Packager
• Multiple Tax Rates
• Tax-Exempt by Customer or Order
• Red Light/Green Light Menu Modifiers
• Define Forced Menu Modifiers
• Unlimited Menu Capacity
• Definable Customer and Prep Tickets
• Drive-thru Functionality
• Intuitive Cash Reconciliation and End-of-Day
• Editing for Cash outs and Closed Days
• Interactive Close Day Screen shows all Outstanding Issues
• Digital Dashboard for Real-Time Sales/Labor Analysis
• Comprehensive Reporting • User-configurable Revenue Centers
• Multiple Labor Types&amp;Pay Rates per Employee
• Built-in Data Redundancy&amp;Configurable Backup System
• Robust Security Module
• Integrated CallerID
• Advanced Credit Card Features
• Call Center Feature
• Enterprise Reporting Functionality
• 2nd Item Pricing
• Easy To Use Menu Builder
• Advanced Combo Meal Package
• Order Comfirmation Display Interface
• Order of Item Level Kitchen Makeline Video System
• Optional Coin Changer
• Gift Cards with Paymentech, Givex, Valuelink, and Stored Value System
• Available Payee System Integration
• Works with all Credit Card Processors
• Deferred Ordering for Future Orders
Solutions
Now there is a comprehensive POS solution from a one solution provider that goes beyond today’s traditional systems. A complete system that provides you with the advanced POS functionality you need in order to manage your business. With today’s pace, all restaurants are finding themselves faced with the trend of“fast food”or“quick service”. Regardless of how you label it, the emphasis is on speed. So it is critical that speed is second-nature to your point-of-sale system along with Reliability, Ease of use, and Flexibility. Revention gives you the tools to efficiently and effectively manage your mission-critical point-of-sale operations.
Revention offers advanced POS functionality thru its open architecture and built-in redundancy. With multiple revenue center capabilities, extensive front and back-of-the-house reporting, and much more, we can meet the needs of your business. Our Restaurant Management System gives you access to the tools you need to effectively and efficiently manage your operations. Our architects’built the Restaurant Management System package in modular fashion with an upgradeable design to allow it to grow with you, accommodate your future needs while enabling you to maximize the life and value of your investment. Basically, Revention gives you a solid point-of-sale system that manages consistent flows of your business so you can focus on things that you cannot control.

Order Taking
• Fast, efficient order entry, configured to fit your specific order flow
• Red light /green light modifier assignment
• Substitution controls to ensure accurate pricing
• Real time ticket update allows for quick and easy edits
• Hold Order allows up to 3 orders to be managed on 1 workstation
• Suggestive selling prompt by menu group or item
• Configurable menu panel to customize look and functionality
• Unlimited menu capacity
Split Tickets
• Interface to allow drag and drop items to separate checks
• Easy name entry on split checks for carryout and delivery
• Separate customer tickets printed along with master
• Collect and close split ticket while other splits remain active
Order Lookup or Recall
• Customized view based on workstation profile
• Order detail viewer for accurate retrieval
• Order retrieval by phone, order, and table
• Sort by order type or payment status
Coupons
• Smart coupons appear only when valid to current order
• Multi-item coupons to accommodate combo pricing
• Minimum value setting to prevent over discounting
• Coupon verification by day and time
• Auto apply coupons for daily specials
• Coupon source code for marketing management
• Coupon description available on order screen
• Intuitive coupon builder, easy for the novice user
Deferred Ordering
• No limit to advanced ordering
• Define time to customer and time to print prep
• Ability to recall deferred orders and print
• System configuration to print all deferred orders in the morning
Caller ID
• Timer on each line to determine next caller
• Real time order status when a curbside customer calls back
• Recall mode in case a caller is dropped
• Name filter to eliminate unnecessary text
• Call management reporting
• One touch order history
In the Pizza Industry? Special Ordering Features Just for You!
Revention POS is amazingly fast, reliable, and efficient. The graphical interface and touch screen features allow for ease-of-use, quick order taking, and a small learning curve. Our on/off toggle buttons permit users to quickly modify customer orders. We have taken the extra steps out of the order taking process by using one push buttons that display the order on-screen as you touch the menu items.

Our ordering system allows you to enter orders the way you take them. By using forced modifiers and pop-up messages, we ensure the order is input correctly. You may also speed up the order taking process thru the use of default order types by station and specialized coupons.

Half&amp;Half is not only for your coffee. Half and half modes allow the pizza operator to better cater to their customers’needs, while Revention handles the division with the touch of a button.

Revention POS provides the integrity that ensures your orders are taken, taxed, and tendered correctly. We also allow you to configure your own customer, preparation, and driver tickets thru an intuitive configuration module. You may add logos, adjust fonts, modify spacing, and include your personal messages and advertisements to all printed tickets.

Deferred Orders allow you to take a future order without the headache of worrying about lost orders. Simply take the order and defer it to the specific date and time needed and printed.

Revention tracks all order transactions, leaving an auditable trail for those special occurrences.

Management Tools
• Real time productivity dashboard
• Employee resource management
• Employee scheduling with time off requests
• Employee messaging with required read option
• Customer marketing module includes export, labels, email
and mapping
• Intuitive menu builder accessible from all workstations
• Time clock editor with auditing
• Advanced security hierarchy managed by group and/or user
Inventory Management
• Easy to use and manage interface
• Quick sorting option by item, item number, vendor, etc.
• Ideal vs. actual inventory analysis
• Recipe and menu costing
• Recipe description for preparation manuals
• Purchase orders with item level posting at receipt
• Historical purchase price tracking by item
• Forced daily, weekly and monthly counts
Check Verification and Collection Services
• Eliminate bad checks by cross referencing customer name, phone,
and address to national database
• Automatic alert of closed accounts and repeat offenders
• Check funds directly deposited into bank account next business day
Credit Card Authorization
• High speed processing available
• Compatible with all processors
• CCV option for manually entered credit card transactions
• Quick and easy tip entry for servers and drivers
Enterprise Reporting Systems
• Centralized data updated in 5 minute intervals for all locations
• Statistical dashboard to allow proactive management of
labor and sales
• Hierarchical reporting to view entire organization or drill
down to region, district, and store level
Employee Features
Your employees are the face of your business, the link between you and your customers. They are the contributing factor to productivity and labor costs. Revention POS provides you with tools to keep track of your employees, while providing employees with tools to help them take care of your customers.

Through the use of our time clock system, you will be provided payroll data and real-time labor/sales reports. We all know one of the keys to a successful business is managing labor costs. That’s why your managers will enjoy the ability to check all vital statistics in real-time in Revention’s Dashboard feature.

There are some employees who do it all. So we allow you to give employees multiple job types with different wages for each job type. We have also gone to great lengths to control security and permissions in the software. You may set various security levels for each labor group, although security clearance can be edited for the individual.
Delivery Features
Revention POS provides you with the tools needed to make delivery a simple, profitable part of your operation. Our system gives you the ability to search for your customers by name, phone, address, street number, location, and more. In addition, all customers can have multiple phone numbers and addresses for those who call you from their home and cell numbers and need deliveries at home and work.

We also store the last order delivered which can be quickly recalled with the touch of a button. Not only will you impress your customers but you will also reduce ordering times.

Revention POS is your little helper keeping track of all aspects of the business. For delivery, our system makes sure orders meet minimum purchase standards, delivery fees and driver compensation are charged, and more. The color coded dispatch screen allows you to see which orders are late or about late and which drivers are slow returning with a quick glance. This allows you to be proactive and follow up on late orders before the customer calls you back.

Thru the integration of Microsoft’s Map Point, Revention POS allows you to view/print maps for drivers who may not be familiar with the area. Street directions are also available at any time from this screen. If you are interested in making suggestions or taking a tour of our software, click the appropriate link below.

Cash Control
• Blind cash out option
• Audit no sale access to cash drawer
• Complete customer account management
• Fast server tip declaration
• Management access to collect on server orders
• Force payment upon order entry for fast casual
Security
• Finger print recognition with option to require for maximum security
• Auto log off upon order completion
• Security settings configured by group or employee
• Employee time clock audit to monitor changes
• Time clock lock to eliminate employee from clocking in early
Reporting
• Detailed sales analysis by server
• Server forced tip declaration
• Comprehensive menu item analysis
• Void/comp audit by user
Kitchen Display System (KDS)
• Configurable ticket display, size and color of font
• Concurrent ticket design to maximize viewable orders
• Priority order type configuration (walk in orders expedited)
• Robust settings, display previous or additional items
• Display present modifiers and/or preferences
• Color coded order timer to alert staff when orders are late
• Order stages configured to accommodate KDS
with print functionality
• Integrate wait staff pager to alert when orders
are ready
Table Management
• Audit table turnover times
• Integrated server paging system
• Hostess table management with pagers
• Table lock out feature
• Call ahead orders for dine in
• Server performance dashboard
Promotional Gift Cards
• Integrated with Givex, Paymentech, and ValueLink
• Free custom card design
• Online reporting
• Website link for customers to check Gift Card balance
• Available for delivery use
 
 delivery , pizzaria , point of sale texas , POS SYSTEM , pos tx , restaurant pos texas , Revention , revention point of sale , revention pos 

1773 total views, 1 so far today

   Email This Post   


 
Sponsored Links
 
One Response to “Restaurant POS System for Sale!” 

 tommy on August 8, 2010 @ 11:47 am 
Hello,My Name is maurizio,I am interested in the revention pos that you have for sale, Please call at 1-585-798-1100 and ask for the owners(Dan/Maurizio)
 
 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
 Name (required) 
 
 Email (will not be visible) (required) 
 
 Website 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Wordpress Hashcash needs javascript to work, but your browser has javascript disabled. Your comment will be queued in Akismet! 
 Contact Map Poster 
 
Item Location
 
To inquire about this ad listing, complete the form below to send a message to the ad poster.

 Name: Email: Subject: Message: Sum of 6 + 3 = 
 
Information about the ad poster

 Listed by: [email protected] Member Since: August 6, 2010 
 
 Home About Dashboard Edit Ad Profile Page Privacy FAQs 
 
©2012 Used POS Systems | Refurbished POS Systems | Used Pos Printers | Pos Software | Pos Hardware. All Rights Reserved.
 
 Pos Systems Miami 


 Restaurant for sale
	</body>
</document>
