<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009739" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20090505234127AAyhYzk" time="2012-07-13-03:08" support="1" score="0.0008834926917129638" bingtitle="Have you ever threw a drink on someone or had a drink thrown on ..." webtitle="Have you ever threw a drink on someone or had a drink thrown on you? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="000239" bing-rank="41"/>
	<description>... some teens just passing buy and threw Slurpee&apos;s or just some drink from a fast food restaurant. ... is your favorite type of food? What is your favorite type of car?</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Entertainment&amp;Music &gt; Polls&amp;Surveys &gt; Resolved Question 
 ☆That&apos;s what she said ☆ Member since: March 15, 2007 Total points: 7,204 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Have you ever threw a drink on someone or had a drink thrown on you?
 what for 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Lifer Member since: August 12, 2008 Total points: 2,573 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 Yeah, I threw a cup of water on my wife. Shes done it to like a million time when she was mad. Her face was priceless though. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 4 people rated this as good 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: lol 
 Action Bar: 3 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (25)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Maty M Member since: December 13, 2006 Total points: 1,092 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I have never thrown a drink at anyone before but I have had people throw stuff at me for no reason. It has happened four times. The first time was in Mexico. A buss was passing by and I was waiting for it to pass so that I can cross the street and someone threw out a bottle of coke at me and hit me right cheek bone. I had a black eye for the whole summer I was 9 years old. Then the other times was out here in Southern Cali while I was walking to either school or the store. Again no reason some teens just passing buy and threw Slurpee&apos;s or just some drink from a fast food restaurant. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Ryan M Member since: March 05, 2009 Total points: 269 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I did today to my 14 year old brother.

We had left home so I could take him to baseball practice at 6. so we left at 5:45 and went to the gas station to get something to drink. So he got a cherry icee. he drank 3/4 of it and then we got to where his practice was. As he was getting his stuff I was like please take your trash out of my car and he&apos;s like no. Then I repeated myself and he&apos;s like my hands are full. So I told him to take it again because I had just cleaned my car out today and I didn&apos;t want his trash in there and he was being hella dick about it. Then he slammed the door so I rolled down the window and threw it at him.

=) 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by CrazyGre... Member since: January 15, 2009 Total points: 2,631 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Yes I have. It&apos;s the most effective way to get a Man to realize the answer is NO for the final time when he is torturing You in a bar and then proceeds to touch You anywhere on Your body and You don&apos;t want to be touched by him anywhere! 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Mr. Bitter Member since: May 04, 2008 Total points: 16,520 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I threw a glass of orange juice in my brother&apos;s face one morning.

I don&apos;t remember why.. I was only 13.

Never had one thrown at me... well, not exactly.

Once, back in the 80&apos;s.. I took an empty beer can to the face during the&quot;Rocky Horror Picture Show.&quot;.

Does that count? 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by dcarpent... Member since: December 09, 2007 Total points: 13,765 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Yes my friend and I was in Mazatlan, Mexico using a pay phone to call his wife. When a man threw a pint of beer at us. We immediately spotted an officer and reported the crime. The man was caught 5 minutes later. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Madisons Mommy =) Member since: March 14, 2007 Total points: 12,313 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Somone accidentally spilled a drink on me at a croweded party...it happens to be my best friends ex...I turned around and spilled my drink entirely on him...=) 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Buster Member since: May 29, 2008 Total points: 866 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Not on purpose. I have had a couple of drinks spilled on me by accident. I feel sorry for the person dumb enough to throw their drink on me if it ever happens. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Capt Blackie Member since: July 29, 2007 Total points: 7,832 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 No I usually use my fists or some sort of effective weapon rather than wasting good booze but I&apos;ve had drinks thrown on me a few times. For various perceived slights and insults, invariably at the hands of a woman. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by ♥To The Only Thing Thats True♥ Member since: August 25, 2008 Total points: 7,847 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 In 6th grade this girl threw her gatorade on me, because I didn&apos;t pass her the basketball in PE one time. 
Source(s):
 Ridiculous. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by ? Member since: April 10, 2009 Total points: 350 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I have threatened with a Glass Bottle to my brother but I have thrown a plastic bottle full of ice at my friend 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by cant_fig... Member since: March 23, 2009 Total points: 2,497 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 yup, i thew water at my little brother once cause i wanted to know what it&apos;s like, he agreed anyways. hahaha
we are weird. :P 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by MIA Member since: December 28, 2007 Total points: 5,539 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I threw my drink on my best friend because she was freaking out over nothing.

I warned her that I was going to if she didn&apos;t chill the fcck out.
She didn&apos;t believe me.
:D 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by ♥Proud Momma of 3 in TN♥ Member since: June 05, 2008 Total points: 3,182 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 i threw a glass of milk on my hubby once lol. he threw a glass of water back on me. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Frenchie Member since: December 19, 2007 Total points: 6,176 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I threw a drink on this douche at a club that called me a B*tch 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 4 people rated this as good 
 by Q Member since: April 20, 2009 Total points: 955 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 water....my fam has this thing about dumping FREEZING cold water on you while you are in the shower it is like a initiation thing 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Asha Member since: October 22, 2008 Total points: 3,916 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Nope 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 by [Krystle... Member since: May 17, 2006 Total points: 18,056 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 One time this drunk guy spilled his beer down my back while we were dancing. :/ lol 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by .mAEjInE... Member since: December 27, 2008 Total points: 1,231 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 omg
NO!
rude people
hahaha 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 by myself... YEAH! Member since: November 20, 2008 Total points: 2,370 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 every time i go to a concert i get beer dumped on me... does that count? lol 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Corneliu... Member since: June 02, 2007 Total points: 31,090 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 does spraying a clown with a seltzer bottle count? 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 3 people rated this as good 
 by ♥ Shortie ♥ Member since: October 02, 2007 Total points: 7,687 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 at my brother when he was being a jerk 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Stεℓℓaя Lauяita.™ ●•·нєαятz·•● Member since: February 02, 2009 Total points: 10,381 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 yes, i was drunk, she told me so. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by tboznchi... Member since: April 05, 2007 Total points: 6,419 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 nope. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 by [M.i.M.i... Member since: November 09, 2008 Total points: 2,339 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 haha yes

i wuz pissed off

xD 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by What? Member since: April 27, 2009 Total points: 540 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Yep, my sis in law is a .... anyway, I threw a drink at that skeezer. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 
Discover Questions in Polls&amp;Surveys 

 Would you move to a different city and give up everything for a man.............? Do you agree with me that....? Which of the following places would you go to? POLL: If I became an Abortion Doctor in Missisippi, would that basically make me a Millionaire? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Related Questions

 Is it normal to almost always throw up after drinking alcohol? how can i not throw up after being drunk? QUICK NO TIME TO LOSE!? when you throw up from drinking too much, do you start… Have you ever wanted to throw your drink on someone...then… Have you ever thrown a drink in someone&apos;s face or had a… 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Entertainment&amp;Music 
 Celebrities Comics&amp;Animation Horoscopes Jokes&amp;Riddles Magazines Movies Music Other - Entertainment Polls&amp;Surveys Radio Television 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

 Lifer CrazyGreenEyed… Madisons Mommy =) 
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
