<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009003" url="http://ph.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20100630071725AALgzmU" time="2012-07-13-02:24" support="1" score="0.001312099157164911" bingtitle="Yahoo! Answers - What do you suggest I observe?" webtitle="Yahoo! Answers - What do you suggest I observe?">
			<query id="000359" bing-rank="196"/>
	<description>For example if people come to a fast food restaurant they must be eating. ... He always gets a seat at the bar which so happens to be Ms ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Philippines Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Social Science &gt; Psychology &gt; Resolved Question 
 Sirius Member since: March 31, 2010 Total points: 17 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
What do you suggest I observe?
 Honestly this is supposed to be in the Anthropology section (ethnography) because this is for an anthropology subject, unfortunately I don&apos;t get a lot of responses in it, and I also thought maybe Psychology people could help because they&apos;re both nuder Social sciences.

So I&apos;m supposed to observe people in a particular location in which I always go to (routine), and to discover things I didn&apos;t know before. I thought of doing it in the fast food chain I always eat in during lunch, but I don&apos;t know what to observe because they&apos;ll all be just eating. So can you suggest? Like, what to observe, or maybe a new topic? 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 

Additional Details
 If you want, more details here:
http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index;_ylt=Auu2qgGol2h2VxwpNCjWRY_sy6IX;_ylv=3?qid=20100629051440AA5dqpr 
 2 years ago 
 by Joshua Member since: June 09, 2010 Total points: 226 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 You were wise in choosing the psychology secion because your task is asking you to extend common knowledge. You said your assignment is to go to a place where you typically go and observe things about people you never noticed before,correct? Well for starters your going into it with the wrong mindset. You are thinking about what the people should typically do at that location. For example if people come to a fast food restaurant they must be eating.

Your assignment isnt asking you to theorize but observe.The same way you visit a food venue on a occasional basis im pretty sure someone else does to. Look beyond the fact their they are eating but look at other things. What they wear, the way they dress, how they eat, how fast they eat. Create a daily log of actions that you observe them doing and your complete assignment should look something like this.

&quot;Mr. Jones lhas a thing for Mrs.kathy, but how would I know this. You see every day Mr.Jones come down to the Cafe&apos;Diner at exactly 11pm the same time that Mrs.Kathy arrives everyday. Mr.Jones is always neatly pressed, freshly trimmed and always scented with this strange cologne. He always gets a seat at the bar which so happens to be Ms.Kathy&apos;s station.He only orders things that she has to personally prepare and he always leaves a minimum of 10 dollars for a tip. Mr. Jones eats his food extremely fast he always leaves exactly at 12pm except for on Wendsdays, but he also has on regular clothes so I assume Wensdays are his only off days.&quot;

Thhats just how your final character evaluation should look.There is so much you can learn doing observations, just open your mind up and watch. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: thank you 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; What do you suggest … &quot;was originally asked on Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (1)
 
 by notyou31... Member since: April 10, 2006 Total points: 215,830 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Make note of how they&apos;re dressed, how they interact with each other and what they order. See if you can figure out their relationship to one another. See if you can hear some conversations. Are they business related or family related conversations? Test your powers of observation. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 
Discover Questions in Psychology 

 My Life Is At An End!!!!!!!? I am STILL too shy, please help? Why do I feel so sad all the time? How to you get better self esteem? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Social Science 
 Anthropology Dream Interpretation Economics Gender&amp;Women&apos;s Studies Other - Social Science Psychology Sociology 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Asia Pacific Pte Ltd. (Co. Reg. No. 199700735D). All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
