<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009335" url="http://www.abestweb.com/forums/abestweb-voting-booth-6/%5B2008%5D-most-favourite-fast-food-restaurants-100595.html" time="2012-07-13-02:42" support="2" score="0.007117440745193761" bingtitle="[2008] Most favourite Fast Food Restaurants? - ABestWeb Affiliate ..." webtitle="[2008] Most favourite Fast Food Restaurants? - ABestWeb Affiliate Marketing Forum">
			<query id="000362" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001115" bing-rank="174"/>
	<description>Clearly, Fudruckers is NOT a fast food restaurant. There use to be one a ... rematt wrote: &gt; &quot;I did spend a night in an Atlanta hospital with food poisoning after eating a ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome, guest!
 » Login Close 
Login to Your Account
 User Name: Password: 
 Remember Me   |   »Forgot your password?    » Join 
 ABestWeb 
 
 Home Forums Featured Advertise 
 
 Join Now! FAQ Rules 91 New Posts Today 


 »Advanced Search   
 Go to Page... 
 Twitter Facebook RSS Rules 
 Home ABestWeb Affiliate Marketing Forum Inside Our Industry Voting Booth [2008] Most favourite Fast Food Restaurants? 

 
 View Poll Results : What Are Your Favorite Fast Food Restaurants? Arby&apos;s 11 13.75% Boston Pizza 1 1.25% Burger King 11 13.75% Carl&apos;s Jr. 7 8.75% Chick-fil-A 8 10.00% Domino&apos;s Pizza 4 5.00% Five Guys 5 6.25% Hardee&apos;s 4 5.00% Harvey&apos;s 0 0% KFC 9 11.25% McDonald&apos;s 9 11.25% Quiznos Sub 9 11.25% Papa John&apos;s 6 7.50% Pizza Hut 7 8.75% Popeyes Chicken&amp;Biscuits 7 8.75% Subway 27 33.75% Taco Bell 18 22.50% Wendy&apos;s 14 17.50% Other [please post] 14 17.50% Multiple Choice Poll. Voters: 80 . You may not vote on this poll 

 
 
 Page 1 of 3 1 2 3 &gt; 
 

 
Thread: [2008] Most favourite Fast Food Restaurants? 
 Tweet   Tools Search 
 
  # 1   January 30th, 2008, 12:19 PM 
 richguy 
 Newbie Join Date: January 30th, 2008 Location: Toronto Posts: 12 
 I know we all enjoy having our junk food once in a while.

What are your most favourite fast food restaurants?

Popeyes
Harvey&apos;s
McD&apos;s
Pizza Nova

What&apos;s yours?

richguy 
 
  # 2   January 30th, 2008, 12:27 PM 
 Daniel M. Clark 
 Formerly known as HecticDMC Join Date: January 7th, 2006 Location: Houston, TX Posts: 2,003 
 Subway, if I&apos;m out and about and need to eat. Papa John&apos;s if I&apos;m ordering a pizza (which I do count as fast food).

I can&apos;t eat at the burger places anymore. I used to eat McDonald&apos;s/Wendy&apos;s/BK on a regular basis... like, 4-5 times a week, but I decided I needed to lose weight and made myself stop eating there. After about two months, I caved and had a quarter pounder at McDonald&apos;s, and I trashed it after about three bites. The sodium content in those things is outrageous. It was easily the saltiest thing I&apos;d ever eaten - I just never noticed it before because after 20 years of eating the stuff, you get used to it. __________________
1. Part time writer and marketer, full time cool dude. 
B. A weekly podcast - geeks raising kids in a digital age. 

&quot;It&apos;s Rayon, not Rayon.&quot; 
 
  # 3   January 30th, 2008, 12:41 PM 
 Rhea 
 Troll Killer and best Snooper!
I decide when the pigs fly! Join Date: January 18th, 2005 Location: New York, USA Posts: 6,204 
 I don&apos;t eat at fast food restaurants. That stuff&apos;ll kill you. __________________
 Funny Fridge Magnets Snarky T-Shirts Sports Fan T-Shirts Foodie T-Shirts Animal Lover T-Shirts 
 
 Join ABW to remove this sponsored message. 
 
  # 4   January 30th, 2008, 12:46 PM
	</body>
</document>
