<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009049" url="http://www.tri-crcc.com/Members/" time="2012-07-13-02:27" support="2" score="0.0019345618310471326" bingtitle="Meet Our Members - Cost of Living" webtitle="Cost of Living">
			<query id="000707" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000300" bing-rank="248"/>
	<description>Waste Management; First National Bank of South Carolina ; South Carolina Bank &amp; Trust ; The Regional Medical Center; Dedicated to improving the communities where our ...</description>
	<body>
		Meet Our Members 

 
 CHAMBER
MEDAL MEMBERS PLATINUM GOLD 
 Giant Cement Holding,Inc. Holcim (US), Inc. Lafarge North
America Low Country Printers 
 
 MeadWestvaco Santee Cooper Town of Santee Town of St. George Town of Holly Hill 
 SILVER BRONZE 
 Waste Management First National Bank of
South Carolina South Carolina Bank&amp;Trust The Regional Medical Center 

 Dedicated to improving the communities where our customers and employees live and work. 
 Trident Technical College Summerville Medical Center AgSouth Farm Credit, ACA Dixon Hughes, PLLC First Citizens
Bank Southern Tank Transport Harleyville Builders Supply, Inc. Orangeburg
Consolidated School District III The Citizens Bank Farmers&amp;Merchant Bank Hardee&apos;s Flying J Travel Plaza 
 

 

 Search Member Directory 
 
 
   

 
 Select a Business Category ACCOMMODATIONS/MOTELS/HOTELS/INNS ACCOUNTANTS&amp;CPAS ALCOHOL&amp;DRUG TREATMENT ALZHEIMER&apos;S FACILITY ANIMAL CARE APPLIANCE REPAIR APPRAISER ARTS&amp;CULTURAL ASSISTED LIVING FACILITY ATTORNEYS ATTRACTIONS/ENTERTAIN/RECREAT AUCTION/AUCTIONEER AUTO DEALERS/SERVICE/BODY SHOP AUTO SALVAGE/PARTS SALES/RECYCLING AUTO/HOME/COMMERCIAL INSURANCE BAKERY BANKS&amp;SAVINGS&amp;LOANS BEAUTY/HAIR CARE/COSMETICS BED AND BREAKFAST BOAT REPAIRS BUILDING SUPPLIES BUSINESS RATING/CONSUMER COMPLAINTS CAMPGROUND/CAMPSITES/LAKESIDE CAR WASH CATERING CEMENT PRODUCTION/RELATED SUPPLIER CHIROPRACTORS CHURCHES&amp;MINISTERS CIVIC CLUBS/COMMUNITY ORGANIZATIONS COLLEGE/UNIVERSITY/TECHNICAL COLLEGE COMMUNITY ACTION&amp;IMPROVEMENT COMPUTER SALES/REPAIR CONCRETE(REDI-MIX)/RELATED PRODUCTS CONSIGNMENT SHOP CONSTRUCTION CONSULTING CONSUMER LOANS CONTRACTORS - BUILDING CONVENIENCE/VARIETY STORE COUNSELING COUNTRY CLUB/GOLF COURSE CRAFT SHOPS CREDIT/LOAN COMPANY/INSURANCE DEBIT/CREDIT CARD PAYMENT PROCESSING SERVICE DELI/PREPARED FOODS TO GO DENTAL CARE/ORTHODONTIST DENTIST DEPARTMENT/CHAIN STORES DEVELOPMENT/ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT DIALYSIS CENTER DOCKS DRY CLEANERS ELECTRIC COMPANIES/ELECTRIC SERVICE COMP ELECTRICAL CONTRACTOR ELECTRICIAN ELECTRONIC PAYMENT SPECIALIST ELECTRONICS SUPPLY STORE EMBROIDERY/MONOGRAM ENGINEERS Enter New Category ENTERTAINMENT ENVIRONMENTAL SERVICES EQUINE CENTER EQUIPMENT COMPANY EVENT RENTALS EXERCISE&amp;FITNESS EXTERMINATORS FAST FOOD RESTAURANT FESTIVALS/COMMUNITY PROMOTIONS FINANCE AND INSURANCE FINANCIAL ADVISORS / STOCKBROKERS FIRE/RESCUE DEPARTMENT FISHING/FISHING GUIDES/FISHING TOURNEYS FLORIST FUNERAL HOMES/CEMETERIES FURNITURE STORES GARDEN&amp;FARM CENTERS GAS COMPANY GIFT SERVICES/CERTIFICATES GIFT SHOPS GOLF/GOLF PACKAGES/GOLF LODGING GOVERNMENT AGENCIES GROCERY/FOOD STORES HARDWARE HEALTH&amp;FITNESS HEALTH PRODUCTS HEALTHCARE SERVICES HEATING&amp;AIR CONDITIONING HISTORICAL PRESERVATION HOME DECOR HOME INSPECTOR HORSE / BULL / BARREL RACING HORSE CARE/ACCOMMODATIONS/MEDICAL TREATMENT HORSE FARM/BOARDING HOSPITALS&amp;CLINICS HOTELS/MOTELS/INNS IDENTITY THEFT PROTECTION INDIVIDUALS INDUSTRIES/MANUFACTURERS INSURANCE COMPANIES INTERNET SERVICES INVESTMENT COUNSELOR IT SERVICES LAKE TOURS LANDSCAPING/MASONRY LEGAL SERVICES/PRE-PAID LEGAL SERVICES LIBRARY LIQUOR STORES LOANS - RESIDENTIAL/COMMERCIAL LOGISTICS/TRANSPORTATION LUMBER/TIMBER COMPANIES MAGAZINES&amp;NEWSPAPERS MANAGEMENT/PROMOTION MARINA/RESORT MARKETING MEDIA/PUBLICATIONS MONOGRAMMING MOTELS/HOTELS/INNS MOTORCYCLE SALES MOTORCYCLE SERVICE MOVING&amp;STORAGE MUSEUM MUSIC NAIL SALON NATURE-BASED TOURISM&amp;RECREATION FACILITY NURSING HOME/LONG-TERM CARE OPTOMETRIST OUTLET MALL PAINTING - COMMERCIAL/RESIDENTIAL PARK PARTY FACILITY/EVENT SUPPLIES&amp;PLANNING PAYROLL SERVICES PET-SITTING SERVICE PHARMACIES PHYSICIANS&amp;SURGEONS PRINTING/PROMOTIONAL ITEMS PRIVATE INVESTIGATORS PUBLICATIONS REAL ESTATE - RESIDENTIAL/COMMERCIAL REAL ESTATE-HOME INSPECTION RECEPTIONS/REUNIONS/PARTIES RECYCLING RESORTS/TIMESHARES/CONDOS RESTAURANTS RETAIL RETIREE RODEO / ARENA SCHOOLS-PUBLIC&amp;PRIVATE SENIOR CITIZENS CENTER SERVICE STATION SHOPPING CENTER SIGNS/SALES&amp;SERVICE SPAS AND SALONS STORAGE SURVEYORS TAX PREPARATION TELECOMMUNICATIONS/HOME/DIGITAL/WIRELESS TOWING SERVICE TOWN/COUNTY/GOVT. TRAVEL/TOURISM TRUCKING COMPANIES T-SHIRT PRINTING UNIFORM SERVICE VETERINARIANS VETERINARY CARE/LODGING VIDEO RENTALS WEDDINGS/EVENTS 

 
 

 Complete Member Listing 
 Listing by Category
	</body>
</document>
