<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009357" url="http://www.job-applications.com/ups-application/" time="2012-07-13-02:43" support="2" score="0.0051760405331164805" bingtitle="UPS Application Online - Print Job Employment Form" webtitle="UPS Application Online - Print Job Employment Form">
			<query id="001499" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="001184" bing-rank="122"/>
	<description>Get the UPS employment application form online. Job-Applications.com is the place to find job ... Inside Sales Representative, Distribution Supervisor, Order ...</description>
	<body>
		The #1 Independent Online Job Application Resource Website 
 
 
 
 
 Home » Delivery Driver Jobs »UPS

UPS Application
 
 
 
UPS Application Online–Print Job Employment Form 

 
 
 
 
 Apply for Jobs at UPS Online 

 Application for UPS: UPS does not provide a printable job application. If you want to get a job at UPS, you must apply for employment on the website by following the link above. Full-time or part-time positions may vary depending on the location.

 Interview Tips: Go to the UPS job interview questions&amp;tips page.

 Available Positions at UPS: Package Handler, Truck Driver, Driver Helper, Package Delivery Driver, Fleet Mechanic, Truckload Driver, Dockworker, I.T. Associate, Technical Specialist, Intermediate Data Security Analyst, Programmer, QA Analyst, Sales Support, Administrative Assistant, Hub Operations Manager, International Freight Specialist, Local Sort Supervisor, Package Data Supervisor, Shift Supervisor, Package Center Supervisor, Automotive Mechanic, Warehouse Associate, Technical User Representative, Inside Sales Representative, Distribution Supervisor, Order Processing Representative, Dispatch Associate, Customer Support Representative, Lead Technical Specialist, Plant Engineering Maintenance Mechanic, Road Driver, Inventory Control Associate

 Minimum Age to Work at UPS : 18 years old (How old do you have to be to work at UPS?)

 UPS Hours of Operation: Available 24 hours a day, 7 days a week

 More Information: UPS Job Info 
 Related Jobs :

 A1Express 
 
Craters and Freighters 
 
DHL 
 
FedEx 
 
Goin’ Postal 
 
OnTrac 
 
P.A.S.S. 
 
Postal Annex 
 
Postal Connections 
 
PostNet 
 
Safe Ship 
 
Unishippers 
 
United Shipping Solutions 
 
USPS 
 
USPack 
 
Worldwide Express 
The online UPS application delivers when it comes to finding meaningful employment opportunities in shipping. Fill out an application form to gain access to a wide range of entry-level jobs and full-time careers. Apply online with the UPS job application to begin work in an exciting career field today.

UPS Job Opportunities

The UPS application provides job seekers both part-time and full-time employment opportunities. Fill out an online application form to begin the UPS hiring process now. Apply online to find United Parcel Service locations hiring today.

Applicants 16 and older seeking entry-level employment may find UPS jobs. Entry-level job hunters may apply online to find exciting employment opportunities in the carrier industry. Career-oriented applicant may also find exciting and rewarding employment at Brown. Apply online to learn about UPS careers today.

Hiring both full-time and part-time employment seekers, UPS needs to hire package handlers and sorters now. Other entry-level job titles, such as administrative assistants and customer service representatives, also need filled at United Parcel Service. UPS offers career positions in corporate offices but generally accepts only applicants at least 18 years old possessing prior experience in the carrier services industry.

The UPS job application may help you find meaningful employment offering the outstanding pay and employee benefits you desire. An online application form exists for the convenience of potential UPS employees. Complete and submit the United Parcel Service job application form to begin an exciting career path today. Apply online to discover UPS jobs now.

 Is UPS hiring for the holidays? 

 Job Titles and Salary Options at UPS 
As a global package delivery company, UPS offers applicants ages 16 and over a wealth of employment opportunities in the shipping and receiving industry. Exciting entry-level jobs and full-time careers need filled at United Parcel Service. Apply online to find more information on job openings, salary options, and employee benefits. UPS needs to staff the following package delivery jobs :

 Driver – UPS regularly needs to hire drivers at many branch locations. United Parcel Service drivers must possess an outstanding driving record and pass company drug screening. Ideal candidates work hard to deliver packages and goods promptly. Driver typically earn average pay around $65,000 per year.

 Package Handler / Sorter – In entry-level jobs, UPS package handlers load and unload United Parcel Service trucks at packaging facilities. Sorters sort packages for loading. UPS package handlers and sorters must exhibit attention to detail as well as ably lift heavy objects. Package handlers and sorters generally earn starting pay around $8 an hour.

 Management – Careers in management also need staffed at UPS. The company needs to hire shift supervisors and branch managers at distribution center locations. Shift supervisors generally need to possess prior experience in shipping and receiving. Branch managers oversee operations at distribution center locations and ensure safety and satisfaction of workers and customers. Shift supervisors at UPS earn an average of $20 an hour. UPS branch managers receive starting salary options of up to $75,000 per year.

In addition to driving jobs, warehouse work, and management positions, UPS also needs administrative assistants and maintenance workers. Brown needs to hire professional associates to fill corporate careers in IT, marketing, logistics, account coordination, accounting, human resources, legal, and consulting, as well. Apply online to find UPS career opportunities today.

 UPS Job Benefits 
UPS offers employees a unique and dynamic work environment. Brown workers enjoy a fast-paced and intensive work environment, paid training opportunities, competitive compensation, and employee benefits . Employment benefits include future planning benefits, health and wellness programs, and insurance coverage.

Offering a wide array of ways to help qualified workers save for the future, United Parcel Service offers 401(k) retirement plans, employee profit sharing plans, and employee stock purchase plans. Brown also offers work and life assistance programs, employee discounts, and paid time off. UPS offers medical, dental, vision, and prescription drug coverage to all eligible employees. Apply online to learn more about UPS pay and job benefits today.

Read more about UPS benefits .

 History 
Originally formed as a messenger company in the United States, United Parcel Service, or UPS, began in 1907. Founded by 19-year old James E. Casey, UPS quickly became one of the leading message carriers in the U.S. After years of success as a messenger company, UPS began branching out into retail and common services carrying. In the late-1920s and early-1930s, UPS underwent massive expansion on the East Coast. In 1953, United Parcel Service began incorporating air delivery services, as well. The completion of the American Interstate system in the late-1960s enabled easier delivery of goods, and the company continued to expand. The 1980s brought international expansion, and UPS began offering delivery services to Canada for the first time. In 1992, United Parcel Service began electronic tracking services.

 Special Services 
UPS offers transportation and shipping to destinations throughout the world. Customers may send, ship, and receive parcels of all shapes, sizes, and weights through land, sea, and air carrier methods. Clients may access same-day, overnight, and traditional delivery options at UPS. In addition to parcel delivery, UPS also operates many retail locations under the banner The UPS Store. These retail locations offer packaging materials and shipping logistic options at affordable prices.

 Community Involvement 
An active member of the community, UPS strives to improve local communities as well as the global public. UPS regularly participates in community and cultural events throughout the world and provides sponsorship to many non-profit charities and organizations. United Parcel Service also helps deliver important goods to communities in need, such as disaster relief materials and overseas care packages.

 Environmental 
As a company involved in diversified shipping and delivery, UPS stands as an industry leader in the innovation of alternative fuel technologies. In addition to implementing strict environmental guidelines, including recycling programs, United Parcel Service operates the largest private alternative fuel fleet in the shipping and transportation industry. Also involved in water conservation efforts, UPS helps save more than 365 million gallons of water annually.

 International 
UPS began international expansion in the mid-1970s. First expanding in to Canada, UPS began offering services overseas in 1976 with the opening of several locations in Europe. The first European UPS locations opened in Germany. As of 2011, United Parcel Service operated in 185 countries and territories around the world.

 Financial 
Existing as a publicly owned company, United Parcel Service trades on the NYSE under the ticker symbol UPS. Headquartered in Sandy Springs, Georgia, UPS and several subsidiaries generate nearly $50 billion in annual revenues. Also known as Brown, UPS delivers to more than 6 million customers each day and controls over $33 billion in total assets.
 9 comments: 
 Shayne Guthrie: 



 Top Comment 
 
I was wondering if UPS had any job applications I could fill out for seasonal work while I am on college breaks? I may also be able to do part time on the weekends. I was also curious to know what the starting salary would be.
 

 
 Tony: 





UPS would be an awesome job. I definitely wanna fill out an application but I have a couple tickets on my driving record. Will that be a big problem?


 
 Nate W: 





I want a job at UPS but I heard it takes a really long time for them to call you back. I need a job pretty soon so does anyone know if thats true?


 
 tristan t.: 





Can someone please tell me about the benefits at UPS. Things I wanna know: how much medical coverage is there? How long do you have to work there before you get coverage? And what the name of the insurance company is?


 
 Sylvia Henderson: 





I would like to be a package handler for UPS, I think it might be fun. I can only work 2nd or 3rd shift however so does anyone know if UPS offers any positions with those hours? I hope so I think it would be great to work for UPS.


 
 cody koballa: 





How do I fill out an application? do I have to go to an actually UPS store ?


 
 Fernando Echevarria: 





I would like work with UPS as soon possible but where I can founded the place for get the application?Tell me the plant where i need go.Thanks yours,Fernando.


 
 Bret: 





Ok Cheryl Told Me To go On-line To Finish Application So They Could Get Me Started.I Am Sorry But I Cannot Find That On Any Of The Web-Sites.


 
 Hasan Zeid: 





I got a interview for UPS tomorrow but does it matter how my driving record is if im applying for loading and unloading job? and do i have to be 18


 
 
 Most Popular Jobs Retail Store Jobs 
 Fast Food Jobs 
 Department Store Jobs 
 Career Research Employee Benefits 
 En Espanol 
 Interview Tips 
 Interview Questions 
 Job Descriptions 
 Job Finding Tips 
 Salary Info 
 Job Newsletter We&apos;ll email jobs to you. Name: Email: Zip Code: Select Category: Retail Fast Food Restaurant Hotel Housekeeping Pharmacy Delivery Driver Footwear Healthcare Automotive Cruise Ship Grocery Store Casino Airline Pizza Delivery 

 Sign Up Job Categories Airline Jobs 
 Amusement Park Jobs 
 Armed Forces Jobs 
 Automotive Store Jobs 
 Banking Jobs 
 Book Store Jobs 
 Casino Jobs 
 Childcare Daycare Jobs 
 Coffee Shop Jobs 
 Computer Store Jobs 
 Cruise Ship Jobs 
 Delivery Driver Jobs 
 Department Store Jobs 
 Fashion Jobs 
 Fast Food Jobs 
 Fitness Health Jobs 
 Furniture Store Jobs 
 Gas Station Jobs 
 Grocery Store Jobs 
 Hardware Store Jobs 
 Healthcare Jobs 
 Home Decor Jobs 
 Hospital Jobs 
 Hotel Jobs 
 Ice Cream Shop Jobs 
 Insurance Jobs 
 Mechanic Jobs 
 Movie Theater Jobs 
 Office Supply Jobs 
 Pet Store Jobs 
 Pharmacy Tech Jobs 
 Pharmacist Jobs 
 Pizza Delivery Jobs 
 Rental Truck Jobs 
 Rental Car Jobs 
 Restaurant Jobs 
 Retail Management Jobs 
 Retail Store Jobs 
 Shoe Store Jobs 
 Smoothie Maker Jobs 
 Specialty Foods Jobs 
 Sporting Goods Jobs 
 Telecommunications Jobs 
 Temp Agency Jobs 
 Tools Jobs 
 Tutoring Jobs 

 All Job Categories 
 
   

 
 Sign up - we&apos;ll email jobs to you. Name:
 Email:
 Zip:
 Select Category:
 Retail Fast Food Restaurant Hotel Housekeeping Pharmacy Delivery Driver Footwear Healthcare Automotive Cruise Ship Grocery Store Casino Airline Pizza Delivery Sign Up 
 
 disclaimer 

 privacy policy 

 terms of use 
 
 
Copyright © 2011, 2012 Job-Applications.com
	</body>
</document>
