<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009216" url="http://www.essortment.com/creative-dating-ideas-fun-cheap-52029.html" time="2012-07-13-02:36" support="1" score="0.0008098620991075403" bingtitle="Creative Dating Ideas: Fun And Cheap - Essortment Articles: Free ..." webtitle="Creative Dating Ideas: Fun And Cheap">
			<query id="000959" bing-rank="167"/>
	<description>Other fast food restaurant ideas are: One person sits on the hood or the car to order and pick up food while going through the drive through window.</description>
	<body>
		Home Relationships&amp;Dating Creative Dating Ideas: Fun And Cheap 
 
 
Creative Dating Ideas: Fun And Cheap
 
Creative dating ideas to keep that spark in your dating experience.
 
First dates are always a thrill. But, dating can become monotonous if you let it. This article will give some ideas on how to keep that spark in your dating experience, especially when you are tired of going to the movies every weekend! Help is on the way for single people as well as couples who have been married for years and need new ideas to ignite the excitement of dating.

Some people take dating too seriously. Usually this happens when the couple that is dating does not consider themselves friends first. Friendship is important to any romance, and fun is important to all friendships! So, remember if your date is going downhill quickly because of lack of a romantic atmosphere you thought should be there, maybe it is time for you to reconsider the purpose of the date and try to spice it up with some fun first. 

There are a lot of ideas for dating that are not expensive and yet they are fun, you just have to be creative. Here are a few silly ideas for fun dates. Just make sure both you and your date are daring enough to try them!

Deserted Island Picnic. Pack a picnic lunch or dinner in a basket, complete with blanket to sit on. Find an &quot;island&quot; in the center of the road and enjoy your picnic as cars pass by. Or, you could order pizza from your deserted island and have it delivered to you. It would be wise to look for just the right &quot;island&quot;. Look for islands that are very wide ( at least 10 feet across); grass and trees would be nice.

A fun thing to do when you pick up your date is let them choose what you are going to do that night with a guessing game. This takes preparation in advance. You will go and take pictures of different places for picnics, walks, eating, or theaters, games to play or sports events before the date. Get the pictures developed and place the them in individually sealed envelopes. When you pick your date up let them choose an envelope. Whatever the picture is, you go and do together. You can let your date open additional envelopes through out the evening that will tell you what you are going to do next.

Fast Food Restaurant Scavenger Hunt. This is a fun date idea when there is more than one couple. You prepare scavenger hunt lists of things you can get at fast food restaurants such as; salt packages, spoons, straws, buns, ice, cups, French fries, ketchup packages, lettuce, children&apos;s meal bag or toy, etc. The couples must go to different fast food restaurants and ask the establishment to donate the items for a scavenger hunt game. Then meet at a designated time at one of the fast food places, see which couple collected the most stuff and losers buy dinner! 

Other fast food restaurant ideas are: One person sits on the hood or the car to order and pick up food while going through the drive through window. Or, get a large refrigerator box or a washing machine box and make a car out of it by cutting and coloring it to you and your date&apos;s liking. Drive through the fast food restaurant in your new card board box car.

A fun date with a group of people is to make your own movie. Get together and write a script, choose actors, directors and a film crew. Now, video tape yourselves. It is a blast to make and watch.

An interesting dating idea is to give your date and yourself 5 or 10 one dollar bills. Walk
down a busy street and hand out the money to who ever you feel like. It is a lot of fun to see the looks on the people&apos;s faces and listen to their protests or thank yous! One of you can walk a few feet behind and pretend you don&apos;t know your date who is handing out the money and just crack up.

Hopefully, some of these ideas made you come up with some of your own. Remember be creative and have fun!

























 
Trending Now
 
More Essortment Articles

 Childrens Fashion: Ways To Stand Out While Wearing A Uniform How To Propose: 10 Bad Ideas She&apos;ll Hate Benefits Of Double-Dating Dating Advice: Dating Someone With A Disability What Is Speed Dating? 
 
 Popular Articles 
 
 Carbon Dating Accuracy: What Are The Flaws Of Carbon Dating? Dating Tips: An Inexpensive Night Out Absolute Dating Techniques Discussing Dating With Teenage Sons 

 Dating On The Internet Lifestyles And Relationships: How To Have An Inexpensive Date How To Overcome Your Fear Of Flying The Mexican Border Patrol 
 
 AdChoices | Privacy Policy | Terms of Use 
 
©Demand Media 2011
	</body>
</document>
