<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009747" url="http://lowcarbdiets.about.com/od/whattoeat/a/whatfruit.htm" time="2012-07-13-03:08" support="1" score="0.002134640001833179" bingtitle="Low-Carb/Low-Sugar Fruits: A list of the best and the worst fruit ..." webtitle="Low-Carb/Low-Sugar Fruits: A list of the best and the worst fruit for low-carb dieters.">
			<query id="000367" bing-rank="240"/>
	<description>low carb food lists; low carb fruit; low carb snacks ... the information is available, based on a half-cup ... What You Can Eat; Low-Carb/Low-Sugar Fruits: A list of ...</description>
	<body>
		Health 
 Low Carb Diets Search 
 Low Carb Diets Getting Started Health and Nutrition Recipes 

 Share 
 Free Low Carb Diets Newsletter! Sign Up 
 Discuss in my forum 
 
 Low-Carb Fruit: Lists of the Best and Worst 

Choose Low-Sugar Fruit

By Laura Dolson , About.com Guide

Updated August 12, 2011

About.com Health&apos;s Disease and Condition content is reviewed by our Medical Review Board 
 See More About: 
 low carb food lists low carb fruit low carb snacks fruit 
 Photo©Karen Struthers Fruit is an area where some of the low-carb diets part company, as some depend more upon glycemic index or glycemic load ( South Beach , Zone ), while others just look at total carbs ( Atkins , Protein Power ). Also, some diets (Atkins, South Beach) don&apos;t allow fruit at all in the first phase. In general, your best bet fruits are the ones near the top of this list, but do check carb counts (alphabetical list). These are roughly arranged by sugar content - where the information is available, based on a half-cup serving of fruit. However, since carb counts vary , all nutritional information is always approximate.
Good news: the fruits lowest in sugar are some of the highest in nutritional value, including antioxidants and other phytonutrients .
If you are considering using organic vegetables, check out this list of which fruits and vegetables have the most and least pesticides to help you guide your choices.
 Quick Tip to Help you Remember Fruits High and Low in Sugar 
Fruits Lowest in Sugar

 Small Amounts of Lemon or Lime 
 Rhubarb 
 Raspberries (more about berries on low carb diets ) 
 Blackberries 
 Cranberries 

Fruits Low to Medium in Sugar

 Strawberries 
 Casaba Melon 
 Papaya 
 Watermelon 
 Peaches 
 Nectarines 
 Blueberries 
 Cantaloupes 
 Honeydew melons 
 Apples 
 Guavas -- Pineapple Guavas (Feijoa) and Strawberry Guavas are probably similar, but information that directly compares them is not available 
 Apricots 
 Grapefruit 

Fruits Fairly High in Sugar

 Plums 
 Oranges 
 Kiwifruit 
 Pears 
 Pineapple 

Fruits Very High in Sugar

 Tangerines 
 Cherries 
 Grapes 
 Pomegranates 
 Mangos 
 Figs 
 Bananas 
 Dried Fruit, such as dates , raisins , dried apricots , and prunes 
 
Related Resources

 Carb Counts of Fruit Glycemic Index of Fruits Berries - Healthy, Delicious, Low Carb 
 
Related Resources

 Low-Carb Vegetable List Fruit List for the South Beach Diet Low-Carb Recipes 
 
Low-Carb Resources

 Low-Carb Home Page Ecourse: How to Cut Carbs Free Weekly Newsletter 
 Related Articles 
 South Beach Diet Diary - Entering Phase Two Sugar on Ingredient Labels - Different Words that Mean Sugar Know the Carbs in Your Fruit - Diabetes, Carbs and Fruit - Carbohydrates an... Diabetes Nutrition Facts for Fruits and Vegetables - Fruit and Vegetable Nu... Passion Fruit - Definition and Information About Passion Fruit 
 
 Laura Dolson 
Low Carb Diets Guide

 Sign up for My Newsletter 

 Headlines Forum 
 Related Video Low Carb Grilled Eggplant How to Make Lemon Grilled Asparagus Low Carb Cauliflower Rice More Health Videos See All About.com Videos Related Searches low carb diets fruits and vegetables organic vegetables protein power beach zone glycemic load Explore Low Carb Diets Must Reads 
 6 Steps for the Beginner How to Get Through the First Week Low-Carb Food Pyramid Top 10 Low Carb Mistakes How to Cut Carbs 
 Most Popular 
 High-Protein Food List Low-Carb Fruits Getting Started on Low Carb Low-Carb Vegetables How to Cook Spaghetti Squash 
 See More About: 
 low carb food lists low carb fruit low carb snacks fruit 
 By Category 
 Low Carb 101 Low-Carb Super Foods What You Can Eat Low-Carb Menus Restaurant Eating Low-Carb Recipes Main Dishes Desserts South Beach Diet Atkins Diet Low-Carb Products Other Popular Diet Plans Science of Low Carb Books and DVDs Low-Carb Blogs 
 Low Carb Diets 
 About.com Health Low Carb Diets What You Can Eat Low-Carb/Low-Sugar Fruits: A list of the best and the worst fruit for low-carb dieters. 
 
 Most Popular Latest Articles RSS 
 Also from About.com: 
 Calorie Count - Nutrition Database 
 
 Advertise on About.com Our Story News&amp;Events Work at About SiteMap All Topics Reprints Help 

 Write for About User Agreement Ethics Policy Patent Info. Privacy Policy Your Ad Choices 
 
©2012 About.com. All rights reserved.

A part of The New York Times Company .
 We comply with the HONcode standard
for trustworthy health information: verify here .
	</body>
</document>
