<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009062" url="http://pul.se/L%C3%B8itens-Aquavit-til-Jul-Pork-belly-aquavit-whisky-blog-loitens-jDZfIdiP1ESS" time="2012-07-13-02:27" support="1" score="0.00038637499970913496" bingtitle="Pork belly - pul.se - Home" webtitle="Pork belly">
			<query id="000654" bing-rank="239"/>
	<description>The pork belly 1.1 Trillion dollar spending bill should be voted down, even at the cost of shutting down government, matter fact, the idea has a somewhat soothing ring to it.</description>
	<body>
		Home Search Real Time Hot Items Topics Help About Login as: Sign up 
 Remember me 
 

Pork belly
 ( Permalink ) 
 
 Løitens Aquavit til Jul! 
 [ Spirits ] ( Dr.Whisky )
Loitens Single Cask Aquavit barrel/fat #1627 Sept 2005-Oktober 201041.5% abv£80 Who says Dr. Whisky doesn&apos;t bring you exclusives any more? I imagine I am the only English language blogger posting about Loitens new single barrel aquavit, matured for five years in ex-sherry casks. This is just one of 950 bottles and a total of 5 casks were released in 2010: numbers 1950, 5315, 6125, 8330, and this one, 1627. Very whisky-esque labelling style and language, even looks like a Bruichladdich or even ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 
 Loitens Single Cask Aquavit 
 barrel/fat #1627 Sept 2005-Oktober 2010 41.5% abv £80 
 Who says Dr. Whisky doesn&apos;t bring you exclusives any more? I imagine I am the only English language blogger posting about Loitens new single barrel aquavit, matured for five years in ex-sherry casks. 
 This is just one of 950 bottles and a total of 5 casks were released in 2010: numbers 1950, 5315, 6125, 8330, and this one, 1627. 
 Very whisky-esque labelling style and language, even looks like a Bruichladdich or even Mackmyra bottle, although probably also similar to many of the cognacs the Norwegians drink so much of. Nonetheless, a unique and new proposition for the aquavit story where once the spicebill differentiated aquavit from aquavit, this one celebrates the maturation. 
 Thank you, Espen! To see all aquavit prescribed by yours truly, click HERE . 
 TASTING NOTES: 
 Rye and caraway seeds with the sweetness of corn or freshly baked bread in the background. 
 Oily and sweet, with a more mildly spiced mid palate than most aquavit and an increasing wave of butter, cloves, and caraway. 
 SUMMARY: 
 All the standard signs scream &quot;hello I am aquavit&quot; from the glass, all the quality cues on the label scream &quot;respect me like scotch whisky&quot; (it even says it is not chill-filtered!), and the liquid is rich and classy, deserving more than the typical SKOL and down. We all sipped slowly and shared ooos and aaaahs. Although that could have been a reaction to the heavenly ribbe ( pork belly ). 
 Best served at room temperature. 
 
 New&amp;Notable January 2011 
 [ San Diego, CA ] ( San Diego Magazine Print Edition )
[ A Modo Mio ] The Busalacchis reincarnate the family flagship and open A Modo Mio in Hillcrest this month. Joe Busalacchi promises a more seasonal menu that changes weekly but still features the famous garlic bread every day.[ Acquamoreé ] The third restaurant to occupy the same space on Prospect Street within a year (Pasquale’s and Tikul both closed shop in 2010), Acquamoreé now offers upscale tapas with lots of Southern flavors — fried catfish, shrimp, ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 [ A Modo Mio ] 
The Busalacchis reincarnate the family flagship and open A Modo Mio in Hillcrest this month. Joe Busalacchi promises a more seasonal menu that changes weekly but still features the famous garlic bread every day.

 [ Acquamoreé ] 
The third restaurant to occupy the same space on Prospect Street within a year (Pasquale’s and Tikul both closed shop in 2010), Acquamoreé now offers upscale tapas with lots of Southern flavors — fried catfish, shrimp, grits and mini-meatloaves all occupy space on the new menu.

 [ Chedi Thai ] 
La Jolla’s latest Thai food spot serves up a hearty selection of vegetarian and seafood items in addition to Thai standards. Our early favorites include the red snapper served whole with cherry tomatoes and bok choy. ­

 [ Flavor Del Mar ] 
Jeff Hunter’s Flavor Del Mar is now open in Del Mar Plaza, with everything from steamed pork buns and hot-and-sour chicken wings to pork belly and short ribs. Foodies will love to splurge on a $12 side of Wagyu bone marrow.

 [ Mint Downtown Thai ] 
With pork skewers, Bangkok wings and drunken fried rice all available for less than $10, Mint Downtown Thai fills a budget dining niche at its new post on Fourth Avenue in the Gaslamp. Daily $7 lunch specials and Happy Hour from 3 to 7 p.m. with $3 beer specials beckon downtown professionals, too. ­

 [ Bo Beau ] 
Bo Beau opens with a Mediterranean menu and new patio in Ocean Beach at the former site of Thee Bungalow. The Cohn family’s restaurant group has been working on the renovation since the end of summer. ­

 [ Sapori ] 
Coronado welcomes a new neighborhood Italian joint on Orange Avenue, with a chalkboard menu that changes daily, offering fresh pasta, soup and other rustic Italian fare.

 [ Cueva Bar ] 
University Heights gets a new tapas spot on Adams Avenue, with a simple selection of empanadas, stews and other small bites featuring Argentinean, Mexican and Southern flavors.

 [ The Lincoln Room ] 
Gaslamp nightclub and restaurant Confidential reopens in early 2011 as The Lincoln Room, with a menu and a dining space targeted at downtown locals rather than conventioneers or tourists.

 [ Addison at The Grand Del Mar ] 
Executive chef William Bradley was recently honored as an official Grand Chef of the ultra-exclusive Relais&amp;Châteaux Hotel Congress at a ceremony in South Africa. He’s the only chef in San Diego with the prestigious designation.

Coming Soon  .  .  .

Asian food spot [ Dragon’s Den ] moves into the East Village.
 [ Green Flash Brewery ] opens a new location in Mira Mesa in 2011.
 [ Stone Brewing Company ] has begun work on a new brewery and pub in South Park.
 
 Time to Learn About Tortellini en Brodo: A Christmas Soup With Serious History 
 [ Food ] ( Grub Street New York )
The dish in question. The newest menu addition at Giano restaurant is Tortellini en Brodo, a traditional Christmas soup of handmade pasta and a rich capon broth. It should be on the restaurant&apos;s menu for the next couple months. And when chef Simone Bonelli first told us about it, we were excited! It&apos;s kind of the ultimate dish you want when it&apos;s cold out, right? So we sent Geoffrey Gray over to the restaurant to try it, and to get the lowdown on the super-traditional dish. Read his full repo ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 The dish in question. 
The newest menu addition at Giano restaurant is Tortellini en Brodo, a traditional Christmas soup of handmade pasta and a rich capon broth. It should be on the restaurant&apos;s menu for the next couple months. And when chef Simone Bonelli first told us about it, we were excited! It&apos;s kind of the ultimate dish you want when it&apos;s cold out, right? So we sent Geoffrey Gray over to the restaurant to try it, and to get the lowdown on the super-traditional dish. Read his full report, below.

“So now it is time I tell you the legend of the tortellini,” Simone Bonelli says. It is cold in the basement of Giano, his restaurant off Tompkins Square Park, and the Italian chef is rolling out sheets of fresh pasta on a plywood table and dotting little squares with a ripineo we’ve been working on.

Today is Day Three, and the reason it’s all taking so long is because that’s the point. The plate Bonelli and I are making — tortellini en brodo — is an exercise in old-world patience, a defiance of modernity and efficiency.

In Modena, the city in northern Italy where the legendary engines for Ferrari and Maserati are made and where Bonelli is from, the dumplinglike tortellini soup is typically eaten only one day of the year, Christmas, so it’s crucial to get the steps of the recipe right, no matter how many days go by.

“If we don’t make the tortellini this way the tradition will die, and that would be horrible,” says Bonelli, who recently moved to Giano from the inventive Perbacco a few blocks away.

In Modena, when Bonelli was a boy, he learned how to make the dish from his grandmother, who spent hours closing up tortellini with her friends around the dining-room table and fried up leftover pasta dough and sprinkled the strips with sugar to appease the many nagging children in the kitchen. Bonelli also learned the plate’s origins from his father, who owned a gas station in Modena.

The soup was a peasant creation. The evolution started with the brodo, a rich broth favored by the ruling classes and made from boiled capon. By the time the broth was ready, all the flavor from the capon’s meat was gone. The house staff in the kitchens throughout Emilia-Romagna didn’t dare throw away edible meat; instead they peppered in crumbs of Parmesan cheese, then scraps of prosciutto or mortadella. The mixture was then ground into a ripineo and smidges were placed on tortellini small enough to fit on a spoon.

Which brings us back to the legend. It started a thousand or so years ago, after a battle between Modena and neighboring Bologna. After fighting one day, the gods Venus and Jupiter retreated to a tavern to spend the night. The innkeeper was so overtaken with Venus’s beauty he spied on her through a hole in the door. The only part of Venus’s body the peeping innkeeper could see was her navel. The innkeeper then retreated back to the kitchen.

“He’s horny and all he can think about is the shape of her belly button,” Bonelli says. “And that’s why we have tortellini.”

The recipe had started out with a massive pork loin, cleaned of all fat and cooked. Then veal, and sausage without fennel seeds (&quot;So important, man!&quot;). After cooking, the fatty juice from the meat is saved and boiled down. Meanwhile, prosciutto and mortadella are sliced and ground, along with the pork , veal, and sausage. We then mixed the ground meats with the boiled-down juice, a few eggs, and nutmeg, and blanketed the concoction with grated Parmesan, mixing and pounding into the precious ripenio.

The next step is the brodo. Instead of using a chicken to make the broth, Bonelli ordered a capon. He brings it to a boil in cold water, with the usual accoutrements: celery, onion, rosemary, thyme, careful to remove the fat. Four hours later, the brodo is ready. The color is a deep brown, almost like curry. It has a rich if not fatty taste, so much so that in Modena a splash of local Lambrusco is often used to cut it. And our tortellini … Unlike store-bought tortellini, which can have a slimy, plastic veneer when cooked, these precious darlings are delectably clean.

They also crunch. The broth is served hot, so the tortellini must be cooked super al dente because they continue to cook once the dish is served. And the power is the ripineo, the amalgam of pork loin, sausage, prosciutto, mortadella, and veal, which join forces to create mini-explosions of flavor.

“A universe of sensations for the mouth,” Bonelli says, and “a small piece of my heart.”

Read more posts by Geoffrey Gray 

Filed Under: historical artifacts , giano , holiday , simone bonelli 

 
 
 
 Lunch Links (The “See You On Monday” Edition) 
 [ New York City, NY , Food , New York City ] ( Midtown Lunch )
All I Want For X-Mas is Some Crispy Pork Belly . Photo by Eat to Blog. Here’s a pretty thorough guide to Fuji Bakery’s lunch specials [Eat to Blog] Our old friend Danny likes Qdoba better than Chipotle [Food in Mouth] Sunrise Mart serves pastries from Panya, and a very authentic Tokyo style soba [Ramen and Friends] Hickey’s has closed ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   All I Want For X-Mas is Some Crispy Pork Belly . Photo by Eat to Blog. Here’s a pretty thorough guide to Fuji Bakery’s lunch specials [Eat to Blog] Our old friend Danny likes Qdoba better than Chipotle [Food in Mouth] Sunrise Mart serves pastries from Panya, and a very authentic Tokyo style soba [Ramen and Friends] Hickey’s has closed [...]
 
 
 
 Where It At? Pork Belly Tacos 
 [ Miami, FL ] ( Short Order )
What it is: Three fat wedges of pork belly stuffed into three teeny tortilla-like shells.Where it at? That&apos;s for you to guess. Place your best bet below in the comments section, and we&apos;ll let y ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   What it is: Three fat wedges of pork belly stuffed into three teeny tortilla-like shells.Where it at? That&apos;s for you to guess. Place your best bet below in the comments section, and we&apos;ll let y... 
 This Week in &apos;New York Times&apos; Food News 
 [ Food ] ( Serious Eats )
Bubbly Galore: Exploring the non-Champagne side of French sparkling wine. Mozza&apos;s Family Dinners: At Osteria Mozza in Los Angeles, pig and beef dinners create ad hoc foodie families. Party Dips and Apps: Recipes for queso fundido with chorizo and jalapeño, and pork belly cracklings.
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Bubbly Galore: Exploring the non-Champagne side of French sparkling wine. Mozza&apos;s Family Dinners: At Osteria Mozza in Los Angeles, pig and beef dinners create ad hoc foodie families. Party Dips and Apps: Recipes for queso fundido with chorizo and jalapeño, and pork belly cracklings. 
 So I&apos;m Getting an Immersion Circulator 
 [ Spirits ] ( eGullet Forums Recently Started Topics )
I just found out that my husband, who is not only willing to put up with me but actually seems to like me a little bit, has gotten an immersion circulator for my Christmas present. Of course I&apos;m going to cook a sous vide egg for him first, but what should I do next? I have lots of fun things in my meat freezer that might be good - pig snouts and trotters, pork osso bucco cuts, lots of venison and rabbit, beef and pork liver, whole jowls, pork belly , and there are probably a few hearts and kid ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   I just found out that my husband, who is not only willing to put up with me but actually seems to like me a little bit, has gotten an immersion circulator for my Christmas present. Of course I&apos;m going to cook a sous vide egg for him first, but what should I do next?

I have lots of fun things in my meat freezer that might be good - pig snouts and trotters, pork osso bucco cuts, lots of venison and rabbit, beef and pork liver, whole jowls, pork belly , and there are probably a few hearts and kidneys floating around in there. And yes, there&apos;s probably any normal cut you can think of in there too. There are worse things to hoard than good meat.

So, any suggestions? Any opinions on what to put in the bag with the meat? 
 How to avoid becoming a pork belly writer in Topeka, KS 
 [ Hypeads ] ( inmedia Public Relations Inc. - High tech public relations )
Regular readers of this blog will recall that a few weeks ago I wrote about the U.K. court case of Meltwater vs. the Newspaper Licensing Agency (NLA), an ongoing story that spotlights the challenges of traditional media outlets to maintain control of, and monetize, their content in the age of Web 2.0 and news aggregation/media monitoring ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Regular readers of this blog will recall that a few weeks ago I wrote about the U.K. court case of Meltwater vs. the Newspaper Licensing Agency (NLA), an ongoing story that spotlights the challenges of traditional media outlets to maintain control of, and monetize, their content in the age of Web 2.0 and news aggregation/media monitoring [...] 
 Portland New Year’s Eve 2010 Restaurant Events 
 [ Food ] ( An Exploration of Portland Oregon Food and Drink )
Looking for somewhere to spend New Year’s Eve? Here’s the 2010 list with all the details! Happy New Year everyone! Beaverton: Monteaux’s Public House - Ring in the New Year with style in suburbia! Chef Michael Keskin’s epic menu: Artisan Cheese Board, Pork Belly w/White Bean, Rack of Lamb, Filet Mignon, Crispy Skin Steelhead, Hazelnut Crusted Sole, Asparagus Truffle Risotto, Read more ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Looking for somewhere to spend New Year’s Eve? Here’s the 2010 list with all the details! Happy New Year everyone! Beaverton: Monteaux’s Public House - Ring in the New Year with style in suburbia! Chef Michael Keskin’s epic menu: Artisan Cheese Board, Pork Belly w/White Bean, Rack of Lamb, Filet Mignon, Crispy Skin Steelhead, Hazelnut Crusted Sole, Asparagus Truffle Risotto, 
Read more... 
 A new dimension of crustiness: mini baguette (bâtard) x mini roast pork belly 
 [ Hong Kong , Asian Food ] ( Cha Xiu Bao )
A whole new level of crustiness is achie ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   A whole new level of crustiness is achie... 
 Restaurant review: North Road 
 [ Guardian ] ( Travel: Restaurants | guardian.co.uk )
Starting with North Road, his final review of the year, and working back to his Worst Restaurant Experience of the past 12 months, Jay Rayner reveals his personal winners and losers of 2010North Road, 69-73 St John Street, London EC1 (020 3217 0033). Meal for two, including wine and service: £110 There were good reasons for choosing North Road as my last restaurant to review before Christmas. With the first heavy snowfalls clogging the capital&apos;s streets, and a sky the colour of gunmetal, it ma ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en-gb   
Starting with North Road, his final review of the year, and working back to his Worst Restaurant Experience of the past 12 months, Jay Rayner reveals his personal winners and losers of 2010

 North Road, 69-73 St John Street, London EC1 (020 3217 0033). Meal for two, including wine and service: £110 


There were good reasons for choosing North Road as my last restaurant to review before Christmas. With the first heavy snowfalls clogging the capital&apos;s streets, and a sky the colour of gunmetal, it made a kind of sense to eat somewhere that takes its cues from Scandinavia. Inside it is all clean lines and blonde wood and a cool, steady light. Danish chef Christoffer Hruskova trained at some of the same restaurants in Copenhagen as the much-lauded René Redzepi of Noma, this year declared the best restaurant in the world in the annual rankings of these things, and he wears that heritage about as lightly as Scandinavians tend to, which is to say not lightly at all.

Which is the second reason for choosing North Road, because if anything came to define 2010 it was the way in which Noma, with its die-hard commitment to Nordic food, set the agenda for everyone else. Chefs who used to get their ingredients merely by standing at the kitchen door and waving in the deliveries this year got down on their knees in the hedgerows for a good old forage. Then they told you all about the foraging they&apos;d been doing so you knew just how much they cared. They banged on about bitter herbs plucked from little-known roundabouts on the A327, and extolled the virtues of bulbs and berries which we used to leave to the birds. It was both rather refreshing and, in the way of hot trends, mildly irritating, too.

Hruskova&apos;s cooking is about as close as you&apos;ll get to Redzepi&apos;s without buying a plane ticket, though to be honest it&apos;s still some way off the precision and acute sense of balance. It&apos;s good without having Redzepi&apos;s brilliance. Being in London he cannot raid the Nordic larder, for that would be against doctrine. Heaven forfend. Instead, the ingredients are distinctly British: think elderberries and salsify, celery and Dorset shrimp. But what he does do, pace Noma, is reject those French or Mediterranean foodstuffs which would make his dishes something other. So no olive oil or olives. No tomatoes or bulb garlic. No chocolate in the desserts. He is more likely to season with vinegars than salts, to rely on smoking and pickling and leave ingredients raw where possible. The result is subtle and, for being unusual, intriguing. Smoked scallops, only just cooked through, come with a julienne of apple and a leaf of bright apple jelly; glazed sweetbreads are paired with lightly pickled onions and hidden under a sheet of crinkly milk skin – the thin solid you get when you boil up milk.

It was a good start. And so, courtesy of a segue worthy of a hairy 1970s Radio One DJ, to my first award, Starter of the Year 2010 , which has to go to Eddie Gilbert&apos;s in Margate and their beautifully simple, exquisitely executed soft duck egg with crisp breaded and deep-fried smoked eel soldiers. It was, as the best food often is, both supremely adult and curiously infantilising. In a year in which, despite the recession, big-name openings kept coming, finding such a good but low-key operation as Eddie Gilbert&apos;s was a joy.

At the other end of the spectrum it seems a little mean to kick a man when he&apos;s down, though when that man is Gordon Ramsay it doesn&apos;t seem mean enough to stop. Because of all those big openings, the one that wins the Why Did the Annoying Schmucks Even Bother? Award has to be his Petrus. It was dull, expensive and, like the man himself these days, tiresome. The determination to hold on to the Petrus name, given that it a) isn&apos;t his and b) had been built up in London by his erstwhile protégé Marcus Wareing, just looked childish. Much like… oh, never mind.

Far better was Bar Boulud at London&apos;s Mandarin Oriental Hotel, a Frenchman&apos;s smart take on a Manhattan brasserie, which arrived fully formed and quickly stole the Best Burger in Town Award . Dense, flavourful juicy meat; proper bun; good but not silly accompaniments. Less pleasing was their insistence that you could only have the table for two hours. If I&apos;m going to drop £100 on dinner I&apos;ll take as a long as I like, thank you very much. In the same vein the Most Profoundly Irritating Trend of 2010 goes to the arrival of computerised reservation books, which require robotic front-of-house staff to demand not just a surname for the booking but a first name, too. I don&apos;t want to be on first-name terms with restaurants. I don&apos;t want to be on their Christmas-card list. It was never necessary before, and it shouldn&apos;t be necessary now.

The person who took my booking at North Road, which uses just such a system, got quite stroppy with me when I said they could put Mister as my first name. Thankfully their cooking made it worthwhile. We very much liked a main course of monkfish with bitter sea beets and sweet pickled clams. Best of all, though, was my loin of venison served very rare and with beetroot, which made the whole plate look like it had been devised courtesy of an industrial accident in an abattoir. In a good way. The slices of venison had been rolled in burnt hay ash, which gave it a fabulous savoury kick, and laid on top were jewels of smoked bone marrow. An impressive dish. But not quite the winner of my award for Main Course of the Year , which has to go to Bistro Bruno Loubet, and the chef&apos;s dark, unctuous hare royale, topped by a ravioli of puréed onion and surrounded by a silky pumpkin purée punched up with mandarin. The return of Loubet to London, along with the likes of Joel Antunes and others, is a sign of just how much of a draw the British capital has become. And if that feels terribly London-centric, you&apos;ll just have to live with it. Because London is where they&apos;re coming to cook, not Droitwich.

Mind you, we do have to take the rough with the smooth, because we also get the real stinkers. Back in January I described dinner at the Criterion in Piccadilly as a serious contender for the title of Worst Restaurant Experience of the Year , despite that year being only three weeks old. We have reached December and nothing came close in gut-twisting, why-did-they-do-it?, someone-must-be-punished awfulness. A violation of the good name of bouillabaisse, a crab risotto which left me needing therapy for which I&apos;m still paying, and a member of staff who kept crossing the restaurant wearing black elbow-length rubber gloves, as though he was helping a cow with an especially tricky breach birth. All in all a terrible waste of a truly beautiful room.

As ever this year, English was treated to cruel and unusual punishment by chefs and restaurateurs whose menu-writing skills suggested it was their second language. The absurdly pretentious paragraph-long menu descriptions at Cabbage Hall in Cheshire were only the very worst examples. But let&apos;s accentuate the positive with the Best Menu Description Award , which goes to the Curlew in East Sussex for its fabulously named chops and chips: beef short rib slow-cooked over two days, with a side of chips cooked in dripping. I adored it, even if my cardiologist was less impressed.

In brief: Most Welcome Arrival Award , for being so simple and yet so good, was the Italian Trullo at Highbury Corner, which delivered on almost every level and made it look easy. Most Cynical Opening is still Tom&apos;s Terrace at London&apos;s Somerset House. A dull menu, which read like it had been phoned in by Tom Aikens, and stupid prices combined to make this a masterclass in how not to do it.

Which leaves only Best Dessert . It has to be said North Road is a serious competitor here, not for its riff on Jerusalem artichokes, which was interesting without being lovable, but for a plate of caramel creams and mousses, the flavours punched through with liquorice. Of all the things we ate here this is the one for which I would return. It was the sort of dish whose end you mourn. But the winner of the title, by a dribble of syrup and a side order of insulin, was the sticky toffee brioche pudding at the Kingham Plough in the Cotswolds. It tasted like it sounds, and looked like a slab of pork belly . If you&apos;ve been reading this column closely over the past year you&apos;ll know that this would do it for me. And if you have been reading with such attention to detail, well then, thank you. I&apos;m touched, in that very special adult way. Have a great Christmas.


Email Jay at jay.rayner@observer.co.uk or visit guardian.co.uk/profile/jayrayner 
 
 Food&amp;drink Restaurants Restaurants 
 Jay Rayner 
 guardian.co.uk © Guardian News&amp;Media Limited 2010 | Use of this content is subject to our Terms&amp;Conditions | More Feeds 
 Home Away from Home for the Holidays 
 [ Washington, D.C. ] ( Examiner RSS )
Jordan Wright Special to The Washington Examiner Charlottesville and the Piedmont The Boar&apos;s Head Inn is a perfect destination for couples or families. Horse and carriage rides with a Blue Ridge backdrop, breakfast with Santa, Christmas Dinner in the Old Mill and gingerbread workshops are some of the holiday activities to choose from. New Year&apos;s Eve celebrations feature the Kings o ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Jordan Wright Special to The Washington Examiner 
 Charlottesville and the Piedmont 

 The Boar&apos;s Head Inn is a perfect destination for couples or families. 

 Horse and carriage rides with a Blue Ridge backdrop, breakfast with Santa, Christmas Dinner in the Old Mill and gingerbread workshops are some of the holiday activities to choose from. New Year&apos;s Eve celebrations feature the Kings of Swing and Executive Chef Bill Justus&apos; lavish Virginia-centric menu offering choices like Braised Veal Cheek Ravioli with Wild Mushrooms, Porcini Marmalade and Leek Froth, Beef Carpaccio with Watercress, Arugula and White Truffle Oil, Lobster Consomme with Black Trumpet Mushrooms and Lobster Quenelles, and Stuffed Veal Chop with Foie Gras, Black Truffle, Fontina and Prosciutto with Chestnut Spaetzle and Brussels Sprouts. Desserts will wow with Green Apple Terrine with Vanilla Bean Sponge and Mascarpone Sabayon, and Milk Chocolate Gateau with Chocolate Mousse, Kettle Corn and Banana Rum Ice Cream. 

 For a special treat the &quot;Radio City Christmas Spectacular Package&quot; includes dinner, overnight stay and tickets to see the Rockettes perform in nearby Charlottesville. Luxuriate in the full-service spa or hit the state-of-the-art fitness center and sports club offering indoor tennis and dozens of classes in zumba, yoga and kickboxing. 

 Keswick Hall&apos;s 48-room Tuscan-style villa sets the gold standard for luxury country inns in Virginia. Enjoy underwater music in the outdoor heated pool, beauty treatments in the spa and fitness facilities, or just relax in the 400-volume library and Tea Room with antique snooker table. In the evenings chestnuts will roast and s&apos;mores will melt on an open fire. Ladle creamy hot chocolate from a copper pot beside the grand fireplace in the hotel&apos;s spacious lobby. On Christmas Eve there&apos;s caroling and a special holiday sunday brunch is served throughout December. 

 Christmas dinner at Fossett&apos;s offers plenty of choices from recently named &quot;Rising Star Chef&quot; Dean Maupin. Indulge in his Maine lobster bisque, Osetra caviar, seared foie gras, Wagyu beef, rack of Fluvanna County lamb or Carolina flounder. For dessert traditional Buche de Noel beckons, as does an over-the-top version of Sticky Toffee Pudding. 

 At the nearby Barboursville Winery&apos;s upscale Palladio Restaurant Executive Chef Melissa Close Hart, who has prepared many a meal at New York&apos;s James Beard House, cooks her delicate version of northern Italian cuisine that pairs brilliantly with the estate&apos;s wines. Most products are sourced from local farms and the exquisite pasta is house-made. 

 While staying in the area view Colonial holiday decorations at nearby Montpelier, the home of James Madison, and at Monticello, Thomas Jefferson&apos;s house and gardens. For ski and snowboarding facilities Wintergreen Resort is about an hour&apos;s drive away. 

 www.boarsheadinn.com 

 www.keswick.com 

 www.barboursvillewine.net 

 www.montpelier.org 

 www.monticello.org 

 On Maryland&apos;s Eastern Shore 

 The Inn at 202 Dover in Easton is certainly one of the most stunning mansions on the Eastern Shore. Boasting five-star luxury appointments, an elegant library, glass conservatory and antique-filled rooms, it has only five suites, each a private themed retreat with 6-foot jetted Jacuzzis and in-room saunas and gas fireplaces. 

 Ron and Shelby Mitchell, transplanted New Yorkers, have brought a sophisticated dynamic to the art of innkeeping. On New Year&apos;s Eve guests will be dancing to D.C. music man Joe Holt and singer Beth MacDonald following a five-course dinner in the intimate Peacock Restaurant prepared by the inn&apos;s Cordon Bleu-trained Chef Mark Knipp, formerly chef de partie at the Inn at Little Washington. They&apos;ll have a four-course dinner with dishes like Poached Carolina Flounder with Sun-dried Tomato Meyer Lemon Risotto, Roast Duckling Gabor with Chestnuts and Pistachios, Vanilla-Poached Lobster with Truffled Root Vegetables, Tournedos of Beef Tenderloin with Truffle Mushroom Port Jus and Cippolino Onion and Potato Puree. Dessert is a decadent Chocolate Flourless Torte with Chambord and Chantilly Cream. 

 Convivial young hosts, Jordan and Alice Lloyd opened the Bartlett Pear Inn in a 220-year-old home in Easton. Jordan, who trained with French chef extraordinaire Michel Richard at Citronelle and Thomas Keller at New York&apos;s Per Se, emerged with his own style, reworking classic dishes with a clean finish. The small bar has become a big draw among upscale locals, but the food is the main draw at this very pretty pear-themed property. New Year&apos;s Eve dinner features a five-course dinner. Roasted Chestnut Soup with Duck Leg Confit, Truffled Maitake Mushroom Veloute Fricassee, Chicken Ballotine with Truffled Sweetbreads, Roasted Apple and Madeira Wine Jus, Braised Beef Short Ribs with Potato Agnolotti are a few of the choices on this elegant menu that finishes with Buche de Noel, Pavlova with Pomegranate Sorbet or Valrhona Hot Chocolate with house-made sugar doughnuts. 

 In Oxford, America&apos;s oldest inn dates back to 1710. This year the historic Robert Morris Inn, recently purchased by British hotelier Ian Fleming, celebrates 300 years in operation. In period-inspired guest rooms you can channel your inner James Michener ... he outlined his sweeping saga &quot;Chesapeake&quot; here overlooking the Tred Avon River. 

 On Christmas Day renowned international chef and proprietor Mark Salter will serve an eclectic menu of favorites culled from his background in Welsh, Scottish, Engish and French cuisine with dishes like Potato Soup with Lobster and Chives, Oysters Rockefeller with Spinach, Bacon and Parmesan Cheese, Chicken Liver Parfait with Beet Apple Chutney and Toasted Brioche, Seared Scallops with char-grilled Red Onion, Scottish Salmon with French Lentils and Kale, Smoked Bacon and Five-Onion Sauce, Pennsylvania Dutch Turkey and Baked Ham with Sage, Onion and Chestnut stuffing, Grilled Tenderloin of Beef with layered Goat Cheese and Potato and Truffled Celery Root Puree with Madeira-Black Pepper Jus. Desserts beckon with a traditional Christmas pudding, Caramelized Apple and Frangipane Tart and Milk Chocolate Creme Brulee with Hazelnut Shortbread. A jazz band accompanies the lavish five-course New Year&apos;s Eve dinner beginning with champagne and canapes. 

   

 The Inn at Perry Cabin is a magnificent destination resort with a chic nautical look reminiscent of the Ralph Lauren style. It overlooks the Miles River within walking distance of the Victorian village of St. Michaels. Executive Chef Greg Brandberg, who earned his stripes under Lydia Bastianich and Iron Chef Masaharu Morimoto, brings an Eastern Shore sensibility. Brandberg plans a sumptuous Christmas feast that includes, Yellow Fin Tuna and Local Crab, Maine Lobster Bisque and Oysters Rockefeller, Grilled Scottish Salmon with Port Wine Glaze, Herb Roasted Beef Tenderloin and Juniper-Scented Braised Pork . 

 The inn&apos;s New Year&apos;s Eve gala features Herb Stuffed Pheasant Roulade, Atlantic Halibut with Black Trumpet Mushrooms, and Beef Wellington plus a ballroom dedicated to divine desserts made by pastry chef Elise Broz who will ring in the New Year by featuring more than 20 different delectable sweets. The 10-piece Eric Felten Jazz Orchestra will play big band standards a la Cole Porter, Duke Ellington and George Gershwin. How romantic! 

 Throughout December horse-drawn wagons ferry passengers around historic downtown Easton, and on New Year&apos;s Eve the town hosts &quot;First Night Talbot&quot; with a parade of sea creature puppets led by a giant mermaid. Bands, gospel choirs, jugglers and scads of other family-friendly acts perform around town culminating in fireworks and a countdown to the kitschy, must-see &quot;Crab Drop.&quot; 

 The beautifully restored Avalon Theatre in downtown Easton plays host over the holidays to a Messiah Sing In night and D.C.&apos;s Eric Byrd Trio doing &quot;A Charlie Brown Christmas.&quot; 

 www.innat202dover.com 

 www.bartlettpearinn.com 

 www.robertmorrisinn.com 

 www.perrycabin.com 

 www.theavalon.org 

 www.easternshore.com/firstnighttalbot 

 On Virginia&apos;s Northern Neck 

 The Hope and Glory in the tiny town of Irvington is a circa 1890 former schoolhouse now bed and breakfast, whose proprietors Dudley and Peggy Patteson encourage their guests to talk among themselves. With a zinc-topped bar that encourages collegial truancy it sports No. 2 pencils and black-and-white composition books to write down your drink order. A large reception area with desks, chess boards and a welcoming fireplace offers itself up for reading a book, sipping a cocktail or meeting your fellow travelers. 

   

 The harvest table prompts guests to share their adventures at their wonderful breakfast. Painted furniture, overstuffed chairs and antiques mix chockablock with stylish decor in an irreverent elegance. No frilly doilies or tea cozies here. It feels just like home ... decorated by Aunt Martha Stewart. 

 Since dinner is not available at the inn the hip Nate&apos;s Trick Dog Restaurant, which had its ups and downs in the past, has bounced back with new chef-to-watch Nate Myers, who along with his wife, Courtney, have recently resurrected the cool vibe and eclectic food. 

 Look for creative and deliciously memorable cuisine driven by bold fusion flavors. Myers will serve a couples-oriented holiday menu for Christmas Eve, New Year&apos;s Eve and New Year&apos;s Day with classic French dishes like cassoulet, chateaubriand, and a deconstructed beef Wellington. 

 Also in Irvington, the Tides Inn is one of the country&apos;s most distinctive resorts. Four generations of the Stephens family have been welcoming both D.C. area and international guests to the hotel&apos;s 106 rooms and suites since 1947 by yacht or motorcar to this quietly luxurious top-drawer destination on Virginia&apos;s Northern Neck. Chef Thomas Flynn plans several different four-course dinners for Christmas Eve, Christmas Day and New Year&apos;s Eve. A few choices are the Rappahannock Oysters with pickled watermelon salsa and Tamarind Ginger Sauce, She-Crab Soup, Herb Roasted Chesapeake Bay Rockfish, Pecan Crusted Rack of Lamb with Cranberry Gastrique and always their famous crab cakes. Desserts range from White Chocolate Creme Brulee to Triple Chocolate Bread Pudding. Be sure to book an appointment to enjoy the posh spa. 

 www.hopeandglory.com 

 www.trickdogcafe.com 

 www.tidesinn.com 

 In Richmond 

 The Jefferson Hotel is one of the nation&apos;s most spectacular historic properties. Built in 1895 to compete with Europe&apos;s most magnificent hotels, everything about it spells graciousness and grandeur. Executive Chef Walter Bundy, who trained with Mark Miller in Santa Fe, N.M., and Thomas Keller in Napa Valley,Calif., grows herbs in the hotel&apos;s garden and includes a myriad of gorgeous vegetables with his main dishes. He will be serving such delicious offerings as Bourbon Braised Ayrshire Farm Pork Belly with Apple Cider Gastrique, Diver Scallops with Ginger Infused Vanilla Bean Orange Butter, and Loch Duart Salmon with Spicy Spaghetti Squash, Edwards&amp;Sons Surryano Ham and Cauliflower Coulis. Desserts are unique and nontraditional -- Peanut Butter Semifreddo with Dark Chocolate Ganache, Pumpkin and Chocolate Chip Bread Pudding with Bourbon Anglaise and Pumpkin Seed Tuile, and a Pear Raisin Cobbler. If you are there for the weekend be sure to enjoy the spoon bread at their legendary Sunday brunch served in the Rotunda beneath soaring 70-foot ceilings. Tweaked and lightened up Southern classics like Surry County Sausage Stuffing, Jamerson Farms Brunswick Stew, and Jefferson Spoonbread share space with all the other fabulous brunch items. 

 While in town catch the Richmond Ballet&apos;s Nutcracker, hop a free ride on the horse-drawn sleigh rides around Carytown, visit the newly renovated Virginia Museum of Fine Arts open 365 days of the year including free access to their exhibitions on Christmas Day, and see the festive display of lights at the Lewis Ginter Botanical Gardens. 

 www.jeffersonhotel.com 

 www.vmfa.state.va.us 

 www.lewisginter.org 

 www.richmondballet.com 
 
 Top Chef Recap: A Better Obsession Than Cocaine or Heroin 
 [ Food ] ( Grub Street New York )
This face was just too good. Last night&apos;s Top Chef went back to form, kicking off with everyone being shocked at Jen&apos;s elimination. But we jumped right into the Quickfire, where Padma split everyone up into four teams for a race against time. We got excited that perhaps this was mega-Restaurant Wars come early, but no. Instead, the chefs were asked to prep three ingredients to guest judge David Chang&apos;s mise en place standards. Whoever finished first got to hit the Staples &quot;that was easy&quot; but ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 This face was just too good. 
Last night&apos;s Top Chef went back to form, kicking off with everyone being shocked at Jen&apos;s elimination. But we jumped right into the Quickfire, where Padma split everyone up into four teams for a race against time. We got excited that perhaps this was mega-Restaurant Wars come early, but no. Instead, the chefs were asked to prep three ingredients to guest judge David Chang&apos;s mise en place standards. Whoever finished first got to hit the Staples &quot;that was easy&quot; button, setting off a timer that counted down fifteen minutes until the hatch imploded and everyone had to be done with both prep and a finished dish.

Despite finishing first, the green team — Fabio, Tiffany, Mike I, and Angelo (wearing black aprons, though, hilariously, because apparently it would not be okay to have a black team) — and their lamb with garlic and tandoori-spiced yogurt ended up in the bottom, along with the red &quot;Hi ladies ... and Dale&quot; team (Antonia, Jamie, Casey, and Caucasian Dale)&apos;s lamb carpaccio with capers and Reggiano cheese. Chang liked the white team (Marcel, Tiffani, Asian Dale, and Carla)&apos;s lamb carpaccio with artichoke salad and garlic oil (apparently having a white team is okay), but gave the win, and $5,000 each, to the blue team (Spike, Richard, Tre, and Stephen)&apos;s crispy lamb chop with artichokes three ways.

The teams were then each assigned an elite New York restaurant to eat dinner at, which would be followed by each chef cooking a dish that could go on that restaurant&apos;s menu. The white team met Wylie Dufresne at wd~50 , blue met Michael White at Marea , red met David Burke at David Burke Townhouse , and green met David Chang at Má Pêche . Obviously, Angelo was beside himself at getting the Asian restaurant, prompting Tiffany to complain about how annoying he is. The blue team got an annoying dinner companion, too, as Stephen talked about Marea like he wrote his thesis on it, while Tre (who some people call the black Italian) marveled at how perfectly cooked the food was. O rly? Never would have guessed that! Carla got nervous at wd~50 while Marcel bugged out in excitement, and we just wondered why Wylie&apos;s hairstyle reminded us of Betty Draper. Oh, and the folks at David Burke had fish swimming in their cocktails.

Thankfully the producers skipped over the shopping at Whole Foods and went straight to the cooking (though not before showing us a shot of Stephen in a white suit and polka-dot tie). Marea was the first stop, where the judges loved Tre&apos;s grilled swordfish with artichokes and mushroom panna cotta, but couldn&apos;t get over how fennel-y Stephen&apos;s salmon with black mission figs was. Anthony Bourdain compared the flavor to a head shop and, well, chances are he would know. The judges then hailed a cab (sadly, not the Cash Cab) to Má Pêche, where they loved Angelo&apos;s tumeric-marinated fish with chorizo, salmon roe, and white chocolate, but were overwhelmed by all the flavors in Fabio&apos;s roasted lamb with hoisin plum barbecue sauce and homemade ricotta.

At Townhouse, most of the judges seemed to favor Casey&apos;s halibut &quot;scallop&quot; with tapioca &quot;caviar,&quot; but David Burke himself really loved Antonia&apos;s seared scallop with carrot puree and, of course, pea puree. There was one thing the judges did agree on — Caucasian Dale&apos;s roasted veal loin with peanuts, popcorn, French toast, and thyme caramel was just an overly sweet dish with veal on it. The last stop was wd~50, where the favorite was Asian Dale&apos;s sunny egg dumpling with braised pork belly and milk ramen with bacon, probably because Dale smartly played to Wylie&apos;s favorite food, the egg. Tiffani&apos;s broken summer heirloom tomato, frozen melons, and powdered ham and cheese was not nearly so successful.

Judges&apos; table was fairly quick, as they&apos;ve finally stopped supersizing the episodes. The judges gave the win, and a trip to New Zealand, to Asian Dale, while sending Caucasian Dale and Stephen (who was feeling a lot of different emotions) packing. Dale suggested he&apos;d return for season sixteen, Top Chef Seniors. Perhaps we&apos;ll recap that one from the retirement home.

Next week: Cooking at the U.S. Open! Someone&apos;s bleeding! Angelo schemes! Everyone&apos;s mad at Jamie! Something is flaccid! That&apos;s still what she said!

Read more posts by Alexandra Martell 

Filed Under: top chef , overnights , pea puree is going to be on every episode for the rest of eternity , recaps , top chef all stars , tv 

 
 
 
 Let the Government Shut Down 
 [ CNN ] ( CNN iReport - Latest )
The pork belly 1.1 Trillion dollar spending bill should be voted down, even at the cost of shutting down government, matter fact, the idea has a somewhat soothing ring to it. After all what could help out our debt and deficit more then a sudden stop of spending, even for a few days gotta save billions. Maybe that an idea to helping cut the budget, lets cut one day off every federal employee a month, maybe even a week. The democrats must really believe changes are coming to Washington, with liter ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
The pork belly 1.1 Trillion dollar spending bill should be voted down, even at the cost of shutting down government, matter fact, the idea has a somewhat soothing ring to it.

 

After all what could help out our debt and deficit more then a sudden stop of spending, even for a few days gotta save billions.

 

Maybe that an idea to helping cut the budget, lets cut one day off every federal employee a month, maybe even a week.

 

The democrats must really believe changes are coming to Washington, with literally thousands of earmark loading down this nearly 2000 page bill. Another 2000 page bill. Are these bill writers getting paid by the page?

 

Now, why would the dems throw such a crucial bill down so late, and make it so complex , and so large, with so little time to get it passed?

 

There an old saying,&quot; Your lack of planning, Doesn&apos;t make my Emergency.&quot;

 

That should be the reply of each member of congress who doesn&apos;t get a chance to completely read and then vote no.

 

If you do read it, and you like it, vote yes, and we&apos;ll give you our opinion in the next election.

 

If you read it and don&apos;t like it the vote no. Don&apos;t allow yourself to be pressured by the dems holding the federal government as hostage. As Obama said we don&apos;t negotiate with hostage takers. And in this case, the function of the federal government truly is being held hostage, by those who presented this bill.
 
 &apos;So You Want to Be A Journalist&apos; [Video] 
 [ Silicon Valley, CA , New York City, NY , Fashion , New York City ] ( Gawker )
#howthingswork This video, explaining everything you need to know about a career in journalism, is being passed around the office at the New York Times. You&apos;ll see why. Would you like to write about pork belly futures, for a trade magazine? More » ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   This video , explaining everything you need to know about a career in journalism , is being passed around the office at the New York Times . You&apos;ll see why. Would you like to write about pork belly futures, for a trade magazine? More » 
 
 Getting Both Sides of the Mado Saga - Brandon Baltzley 
 [ Chicago, IL , Chicago ] ( Chicagoist )
Last week, Chicago magazine spoke to Brandon Baltzley, the former chef of Mado (who left the restaurant last week) and David Richards, the owner of the restaurant, about the circumstances surrounding all of the goings-on at the restaurant. We published part of the story last week, but we wanted more details, and contacted both Baltzley and Richards for more details on the story. Below is an edited transcript of our recorded conversation with Chef Baltzley. We&apos;ll present Richards&apos;s side of th ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 Last week, Chicago magazine spoke to Brandon Baltzley, the former chef of Mado (who left the restaurant last week) and David Richards, the owner of the restaurant, about the circumstances surrounding all of the goings-on at the restaurant. We published part of the story last week, but we wanted more details, and contacted both Baltzley and Richards for more details on the story. Below is an edited transcript of our recorded conversation with Chef Baltzley. We&apos;ll present Richards&apos;s side of the story tomorrow this afternoon.

 Chicagoist - We read your interview with Penny [Pollack] in Chicago magazine, which I think was the last published “straw” in this argument. Have your plans to buy the restaurant moved forward?

 BB - We’re supposed to hear about our proposal today, but based on new information, I don’t think we’re going to go with Mado - we need to find out own space.

 Chicagoist - Given the drama, that makes some sense! So, forgive our bluntness - What the hell happened at Mado?

 BB - I found out some crazy stuff. I found out that we had been operating under an expired business license since I was hired. The reason for that is that he (Richards) owes a large amount in back taxes, which is why he’s opening his new restaurant in the suburbs.

 Chicagoist - You only found this out later?

 BB - I found this out two days ago.

 Chicagoist - So that had nothing to do with the decision?

 BB - No, that just added onto it. The decision to leave was this: Me and the general manager found out that David was taking money we made to go the new restaurant. We weren’t making great money or anything, but we were breaking even after payroll, after purchasing.

 Chicagoist - In the midst of the changeover, breaking even sounds like a reasonable goal.

 BB - It’s a reasonable goal to break even in the first year. I read that Per Se grossed 80 dollars at the end of their first year, and they thought that was amazing. You don’t make money. When I say make money, I mean everyone is getting paid, but the owners are not going to profit for at least 5 years; that’s how the industry is. I think he was just buying time.

 BB - He doesn’t care about his employees. I had a really good crew working for me - they literally worked 18 hours a day, six days a week, and on our one day off we came for at least 8 hours. I was making decent money, but all of my cooks were making shit money, and he wanted to fire two of them. But then he realized his unemployment insurance was going to go up, so let’s not fire them, let’s only give them a few hours a week at $8.50 an hour.

 Chicagoist - In the initial piece that came out (on Eater Chicago) the story was that he had told you to fire the staff, and you had walked out.

 BB - People pick and choose what they write. What happened was this: We had been discussing cost cuts, but it was all discussion - I was fighting against it, because I knew we were breaking even. Obviously, he wanted to cut costs. I had two dishwashers and three cooks, and then me. That was the staff. I was going to fire one dishwasher, that was our agreement, and then going to replace one of our cooks. That was the agreement that we had before I missed a couple days of work. I got a call telling me that I had to fire two cooks and that I could only bring in a dishwasher on a night when I was serving more than 35 people. He wanted me and my sous chef - who is still in culinary school! He goes to school from 5a.m. to 11a.m., and then he works for me from noon to 1a.m. David wanted him and me to run Mado.

 Chicagoist - Including washing the dishes?

 BB - Yes. Everything.

 Chicagoist - That’s a lot to ask.

 BB - Yes. And coupled with that, that same day when all that shit went down, we had a meat delivery show up. They had quit accepting checks from us, because every check we had given them had bounced since I took over. We were on a COD basis, but he [Richards] couldn’t make it to the restaurant with $128 to get our meat. His exact words were, “You’re a chef, make it work.” So, that amount of obliviousness - I don’t know if he was delusional, or just didn’t care, or didn’t know what we did there.

 BB - He had no problem with the food. What he had a problem with was the labor, the food costs. He fudged his story with Penny. He fed her labor costs of 50% or something, that is ridiculous. A lot of the things in his interview are just plain wrong. He said I was sick during Thanksgiving when we pulled the numbers, which is totally false, I was sick last week. We pulled the numbers from the day we reopened.

 Chicagoist - Let’s talk about the new stuff - the dinner, and the future space, things that we can eat, rather than drama. You are doing a dinner at Delicious on Friday?

 BB - I think its great. When my sous-chef told me about this spot, I went to the website and immediately started laughing. The place looks ridiculous. It’s a really strange spot - red chairs, black tables. It looks like a cross between a fast food restaurant in Japan and a shitty hipster hotel. It’s really cool, because we’re gonna milk it up - we’re not bringing in any special plates . . . just tablecloths. We’re doing it for a very good price, we’re not making any money off of this at all. We are putting our profit back into the food costs so we can provide people a great meal and that they get their $50 worth. It says 5 courses, but we’re going to do a few extra. The future dinners will be more expensive.

 Chicagoist - Are you planning on opening a new spot soon?

 BB - Yes, we are. It’s seeming like it will take more time than expected. We don’t have time to build - we’re looking for a turnkey operation. We’re not rich, we’re doing these pop-up dinners to make ends meet, and because we like working together. I could go get an executive chef’s job at whatever restaurant, but I couldn’t bring my staff with me.

For more information about Chef Baltzley&apos;s dinner on Friday night at Delicious, call 773-914-2622. The five course meal will be $50, and there will be seatings at 6 and 9 PM. Courses will include Thai curried pork belly , a Cuban cigar panna cotta with scotch caramel, and a homemade pumpkin soda shooter with jalapeno gel.


 
 
 Pigging Out: Baltimore Bar Hosts &apos;Bacon Happy Hour&apos; 
 [ Crime , Finance , Midlife , Music , Personal Finance ] ( AOL News )
They say bacon makes everything better, so a dive bar in Baltimore has decided to host a monthly event called &quot;Beer&amp;Bacon Happy Hour.&quot; For one highly anticipated night each month, the bacon flows as freely as the beer and every patron leaves with a pork belly full of bacon and booze. Cheers.
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
They say bacon makes everything better, so a dive bar in Baltimore has decided to host a monthly event called &quot;Beer&amp;Bacon Happy Hour.&quot; For one highly anticipated night each month, the bacon flows as freely as the beer and every patron leaves with a pork belly full of bacon and booze. Cheers.
 
 Saturday Night At Hapa Ramen&apos;s New Stand 
 [ San Francisco , San Francisco, CA ] ( 7x7 - Insider&apos;s Guide to the Best of San Francisco )
So I was driving to an event in the Mission District on Saturday night, wondering what the hell I was going to feed the kids for dinner, when low and behold, what were my headlights shining on? But a stand being set up by Hapa Ramen. My boys and I were the first customers at this little pop-up stand that they just started, located outside the loading docks of their kitchen. (Think Kitchenette, but at night.) Owner Richie Nakano was there, his eggs cooking sous vide, the water for the noodles jus ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
So I was driving to an event in the Mission District on Saturday night, wondering what the hell I was going to feed the kids for dinner, when low and behold, what were my headlights shining on? But a stand being set up by Hapa Ramen. 

My boys and I were the first customers at this little pop-up stand that they just started, located outside the loading docks of their kitchen. (Think Kitchenette, but at night.) Owner Richie Nakano was there, his eggs cooking sous vide, the water for the noodles just coming to a boil. Christmas lights, a few stools and a table decked in oil cloth, made for a little festivity. And though it wasn&apos;t one of our colder nights, a bowlful of hot, rich ramen broth and some good fatty pork hit the spot. Richie, not intent on absolute tradition, always tops his ramen with some vegetables like winter squash and shredded watermelon radish. He also might be the only ramen cook in the world to round out his miso-based broth with a little tahini for a distinctively NorCal flavor.

The last time I had Hapa ramen, it was for this article when Hapa Ramen had just launched. Things have changed a bit, and I think for the better. Nakano is now using organic, vegetarian fed pork from Llano Seco in Chico, which basically slaughters to order. The pork is leaner, but Nakano only uses belly in the ramen (so lean is not really an issue). Nakano originally started out making his own noodles, an ambitious endeavour, but he now has Hideyuki Yamashita, a noodle maker who has a company called Yamachan in San Jose, making his organic ramen noodle recipe for him.

This Saturday night Hapa will be back again, same time (starting around 7 pm), same bad place. Although I was there for the early bird special, they sold out at midnight last Saturday. If it&apos;s really freezing outside, you might want to bring a flask of whiskey for the perfect pairing.

 At 18th and Harrison, Saturdays, 7 pm until they sell out. 
 
 5 New York City-Centric Food Trends for 2011 
 [ New York City, NY ] ( Fork in the Road )
Predictions for the upcoming year in food are always a mixed bag. Some are aversions to this year&apos;s trends (pie to cupcakes, lamb belly to pork belly ) while others are just random (sweet pot ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Predictions for the upcoming year in food are always a mixed bag. Some are aversions to this year&apos;s trends (pie to cupcakes, lamb belly to pork belly ) while others are just random (sweet pot... 
 How to grow Szechuan pepper and make Chinese five spice 
 [ Guardian ] ( Life and style | guardian.co.uk )
Native to southern India, the black pepper that most of us have in our grinding mills at home is sadly beyond viability away from tropical climes. Fortunately however the livid red berries of the Szechuan pepper grow perfectly happily in most temperate areas and make for a delightful alternativeWhile not botanically related to black or white pepper, Szechuan pepper and a number of other members of the Zanthoxylum genus are certainly its culinary cousins. Like the other Zanthoxylum peppers, Szech ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en-gb   
Native to southern India, the black pepper that most of us have in our grinding mills at home is sadly beyond viability away from tropical climes. Fortunately however the livid red berries of the Szechuan pepper grow perfectly happily in most temperate areas and make for a delightful alternative

While not botanically related to black or white pepper, Szechuan pepper and a number of other members of the Zanthoxylum genus are certainly its culinary cousins. Like the other Zanthoxylum peppers, Szechuan pepper forms a naturally untidy, deciduous, spiky bush that grows eventually to about 7m in height and width, though it is perfectly happy being pruned smaller and grown in a large pot.

The leaves of the Szechuan pepper are similar to those of the ash tree, which along with the spikiness gives rise to one of its common names – prickly ash. The leaves emerge in early- to mid-spring, followed quickly by the young flowers that develop through the summer, resembling small elderflower florets. As with elder, once the Szechuan flowers turn into berries through the hotter months they flip over, hanging down and reddening as they ripen.

The red berries of the pepper open as they become fully ripe to resemble miniature beechnuts, 5mm or so in diameter, and for once it&apos;s not the present concealed inside you&apos;re after it&apos;s the wrapping – as that&apos;s where the flavour lies. And what a prize it is. It has been the subject of wars and great expeditions to seek the best routes to where it was grown, and its trade is still a hugely important part of the world-food business.

Szechuan pepper, like all peppers, is much more an experience than a flavour. In Chinese cooking there&apos;s a beautiful distinction made between the two elements of pepperiness: the numbing pungency (&quot;ma&quot;) that sets the tongue and lips tingling, and the spicy heat (&quot;la&quot;) more akin to the heat from a chilli. A crucial ingredient at the heart of Chinese cuisine, Szechuan pepper is usually more &quot;ma&quot; than &quot;la&quot;, and so is often accompanied by chilli in hotter dishes – including the mala sauce made predominantly from Szechuan pepper, chilli, oil, garlic and ginger.

If you&apos;re inquisitive about Szechuan pepper and the concepts of &quot;ma&quot; and &quot;la&quot; and want to know more before you commit to growing it, it&apos;s easy to acquire peppercorns of excellent quality. Chances are they&apos;ll come with the outer pink casing open and without the black seed held within. But whether you&apos;ve bought or grown your own peppercorns, it&apos;s worth taking a little time to enjoy your first tasting. Split a seed case in two and nibble slowly on a single half at the front of your mouth. Don&apos;t rush this, as the flavours and sensations take time to unfold and, the more you chew, the quicker these subtle changes take place. The experience is very much longer and more complex than with black pepper, so let it develop slowly.

This usually begins with a citrusy, lemon sherbet wave that gradually gives way to warm heat (the &quot;la&quot;). It&apos;s a sweet marriage, like the perfect tomatoes with acid and sweet in beautiful balance, but it passes, almost with the click of a switch, into a strangely numbing, almost anaesthetic feeling (the &quot;ma&quot;) on the lips and tongue. It can be slightly unnerving at first but it is peculiarly addictive, perhaps because it is purported to give you a spiritual lift to go with that sensual experience.

Spiritual or otherwise, there&apos;s simply nothing quite like it – it&apos;s a delightful window into the hidden world of pepper.

Varieties

There are several different species of Szechuan pepper, as well as many more closely related peppers within the Zanthoxylum group, each of which lends their own characteristic flavour to their particular regions&apos; cuisine.
Zanthoxylum schinifolium and Z. simulans are the two most common varieties of Szechuan pepper. If you have room for just one variety I&apos;d go for the former. I prefer its lighter touch – it&apos;s more &quot;ma&quot; than &quot;la&quot;. The peppercorns aren&apos;t overly powerful but do have a wonderful light wave of heat to accompany their bright lemony overtones and characteristically tingly &quot;ma&quot;-ness.

Growing

Buying peppercorns can be expensive, yet the plants are perfectly easy to grow, and by doing so you&apos;ll get all those wonderful &quot;ma&quot; and &quot;la&quot; qualities at the top of their game. You can grow plants from seed but you&apos;ll be a good few years away from harvesting. Plants, by contrast, will afford you a harvest considerably sooner and are relatively cheap, as you&apos;ll easily make the outlay back in earlier harvests. Simply plant your bush and prune to the size you like as it grows.

Mulching around the base is vital to minimising competition as the plant establishes. It&apos;s also sensible to wind a tree guard around the base of the young bark as it makes easy nibbling for rabbits that are perhaps partial to a sensuous lift too.

As well as the prospect of peppercorns, your plant gives you the excuse to stop every time you pass, to rub the leaves for their heady hit of spice and citrus. Like a tea break, it provides a perfect punctuation to the day, and is up there with popping fresh peas into your mouth as one of the finest kitchen-garden treats.

Keep your Szechuan pepper plants away from any other citrus plants you may have. They are in the same family (Rutaceae) as limes, oranges and lemons and Szechuan peppers can carry the canker that attacks citrus trees. In 1968 the US Agriculture Department banned the import of all Rutaceae plants as well as their products – including Szechuan peppercorns – sparking off a lively underground market for the peppercorns, especially within Chinese communities where its &quot;ma la&quot; qualities are so crucial to many dishes. Thankfully the ban was lifted in 2005 for peppercorns that had been heat-treated to kill off any potentially harmful bacteria.

Harvesting

Harvesting is best done as soon as the pinky red seedcases begin to open and show their dark seed – usually as summer turns to autumn. The outer shell is where the heat and aromatics are held (the seed is usually flavourless) but pick whole florets, leave them to dry somewhere warm for a day or two, and they should be ready to go into the peppermill.

If the peppercorns are still closed in mid-autumn, pick them and lay them out on a piece of paper indoors. Within a couple of days the heat from the house will dry the outer skins and they&apos;ll split to reveal the seeds.
I&apos;ve read that the dark seeds can be bitter – this is not my experience, but some find the seed a little gritty. If so, you may wish to lightly bash them using a mortar and pestle as this splits the outer cases, releasing the seed for separating.

Store the unground peppercorns in an airtight container away from bright sunlight until you&apos;re ready to use them; they should retain their oomph for a year or so if kept in this way.

Eating

Once under its spell, you&apos;ll find endless uses for Szechuan pepper in the kitchen. However you plan to use the peppercorns, a gentle toasting should really bring out those aromatics (and fill your house with its fine perfume) but it&apos;s best to toast and create your powder in relatively small quantities – as the peppercorns retain that potent zing for longer than after grinding.

Szechuan pepper is often used in the form of flavoured salt. It is wonderfully simple to prepare. Toast or dry fry equal amounts of coarse salt and peppercorns together until it just starts to smoke. When the mix is cool, use a mortar and pestle or a coffee grinder to reduce it to a coarse powder. You can use it any time you might salt and pepper: to season meat before, during or after cooking, (try it sprinkled over slow roast belly pork ), but my favourite way of using Szechuan salt and pepper is to toss a bowlful of chips in a little of the mix and enjoy it with a cold beer. The combination of the hot chips, the tingling &apos;ma&apos; and the peppery &quot;la&quot; quenched by the cold beer is unbeatable.

Chinese Five Spice Powder is very much at the heart of Szechuan cooking and has recently become popular across the world. Making your own is simple, and the results are infinitely superior to even the very best shop-bought jar.

Chinese five spice powder

Chinese Five Spice goes wonderfully well with chicken and pork as a marinade, but nothing quite beats it rubbed into the lightly-oiled skin of a duck or goose before roasting.This recipe works perfectly well using already ground spices, but if you can use whole spices and grind them yourself you&apos;ll notice a keenness about the flavours that&apos;s really special. The resulting blend will be beautifully fresh, alive and bright, without the need for the citrus that&apos;s often added to commercial mixes.

Makes about 1 x 225g jar

 2 star anise or 1½ tbsp ground star anise
1½ tsp fennel seeds
5cm of cinnamon stick or 2 tsp ground cinnamon
½ tsp Szechuan pepper
6 cloves 

Preheat the oven to 140C/Gas 1. Place any of the spices that you are using whole on a baking tray and put them in the oven for 4 minutes, until lightly toasted.

Use a clean coffee grinder or pestle and mortar to reduce the spices to a fine powder. Sieve out any larger particles if you prefer, and store in an airtight jar away from direct sunlight. The spice powder mix should keep its zing for 3 months or so.

Five spice pork rillettes

Rillettes is as much a way of cooking as it is a recipe. The principle is simple – it is just meat ( pork in this case, though it works equally well for rabbit and most poultry) cooked very gently in its own fat. The addition of Chinese Five Spice Powder here adds a warm depth and fragrance to the rillettes that improves with age.

Makes about 1kg

 300g pork fat or lard
1kg pork shoulder or pork belly , cut into chunks
4 garlic cloves
1 tsp Chinese Five Spice Powder
1 tbsp salt
1–2 tbsp olive oil
4 sprigs of fresh thyme
3 bay leaves
10g parsley, tough stalks removed
6 spring onions, sliced lengthways
Salt and freshly ground black pepper
2 tbsp cider apple brandy or dry sherry 

Preheat your oven to 70°C/Gas ¼.

Place your pork fat in a dish at the bottom of the oven and render slowly, pouring the liquid fat off into a bowl every 15 minutes or so. Leave to cool.

Turn the oven up to 140°C/Gas 1.

Cut the pork into strips 2cm wide along the grain of the meat. Crush the garlic and mix it with the Five Spice Powder, the salt and enough olive oil to make a thick paste and rub in into the pork strips. Place two-thirds of the rendered fat or lard in a wide ovenproof dish, pour in 100ml water and add the meat. Tie the herbs and spring onions together in a small square of muslin and add to the water. Place the dish in the oven and let it cook for a minimum of 4 hours. The liquid should be just moving, rather than bubbling hard – turn it down a little if necessary.

After 4 hours, take the dish out of the oven and carefully take 2 forks to it – if the meat is completely tender and it tears apart easily, it&apos;s done. If it&apos;s not ready, turn the oven off and return the dish to the oven for a further hour.

When the meat has cooled enough to handle, take out the herb bag and shred the meat thoroughly with 2 forks. Taste a little, and add salt and pepper if you fancy. You can add a little extra Five Spice at this stage if you&apos;d like a stronger flavour, but you probably won&apos;t need to as it will develop over time. Add a splash of cider apple brandy or dry sherry and mix everything together.

Transfer the rillette to a sterilised terrine or kilner jar, compacting the mixture lightly to push out air pockets and submerging the meat under the fat. Pour over the remaining third of the warmed, rendered fat. Cool, then refrigerate. The rillette is best left for the flavours to develop for a few days.

Rillettes are good straight from the fridge on crusty bread, better at room temperature, and incredible warmed gently until the fat begins to run. Serve with something sharp such as pickled gherkins or Jerusalem artichokes, or a salad with a lively dressing. Rillettes will keep in the fridge for several months in clean jars, so long as the pork is preserved under 5mm or so of fat.

• This extract is taken from A Taste of the Unexpected by Mark Diacono (Quadrille, £20)
 
 Chinese recipes Gardening advice Food&amp;drink 
 Mark Diacano 
 guardian.co.uk © Guardian News&amp;Media Limited 2010 | Use of this content is subject to our Terms&amp;Conditions | More Feeds 
 
 
 
 RED WAGON CAFE 
 [ Vancouver ] ( VANCOUVER SLOP )
[Begin conversation]Joe: So you didn&apos;t like Red Wagon at all?Matt: It was ok. Nothing special. Joe: It reminded me of places we used to go to in Calgary. The mismatched plates, furnitureIt&apos;s odd because, on one hand, it seems like they don&apos;t care. But on the other hand, it takes a lot of conscious effort to purposely find mismatched plates, etc Matt: It felt like a Chinese diner. Joe: Was the pork belly good? Matt: It was ok, part of it was really fatty, like 3/4 fat. Actually it was decent. ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 [Begin conversation] Joe : So you didn&apos;t like Red Wagon at all? Matt : It was ok.
Nothing special.
 Joe : It reminded me of places we used to go to in Calgary.
The mismatched plates, furniture...It&apos;s odd because, on one hand, it seems like they don&apos;t care. But on the other hand, it takes a lot of conscious effort to purposely find mismatched plates, etc
 Matt : It felt like a Chinese diner.
 Joe : Was the pork belly good?
 Matt : It was ok, part of it was really fatty, like 3/4 fat.
Actually it was decent.
Lots of fat but tender, and a little crispy.
Potatoes werent too flavourful nor was the soup.
 
 
 Joe : What soup was that?
 Matt : Borsht.
 Joe : I had the pulled pork benny. The eggs were well-cooked, but I suppose you&apos;re supposed to assume that people will poach eggs properly. The pork was alright, definitely slow-cooked for a long time, but not nearly as good as Re Up&apos;s.
Same with the smoked salmon benny. You don&apos;t really ever expect people to mess that up, and they didn&apos;t. But the potatoes were bland.
 Matt : Potatoes were bland.
My pork belly was ok.
 Joe : Did you have problems with the server?
 Matt : Service was great.
 Joe : When we went, at the end the server asked if we wanted to break any bills for change...like, for her tip.
 Matt : Our server kept us in the loop when tables were becoming available and was very informative.
I liked her.
 Joe : So, overall it sounds like you didn&apos;t have many problems with Red Wagon, but you still wouldn&apos;t go back?
 Matt : The food was not good enough to make me return.
I love my potatoes and they were bland
It was an ok experience, just not fantastic as I was hoping
 Joe : Yeah, it was pretty meh for me.
I was expecting to be blown out of my mind after all that hype.
 Matt : I was hoping it would be good, it was just all right.
[End conversation]

Red Wagon Cafe
2296 East Hastings Street
Vancouver, BC
(604) 568-4565
 

 
 Maple Roasted Pork Cutlet with Apples and Onions 
 [ Food , Recipes ] ( 80 Breakfasts )
 Pork . To me, one of God’s most delicious gifts, brimming with good things from the tip of its pert nose to the end of its squiggly tail. Despite the tides all turning to healthier and more sensible eating, I still stubbornly throw myself with wild abandon at all things pork . That being said, there was one cut of pork that I didn’t quite enjoy as much as the others… pork chop. Strange, as I live in a country where almost everyone loves a good pork chop (including my best friend who doesn ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 Pork . To me, one of God’s most delicious gifts, brimming with good things from the tip of its pert nose to the end of its squiggly tail. Despite the tides all turning to healthier and more sensible eating, I still stubbornly throw myself with wild abandon at all things pork .

That being said, there was one cut of pork that I didn’t quite enjoy as much as the others… pork chop. Strange, as I live in a country where almost everyone loves a good pork chop ( including my best friend who doesn’t even like pork anywhere near as much as I do! ). I, though, find chops, dare I say it, too lean . I prefer getting my pork in the form of a slow cooked belly or hock, a whole roasted lechon, smoky barbecue ribs, or a pata tim in its sweet-sticky sauce. With a pork chop, you’ve got a whole lot of loin and a thinnish strip of fat at the end. It just doesn’t do it for me.

 Until I met King Henry… 

 Maple Roasted Pork Cutlet with Apples and Onions 

 1 x 400 gram bone-in pork cutlet, preferably a King Henry cutlet 2 tablespoons + 1 tablespoon soy sauce 1 tablespoon + 1 tablespoon maple syrup 1 apple, cored, peeled and sliced into wedges 1 big white onion, peeled and sliced into wedges Extra virgin olive oil Sea salt and freshly cracked black pepper 
 
 - Score the fat side of the cutlet in a cross-hatch pattern.
- Mix 2 tablespoons of the soy sauce with 1 tablespoon maple syrup. Pour over the pork cutlet and sprinkle with some freshly cracked black pepper. Leave to marinate, turning every so often, for at least 30 minutes. Make sure to get the marinade into the scored fat side as well.
- Mix 1 tablespoon soy sauce with 1 tablespoon maple syrup. Set this aside – this will be the basting sauce.
- Pre-heat the oven to 200C/400F.
- In a roasting pan or tray toss the onions and apple slices with some olive oil. Season with salt and pepper and place the pan in the oven.
- Heat a non-stick skillet on the hob over medium high heat. Add a good glug or two of oil. When the oil is hot add the cutlet. Let this sear in the hot oil for about 3-5 minutes on both sides until golden brown. Hold the cutlet with a pair of tongs and sear its fat side, giving it a nice burnished hue and crisping up the edges.
- When your pork culet has achieved a nice sear all around ( don’t forget the fat side! ), take the roasting pan out of the oven and lay the cutlet on the onions and apples. Return to the oven and roast for 25-30 minutes, basting with your saved soy-maple mixture every 10 minutes or so, or until done to your liking.
- This serves one but is easily scalable to serve more.

A King Henry cutlet is cut from the mid-loin to about 1-inch thick. The bone is French trimmed ( fancy! ) and the skin removed. Although, for all intents and purposes, this is still technically a pork chop, its hefty size and correspondingly largish swipe of glistening fat help me to be forgiving. In fact, we ( yes, I drag my husband along my wicked ways ) have become big fans of this cut of pork ! It always feels luxurious and celebratory at a fraction of the price of a good (beef) steak. Indulgent yet thrifty...I can definitely get behind that :) 
And speaking of easily attainable, this is a snap to make. The marinade/basting sauce consists of only two ingredients…ok, three counting the pepper. It may seem a bit fiddly to score the fat but believe me it is worth the miniscule bit of effort it will take for you to do it…you will be rewarded with crunchy edges of fat caramelized in a sweet and savory glaze. If you’re really feeling lazy you can forgo the roasted apples but I urge you to give it a try. It goes amazingly with the pork ( as apples are wont to do ) and just think of it as doing your main dish and sides in one pan! As the pork roasts on the apples, the maple-soy marinade, along with the juices from the pork , mingles with the apples and slowly caramelizing onions. I know, yum!

King Henry is now on our regular grocery rotation, gracing our table once in a while, another cut of pork I have grown to love. Worry not, I do also actually love many healthy things , but pork still remains a steadfast friend, never abandoning me in times of heartache or stress. And I too vow to never abandon my loyal, delicious, and oft misunderstood pig. 
 Root Beer Jelly on Pork Belly on Crispy... 
 [ Design , Trends ] ( NOTCOT.ORG )
Root Beer Jelly on Pork Belly on Crispy Grits and other southern meets socal meets molecular gastronomy dishes at Vu.
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Root Beer Jelly on Pork Belly on Crispy Grits... and other southern meets socal meets molecular gastronomy dishes at Vu. 
 Aarti Party: A Fairytale for Foodies 
 [ Video ] ( Tubefilter News )
A Cinderella story. The American Dream. A jackpot. Call it what you want, but Aarti Sequeira has parlayed her warm smile, charming personality and delicious recipes into a thriving career in front the of the camera. Sequeira&apos;s self-produced cooking show web series, Aarti Party helped her secure a coveted spot on The Next Food Network Star show to compete for a great grand prize, her own Food Network show. By surviving several exhausting challenges, cooking great food and winning the hearts of t ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   A Cinderella story. The American Dream. A jackpot. Call it what you want, but Aarti Sequeira has parlayed her warm smile, charming personality and delicious recipes into a thriving career in front the of the camera. Sequeira&apos;s self-produced cooking show web series, Aarti Party helped her secure a coveted spot on The Next Food Network Star show to compete for a great grand prize, her own Food Network show. By surviving several exhausting challenges, cooking great food and winning the hearts of the judges, she won. Her food pays homage to her family’s roots in India and other cultures around the world that have influenced her kitchen technique. Through all of the excitement, Sequeira hasn’t forgotten the web fans who encouraged her along the way. She continues to create webisodes for the Food Network site and consistently updates her personal blog. Sequeira’s television show enters a second season on Sunday. Tubefilter caught up with a very busy Sequeira to find out about the new season on the Food Network, how her web series influences her TV show, and her advice for people who want to create a cooking program online. Tubefilter: Your show started as a web series and became a Food Network Show after your won The Next Food Network Star. Now that you are going into your second season on Food Network, how much do your original webisodes influence how you approach the half-hour TV programs? Sequeira: Having done a web-show helped tremendously. I mean, first off, I can look at it whenever I want and see what I&apos;m like when I&apos;m entirely comfortable, shooting in my kitchen with my husband behind the camera. I mean, talk about no pressure! That&apos;s when the gold comes out. Then, I try to bring that same level of comfort and familiarity when I&apos;m in front of the kazillion cameras in the big, daunting studio. Also, having edited those webisodes myself, I&apos;ve literally watched hours of myself on camera, so I know what works, and what doesn&apos;t. How you need to almost unnaturally look up at camera every few seconds - even if you have nothing to say - just to stay connected, how I grimace when I&apos;m focused, etc. Basically, the webisodes have made me a much more polished host. Tubefilter: You are also filming new webisodes for the Aarti Party page on the Food Network site. Why is it important to you to continue to create video content? Sequeira: The web videos were actually the prize for my winning the fan favorite vote during The Next Food Network Star. I believe in staying true to what got me here, and that&apos;s the internet! I like to think that it sets me apart, since I know how to create web content because I did it for so long. Web viewers are different to me than TV viewers... they&apos;re looking for something a little more raw, a little quirkier, a little more natural I think, than what we have grown to expect out of the television set. Plus, I didn&apos;t have cable for a few years and I still know tons of folks who get their entertainment online. It&apos;s important for me to have a presence online for those people who have given up on TV. Tubefilter: When you are developing new recipes, how do you know one will be right for the show? How did you decide what recipes to include in the new webisodes? Sequeira: See, that&apos;s where doing the web version of Aarti Paarti was so handy. I literally know which episodes were hits because those are the most viewed ones. I learned that people are really interested in India&apos;s famed dishes; that&apos;s how you get people to watch your channel on YouTube. My samosa episode was the first one to really garner some eyeballs that didn&apos;t belong to my friends and family. So this season, I&apos;m doing an episode dedicated to a few of Indian cuisine&apos;s &quot;greatest hits&quot; so to speak: Chicken Tikka Masala and Mango Lassi... and an episode dedicated to demystifying the curry. Then there&apos;s Facebook: I asked members on my fan page what recipes they&apos;d like to see and I got 300 responses within 20 minutes!   I get a lot of the same questions over and over again, so we decided to focus on answering those in the web videos. There&apos;ll be episodes dedicated to the spices I always have on hand, and another on what exactly makes a curry... there&apos;ll be a few recipes in those videos, but they will focus mostly on educating people about a few Indian food basics. Tubefilter: Is there a different approach to filming the show and the webisodes? Or is it the same camera and crew? Sequeira: The webisodes are pretty similar to the show - a different crew but similar feel. Actually, the crew who shot the webisodes shoots Giada&apos;s show so it was cool to see how another crew does things. One day, I&apos;d love to resurrect the original ambience and timbre of Aarti Paarti (the web show); I love the quirkiness of those videos, and how they invited other people&apos;s talents to shine including jugglers, singers, and belly dancers. Tubefilter: What can your viewers looking forward to this season on your show and it your new videos? Sequeira: Tons of great recipes! I&apos;m really proud of the recipes this season because I expanded beyond just the Indian flavors people know me for. See, if you came over to my house for dinner, you might be surprised because I don&apos;t cook Indian food every day. That&apos;s why this season you&apos;ll find recipes for things like Thai Curry Mac&amp;Cheese, or Lebanese Meat Pitas (Arayes) or heck, the Vanilla and Black Pepper Pork Loin that kicks off the whole thing. Oh, and I&apos;m doing a Beer Tasting episode too, with beer sommelier Christina Perozzi. She brings the beer and I bring the food to match!   Also, you&apos;ll see some of my friends and family on the show! The biggest motivator for me when it comes to cooking is whom I&apos;m cooking for. I&apos;m so excited to share the magical people in my life who have motivated me to make great food! And you&apos;ll find a little taste of the old Aarti Paarti when a belly dancer surprises my friends at one of my parties - super fun! 
 The Main Dish 
 [ San Diego, CA ] ( San Diego Magazine Print Edition )
DECEMBER&apos;S MEAL TO REMEMBER By Candice Woo The Appetizer Raviolis aux champignons at Tapenade This often-copied dish, a signature staple of the La Jolla restaurant’s menu, can be ordered in the elegant dining room or in their more casual bar/bistro area, where $8 gets you three plump pillows of pasta, hand-folded and pinched around an earthy, savory filling of wild mushrooms. Shavings of parmesan ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 

 
       

 
   DECEMBER&apos;S MEAL TO REMEMBER 
 By Candice Woo       
 
 The Appetizer 
Raviolis aux champignons at Tapenade 

 This often-copied dish, a signature staple of the La Jolla restaurant’s menu, can be ordered in the elegant dining room or in their more casual bar/bistro area, where $8 gets you three plump pillows of pasta, hand-folded and pinched around an earthy, savory filling of wild mushrooms. Shavings of parmesan gild each ravioli, which lounge in a shallow pool of white truffle oil-enriched, lightly frothed broth made from port wine. They wisely set down a spoon alongside this dish, so you can scoop up every last bit of the luscious sauce. More Details » 

 The Entrée 
Chicken Tawook at Alforon 
 
This friendly, family-owned eatery—a newcomer to the College Area—specializes in authentic Lebanese snacks called manakish, rounds of flatbread dressed with everything from a spice blend called zaatar to combinations of cheese and meat. Georges, Alforon’s chef-proprietor, stretches homemade dough into thin disks which cook in matter of seconds and emerge crisp from the restaurant’s brick oven. My favorite flatbread, Chicken Tawook, gets a topping of grilled chicken and two sublime condiments made in-house—a creamy, feather-light garlic paste and zingy pickled vegetables. More Details » 

 The Drink 
 Whole Foods Seasonal Beers 

 Consider beer or cider for holidays meals this year, which can be just as food friendly as wine. The refreshing dryness of Julian Hard Cider would pair deliciously with a salad or a light seafood course. A fruit beer, bright with jammy flavor, is a great sipper alongside a cheese platter and with dessert, try a winter warmer infused with spices or roasty notes of coffee and chocolate. For New Year’s pop open a bottle of bière de Champagne, beers that are brewed in Belgium and then sent to the Champagne region of France, where they undergo the same &quot;methode Champenoise&quot; of cave-aging as their vinious cousins. And most biere de Champagne&apos;s are thankfully more affordable than a good bottle of bubbly. For more beer/food consultation, visit Dre Sparks, the beer specialist at Whole Foods in Hillcrest. More Details » 

 The Dessert 
Macaroons at Opera Patisserie 
 
 Though this French bakery and cafe in Sorrento Valley excels at all sorts of sweet and savory treats, it is their macaroons which are truly nonpareil. The delicious meringue sandwich cookies—simultaneously soft, chewy and crisp—come in a variety of flavors, including pistachio, raspberry, cinnamon and chocolate. They may not be quite on par with Paris&apos; famous Ladurée , but a boxful of these delicate, candy-colored confections are guaranteed to be a very well-received holiday gift. More Details » 
             
 MORE FROM THE SAN DIEGO MAGAZINE FOOD FILES

 
       
 Hot Breakfast Spots : Flapjacks. Omelets. And someone else doing the cooking. Whether your scenario involves a stressful work and one too many gin-and-tonics the night before or simply the desire to start your day with a menu full of morning choices, the remedy is a warm plate of eggs or pancakes served with fresh-squeezed OJ and an ocean breeze. Check out our list of the hottest breakfast spots in town—from downtown to Encinitas, diet-friendly to decadent, classic to creative.
 

 Table Talk : Dining critic Candice Woo reveals which local eateries were recognized in a fancy San Francisco ceremony and reports from inside Bencotto’s authentic pasta lab. 

 Local Bounty : Caron Golden dishes on Calamansi lemons, local apple cider, Latke-worthy potatoes and more farmers&apos; market finds, plus recipe ideas and tips. 



 
     
 
   EVENTS     
 Holiday Night on Adams Avenue 
 
 Saturday, December 11 from 5 p.m. to 10 p.m. 
Head out to Adams Avenue for a holiday walkabout. Stroll, shop and snack through neighborhood businesses, as they stay open late and host open houses, art exhibits and live music. Participating restaurants offering food and drink specials include Blind Lady Ale House, Mariposa Ice Cream, Jayne’s Gastropub, Viva Pops and more. More Details » 
 
 
 The 2010 Gingerbread Collective 
 
 Saturday, December 18 from noon to 4 p.m. 
Local design firm Arclinea San Diego is hosting its second-annual gingerbread competition by inviting area chefs and mixologists to create sweet and savory dishes and drinks using gingerbread flavors. More Details » 
 
 Wine Vault&amp;Bistro&apos;s Ten-Course Tasting Dinners 
 
 Sunday, December 19 and Monday, December 20 
Celebrate the holidays with ten course tasting menu prepared by the restaurant’s talented Executive Chef, KC Howland. The locally-sourced lineup includes a sunchoke bisque, chestnut risotto, herb roasted pork belly and gingerbread pudding with dulce de leche ice cream and whiskey sabayon. More Details » 
                           
     
 

 
 Click to forward to a friend. 

 Submit ideas for The Main Dish to
Candice Woo at candicew@sandiegomagazine.com .
If submitting an event, submit by the 15th of the month prior to the event.

 Become a San Diego Magazine partner! 
 San Diego Magazine is now offering banner ads on all of our e-newsletters.
Space is limited. Please contact Brittany Horton at brittanyh@sandiegomagazine.com .

Produced by the San Diego Magazine Marketing department 
 
 Tis the Season for Lists - The Stew is Trendspotting 
 [ Chicago, IL , Chicago ] ( Chicagoist )
We were on top of this trend in 2008! Good veggies never go out of style. Many of our readers probably caught Time Out Chicago&apos;s famous&quot;100 Best Things We Ate This Year&quot; list earlier this week - one of our favorite pieces of food coverage every year. December is the season for lists of one sort or another, and they will start coming fast and furious over the next few weeks. The Stew just released its list of dining trends for 2011 - in the model of Project Runway, they have announced what will ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 We were on top of this trend in 2008! Good veggies never go out of style. Many of our readers probably caught Time Out Chicago&apos;s famous &quot;100 Best Things We Ate This Year&quot; list earlier this week - one of our favorite pieces of food coverage every year. December is the season for lists of one sort or another, and they will start coming fast and furious over the next few weeks. The Stew just released its list of dining trends for 2011 - in the model of Project Runway, they have announced what will be &quot;in&quot; and what will be &quot;out.&quot; The list, whatever it&apos;s other qualities, is a hilarious read, though we are hoping that not all of it comes true.
Each dead 2010 trend will be replaced with something new - for instance, our love of beets will be replaced by new affection for brussels sprouts . They might be a little behind on this one - we&apos;ve seen both on the menu at every spot we&apos;ve dined at for six months. &quot;Cooking meat&quot; will be replaced by &quot;butchering meat&quot; which seems dead on, given all the recent opening announcements , and we welcome the replacement of the played-out St. Germain with Carpano Antica .

We&apos;re not so sure about the demise of bacon, short ribs and pork belly - they are just so wonderful. Especially when the replacements aren&apos;t quite as seductive - chicken skin, goat belly and neck bones. Wonderful things, all, but they will have to pry the pork belly out of our cold dead hands. And if the cupcake trend gets replaced by a meatball trend, please someone bludgeon us to death with a tenderizer. Check out the whole list if you need a diversion. What trends do you think are on their way out?



 
 
 North Pole Cupcakes&amp;Crisp Crackling Roast Pork Belly Delicious links for 12.9.2010 
 [ Food ] ( The Kitchn )
Plus celery-potato soup, and a breakfast bowl of cinnamon baked oatmeal.
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
Plus celery-potato soup, and a breakfast bowl of cinnamon baked oatmeal.
 
 Healthy Dose Link Time 
 [ Weight Loss ] ( FitSugar )
Pull out your slow cooker for easy, peasy pulled pork - Peanut Butter Fingers Beyond heart health, belly fat puts women at risk for osteoporosis - AOL Health Not sleeping makes losing weight that much harder - Health Raid your spice cabinet and flavor up your acorn squash - That&apos;s Fit.ca Motivation waning? Train for a destination race in the tropics - Fit Bottomed Girls ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 Pull out your slow cooker for easy, peasy pulled pork - Peanut Butter Fingers Beyond heart health, belly fat puts women at risk for osteoporosis - AOL Health Not sleeping makes losing weight that much harder - Health Raid your spice cabinet and flavor up your acorn squash - That&apos;s Fit.ca Motivation waning? Train for a destination race in the tropics - Fit Bottomed Girls 
 
 Sam Talbot Previews Imperial No. 9, Shows Off Artwork At Art Basel Miami Beach (PHOTOS) 
 [ The Huffington Post , Huffington Post , Celebrity Blogs ] ( The Full Feed from HuffingtonPost.com )
Sam Talbot is known for many things — his stint on &quot;Top Chef,&quot; his friendship with Kelly Bensimon, his work at Montauk&apos;s Surf Lodge — but his artwork is not generally at the top of that list. Until, perhaps, now. The chef, who is opening a restaurant in the new Mondrian Hotel in SoHo in February, showed off some of his nautical-themed paintings over the weekend at an intimate dinner during Art Basel Miami Beach.Talbot hosted a preview of his upcoming Imperial No. 9 Saturday night a ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en-US   
Sam Talbot is known for many things — his stint on &quot;Top Chef,&quot; his friendship with Kelly Bensimon, his work at Montauk&apos;s Surf Lodge — but his artwork is not generally at the top of that list. Until, perhaps, now. The chef, who is opening a restaurant in the new Mondrian Hotel in SoHo in February, showed off some of his nautical-themed paintings over the weekend at an intimate dinner during Art Basel Miami Beach.

Talbot hosted a preview of his upcoming Imperial No. 9 Saturday night at Miami&apos;s Mondrian Hotel. The menu — modeled on Imperial No. 9&apos;s concept of sustainable seafood — included fried oysters with chow chow and crispy ham, seared toro and braised pork belly on stecca with a dashi broth, lemon king crab a la plancha with sweet and sour butter and crispy garlic chips and a four-hour octopus with chilies, soy and lime. Talbot also served vegetable selections — including a confit of beets with lemon, thyme and fresh ginger and scrambled corn with a poached egg, comte, coffee and maple jus — as well as crispy lamb belly and braised lamb rillette with ratatouille and crispy toast.

The dinner was co-hosted alongside photographer Poppy de Villeneuve — whose photos were displayed alongside Talbot&apos;s artwork — and Art + Culture Editions , a new web platform that sells limited edition prints and original artwork as low as $50 in an effort to make great art accessible to wider audiences. Talbot&apos;s work will be sold on Art + Culture Editions, which also sells work from artists including Nick Cave , Eric Fischl and Micah and Whitney Stansell .

 Read More... 
 More on Art 
 
 
 
 Dixie Meat Rub 
 [ Vegan ] ( Suicide Food )
Even stuffed to bursting with the meat of his kinsmen, he has but one thought. His abdomen taut, his pulse sluggish, his eyes heavy with impending slumber, he just a singular idea buzzing in his spongy brain like a dozy bumblebee: Must. Prepare. Self. For imminent eating. Must have rub. Applied to belly . Unable to muster the energy to speak the words aloud, instead he thinks them into being. Rub my belly . He pats his girth helpfully. &quot;Here,&quot; he seems to say. &quot;The rub goes right here.&quot; And ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Even stuffed to bursting with the meat of his kinsmen, he has but one thought.

His abdomen taut, his pulse sluggish, his eyes heavy with impending slumber, he just a singular idea buzzing in his spongy brain like a dozy bumblebee:

Must. Prepare. Self. For imminent eating. Must have rub. Applied to belly .

Unable to muster the energy to speak the words aloud, instead he thinks them into being. Rub my belly .

He pats his girth helpfully. &quot;Here,&quot; he seems to say. &quot;The rub goes right here.&quot; And then, before sinking into his pork coma, he prays you will know what to do with his lifeless body.

 




Addendum: Have we, perhaps, already seen this type of glutton (for punishment as well as for the meat of his own kind)? Yes, we have . 
 Soy-Braised Chicken Wings with Quail Eggs (ปีกไก่ต้มเค็มกับไข่นกกระทา) 
 [ Food ] ( shesimmers )
Since we&apos;re in the midst of the holiday season, I thought I would continue with the &quot;homesick menu,&quot; inaugurated by my mother&apos;s Pork Chops with Crispy Garlic and Lemongrass, with this simple dish which my aunt used to make all the time. This dish is based on the various Chinese five-spice soy-braised dishes (Pa-Lo พะโล้). Most notable among such dishes is the version with hard-boiled eggs and pork belly (Khai Pa-Lo ไข่พะโล้) which has been adopted into the Thai cuisine ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Since we&apos;re in the midst of the holiday season, I thought I would continue with the &quot;homesick menu,&quot; inaugurated by my mother&apos;s Pork Chops with Crispy Garlic and Lemongrass, with this simple dish which my aunt used to make all the time. This dish is based on the various Chinese five-spice soy-braised dishes (Pa-Lo พะโล้). Most notable among such dishes is the version with hard-boiled eggs and pork belly (Khai Pa-Lo ไข่พะโล้) which has been adopted into the Thai cuisine at large and fondly...

.... 
 Pork Belly and Taro Buns 
 [ Posterati ] ( Thousand Leaves )
via flickr.com Permalink | Leave a comment » ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   via flickr.com 
 Permalink | Leave a comment  » 
 
 Reader Roundup: Hark The Herald Frankfurters Sing, Glory To The Newborn Pork Belly [Commenter Quips] 
 [ Feminism , Fashion ] ( Jezebel )
#commenterquips Christmas is coming, and with it a whole plate of carols. Memorize them, teach them to your friends and family, rejoice! More » ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Christmas is coming, and with it a whole plate of carols. Memorize them, teach them to your friends and family, rejoice! More » 


 
 About Tonight 
 [ Washington, D.C. ] ( DCist )
Photo by ekelly80 FOOD&amp;DRINK: Dino&apos;s (3435 Connecticut Avenue NW) Three Little Pigs dinner is deceptively named, since it features pork 10 ways (not 3). Pig out on pork in duck fat, aged prosciutto, pork tater tots, headcheese, pork sausages, pancetta, pork belly , pasta with meats, pork confit and chocolate torte with pancetta. Call 202-686-2966 for reservations. 6 p.m.-9:30 p.m. $65 per person (add wine pairings for an extra $30). READING: The Bizarro Fiction Reading at Big Bear Cafe (1700 F ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 Photo by ekelly80 FOOD&amp;DRINK : Dino &apos;s (3435 Connecticut Avenue NW) Three Little Pigs dinner is deceptively named, since it features pork 10 ways (not 3). Pig out on pork in duck fat, aged prosciutto, pork tater tots, headcheese, pork sausages, pancetta, pork belly , pasta with meats, pork confit and chocolate torte with pancetta. Call 202-686-2966 for reservations. 6 p.m.-9:30 p.m. $65 per person (add wine pairings for an extra $30).
 READING : The Bizarro Fiction Reading at Big Bear Cafe (1700 First Street NW) tonight features readings from authors who write in the bizarro genre, &quot;underground writing that combines elements of surrealism, science fiction, horror, and pulp fiction.&quot; Tonight, hear from novelists John Edward Lawson and Jeff Bagato and comic book author Rafer Roberts. 7 p.m. Free.

 MOVIE: The Library of Congress is showing the Beatles documentary Let It Be in the Mary Pickford Theater (3rd Floor, James Madison Building, Independence Avenue between First and 2nd Streets) as a part of the Sir Paul McCartney Film Fest , presented to celebrate his winning of the 2010 Library of Congress Gershwin Prize for Popular Song. 7 p.m. Free, no tickets required.

 Coming up this week... 

 Tuesday: Spirit of the Festival is a cocktail and food-pairing contest and tasting event featuring five chef-mixologist teams from Founding Farmers, Urban Bistro, PS7&apos;s, Equinox and Aria at the Ronald Reagan Building and International Trade Center (1300 Pennsylvania Avenue NW). The pre-event mixer starts at 6 p.m., the festival goes from 7 to 9 p.m. Tickets to pre-event mixer $79, main event $55.

 Wednesday: The National Chanukah Menorah Lighting on the Ellipse will take place this Wednesday, the first night of Chanukah. Violinst Itzhak Perlman will perform, &quot;The Three Cantors&quot; will sing and there will be hot latkes and donuts. 4 p.m. Free, but tickets are required (call (202) 332-5600 or go online ).

&gt;&gt; Neko Case speaks at National Geographic Live! (1600 M Street NW) as part of their Music on Photography series . 7:30 p.m. $20.

 Thursday: Lumbergh look-alikes, an &quot;O face&quot; competition, trivia and a screening of Office Space during the Bi-Annual TPS Report Managers Meeting at Arlington Cinema and Drafthouse (2903 Columbia Pike, Arlington). The fun starts at 7 p.m., followed by the movie at 8:30 p.m. $12.

 Friday: It&apos;s Ben Folds&apos; turn to speak at National Geographic Live! (1600 M Street NW) as part of the Music on Photography series . 7:30 p.m. $20.


 
 
 #107827 - Crackled Pork Belly 
 [ Food ] ( TasteSpotting )
This tasty Cantonese roast crackling pork is a popular dish in Cantonese cuisine. Here is the recipe of this authentic Cantonese roast crackling pork . craving more? check out TasteSpotting ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   

This tasty Cantonese roast crackling pork is a popular dish in Cantonese cuisine. Here is the recipe of this authentic Cantonese roast crackling pork .

craving more? check out TasteSpotting 

 
 How to do The Trip on the cheap 
 [ Guardian ] ( Travel: Restaurants | guardian.co.uk )
Fancy following Steve Coogan and Rob Brydon&apos;s grand gastronomic tour of the north of England but think it will bankrupt you? Fear not, we tell you where to eat the region&apos;s top food on a budgetSeen through the lens of Michael Winterbottom, director of The Trip, now showing on BBC2, the north of England has rarely looked so imposing. Add the idea of punctuating days in Lancashire, the Lake District and the Yorkshire Dales with long lunches at a swanky restaurants, the way Steve Coogan and Rob Bry ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en-gb   
Fancy following Steve Coogan and Rob Brydon&apos;s grand gastronomic tour of the north of England but think it will bankrupt you? Fear not, we tell you where to eat the region&apos;s top food on a budget

Seen through the lens of Michael Winterbottom, director of The Trip, now showing on BBC2, the north of England has rarely looked so imposing. Add the idea of punctuating days in Lancashire, the Lake District and the Yorkshire Dales with long lunches at a swanky restaurants, the way Steve Coogan and Rob Brydon do, and a tour of the area becomes even more appealing. There is only one problem: money. At L&apos;Enclume and Hipping Hall , the duo&apos;s bills topped £150, which, unless a fictional version of the Observer Magazine has agreed to cover your expenses, is no laughing matter.

But there&apos;s more to northern gastronomy than fine dining, and there are even, if you&apos;re canny, ways of getting close to its Michelin stars at a fraction of the cost. Here&apos;s the Guardian&apos;s guide to taking The Trip on a budget.

Lancashire: Forest of Bowland

You can understand why The Trip started at the Inn at Whitewell (01200 448222, innatwhitewell.com ). Bang in the middle of the Forest of Bowland, an Area of Outstanding Natural Beauty, this 14th-century manor house and coaching inn amid a tangled wood is remote, rambling and very beautiful. Historically, the food here has been reliably hearty, rather than outstanding. So, instead of dropping £93.80 on three courses in the riverside dining room, à la Coogan and Brydon, eat in one of the bar areas, where you can enjoy a small plate of, say, crispy confit Goosnargh duck leg from nearby Longridge with bubble and squeak and tip-top Bowland Brewery ale for £10pp.

That focus on local produce is typical. This area, and the Ribble Valley particularly, is home to one of the country&apos;s most vibrant food scenes. Myriad small farmer-producers, such as Leagram&apos;s organic cheeses ( leagramorganicdairy.co.uk ) and Mrs Dowsons ice-cream ( mrsdowsons.com ), work closely with the valley&apos;s pubs and restaurants.

A key catalyst in this move towards local, seasonal ingredients is chef Nigel Haworth . His Michelin-starred Northcote (01254 240555, northcote.com ) in Langho, near Blackburn, offers a £25 set lunch (a steal), and his pub, the Three Fishes in Whalley, near Clitheroe (01254 826888, thethreefishes.com ), has mains from around £10. Other notables include a deli-cafe, Food by Breda Murphy , (01254 823446, foodbybredamurphy.com , also in Whalley); the Lower Buck pub in Waddington (01200 423342, lowerbuckinn.co.uk ), which is good for superior sandwiches and full meals; and the excellent Red Pump Inn in Bashall Eaves (01254 826227, theredpumpinn.co.uk ), whose slow-roasted Pendle pork belly (£13.95) is exceptional.

Incidentally, the Pump&apos;s three bedrooms are warmly contemporary and, while not cheap at £95, are good value. If there are a few of you, the Coach House, a self-catering cottage on a working farm (sleeps four; three nights from £270; 01254 826285, cloughbottom.co.uk ) is a good option, not least for the homemade teabread and Lancashire cheese in the welcome hamper. For further supplies and details of farm shops/food centres, see ribblevalleyfoodtrail.com 

Lake District: Cartmel


No, it is not L&apos;Enclume proper. At Rogan and Company (01539 535917, roganandcompany.co.uk ), you will not be served, as Coogan and Brydon so memorably put it, an innovative, left-field amuse with the &quot;consistency of Ray Winstone&apos;s snot&quot;. However, Simon Rogan&apos;s spin-off brasserie does offer an entry-level insight into the chef&apos;s rigorous culinary sensibility via a menu of crowd-pleasers such as fish pie or a gourmet burger, and smooth, elegant dishes, such as roast venison with creamed cabbage, chestnut and caramelised pear (mains from £10.50). It&apos;s also an opportunity to taste some of the vegetables and herbs that Rogan grows at nearby Howbarrow farm.

Like Rogan&apos;s stylish restaurants, Cartmel is pretty hip for the Lake District. There are the ubiquitous craft and gift shops, and a couple of excellent traditional pubs, such as the King&apos;s Arms (01539 536220) and the Royal Oak (rooms £70; 01539 536259, royaloakcartmel.co.uk ), where you can nurse a pint of Hawkshead or Barngates by an open fire. But, equally, Cartmel has modish food shops such as the Bread Shed (01539 533839, breadshed.co.uk) and Cartmel Cheeses (01539 532845, cartmelcheeses.co.uk ), and sensitively modernised self-catering properties like Longlands, a secluded courtyard of cottages around an early-19th-century country house (weekend breaks for two from £150; ainscoughs.co.uk ). If you are self-catering, stock up en route at Low Sizergh Barn (01539 560426, lowsizerghbarn.co.uk ) farm shop, which you&apos;ll pass coming from junction 36 on the M6, or at Cartmel Village Shop (01539 536280, cartmelvillageshop.co.uk ), famous for its sticky toffee pudding.

Coogan and Brydon headed on from Cartmel to Holbeck Ghyll at Windermere (01539 432375, holbeckghyll.com ). Chef David McLaughlin&apos;s refined Michelin-starred food is of a piece with the old-school, oak-panelled restaurant, best experienced, if you&apos;re keeping a nervous eye on your credit card bill, at lunch (two courses £24).

Yorkshire Dales: Kirkby Lonsdale

On The Trip, Kirkby Lonsdale itself was bypassed in the rush to get to nearby Hipping Hall (Sunday lunch £29.50; 01524 271187, hippinghall.com ). That was a mistake. This attractive market town is home to the exemplary Churchmouse Cheeses (01524 273005, churchmousecheeses.com ) – perhaps the only cheese shop in the country with its own Saturday afternoon pianist – a first-rate butcher, Dales (01524 271278, dalesbutchers.co.uk ), and the self-explanatory Chocolat (01524 272830, chocolatemine.co.uk ).

The Sun Inn (mains from £13.95; 015242 71965, sun-inn.info ) and boutique restaurant-with-rooms Plato&apos;s (pasta mains from £9.95, others £12.95; 01524 274180, platoskirkbylonsdale.co.uk ) are good places to refuel after shopping or to bed down for the night (doubles from £100). Steve Coogan would surely approve of Plato&apos;s serving breakfast until 2pm. Both offer cheaper, snackier bar food during the day, with an emphasis on local ingredients such as Lune Valley steaks and Lakeland lamb.

Just outside Kirkby is another of chef Nigel Haworth&apos;s pubs: the Highwayman (01524 273338, highwaymaninn.co.uk ). In fact, between the Three Fishes, the Highwayman and the Bull at Broughton (thebullatbroughton.com) near Skipton, you could pretty much shadow The Trip&apos;s route eating exclusively at Ribble Valley Inns pubs. This would be no bad thing.

Alternatively, follow Coogan and Brydon&apos;s route down into the Dales, to the Michelin-starred Yorke Arms (lunch, three courses, £30; 01423 755243, yorke-arms.co.uk ) and the Angel Inn at Hetton (01756 730263, angelhetton.co.uk ). The Angel is a fine example of a phenomenon that Yorkshire (a part of the world that never wants to be too far away from a perfect pint of Black Sheep, even while eating fine food) has made its own: the polished, ambitious dining pub. See also, the Star Inn at Harome (01439 770397 , thestaratharome.co.uk ); Pipe&amp;Glass Inn in South Dalton, near Beverley (01430 810246 , pipeandglass.co.uk ); and the General Tarleton at Ferrensby (01423 340284, generaltarleton.co.uk ). Given their pub origins, such venues usually offer affordable food, in some form. The Angel&apos;s bar menu runs from posh sandwiches at around £7 to gussied-up pub dishes like lamb hotpot at £14.25.
 
 United Kingdom Food and drink Food&amp;drink Restaurants Restaurants Lake District Lancashire Yorkshire 
 Tony Naylor 
 guardian.co.uk © Guardian News&amp;Media Limited 2010 | Use of this content is subject to our Terms&amp;Conditions | More Feeds 
 This column will change your life: The power of persuasion 
 [ Guardian ] ( Life and style: Health&amp;wellbeing | guardian.co.uk )
Is reasoning your way to a decision, or being convinced by others&apos; arguments, any better than trusting your gut?Whenever I&apos;m worried I might be turning into a total eccentric – due to over-exposure to self-help books, maybe, or just as a natural progression from being a partial eccentric – I check in with Seth Roberts, an American psychology professor based in China. After rigorous self-experimentation, he recently concluded that eating a 60g half-stick of butter every day made him 5% faster ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en-gb   
Is reasoning your way to a decision, or being convinced by others&apos; arguments, any better than trusting your gut?

Whenever I&apos;m worried I might be turning into a total eccentric – due to over-exposure to self-help books, maybe, or just as a natural progression from being a partial eccentric – I check in with Seth Roberts , an American psychology professor based in China. After rigorous self-experimentation, he recently concluded that eating a 60g half-stick of butter every day made him 5% faster at mental arithmetic. Previously, he&apos;d improved his sleep by eating quantities of pork belly each night. But if Roberts&apos;s single-mindedness is a little scary, it&apos;s surely also admirable: he approaches his body like a scientist, pushing aside personal biases, adjusting inputs and measuring outputs to see what influences his happiness and health.

On a more modest level, even those of us who couldn&apos;t stomach buttered butter for breakfast like to think we deal with life this way. Faced with any choice, especially big ones, we use our rational minds to identify reasons for and against, test them if possible, then do what seems most sensible. We know we&apos;re not infallible: numerous biases lead us astray, and we&apos;re horribly prone to rationalisation – that is, misusing our reasoning faculties to corral our emotions into line. But these are exceptions, we tell ourselves. After all, we&apos;re rational beings. That&apos;s what separates us from horses, or sardines, or Jeremy Clarkson.

Yet a forthcoming paper by the cognitive scientist Dan Sperber and the philosopher Hugo Mercier , Why Do Humans Reason?, proposes a radical alternative. What if we evolved the capacity to reason not to get closer to the truth, but to persuade others (and ourselves) of viewpoints, regardless of their relation to truth? In evolutionary terms, the survival benefits of such a talent are obvious. Maybe – to borrow the analogy used by Jonah Lehrer, who highlighted the paper on his blog at wired.com/wiredscience – we don&apos;t go about life as quasi-scientists, as we flatter ourselves, but as quasi-talk radio hosts, devoting our reasoning energies to concocting arguments that feel persuasive.

This is speculation, but Sperber and Mercier show it makes sense of countless psychological quirks that otherwise seem mysterious. Lehrer cites the famous study in which people were asked to rate five jams previously rated by food experts. Non-experts ranked them the same as experts – except those who were asked to provide reasons, who diverged hugely, preferring jams that (according to expert opinion) were worse. Seemingly, they were casting about for convincing-sounding reasons – &quot;Smoother jam is better&quot;, say – which threw them from their instinctive preference for the jams everyone else agreed were best. If reasoning is about truth-finding, this is bewildering, but if it&apos;s about generating fuel for persuasion, it makes sense. Rationalisation, from this perspective, isn&apos;t a failure of reasoning. It&apos;s what reasoning&apos;s for.

If so, the implications are big. It hints that reasoning your way to a decision, or being persuaded by others&apos; arguments, is unlikely to be better than trusting your gut. And it suggests that to engage in self-experimentation like Seth Roberts is a constant battle against biases that aren&apos;t just bugs in your mental software but, rather, fundamental to how it works. You can probably think of many persuasive reasons why eating half a stick of butter a day isn&apos;t sensible. But just because they&apos;re persuasive, does that makes them more likely to be true?

 oliver.burkeman@guardian.co.uk 

 twitter.com/oliverburkeman 
 
 Psychology Health&amp;wellbeing 
 Oliver Burkeman 
 guardian.co.uk © Guardian News&amp;Media Limited 2010 | Use of this content is subject to our Terms&amp;Conditions | More Feeds 
 
 
 
 Review - Saigon Sisters 
 [ Chicago, IL , Chicago ] ( Chicagoist )
The dinner menu at the recently opened Saigon Sisters on Lake Street is, if nothing else, an informative vocabulary lesson in Vietnamese cuisine. We learn of op la (over-easy eggs served with an array of pork products); goi du du (papaya salad with house-made beef jerky); and banh bao (open-faced steamed buns filled with glazed pork , chicken or beef). But really, the menu is an important document, precious even—you’re being slipped the passwords to a world of dizzying flavor. The Sa ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en               
The dinner menu at the recently opened Saigon Sisters on Lake Street is, if nothing else, an informative vocabulary lesson in Vietnamese cuisine. We learn of op la (over-easy eggs served with an array of pork products); goi du du (papaya salad with house-made beef jerky); and banh bao (open-faced steamed buns filled with glazed pork , chicken or beef). But really, the menu is an important document, precious even—you’re being slipped the passwords to a world of dizzying flavor.

The Saigon Sisters stand at Chicago’s French Market dispenses hearty banh mi (Vietnamese sandwiches) and spicy pho soup to the downtown lunch set. At their new sit-down restaurant, around the corner from the French Market, the chefs are presenting an inspired take on traditional Vietnamese dishes. The same tasty sandwiches are available at lunch, but come dinner, you can really explore the flavors and ingredients in creative new preparations and combinations.

Mention “bun nem la lot” with a knowing wink, and you&apos;re on your way to the fantastic betel leaf beef salad. The chefs wrap small pieces beef in betel leaves and then grill them (think Mediterranean grape leaves). They sit alongside mini pork spring rolls and grilled shrimp atop a bed of Asian slaw and rice noodles tossed in tangy, vinegary dressing. In many areas of South and Southeast Asia, Betel leaves are chewed for their breath-freshening and digestive benefits. Here they lend an herbal, medicinal contrast to the smoky the beef while keeping it moist and tender. An inspired combination.

The spring rolls are delightfully light and crispy and bring a welcome texture and crunch to a bowl of mostly slippery stuff. You’re meant to eat them with a mysterious (i.e., bland) dipping sauce that comes on the side, but we found ourselves avoiding it. What&apos;s it there for? The dish is not lacking in liquid—thanks to the sweet, pungent slaw dressing—and certainly not short on flavor. The real finishing touches are the whole mint and cilantro leaves you find tucked here and there, which bring even more freshness and fragrance to an already bright dish.

To get your chopsticks on the rich and comforting pork belly , egg and rice, ask for the pork belly , egg and rice (this one is listed in English). It combines slices of glazed pork belly , rice, Brussels sprouts and a so-called “5:10” egg. Turns out that’s the magic number for boiling an egg to perfection—five minutes, 10 seconds. The chopped Brussels sprouts, at the north end of our bowl, are sautéed in the pork belly ’s juices and hit with pepper; making them a great bite on their own but even better when you mix and match them with the other ingredients. We’re talking a flavor Venn diagram, here; different ingredients can be mixed and matched as you eat for innumerable combinations of flavor.

For dessert we tried the che (pronounced “jay”), which consists of butternut squash, formed into a mousse-like rectangle, a dusting of salt and peanut crumbles, a faro chip and a squeeze of sticky-rice-and-vanilla sauce. Apart from the sauce’s texture—too much like Elmer’s glue for us—the dessert was a hit; the familiar flavors of fall, by way of Southeast Asia.

When the day comes that you desperately want the opposite of turkey and gravy, Saigon Sisters has your sweet and spicy antidote.

 Saigon Sisters is located at 567 W. Lake St.; and Saigon Sisters’ sister location (couldn’t help ourselves) is located at 131 N. Clinton Street, inside the French Market.
 

 By Roger Kamholz 


 
 
 My Thanksgiving Thanks 
 [ Los Angeles , Los Angeles, CA ] ( LAist )
&quot;Look food trucks!&quot; (Julie Wolfson / LAist) Looking back on 2010, the year has been full of an abundance of things that I am thankful for. My family and friends. Food adventures in LA. Travel adventures around California and the world. So today I list a few of the things that made me feel truly grateful. Giving back/ giving thanks: mentoring at The Virginia Avenue Project, working with the Solar Cooker Project, working with Share Our Strength on Taste of the Nation, meeting Chef Cavaliere wit ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 &quot;Look food trucks!&quot; (Julie Wolfson / LAist) 
Looking back on 2010, the year has been full of an abundance of things that I am thankful for. My family and friends. Food adventures in LA. Travel adventures around California and the world. So today I list a few of the things that made me feel truly grateful.

Giving back/ giving thanks: mentoring at The Virginia Avenue Project, working with the Solar Cooker Project, working with Share Our Strength on Taste of the Nation, meeting Chef Cavaliere with students at Melrose Elementary at the Chefs Move to Schools project, covering Osteria La Buca&apos;s donation to Susan G Komen Foundation for Breast Cancer month, and writing about Charity Water clean water projects in Africa.

Food adventures with friends: tacos arabes at Pal Cabron, Jazz&apos;s BBQ pork with noodles at Jitlada, chicken pot pie at Wood Spoon, kimchi rice cakes&amp;tofu balls at Starry Kitchen, farro salad at Culina, Tokyo premium tonkotsu ramen at Jinya, pork belly adobo&amp;ube cupakes at The Manila Machine, patatas bravas at Tres, marinated mackerel at LudoBites, liege waffles with speculoos at Shaky Alibi, peking duck at WP24, chiliquiles at Local, lasagna at Osteria La Buca, every soup at Cube, Javier Plascencia&apos;s Test Kitchen tasting menu, Hi Tops at Frosted, the Bloody Mary at Library Bar, trying poutine for the first time at the Yard, and everything at The Dining Room. (I can&apos;t wait for Ink.)

Favorite art moments: Lola, Natalia Fabia&amp;Buff Monster at Corey Helford Gallery, Kathie Olivas and Brandt Peters at Gallery 1988, Ed Emberley at Scion Space, John Baldessari at LACMA Playmountain at Heath, the Warholian at Royal/T, Sanrio 50th anniversary at Barker Hanger and sitting in on a rehearsal in Disney Hall before interviewing Robert Vijay Gupta of the LA Phil.


Favorite travel adventures: volunteering for The Ritz-Carlton Community Footprints Project in Tucson, geocaching in Ojai, building sand castles in Santa Barbara, visiting a water village in Shanghai, catching fireflies in Central Park, sharing drinks with friends at a Cocktail Collective event at The Royalton in NYC, seeing Gogol Bordello and checking out the Wine Lands tent at Outsidelands in San Francisco, horseback riding on Manchester Beach&amp;seeing blue whales on the Mendocino Coast, kayaking on the Gualala river, tasting the Highland Park 50 in London, and learning about making whisky at The Macallan in Speyside.

And every day I am thankful for the opportunity to learn more about &apos;the real Los Angeles&apos;.

Happy Thanksgiving everyone!


 
 
 Nagasaki-Style Braised Pork : Buta Kaku-ni 
 [ Asian Food ] ( Tess&apos;s Japanese Kitchen )
http://1tess.wordpress.com Braised pork belly , buta kaku-ni, is a special occasion dish—so very rich and succulent that one wouldn’t eat it everyday. Today is this blog’s third birthday so celebrate with me! It’s Thanksgiving Day, and while it’s too late for you to make this recipe for the holiday, it would be perfect to serve as ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   http://1tess.wordpress.com Braised pork belly , buta kaku-ni, is a special occasion dish—so very rich and succulent that one wouldn’t eat it everyday. Today is this blog’s third birthday so celebrate with me! It’s Thanksgiving Day, and while it’s too late for you to make this recipe for the holiday, it would be perfect to serve as [...] 
 All That Jazz&amp;More at Zen Dog Café in Rhinebeck -- Food Section -- News 
 [ Rural ] ( Rural Intelligence )
Zen Dog Café, which opened in Rhinebeck three months ago, is astonishingly eclectic. Located in an old house on Route 9 a stone’s throw from the Beekman Arms, Zen Dog is a crazy quilt of rooms that are home to a bar, café, bookstore, jazz club, gift shop, art gallery and several lounges. Walking in is a bit like falling into the proverbial rabbit hole, for it’s not quite like anyplace else you’ve ever been before. “It’s really hard to explain,” says owner D J Kadagian. “But it’ ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Zen Dog Café, which opened in Rhinebeck three months ago, is astonishingly eclectic. Located in an old house on Route 9 a stone’s throw from the Beekman Arms, Zen Dog is a crazy quilt of rooms that are home to a bar, café, bookstore, jazz club, gift shop, art gallery and several lounges. Walking in is a bit like falling into the proverbial rabbit hole, for it’s not quite like anyplace else you’ve ever been before. “It’s really hard to explain,” says owner D J Kadagian. “But it’s nothing you expect.” The enigmatic Kadagian is a materialist turned idealist. Growing up in Westport, CT, he felt “broke” compared to his wealthy friends and after attending Cornell’s Hotel School he opted out of low-paying restaurant work to go into finance. “I started at Shearson Lehman in 1987, the week the stock market crashed,” he recalls. Eventually, he opened his own investment firm and developed a proprietary trading software but he found material success unfulfilling. He briefly enrolled at Yale’s School of Divinity but dropped out when he realized he did not have the patience to study for exams and write papers. “I had learned so much about spirituality from Bill Moyer’s series on Joseph Campbell, The Power of Myth, so I decided to start making documentary films myself. I could interview the people who moved me and who I thought would move other people.” Kadagian had success with his initial series of movies called Crisis of Faith, which did the film festival circuit. “The movies have been shown on PBS and the Hallmark and Discovery channels. I thought I was going to be the next fill-in-the-blank big director,” he says sheepishly. It was through filmmaking that he discovered Rhinebeck. “My wife had been to Omega a bunch of times, and I went there to interview Sam Keen and Huston Smith, who was teaching there and who is one of the two truly holy people I have met in my life,” he says. “We stayed at the Beekman and fell in love with the town. People were sitting outside at cafes—it felt like Europe. And then we went driving around and saw the landscape and we were blown away. It’s a much different vibe than Fairfield County.” He approached creating Zen Dog the same way he made movies. “I don’t think linearly,” he explains. “When you are editing a film, it’s a little like assembling a puzzle. And though my movies are based on interviews, they are driven by music and so is the restaurant.” The music that drives Zen Dog is Brazilian and West Coast Jazz. “It’s the music of the 1950s and 1960s,” he explains. “You hear it with your heart, not your head. It’s the music of Dave Brubeck, Chet Baker and Art Pepper who is my all-time favorite. We have jazz every Thursday night and we’ll be adding a second night soon. It’s not easy to find artists who play this music well.” The cafe has a vintage Mason&amp;Hamlin baby grand piano that is a lure for musicians. “Most guys are used to playing now on an electronic keyboard, but we try to keep everything acoustic here.” Not surprisingly, the menu is eclectic, and it’s designed for improvisational meals. There are $5 tapas (roasted pork belly buns, prosciutto-wrapped figs, shrimp spring rolls), $12 charcuteries plates (with cheese, pates and cured meats), $9 sandwiches (roast beef with tomato tapenade and garlic aioli, ham with camembert and quince jam), and a few hearty entrees in the evening such as the Shepherd’s Pie and lamb tagine. “I am really proud of our pizzas,” says Kadagian, citing the ten-inch Mumbai Pie ($13) as his favorite; it has a spicy Indian-inspired tomato sauce, roasted squash and Panir-style cheese. Zen Dog is unapologetically “alternative,” which is symbolized by the electric car chargers in the parking lot. “I think we may be the first private business to have them in New York, ” says Kadagian who’s pleased that Zen Dog feels like a community hub. “It’s a place where you can start a conversation with a stranger, or grab a book and start reading,” he says. “The whole point is that it’s a place to hang out.” Zen Dog Café 6367 Route 9, Rhinebeck; 845.516.4501 Wednesday - Thursday 10:30 a.m. - 11 p.m. Friday - Saturday 10:30 a.m. - midnight Sunday 10:30 a.m. - 9 p.m. Closed Monday&amp;Tuesday during the winter Live Jazz Every Thursday 7 - 10 p.m. Wine Tasting Every 2nd Wednesday 6 - 7 p.m. Art Opening Every 3rd Saturday 5 - 8 p.m.   
 I revolted, felt revolting and revolted some more: The Swartland Revolution 2010 
 [ Africa ] ( Afrigator )
I can confidently say that the Swartland Revolution was by far the most enjoyable wine event I have been to. It was run with Germanic efficiency but full of South African gees. There was a balance between formal tastings and lounging on the grass sipping Bollinger. We ate till we were fit to burst, and drank till we were dancing (read: falling off)&amp;#160; hay bales, we chatted&amp;#38; laughed, sipped and smiled; this was a revolution against boring wines, against boring events; this was a r ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   I can confidently say that the Swartland Revolution was by far the most enjoyable wine event I have been to. It was run with Germanic efficiency but full of South African gees. There was a balance between formal tastings and lounging on the grass sipping Bollinger. We ate till we were fit to burst, and drank till we were dancing (read: falling off)&amp;#160; hay bales, we chatted&amp;#38; laughed, sipped and smiled; this was a revolution against boring wines, against boring events; this was a revolt against the plain and the sad, the straight and the narrow; it was simply a benchmarking of joie de vivre. OK. Ive gushed enough now I can get on with my story. On Friday (a week and a bit ago I never said I was into current affairs) I packed my bag with essentials (extra tobacco, bottle opener, hat, waistcoat, rizla, headache pills, pen and notebook) and headed out in what would also turn out to be my accommodation: The four star Chez Citi Golf* I arrived early and popped in at the Royal Hotel for a quick glass at the bar. Soon the other attendees began to arrive and register. Bottles were bought and consumed in the sun as we waited for things to get under way. I spotted one of my partners in crime Jrg Pftzner and we headed out for a crafty G&amp;#38;T and a sneak preview of the following days lunch&amp;#160; at Bar Bar Black Sheep.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Cancel all my appointments, Im revolting&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; The deep fried baby marrow flowers were orgasmic Ready to revolt we made our way back to the Royal Hotel for the first tasting: Quality First eight wines from Michael&amp;#38; Stephane Ogier of the Northern Rhone. We started with the Saint Joseph Blanc 2008&amp;#160; made from 100% Marsanne. I found it quite grapey with&amp;#160; pineapple and spice, nutmeg perhaps. A very satisfying wine, although I found the palate to be boxy, structured around the sides but not much weight in the middle. The decidedly mineral finish was very tasty. The 100% Viognier Condrieu&amp;#34;La combe de Malleval&amp;#34; 2009 was not quite as good for me and seemed a touch clingy on the palate. But I enjoyed the richness with dollops of white fig. What can I say, I battle with 100% Viogniers. Then there was a series of Syrahs from Cte-Rtie starting with the L&amp;#8217;Ame Sur 2007 from vineyards in Seyssuel that provide schist soils. I thought this an excellent wine, with tomato leaf, black cherries and cedar dominating for me. The tannins were fine and the wine was quite accessible. My favourite was the Cte-Rtie&amp;#34;Belle Hlne&amp;#34; 2007 which was gritty with serious weight. Muscle weight, not weigh-watchers weight. And although quite powerful, showed excellent balance. Very young and tight, this will be a brilliant wine. The 99, and I have to agree with Mr. Pendock here, was quite stinky, but I kinda liked it. Just like your own farts smell like roses, here the stink was charming rather than nasty. I loved the 2005 Roussanne, so rich and textured with touch of veggies, but also some spice. There was some debate as to whether more than a glass would be too much. I finished all my absent neighbours glasses to find out. I can confidently report that two are fine, but a bottle without food could become a little tiring. After the tasting we all trooped up the hill for a braai at The Ou Pastorie&amp;#160; prepared by Rueben Riffel. Oh what joyous delights were presented to my mouth. Slabs of pork belly , chops, steaks, hamburgers and sausages, salads and potatoes and more that I have forgotten were liberally piled onto plates, and glasses were filled with mystery Swartland Wines. I wandered about video camera in one hand, glass in the other. I found this snapshot from late in the evening. Gulping and lurching from one bottle to the next we left the braai and headed into town. A bar was found. One G&amp;#38;T later and I did a bit of a runner.&amp;#160; When I saw springboks lining the bar being made with Patrn Tequlia, I decided I would preserve myself. A tad too revolting for me. Hazily I made my way to my accommodation. I was staying by the Royal Hotel; well, to be a little more precise just outside the Hotel, in my car. I realised the next morning that I should perhaps have parked a little further away when people I had never met before started asking how I slept and if my neck was stiff. You see, as the early risers left the hotel they all stopped to peer in at this wino nestled in his sleeping bag. Stepping from my car I was promptly handed a crate of ice and set to work always happy to help I joined in with gusto assisting the revolutionaries polish glasses and pour the wines for the next session. But before that started it was Babelaas Breakfast Burgers for everyone. Adi Badenhorst, wine-maker, parrot breeder and mutton-chop grower,&amp;#160; was of the opinion that the whole weekend was setup around these burgers. Quite possible, as without the revolution there would be no Babelaas, and who wants plain old breakfast burgers anyway? Burgers in our bellies we all filed into the tasting venue for the Eben&amp;#38; Adi Show moderated by Dr. Tim James. Dr. James lamented that he always has to get stuck with a Dr. in front of his name when another wine writer also has a Doctorate in an irrelevant subject. Is it perhaps the striking resemblance he bears to another Doctor of Journalism? The tasting was kicked off in true showman-like fashion by Eben Sadie doing a cartwheel in front of the crowd as a result of a lost bet. Ebens tasting was focused around the importance of having an in-depth knowledge of the soils vines are planted in. He spoke of how in the Cte de Nuits and the Mosel they know their land intimately. Theyve spent years mapping their soils and it is something weve got to start doing. He said there are two ways to map the soil: one is by drilling holes and testing the soil, and the other is by tasting the soil in the glass. It is when these two maps start to correlate that you have the truth. But the most important thing is to start. To illustrate he poured four wines from the 2010 vintage. The first three were Syrahs from single vineyards and the third a blend of the three. They were from some of the vineyards that go into making the Columella. Eben described how he had intended to make three Syrahs from three different vineyards but found that the blend was always a better wine than any of the individual ones. Also, he quipped, it is cheaper to produce a single label.&amp;#160; All the wines came from 3 year old casks. What is the point, Eben argued, of spending a year trying to get wines to taste of the soil and then putting it in new wood to taste like a tree from France. An interesting point here was that in his earlier Columellas Eben admitted to using more new wood, and it is from these wines that he scored higher points from the yanks. The first wine was from granite soils, which according to Eben have a great affinity with Syrah. It offered loads of spice and bright purple fruits, with some serious intensity. There was a weighty feel to the mid palate, but still a linear wine. I found it stern, but not without attraction, like a sexy librarian. Wine number two was made from vineyards planted in schist or slate soil. He explained how there are not many wine growing areas with slate soils but wherever they are they produce some of the most extraordinary wines in the world. For example Cote Rotie, the Mosel, and Priorat. If we were to take a scale of red wines with Gamay on the one side and Cabernet on the other, Eben says that the Syrah coming from slate leans more to the Gamay side. It is leaner, like having two safety belts on, and provides the element in the Columella that makes it approachable younger. I found it offered floral notes instead of spice, a violet wine. There was an interesting combination of creaminess and leanness. I could drink this on its own easily. The third wine was from clay rich soil. In Malmsbury there are slivers of clay ridges, and Eben&amp;#160; claimed that everyone who makes wine in the Swartland has at least one parcel of vines in this soil. The reason is that it provides such remarkable structure. Clay soils make big big wines. This one was no different. It was the one wine of the tasting that I would not want to drink by itself. Or at least not for the next ten years. It was bold, with massive body and mouth rape-ish tannins. A swashbuckling, hide your daughters wine, a wine that doesnt beat around the bush, it simply beats the bush into mulch. Finally there was the blend of the three in equal parts. Eben was right, I thought this was the better wine, although for me the granite one was a very close second. Eben said to be a serious blender you have to start blending with the vineyards. For example he has vineyards he includes just for acidity, some for purity etc.; he says he blends what he gets given from the vineyards. And I think this is a point central to the revolution. If your acidity is poked, adding something from a bag on a shelf is counterrevolutionary. The revolution is about purity. Following Eben was Adi Badenhorst who started off in his usual self-depreciating manner by saying that Ebens wines are linear well made wines, mine are anything but that. Nonsense. But thats why we love Adi, he makes winemaking sound as easy as making mud-pies, gooi something there, chuck some of that, wait for 8 months and you have a wine. We all know he is bullshitting. He presented seven interesting white wines from younger vineyards. He described how he wanted substance in wines, not just showy wines with nothing behind them. Its like when you have Meryl Streep in a movie, he explained you know you will get substance, maybe not sexy but you will get substance. And substance can come from originality, which he admits is a challenge:&amp;#160; It is very difficult to come up with original stuff. You have to stand back. This seems almost counterintuitive, but his point seems to be that we have incredible vineyards that are able to produce wonderful original wines, if we simply dont fuck up the process. Adi beautifully compared terroir to bees: you have thousands of bees that go out to collect pollen from many many different flowers, and the result is exquisite honey. Terroir is a combination of a multiplicity of elements that go into wine. Another revolutionary point I took away from this (and I am saying this not Adi) is that man is not terroir, by standing back and letting nature do her thing you are able to express the terroir through interesting, original wines of substance. I enjoyed all of Adis whites; the Chenin was round and fresh with mineral chunks and stone fruit flavours. The Grenache Gris was weird (well to me a grenache gris virgin) but wonderful, lots of litchi skin on the nose that followed to the palate, quite oxidative but still fresh and a long finish with a little tannin grip. An exciting interesting wine that makes you think. 10 points (not wine scoring points mind you, more like a high five). The colombard was funky, fighting fresh and rad. The Verdelho had lovely lines, a very pretty wine that I have dreamt of since. Racy, almost salty with some oily limeyness. Fan-bloody-tastic to quote Jrg. There was also the blend which I would have bought a case of given half a chance. I really hope we start to see some of these single varieties being bottled and adding a bit of spice to the local offerings at wine shops. All happy and bouncy we left the tasting venue and collected a complimentary Riedel flute at the exit. Flutes in hand everyones eyes darted this way and that looking for what was going to fill them. Happily the revolutionaries appeared, Bollinger in hand, to fill everyones glasses. Revolutionary Chris Mulineux getting in on the action Mr. Bubbles himself I spotted one revolutionary who seemed to be enjoying the Bolly as much as me, wine maker Callie Louw.&amp;#160; This proved biblically positive as my cup did runneth over. Michael Fridjon was up next after an introduction by Marc Kent. The speech he gave served two purposes, one was to launch Swartland Independent, the central committee if you will, to the revolution which aims to carry on the good fight and promote the Swartlands interests; the second was the launching of South African Sommelier of the Year. I found the speech level headed and necessary, although when the ANC was mentioned (as how not to carry through with a revolution) I cringed as bolly, sunshine and lounging on the grass seemed to be the antithesis of politics. But the points were important and well made, to read the speech see here. Bolly finished and stomachs grumbling the revolutionary mob made their way to the best restaurant in the known universe** Bar Bar Black Sheep. I, as usual, followed the wine and, also as usual, Jrg Pftzner with his travelling Riesling cellar provided. The Bucket O Riesling After drinking and eating steadily for an hour or so an auction was held where amongst other items a Nomblot concrete egg fermenter was sold for R40 000. But thats not all, thrown in at no extra cost was 600 litres of Chenin donated by Eben and Adi. But more on that later, all I will say for now is watch out for the Silwer Vis. From this point things got a little wild and woolly. The Real men Wild Ferment walk around tasting began, although there was no word from the host Neil Pendock. Apparently the sound system had disappeared, a bit of a poor excuse I thought, but it did give him something to blog about. I loped merrily from one stand to the next gulping wines with what some may have considered reckless abandon, but I just thumbed my nose at them and called them counterrevolutionary. A stand out was from a buddy of mine Bryan MacRobert (thus I am obviously biased) the Tobias Chenin. It stood out for its ludicrously mineral finish that made me think immediately of all the Rieslings I had just had. Another style of Chenin which I hope we will see more of. The day wore on as comfortably as a silk pair of drawers. Before I knew it the sun had disappeared along with the majority of attendees and I found myself performing interpretive dance to Florence and the Machine on top of hay-bales with Tessa Miles. This ended when I managed to fall arse-over-kettle-over-pot and landed rather heavily on the pavement; though I must add not a drop of wine was spilt. The hangers on went for more dinner at Bar Bar Black sheep (this time the best T-bone this side of anywhere***). During dinner a couple sitting in the corner decided this was an appropriate time to get engaged. We all felt this was fitting and we joined in the celebrations loudly and vehemently. I trust we will make a story at their wedding. Memories now become patchy. Some of us then kidnapped a waitress, a few bottles of Mullineux White and headed for a lookout point. Then a vineyard. We all awoke in a car with a farmer shouting at us. Shir thish ish private property, you musht leave now. Groggily, OK, but we were just having a kip. Opening his car door menacingly Lishen hear, thish ish private property and you must go right now. Pleash sir, go now! Ok but who do you sell your grapes to? Because were never buying it again. We then sped off back into town for a few breakfast G&amp;#38;Ts. Being chased off a vineyard seemed the perfect punctuation mark to end the weekend. We revolted, felt revolting and revolted some more. We drank wines of substance, of personality; they were of the soil, from the heart and fresh as&amp;#160; daisies. We also made friends, companions in wine, lovers of complexity fine food and a helluva party. As I made the long trek to Steenberg to pick up some 2005 Sauvignon Blanc for a old white wine tasting that Sunday afternoon, I reflected that this was the way of the future. Outside of the technical aspects of winemaking the Swartland Revolutionaries had made sure their weekend was fun, an aspect of wine drinking that is oft forgotten. They provided style in swathes and I will be back next year. Maybe it will not be a revolution then, but I can promise you one thing, on Sunday morning Ill be feeling just as revolting. The egg A fair question Eben The Revolutionaries&amp;#160; *According to the HRH accommodation when you have no accomodation review. **according to the HRH Restaurant Review it is biased, and impossible, but more than likely true. ***According to the HRH T-bone review Also biased and ridiculous, but probably true as well 
 11/27/2010 - Central City Brewing Co. Presents: The Offal Tasty Beer Dinner 
 [ Jobs ] ( All Events - Vancouver Events Calendar )
Head Chef Carl Sawatsky has created a masterful menu in celebration of the oft forgotten offal. Offal is a culinary term used to refer to the entrails and internal organs of a butchered animal. People in some cultures shy away from offal as food, while others use it every day. We at Central City Brewing Co. believe that when prepared properly the offal is delicacy that must be experienced. With that in mind we present you with The Offal Tasty Beer Dinner. 1st Course Fried Veal Tongue Rillettes ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
Head Chef Carl Sawatsky has created a masterful menu in celebration of the oft forgotten offal. Offal is a culinary term used to refer to the entrails and internal organs of a butchered animal. People in some cultures shy away from offal as food, while others use it every day. We at Central City Brewing Co. believe that when prepared properly the offal is delicacy that must be experienced. With that in mind we present you with The Offal Tasty Beer Dinner.

1st Course
Fried Veal Tongue Rillettes Studded with Black Truffle on Brioche with Pale Ale Jelly
Beer Paired: Red Racer Pale Ale
Food Fact: Rillettes is a preparation of meat similar to pâté. Originally made with pork , the meat is cubed or chopped, salted heavily and cooked slowly in fat until it is tender enough to be easily shredded, and then cooled with enough of the fat to form a paste. They are normally used as spread on bread or toast and served at room temperature.

2nd Course
Crispy Sweetbreads, Mushrooms, Asparagus and a B.C. Morel Mushroom Demi Glace
Beer Paired: Red Racer White Ale
Food Fact: Sweetbreads or ris are culinary names for the thymus (throat, gullet, or neck sweetbread) and the pancreas (heart, stomach, or belly sweetbread), especially of the calf (ris de veau) and lamb (ris d&apos;agneau)

3rd Course
Phở Soup with Tripe, Offaly Good Meat Balls and Crispy Pig Ear Garnish
Beer Paired: Red Racer Märzen
Food Fact: Phở is a Vietnamese Noodle Soup. The soup includes rice noodles and is often served with basil, lime, bean sprouts, and peppers that are added to the soup by the consumer.

4th Course
Lemon Meringue Surprise
Beer Paired: Red Racer Tripel

Tickets:
Brewery Creek on Main&amp;15th in Vancouver
Firefly Fine Wines&amp;Ales on Cambie&amp;12th in Vancouver
Central City Brewing Company

*** Ticket sales cut off two weeks in advance to ensure the freshest meats available. ***
 
 Rainy Day: Making Bacon 
 [ Bacon ] ( bacon«WordPress.com Tag Feed )
Last week I found a couple of slabs of pork belly at MaineSource and decided to try making bacon. Na ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Last week I found a couple of slabs of pork belly at MaineSource and decided to try making bacon. Na 
 Samgyeopsal 삼겹살 - a pork belly lettuce wrap 
 [ Bacon ] ( bacon«WordPress.com Tag Feed )
Samgyeopsal 삼겹살 is a popular Korean BBQ – grilled strips of pork belly , similar to bacon. The ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Samgyeopsal 삼겹살 is a popular Korean BBQ – grilled strips of pork belly , similar to bacon. The 
 Pressing pork matters 
 [ Q&amp;A ] ( Ask MetaFilter )
I&apos;ve got a nice big piece of pork belly , and I&apos;m going to braise it in cider and wine, as in this recipe. I&apos;ve made it before, and it was excellent. Which wine (or cider, or even beer) would you pair it with? Also, in most recipes for twice-cooked (confit) pork belly ( like this one ) the meat is weighed down/pressed overnight after it&apos;s been cooked once in fat. Why is that? Would it make sense to use this technique in a non-confit recipe, like the braise?
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   I&apos;ve got a nice big piece of pork belly , and I&apos;m going to braise it in cider and wine, as in this recipe . I&apos;ve made it before, and it was excellent. Which wine (or cider, or even beer) would you pair it with?

Also, in most recipes for twice-cooked (confit) pork belly ( like this one ) the meat is weighed down/pressed overnight after it&apos;s been cooked once in fat. Why is that? Would it make sense to use this technique in a non-confit recipe, like the braise? 
 Foodsday Tuesday: What to Do About That Carcass 
 [ Philadelphia, PA , Philadelphia ] ( Phillyist )
Image Credit: Jess J Thanksgiving. A holiday whose celebration tends to mean decadence and gluttony—and a ton of organic matter in the garbage. It&apos;s wasteful, and it&apos;s not that healthy. Your turkified trash can is going to attract every squirrel, mouse, and feral cat in the neighborhood. You can cut down on the waste substantially if you use the turkey parts nobody eats (specifically the carcass and giblets) to make stock, rather than throwing away what actually amounts to a lot of food ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 Image Credit: Jess J Thanksgiving. A holiday whose celebration tends to mean decadence and gluttony—and a ton of organic matter in the garbage. It&apos;s wasteful, and it&apos;s not that healthy. Your turkified trash can is going to attract every squirrel, mouse, and feral cat in the neighborhood. You can cut down on the waste substantially if you use the turkey parts nobody eats (specifically the carcass and giblets) to make stock, rather than throwing away what actually amounts to a lot of food. You can also keep the vegetable parts you&apos;d ordinarily throw away from your stuffing and side dishes (carrot tops, unused celery stalks, bell pepper stems, onion skins—turnips that didn&apos;t make it to the roaster, etc.) and use them to enrich your stock.
To make, take as much meat off of the turkey as you can (it freezes well if you&apos;re worried that you won&apos;t eat it all). Skin can go into the stock or not; your call. Separate the bones as much as possible so that what remains can easily fit into a stock pot, with room for other stuff. Put your leftover veggie parts in the pot with the carcass, and add any additional vegetables you want (especially if you don&apos;t have a lot of scraps leftover), and fill the pot with water so that everything is covered. Season with some salt and pepper, a few bay leaves, and whatever dried herbs you want to use and let that sucker boil. It will take a while. Go watch some football.

After your pot has come to a boil, reduce the heat, cover the pot, and simmer for three or four hours, stirring occasionally and spooning off fat if/when it rises to the top (if it doesn&apos;t, or you can&apos;t navigate around the other things in the pot to skim effectively, don&apos;t worry—there&apos;s time for that later). You&apos;ll also want to check your seasoning once in a while after the first hour or two is passed and you&apos;re sure that the giblets (if you used them—but you really should) are cooked through. No need for salmonella-stock!

After the color and flavor have developed sufficiently (it&apos;s like pornography; you&apos;ll know it when you see it), remove the stock from the stove and strain through a colander draped with a cheesecloth into a large bowl. The cheesecloth is to prevent any of the dried herbs from getting through to the stock; it&apos;s not necessary but it&apos;s helpful. Allow the broth to cool completely (you can speed the process by placing the bowl in an ice bath) and skim what fat you can find, then refrigerate.

Now here&apos;s the really fun part, and the part that&apos;s really scary to many first-time stock-makers. The next day, when you open your fridge, you&apos;ll note that the contents of your bowl have turned to a meaty Jell-O. This is because the turkey bones have lots of marrow in them, and marrow is what makes gelatin. Your stock has gelled because you made it right, not because you screwed something up. Remove the bowl from the fridge, scrape off whatever fat remains (it will be opaque and easy to distinguish from the actual stock), and then heat whatever portion of the stock you wish to use. It&apos;ll turn back to liquid in no time. If you&apos;re not using it right away, portion the stock into separate containers and freeze until you want it. (Note: if you don&apos;t feel like making stock within a day or two of having made your turkey, you can also freeze the carcass and vegetables for up to about a month.)


 Quick Nosh 


 The dearth of Mexican restaurants in Philadelphia that we observed several years ago is quickly turning into a surplus in South Philadelphia. Tres Jalapeños (not to be confused with Los Jalapeño in Pennsport), a Mexican BYOB, has recently opened its doors at 8th and Christian in the Italian Market. For more information, contact 267.239.2358. Chaddsford Winery will be hosting four holiday open houses in December with snacks, mulled wines, and several gift ideas. We love this idea so much that we&apos;re willing to forgive the misplaced apostrophe in the event description. While perhaps a bit excessive for friends to whom a Harry and David fruit-of-the-month membership is the height of gourmet holiday eating, the Garces Trading Company will this year sell foodie gift baskets for your more adventurous giftees. Baskets will range in price from $75 to $120. Hey Chosen People: Philly&apos;s most famous (only?) part-Israeli chef doesn&apos;t want to leave you out in the cold this holiday season. December 22nd, in stereotypical style, he&apos;ll be offering a movie and Chinese food at Zahav , specifically tailored to the non-believers amongst you. But observant Jews beware: at least one course on the menu ( PDF) will feature the very treyf pork belly . 
 

 
 
 Gluttony Pants Encourage You to Stuff Yourself at the Thanksgiving Table 
 [ Parenting , AOL , Moms ] ( ParentDish )
Filed under: Holidays, In The News, Funny Stuff Just how big of a pig will you be at your holiday dinners? Credit: Betabrand.com Hey guys, there is a fashion god. And it wants you to eat, drink and, well, eat and drink some more. Ever wished for trousers that could actually make room for your post-Thanksgiving pooch? Now, you can be thankful for Gluttony Pants from Betabrand.com. With three expandable buttons labeled &quot;Piglet,&quot; &quot;Sow&quot; and &quot;Boar,&quot; the caramel-colored canvas pants adhere to th ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
Filed under: Holidays , In The News , Funny Stuff 
 
Just how big of a pig will you be at your holiday dinners? Credit: Betabrand.com 
 Hey guys, there is a fashion god. And it wants you to eat, drink and, well, eat and drink some more.

Ever wished for trousers that could actually make room for your post-Thanksgiving pooch? Now, you can be thankful for Gluttony Pants from Betabrand.com . With three expandable buttons labeled &quot;Piglet,&quot; &quot;Sow&quot; and &quot;Boar,&quot; the caramel-colored canvas pants adhere to the notion that the wider your belly expands, the larger a pig you become, MSNBC reports.

The brainchild of San Francisco chef Chris Cosentino, they&apos;re kind of the male version of &quot;Mom&quot; jeans , those high-waisted, hideous and generously-cut pants that scream &quot;I&apos;m not a woman any more. I&apos;m a mom.&quot;

&quot;Everybody has that Uncle Tony who eats too much and has to unbutton his pants at the table,&quot; Cosentino, who designed the pants, tells MSNBC.

 
Go ahead, take another taco. These pants encourage gluttony. Credit: Betabrand.com 
 
Cosentino, a Food Network star, executive chef of Incanto restaurant in San Francisco and an offal specialist (offal are those parts of an animal not normally served up -- think giblets, brains, entrails and other generally icky pieces), says being labeled a pig shouldn&apos;t be offensive, as pork served as his loving inspiration for designing the pants.

In honor of Thanksgiving, the pants&apos; fabric, which comes in a deep caramel color, pays homage to turkey, with the pockets lined in the burgundy color of cranberry sauce, he tells MSNBC.

Unfortunately for moms who plan to reach for another piece of pecan pie, Gluttony Pants currently only come in men&apos;s sizes, 30 to 42. At $100 a pop, they&apos;ve been flying off the virtual shelf since they debuted on Betabrand.com in August, Chris Lindland, owner of the site, tells MSNBC.com.

Cosentino tells MSNBC he rocks his Gluttony Pants on a regular basis and loves using them as a conversation piece. But he has yet to upgrade from &quot;Piglet&quot; to &quot;Sow.&quot;

&quot;I haven&apos;t had to move to the next button yet,&quot; he says. &quot;But then again, we haven&apos;t hit Thanksgiving.&quot;



 Permalink | Email this | Comments 
 
 #107570 - Slow Roasted Pork Belly with Ginger Beer Jamie Oliver 
 [ Food ] ( TasteSpotting )
Slow roasted pork belly with ginger beer - Jamie Oliver craving more? check out TasteSpotting ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   

Slow roasted pork belly with ginger beer - Jamie Oliver

craving more? check out TasteSpotting 

 
 Inside the Kitchen Door - How to Cook Pork Belly - Part One 
 [ Men ] ( recent posts - blip.tv )
Cocktails and their myriad incarnations lend themselves very well to food pairing. In this inaugural episode of Inside the Kitchen Door, Chef and Host Andrew Lanier discusses the art of pairing food and cocktails. This often over looked realm of cuisine, most often left to wine, is an absolute necessity when preparing any restaurant or dinner party menu. In particular, Chef Lanier looks at Maker&apos;s Mark Bourbon and draws on its flavor profile when creating a savory dish. Distributed by Tubemogul.
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en-us   
Cocktails and their myriad incarnations lend themselves very well to food pairing. In this inaugural episode of Inside the Kitchen Door, Chef and Host Andrew Lanier discusses the art of pairing food and cocktails. This often over looked realm of cuisine, most often left to wine, is an absolute necessity when preparing any restaurant or dinner party menu. In particular, Chef Lanier looks at Maker&apos;s Mark Bourbon and draws on its flavor profile when creating a savory dish. Distributed by Tubemogul. 
 ©2010 Something Simpler Systems Inc. ( contact ) Categories 

Produced with the financial participation of Telefilm Canada
 [ close ]
	</body>
</document>
