<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009302" url="http://restaurantfunds.com/" time="2012-07-13-02:41" support="1" score="0.0021541377719013913" bingtitle="Restaurant Business Plan How to Fund &amp; Open a Restaurant" webtitle="Restaurant Business Plan How to Fund&amp;Open a Restaurant">
			<query id="001175" bing-rank="240"/>
	<description>Restaurant Business Plans That Get Funded- Guaranteed! ... we show you exactly what you need to do, in the order ... all the tedious work out of it and in fact we tell you ...</description>
	<body>
		Everything for Your Restaurant Business Plan&amp;Starting a Restaurant.

Learn how to plan, fund and open a restaurant- and then run it profitably.
 
Our Proven Restaurant Business Plan and
Complete Restaurant Plan Software Package

A restaurant business plan is the first step toward a successful restaurant- including getting the funds to open. Check out our simple plan writing process and complete software package to get done quickly and easily.
 
 Biz Plans 

Create Yours

Restaurant Business Plans- Easy&amp;Proven.

Find out more
 
Learn How to Start and Open a Restaurant From Scratch: Menus to Marketing and More

Starting a restaurant involves covering a million details. Find out more here about what you need to do and the best ways to get everything done without going crazy or losing track of where you&apos;re at in the process.
 
 Startup 

All the Details

Start a Restaurant From Scratch.

Find out more
 
Considering a Restaurant Franchise ? Everything You Need to Know is Here

Opening a restaurant franchise involves lots of decisions- starting with which franchise to pick. Use our resources to narrow the choices and educate yourself about the process and how to do it right.
 
 Franchise 

Find and Compare

Restaurant Franchise Options and Info.

Find out more
 
Buying a Restaurant for Sale Can Be Tricky- Learn How to Do It Right at the Right Price

Buying a restaurant for sale can mean instant cash flow and customers but it can also involve a lot of headaches and requires a good BS detector. Find out how to be a successful buyer and avoid getting burned.
 
 Buy One 

Doing the Deal

How to Buy a Restaurant For Sale.

Find out more
 
Start your restaurant right with a solid, fundable restaurant business plan using all of our resources to help you create the perfect path to profitability and success.

We are the number one online resource for anyone aspiring to open a restaurant and run it right whether you are starting from scratch, opening a restaurant franchise or buying an existing restaurant for sale .
 
Join the over ten thousand people who have put our plan software and restaurant services to work or one of the hundreds of thousands of people who have turned to our blog, articles and resources for restaurant help and advice.
 
You Can Create a
Restaurant Business Plan&amp;
Get the Money You Need to
Open the Restaurant You Want! 

The money you need to open the restaurant of your dreams is available for anyone if you know the right steps to go and get it.
And you can do it because we show you exactly what you need to do, in the order it needs to be done, so you can make your dream into a reality.
The best part is that it doesn&apos;t take forever. In fact, we&apos;ve cut the process down so much and made it so easy you can literally create a restaurant business plan and financials package is just a few days or less- not the weeks and months most people think they need to spend working on it.
Do It in One Weekend? Is That Really Possible?

Yes! We&apos;ve taken all the tedious work out of it and in fact we tell you how you can accomplish the plan writing in as little as a couple of hours.
And we aren&apos;t talking about a low quality plan that won&apos;t get the job done- this is a plan that you can be confident to show to any investot, partner or banker and that will include 100% of everything you need to raise money and launch your concept.
And the restaurant financials are just as
easy . You don&apos;t have to be a &quot;numbers&quot; person- our program does everything, step by step, and makes you a food service financial whiz. 
And once you have the plan, we help you raise the money by providing a whole list of ways to raise the money you need including tapping banks, investors, partners and more, and complete info on how to structure the best deal for yourself by combining the sources into a total funding package.
And we Guarantee our proven plan will raise the money you need, or it won&apos;t cost you a cent! 
And the best part is:
Most people can complete our plan and financials and be ready to start raising money in less than 10 hours. 

There Must Be More to the Restaurant Business Plan Than That!

Sure, to get your plan and your business fully ready you need to do some research and investigating but probably less than you think and we make it very easy by telling you exactly what you need to do and where to go for each bit of information.
It is not hard and it won&apos;t take long.
You&apos;ve probably already spent some time thinking about how you want your restaurant to be, how exciting it will be when you open the doors and the rush of pride and excitement as your first guests get their food and your register rings up those sales turning your dream into tangible profits .
There are some details to work out between here and there of course but we walk you through all of them step by step.
We help you figure out answers to all the important questions you need to think through to complete a solid, fundable plan. Answers to things like:
 How much will the equipment cost ? What about leasing ? What kind of staff do I need? How much is the food going to cost - and what should I charge? What&apos;s the best location ? How much rent can I afford? What will it cost to launch ? How profitable will I be? And tons of others - all made simple and easy to understand and answer! 

The way you get your money to make it all happen is to convince the money sources that you have the answers they&apos;re looking for- and with this package, you will! 
 
What Exactly Do You Get With a Complete Restaurant Business Plan Package?

You get a whole package we call the Restaurant Success Kit , and it includes a ton of stuff...
 Restaurant Business Plan creation tool Restaurant Financials creation software Complete 200+ page Restaurant Owner&apos;s Guide E-book to help answer all your restaurant financing, startup and operations questions


But, those are just the main ingredients, if you will. 

The complete package ( see all the details of our packages here ) also includes many more important materials to help you successfully fund and launch your restaurant:
 Business Plan Writing Guide E-Book Restaurant Financials Creation Guide E-Book Restaurant Plan PowerPoint Presentation pre-formatted slide deck Start up Cost Calculator spreadsheet Funding Calculator spreadsheet Extensive Idea-to-Launch Checklist of things to do Complete Resources Guide - including how to get tons of free information for new restauranteurs SBA forms and Application Guidelines- Integrated with your Financials List of SBA Lenders and business friendly banks Break even Analysis Spreadsheet Application Deal Structure Maximization Calculator spreadsheet Four full color integrated financial graphs Restaurant Ratio Performance Analysis Application Equipment List w/ Expense and Leasing Option Calculator Menu Price and Cost Calculator Application Financing Your Business Guide E-Book And much more! 

This is the most complete , most powerful , most easy to use and best value restaurant business plan and financials package available anywhere.
But of course, we know you have choices, and we are willing to go head to head with any of them...

Smart Shoppers Compare Restaurant Business Plan Options...

You know there are lots of options for doing this and we aren&apos;t the only solution out there. But let&apos;s look at the choices:
There are lots of free templates out there, but most aren&apos;t for restaurants and few of the free options are going to do you much good when they don&apos;t explain how or where to get the info you actually need to complete the plan
There is lots of generic business plan software available but have you ever tried to fit a square peg into a round hole? Doing a restaurant plan, and particularly trying to do accurate restaurant financials on a generic plan template is going to be frustrating at best and a disaster at worst. And these are the numbers you are relying on to get your business funded and profitable!
There are a couple of restaurant specific plans out there, but none match us in support, guarantee, value or proof of knowledge- just check out our 200+ blog posts and counting to see we are living and breathing restaurants every day while some of the other guys haven&apos;t updated their websites in years!
So how do you actually benefit from using our software...
 
How You Get More From Our Restaurant Business Plan

First, the plan you will write is only 12-15 pages on average. Why? That&apos;s all you need to write!
Most other software is aimed at 25, 30 and even 50 page plans - but you don&apos;t need that. No one is going to read it, and certainly there is no requirement that says a plan must be long if it is to get the money.
What really matters is content , and using our plan you will only put in exactly what you need and nothing more. We know what the banks and investors want to see, and we know what goes into a successful plan- and you will, too. In fact, some of it is even already written for you!
Second, you will be told exactly where to find everything you need to put in the plan. There is no guess work, and no mystery about where to find the info you need. You just don&apos;t get this kind of help from any of the other plans out there.
And the financials...

How You Get More From Our Restaurant Financials

You will be amazed at how easy they are to complete, and how fast the process goes. The real benefit to you, however, is that they will help you raise the money .
How can we be so sure? Our financials are designed to produce the most conservative estimates of any program. And to a bank or investor or partner, conservative means realistic, and a realistic business owner is one they can trust to make the deal work out profitably.
In plain language, this means you will get the loan because you will seem less risky than someone who comes in with financials created elsewhere. The financials you create will be based on proven knowledge of the industry, and proven experience in raising money.
The value of the rest of the kit is in the inside secrets you&apos;ll learn...
 
A Complete Restaurant Operations Education

You will learn more from the Operations E-Book than 6 months in the restaurant business will teach you! It alone is worth the cost of the kit as you will learn how to attract customers, how to hire the best workers, how to manage your manager, how to prevent employee theft, how to plan your menu and a ton of other critical lessons in running a profitable, successful restaurant.
You will likewise learn more about getting a loan from our loan info section than from making 10 trips to ten banks. You will learn the inside info on how to make the most of your loan package, and how to get to &quot;yes&quot; with the least amount of effort.
See ALL the manuals and guides we include with our complete package here - it&apos;s like a virtual restaurant owner&apos;s library thrown in free with the software!
Opening a restaurant is a whole process, with many different tasks you must complete- it about learning a whole new business from inside out and in a short amount of time. The best way to do this is to absorb the knowledge of the people who have already been there and learned the hard way- no need to reinvent the wheel! 
By ordering this package you will be very well prepared on all the different challenges you will face- writing a plan, creating the financials, and learning everything you need to know about running your new business. You won&apos;t find this complete set of knowledge and tools anywhere else.
You Get Unlimited Restaurant Business Plan Support

Along with everything else, you also get unlimited support .
And that doesn&apos;t mean some low level customer service person helping you get your download open (although we can help with that, too!).
Our support is from business consultants who know the startup business and know the restaurant industry . If your question is about the software, raising money or anything about starting or running a restaurant business in general- we&apos;ve got the answers you need.
That isn&apos;t something you will find with any other restaurant business plan package anywhere for any price, period.
You are essentially getting an on call restaurant consultant for the cost of a nice dinner out and what amounts to a tiny fraction of what it would cost to hire us for a normal job.
Plus, since we guarantee this will work you are surely wondering what is this guarantee all about ...

 
Our Guarantee to You

If you buy our kit, and put together a plan, and you can&apos;t, for whatever reason, raise any money with it, then send it to us, and we&apos;ll give you a full refund- no hassles, no problem.
Try it for a week. Try it for a month.
 Try it for up to one full YEAR! 
Now, why would you need it for a year if it only takes 10 hours to use? Well, maybe it takes awhile to close the deal. Maybe the right location hasn&apos;t opened up yet. Maybe you&apos;re still just evaluating the idea of opening your own place.
Sometimes these things just take time. That&apos;s why we give you a whole year. Just in case you need it. 
But now you might be wondering...
 
Who Are We Anyway?

Glad you asked. The reason we can put together a program like this is because we&apos;ve been there- for a long time! Our combined experience includes over 30 years in the restaurant business, and over 10 years consulting to startups and helping companies raise money. 
Throw in some technical experience and software design ability, and you have the perfect combination of skills to develop the ultimate package for launching new restaurant owners to success.
That is a long time- and a lot of reputation to stand on- which is why we won&apos;t put out anything less than a great product- and we don&apos;t want your money if you&apos;re not satisfied.
Want some more details of just what we are all about? Check out our About Us page to find out everything you want to know- or just ask us!

Can This Really Work for Me?

Yes, check out a fraction of our testimonials here .
In fact- check out the news here - we hit our 10,000th satisfied customer in December 2010 !
But what about YOUR chances of success ? What about your situation ? Here are the top five questions we get from people like you every day...
 
Top Five Restaurant Business Plan Skeptics Questions Answered

 Q: How can you really guarantee people will get funded? 
A: We know you aren&apos;t stupid. Of course we can&apos;t actually promise you will get money if you use our plan. Many people do but not everyone. What we can promise is this- we WILL give you a refund if you want one. We also promise that if you are serious and you are willing to work for it we will work with you until you make it. Period.
 Q: My credit is not so hot- will this work for me? 
A: Yes. We tell you how you can overcome poor credit. It takes a little more effort, but not much. If you are serious about doing this, bad credit won&apos;t stop it from happening.
 Q: I don&apos;t have any money of my own to put into this. Can I still get a restaurant started? 
A: Money helps, no question. But if you have the desire but not the cash you can still make it work. We give you three very workable alternatives for starting without investing your own money.
 Q: I don&apos;t have any restaurant experience or business experience- can I do this? 
A: This whole package is made for someone with no experience. If you have experience it will definitely help but we cover everything from the very basics on up so no one will have to struggle to follow our plan or use our software.
 Q: This still sounds too good to be true. What&apos;s the catch? 
A: The catch is this will take some work on your part. Your job will be ten times easier with this information, but you are smart enough to know starting a restaurant from the ground up is going to require some work. If you aren&apos;t prepared to put in some effort this isn&apos;t going to happen for you.
More questions? Start in the FAQs , and get some additional insight into what we&apos;re all about.
Still want to know something? Send us an email (info @ restaurantfunds.com) and we will respond personally- usually within a few hours or less.
OK, just want to know what all this is going to cost you?
And This is Going to Cost What?

Currently, the price for the entire contents of our complete restaurant business plan package listed above is just $97.00. 
Or check out our full set of product options here .
But, if you buy our kit, and you use it, and you don&apos;t raise any money, the whole thing is FREE. 
You see, in that case, then we didn&apos;t really do our job, and therefore
 we encourage you to return it to us and get your money back. 
So, bottom line , for $97 you have the best possible chance of getting the cash to open your own restaurant . And if it doesn&apos;t work out, you can have your $97 back.
So what else do you need to know to decide to get started?
 
The Best Way to Decide is By Doing It!

Since there is no risk in ordering our kit- we encourage you to go ahead and see what happens once you get it. You will either raise the money you need and be busy running your new restaurant, or if, for some reason, it doesn&apos;t work out for you- you can return it, and you&apos;ve lost absolutely nothing. 
Still want more? Read all about our restaurant business plan products here or jump right to the order page here to get started right now!

 
 Read More About Our Restaurant Business Plan 
 
More Starting a Restaurant Information:

 
 The Starting a Restaurant Blog 
 
Find hundreds of blog posts on every topic related to starting a restaurant and running it successfully. 
 Restaurant Marketing Blog 
 
All of our restaurant marketing related posts gathered together in one place to help you keep your restaurant packed at all times. 
 Restaurant Articles 
 
Find more of what you want to know about starting and running a restaurant 
 
 Back to Top 
Restaurant Services:

 
 Restaurant Web Design 
 
Every restaurant needs a website, period. See samples, get a quote, learn more, etc. 
 Restaurant Social Media Design 
 
Get yourself on Facebook and Twitter and then keep up a regular conversation with your current customers and attract new customers. 
 Restaurant Logo Design 
 
Get a great looking logo for your restaurant at a great price. Check out different styles, fonts, design ideas, etc. 
 Restaurant Business Plan Review 
 
Have one of your experienced experts look over your plan for holes, gaps and problem areas you can fix before your present it to the money guys. 
 Restaurant Buyer Consulting 
 
Need some help making sense of a restaurant for sale opportunity? Not sure what questions to ask or how to evaluate the books? Let us help. 
 
 Back to Top 
Restaurant Resources- Directories:

 
 Restaurant Equipment Suppliers 
 
Everything from A - Z listed by city and state for the US restaurant equipment suppliers. 
 Restaurant Design and Planning Firms 
 
Find a specialist in your area for designing restaurant interiors from the ground up and for interior build outs. 
 Restaurant Contractors 
 
Locate a contractor who specializes in and thoroughly understands the requirements for building out a restaurant in your area- including permits, codes, etc. 
 Restaurant POS System Buying Guide&amp;Reviews 
 
Your Restaurant POS (Point of Sale) System is a critical piece of technology for running your business by the numbers and making sure you have a good handle of what&apos;s coming in and where it&apos;s going out. 
 Restaurant Hood and Fire Systems Buying Guide 
 
The hood is one of your bigger equipment investments and it also effects your location construction and planning- make sure you get this vital piece of gear right the first time. 
 
 Back to Top 

Copyright 2001- RestaurantFunds.com
	</body>
</document>
