<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009008" url="http://www.westchesterrestaurantguide.com/htm/lnk/Link0182.html" time="2012-07-13-02:24" support="3" score="0.0030419497938195122" bingtitle="Restaurants - Japanese &amp; Sushi - Westchester County" webtitle="Restaurants - Japanese&amp;Sushi - Westchester County">
			<query id="000641" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000635" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="000654" bing-rank="127"/>
	<description>Sushi Condiments The important seasonings are soy sauce ... This is a kind of sushi &quot;fast-food&quot; restaurant in Japan and is ... your favorite sushi comes near you, then you pick ...</description>
	<body>
		Featured

Restaurants

Japanese&amp;Sushi
 
 
     
 
 
 
 
  Mamaroneck Village (Westchester) 
  All Mamaroneck Village Listings   all Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Toyo Sushi &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; 
 914-777-8696  
      Click to read review 
Toyo Sushi, serving traditional Japanese cuisine and sushi, is located at 253 Mamaroneck Avenue in Mamaroneck, NY 10543. Upon entering Toyo Sushi, you are warmly greeted in traditional Japanese fashion &quot;IrasSHAI-maSE&quot; and begin your journey of relaxation and exquisite culinary delight. &quot;Our attentive staff will ensure every aspect of your visit is a pleasure as you experience the finest Japanese cuisine created by talented master chefs Toyomoto Kenji and Oyama Katuya. All seafood is selected at the fish market daily.&quot; Just one bite confirms that Toyo Sushi&apos;s cuisine surpasses even the highest expectation.
 The Westchester Restaurant Guide : &quot;Toyo Sushi provides a gracious and charming atmosphere. The food is very good and our dining experience was excellent. Every detail was addressed, from fresh flowers on each table to food presented with artistry and care. The sushi is fresh and the kitchen entrees are creative as well as delicious. Even the desserts are good at Toyo Sushi.&quot; Press blue button for menus, photos, and Toyo Sushi&apos;s website.

 Restaurant Features 
Open 7 days per week
Take-Out

   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
Restaurants

Japanese&amp;Sushi
 
 
 Select by Name Abis Traditional Japanese Cuisine Akari Sushi&amp;Japanese Azuma Sushi &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Bamboo Gardens Buddha &quot;Hibachi&amp;Suschi&quot; Bull&amp;Buddha East Harbor &quot;Chinese&amp;Japanese&quot; Eden Wok &quot;Kosher Chinese&amp;Sushi&quot; Edo &quot;Sushi Bar&amp;Japanese Steakhouse&quot; Edo Sushi Fuji Mountain Fujinoya Restaurant &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Garden Sushi &quot;Asian&amp;Fusion Sushi Bar&quot; Gasho of Japan &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Haiku Asian Bistro&amp;Sushi Bar - Cross River Haiku Asian Bistro&amp;Sushi Bar - White Plains Hajime &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Hana Japanese Restaurant Hana Market &quot;Sushi Bar&quot; Hana Sushi Hanada Hibachi Hanada Sushi &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Hanako Sushi &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Haru Hana &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Hinode Japanese Restaurant Hokkaido Ichi Riki &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Izumi Japanese Restaurant Japan Inn &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Karuta Sushi &quot;Asian-fusion&quot; Kicho Kiku Sushi &quot;Japanese take-out&quot; Kira Asian Bistro&amp;Sushi Bar - Armonk Kira Asian Bistro&amp;Sushi Bar - Chappaqua Kirari &quot;Sushi and Sashimi&quot; Koo Kumo Japanese Bistro Kyo Sushi &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Made in Asia, Bistro and Sushi Bar Momiji &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Momiji Sushi Steak House&amp;Bar Murasaki Nagoya &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; NEO World Bistro and Sushi Bar Nishi &quot;Japanese&quot; Nuage &quot;French&amp;Japanese&quot; O Asian, formerly Hunan Ritz &quot;Chinese&amp;Japanese&quot; Oishii &quot;Asian Fusion&quot; Okinawa Hibachi Steakhouse Okinawa Japanese Restaurant &quot;Hibachi&amp;Sushi&quot; Osaka Osaka Japanese Restaurant Sakura Garden &quot;Sushi&quot; Samurai &quot;Sushi&amp;Hibachi Steakhouse&quot; Sapporo Japanese Restaurant Sarku Japan at The Galleria &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Sazan Restaurant &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Season&apos;s Japanese Bistro Sun Xing Garden &quot;Chinese&amp;Japanese&quot; Sushi Man Japanese Restaurant Sushi Mike&apos;s &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Sushi Nanase Restaurant &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Sushi Niji Sushi Plus &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Take Sushi Temptation Tea House &quot;Asian-fusion&quot; Tenbo Cuisine Toro, Japanese&amp;Chinese Cuisine&amp;Sushi Bar Toyo Sushi &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Tsuru &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; Tuxedo Sushi Wasabi Wasabi &quot;Japanese Fusion&quot; Wasabi &quot;Japanese and Sushi&quot; Wasabi Restaurant &quot;Sushi&quot; Water Moon &quot;Pan Asian&quot; Yama Fuji Sushi &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; * Featured Japanese&amp;Sushi Select by Location Ardsley Village Armonk Bedford Hills Brewster Briarcliff Manor Village Bronxville Village Carmel Chappaqua Cross River Croton-on-Hudson Village Dobbs Ferry Village Elmsford Village Greenwich Harrison Village Hartsdale Hastings-on-Hudson Village Hawthorne Hudson Irvington Village Larchmont Village Mamaroneck Village Mohegan Lake Mount Kisco Village New Paltz New Rochelle, City of Nyack Ossining Village Pearl River Piermont Pleasantville Village Port Chester Village Poughkeepsie Red Hook Rhinebeck Rye Brook Village Rye, City of Scarsdale Village Sleepy Hollow Village Somers Stone Ridge Thornwood Tivoli Tuckahoe Village Tuxedo White Plains, City of Yonkers, City of Yorktown Heights 
 
 
 
 
  Ardsley Village (Westchester) 
  All Ardsley Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Nishi &quot;Japanese&quot; 
 914-693-2500  
 Nishi Japanese Restaurant is located at 473 Ashford Avenue, Ardsley, NY 10502 in Westchester County.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
  Sazan Restaurant &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot;
 914-674-6015  
      Click to read review 
Sazan Restaurant, serving Japanese food and sushi, is located at 729 Saw Mill River Road, Ardsley NY 10502, Westchester County in the Hudson Valley.
 The word is Terrific appetizers and small plates and you can always expect fresh sushi.
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
  Sushi Man Japanese Restaurant
 914-693-8800  
      Click to read review 
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Armonk (Westchester) 
  All Armonk Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
  Kira Asian Bistro&amp;Sushi Bar - Armonk
 914-765-0800  
 Kira Asian Bistro&amp;Sushi Bar, serving sushi and Traditional Japanese, is located at 575 Main Street, Armonk, NY 10504 in Westchester County.
 The word is Good value for sushi and take out.
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
    Made in Asia, Bistro and Sushi Bar 
 914-730-3663  
      Click to read review 
Made in Asia, an Asian and Japanese Bistro and Sushi Bar, is located at 454 Main Street, in Armonk, Westchester NY 10504; in the Food Emporium Shopping Center off of Main Street.
 The word is Very good food and presentation.
   
 Also in Cuisine 
 Specialties 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Bedford Hills (Westchester) 
  All Bedford Hills Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
  Kicho
 914-666-3332  
      Click to read review 
Kicho, serving sushi and Japanese hot food, is located at 352 North Bedford Road in Bedford Hills, Westchester NY 10507.   
 Also in Feature 
 Outdoor Dining 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Briarcliff Manor Village (Westchester) 
  All Briarcliff Manor Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
  Kiku Sushi &quot;Japanese take-out&quot;
 914-762-4040  
 Kiku Sushi, serving sushi and Japanese food, is located at 1116 Pleasantville Road in Briarcliff Manor, Westchester NY 10510.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
    Yama Fuji Sushi &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; 
 914-941-3100  
      Click to read review 
Yama Fuji Sushi is located in Briarcliff Manor, Westchester County, NY 10510. Press blue button to see menu and more information about Yama Fuji.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Bronxville Village (Westchester) 
  All Bronxville Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
  Japan Inn &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot;
 914-337-1296  
      Click to read review 
Japan Inn, serving sushi, is located at 28 Palmer Avenue, Bronxville NY 10708 in Westchester County.   
 Also in Feature 
 Outdoor Dining 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Chappaqua (Westchester) 
  All Chappaqua Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Kira Asian Bistro&amp;Sushi Bar - Chappaqua 
 914-861-2727  
 Kira Asian Bistro&amp;Sushi Bar is located at 95 King Street #7, Chappaqua, NY 10504 in Westchester County.
 The word is Enjoy fresh and creative sushi at this Chappaqua Sushi and Asian.
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Cross River (Westchester) 
  All Cross River Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Haiku Asian Bistro&amp;Sushi Bar - Cross River 
 914-763-9120  
      Click to read review 
Haiku Asian Bistro&amp;Sushi Bar, serving Pan-Asian&amp;sushi, is located at 1 Cross River Shopping Center, Cross River, NY 10518.   
 Also in Cuisine 
 Chinese Food 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Croton-on-Hudson Village (Westchester) 
  All Croton-on-Hudson Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
  Samurai &quot;Sushi&amp;Hibachi Steakhouse&quot;
 914-271-8988  
      Click to read review 
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Dobbs Ferry Village (Westchester) 
  All Dobbs Ferry Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Sushi Mike&apos;s &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; 
 914-591-0054  
      Click to read review 
   
 Also in Category 
 Activities | Attractions | Places to Go 
 Attractions | Places to Go | Activities 
 Hudson River Towns 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
  Sushi Niji
 914-693-8838  
      Click to read review 
   
 Also in Category 
 Activities | Attractions | Places to Go 
 Attractions | Places to Go | Activities 
 Hudson River Towns 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
  Tenbo Cuisine
 914-674-2138  
      Click to read review 
   
 Also in Category 
 Activities | Attractions | Places to Go 
 Attractions | Places to Go | Activities 
 Hudson River Towns 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Elmsford Village (Westchester) 
  All Elmsford Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
  Bamboo Gardens
 914-593-0555  
 Bamboo Gardens, serving Chinese and Japanese food, is located at 353 East Main Street, Elmsford, NY 10523 in Westchester County.   
 Also in Cuisine 
 Chinese Food 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
    Ichi Riki &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; 
 914-592-2220  
      Click to read review 
Ichi Riki, serving fine Japanese hot food and sushi, is located at 1 East Main Street in Elmsford, Westchester NY 10523.
 The word is Very good sushi and hot food.
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Harrison Village (Westchester) 
  All Harrison Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
  Hajime &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot;
 914-777-1543  
      Click to read review 
Hajime Japanese Restaurant is located at 267 Halstead Avenue, Harrison, NY (across from Harrison Train Station) 10528 in Westchester County.
 The word is &quot;Eat sushi where the Japanese go&quot; at this &quot;expensive, but fabulous sushi restaurant&quot; serving the &quot;best sushi, always fresh and served at room temperature&quot;.
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
    Momiji &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; 
 914-835-1078  
      Click to read review 
Momiji Japanese Restaurant, serving sushi and traditional Japanese food, is located at 261 Halstead Avenue in Harrison, NY 10528 in Westchester County.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Hartsdale (Westchester) 
  All Hartsdale Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
  Azuma Sushi &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot;
 914-725-0660  
      Click to read review 
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
    Fujinoya Restaurant &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; 
 914-428-1203  
 Fujinoya Restaurant, serving fine Sashimi, sushi and cooked dishes, is located at 26 South Central Ave Hartsdale, NY 10530.
 The word is Fujinoy is a small restaurant offering &quot;amazing food&quot; and warm friendly service. The incredibly fresh sushi is great&quot; prepared by seasoned sushi chefs. The &quot;hot foods are equally delicious&quot;. Don&apos;t miss dining at this fabulous new restaurant, also offering very reasonable prices; and fine House Sake
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
    Kyo Sushi &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; 
 914-682-6688  
      Click to read review 
Kyo Sushi, serving Traditional Japanese food and sushi, is located at 17 East Hartsdale Avenue, Hartsdale, NY 10530 in Westchester County.
 The word is &quot;The sushi is incredibly fresh&quot; and served by the &quot;most gracious wait staff&quot; at &quot;very reasonable prices&quot;. &quot;We have become regulars&quot; at this fabulous sushi restaurant in Hartsdale.
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
    Tsuru &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; 
 914-761-0057  
      Click to read review 
Tsuru Japanese Restaurant&amp;Sushi Bar, serving both traditional Japanese cuisine and sushi, is located at 259 N. Central Avenue (Marshall Shopping Centre), Hartsdale NY 10530, Westchester County.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Hastings-on-Hudson Village (Westchester) 
  All Hastings-on-Hudson Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Sakura Garden &quot;Sushi&quot; 
 914-478-1978  
      Click to read review 
Sakura Garden, serving sushi and kitchen hibachi dishes, is located at 531 Warburton Avenue, Hastings-on-Hudson 10706 in Westchester County.
 The word is Enthusiastic accolades about this Japanese and sushi restaurant serving &quot;extremely fresh sushi&quot; and &quot;excellent cooked dishes&quot; in a &quot;relaxing comfortable&quot; atmosphere. Sakura is &quot;one of the best Japanese restaurants&quot;.
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Hawthorne (Westchester) 
  All Hawthorne Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Gasho of Japan &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; 
 914-592-5900  
      Click to read review 
Gasho Hibachi Steakhouse is located at 2 Saw Mill River Road, Hawthorne, NY 10532.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Irvington Village (Westchester) 
  All Irvington Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Haru Hana &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; 
 914-479-1688  
 Haru Hana, serving Japanese food, is located at 35 Main Street, Irvington, Westchester NY 10533.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Larchmont Village (Westchester) 
  All Larchmont Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
  Fuji Mountain
 914-833-3838  
      Click to read review 
Fuji Mountain, a Japanese Steakhouse also serving sushi, is located at 2375 Boston Post Road, Larchmont, NY 10538.
 The word is Fun for the kids, also serving good sushi.
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
  Wasabi &quot;Japanese Fusion&quot;
 914-834-2833  
 Wasabi, a Japanese fusion restaurant, serving sushi and Pan Asian dishes, is located at 158 Larchmont Avenue in Larchmont, Westchester NY 10538.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Mamaroneck Village (Westchester) 
  All Mamaroneck Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Toyo Sushi &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; 
 914-777-8696  
      Click to read review 
Toyo Sushi, serving traditional Japanese cuisine and sushi, is located at 253 Mamaroneck Avenue in Mamaroneck, NY 10543. Upon entering Toyo Sushi, you are warmly greeted in traditional Japanese fashion &quot;IrasSHAI-maSE&quot; and begin your journey of relaxation and exquisite culinary delight. &quot;Our attentive staff will ensure every aspect of your visit is a pleasure as you experience the finest Japanese cuisine created by talented master chefs Toyomoto Kenji and Oyama Katuya. All seafood is selected at the fish market daily.&quot; Just one bite confirms that Toyo Sushi&apos;s cuisine surpasses even the highest expectation.
 The Westchester Restaurant Guide : &quot;Toyo Sushi provides a gracious and charming atmosphere. The food is very good and our dining experience was excellent. Every detail was addressed, from fresh flowers on each table to food presented with artistry and care. The sushi is fresh and the kitchen entrees are creative as well as delicious. Even the desserts are good at Toyo Sushi.&quot; Press blue button for menus, photos, and Toyo Sushi&apos;s website.

 Restaurant Features 
Open 7 days per week
Take-Out

   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Mohegan Lake (Westchester) 
  All Mohegan Lake Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Hanada Hibachi 
 914-526-3370  
      Click to read review 
Hanada Hibachi, serving Japanese and Hibachi, is located at 1889 East main Street, Mohegan Lake, NY in Westchester County.
 The word is Fun and entertaining for the kids.
   
 Also in Cuisine 
 Specialties 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Mount Kisco Village (Westchester) 
  All Mount Kisco Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    NEO World Bistro and Sushi Bar 
 914-244-9711  
      Click to read review 
Neo World Bistro, &quot;serving cuisines from around the world&quot;, is located at 69 South Moger Avenue in Mount Kisco, New York 10549 in Westchester County. &quot;NEO is not a cookie-cutter Asian-fusion restaurant. Its vision stretches far beyond Asia.&quot; by M.H. Reed, New York Times.
 The word is Rave reviews are pouring in for this &quot;food from around the world&quot; restaurant in Mount Kisco.
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
    Oishii &quot;Asian Fusion&quot; 
 914-666-2348  
      Click to read review 
Oishii Japanese Restaurant, serving sushi and traditional Japanese food, is located at 176 North Bedford Road in Mount Kisco, NY 10549 in Westchester County.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
  Okinawa Japanese Restaurant &quot;Hibachi&amp;Sushi&quot;
 914-666-8188  
      Click to read review 
Okinawa Japanese Restaurant, serving sushi and Hibachi, is located at 39 South Moger Avenue, Mount Kisco, NY 10549 in Westchester County.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
  Temptation Tea House &quot;Asian-fusion&quot;
 914-666-8808  
      Click to read review 
Temptation Tea House is located at 11A South Moger Avenue, Mount Kisco, NY. Temptation Tea Room has the decor of a large Chinese tearoom, serving Asian-fusion cuisine. Temptations serves over 100 different teas - mostly from China and Taiwan. For the many people searching for a good green tea - you will find it at Temptation.   
 Also in Cuisine 
 Caf, Coffee Shops&amp;Tea 

 Also in Feature 
 Outdoor Dining 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  New Rochelle, City of (Westchester) 
  All New Rochelle Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Eden Wok &quot;Kosher Chinese&amp;Sushi&quot; 
 914-637-9363  
 Eden Wok, serving Kosher Chinese and sushi, is located at 1327 North Avenue, New Rochelle, NY 10804. &quot;Our menu combines Far East standards with sushi, sashimi and even a number of Pacific fusion and American grill selections - at a family friendly price.

 Press blue button for menus and more about Eden Wok, Kosher Chinese food.


 Restaurant Features 
Kosher Chinese and Kosher sushi


 The word is New Rochelle&apos;s Eden Wok is under strict Kashruth Supervision of Vaad of Westchester.
   
 Also in Cuisine 
 Chinese Food 
 Kosher Food 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
  Karuta Sushi &quot;Asian-fusion&quot;
 914-636-6688  
      Click to read review 
Karuta Sushi, serving sushi and Japanese hot food, is located at 77 Quaker Ridge Road in New Rochelle, NY 10804 in Westchester County.
 The word is The locals love the fresh sushi and sashimi.
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Ossining Village (Westchester) 
  All Ossining Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Okinawa Hibachi Steakhouse 
 914-762-9888  
      Click to read review 
Okinawa Hibachi Steakhouse, a Japanese steakhouse also serving sushi, is located at 218 South Highland Avenue, Ossining NY 10562, in one of the River Towns of Westchester County.
 Restaurant Features 
Hibachi
Noise level = loud


 The word is If you&apos;re going for the Hibachi, enjoy a fun experience in a &quot;gorgeous space&quot; (if you like Las Vegas), offering excellent service and good food; be sure to bring the kids. If sushi is your choice, &quot;it&apos;s the best sushi in Northern Westchester&quot;.
   
 Also in Location 
 Ossining 

 Also in Cuisine 
 Steak&amp;Seafood 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Pleasantville Village (Westchester) 
  All Pleasantville Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Hanada Sushi &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; 
 914-769-0638  
      Click to read review 
Hanada Sushi, serving sushi and cooked Japanese dishes, is located at 8 Pleasantville Road in Pleasantville, Westchester NY 10570.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Port Chester Village (Westchester) 
  All Port Chester Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Edo &quot;Sushi Bar&amp;Japanese Steakhouse&quot; 
 914-937-3333  
      Click to read review 
Edo Japanese Steakhouse and Sushi is located at 140 Midland Avenue, Port Chester, NY 10573 in Westchester County.
 Restaurant Features 
Hibachi Chefs
Sushi also served


 The word is Rave reviews for Edo in Port Chester, where Hibachi-style chefs make your evening fun&amp;exciting as they cook your meal right in front of you - don&apos;t forget to bring the kids.   
 Also in Cuisine 
 Steak&amp;Seafood 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Rye Brook Village (Westchester) 
  All Rye Brook Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
  Buddha &quot;Hibachi&amp;Suschi&quot;
 914-481-4651  
 Buddha, an Asian restaurant serving Asian fusion, hibachi-dining, and sushi bar, is located in Rye Ridge Shopping Center at 142 South Ridge Street, Rye Brook, NY 10573 in Westchester County.
 The word is As of July 2011 - new restaurant in Rye Brook.
   
 Also in Cuisine 
 Asian - Pan Asian&amp;Asian Fusion 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Rye, City of (Westchester) 
  All Rye Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Koo 
 914-921-9888  
      Click to read review 
Koo, serving neo-Japanese cuisine, and sushi, is located at 17 Purdy Avenue, Rye, NY 10580 in Westchester County.
 The word is Most agree that they &quot;love going to Koo where the sushi is amazing&quot;, although a bit pricey.
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
    Water Moon &quot;Pan Asian&quot; 
 914-921-8880  
      Click to read review 
Water Moon is located at 66 Purchase Street, Rye, NY 10580 in Westchester County. Water Moon restaurant is an East meets West, Manhattan styled, Pan-Asian infusion of taste and creativity.
 The word is &quot;No wonder Water Moon is always packed, with reasonable prices, delicious dishes and service comes with a smile.&quot; Although the food is great &quot;you need ear plugs&quot; because of the high noise level.
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Scarsdale Village (Westchester) 
  All Scarsdale Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
  Hana Market &quot;Sushi Bar&quot;
 914-713-7292  
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
    Kirari &quot;Sushi and Sashimi&quot; 
 914-725-3730  
 Kirari Sushi Restaurant, serving sushi, sashimi, and traditional Japanese entrees, is located at 30 Garth Road, Scarsdale, NY 10583 near the train station. Kirari serves a wonderful selection of fresh sushi and hot Japanese dishes. Free delivery.
 The word is Good sushi.
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
  Sushi Plus &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot;
 914-723-9090  
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Sleepy Hollow Village (Westchester) 
  All Sleepy Hollow Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
  Wasabi Restaurant &quot;Sushi&quot;
 914-332-7788  
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Somers (Westchester) 
  All Somers Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
  Hana Japanese Restaurant
 914-277-0894  
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Thornwood (Westchester) 
  All Thornwood Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Abis Traditional Japanese Cuisine 
 914-741-5100  
 Abis Traditional Japanese cuisine is located at 14 Marble Avenue in Thornwood, NY 10594. Abis offers sushi, Sashimi, Hibachi and traditional Japanese cuisine.   
 Also in Feature 
 Sunday Brunch 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
    O Asian, formerly Hunan Ritz &quot;Chinese&amp;Japanese&quot; 
 914-747-0701  
      Click to read review 
O Asian, (formerly Hunan Ritz) serving Chinese and Japanese food, is located in the Rose Hill Shopping Center, 636 Columbus Avenue, Thornwood, NY 10594 in Westchester County.   
 Also in Cuisine 
 Chinese Food 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Tuckahoe Village (Westchester) 
  All Tuckahoe Village Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Garden Sushi &quot;Asian&amp;Fusion Sushi Bar&quot; 
 914-361-1386  
 Garden Sushi, serving Japanese and Asian Fusion, is located at 29 Columbus Avenue in Tuckahoe NY 10707, Westchester County.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  White Plains, City of (Westchester) 
  All White Plains Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Haiku Asian Bistro&amp;Sushi Bar - White Plains 
 914-644-8887  
      Click to read review 
Haiku Asian Bistro, a Pan-Asian restaurant,provides a modern take on classic Asian dishes representative of China, Thailand, Japan, Malaysia&amp;elsewhere in the East&amp;South Asia. Haiku Asian is located at 149 Mamaroneck Avenue, White Plains, New York. 10601.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
    Sarku Japan at The Galleria &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot; 
 914-683-8873  
 Sarku Japan, serving Japanese cuisine, is located at 100 Main Street, White Plains, NY 10601 at the Galleria shopping mall. Sarku serves Japanese food including rice bowls, noodle bowls and sushi rolls.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
  Season&apos;s Japanese Bistro
 914-421-1163  
      Click to read review 
Season&apos;s Japanese Bistro is located at 105 Mamaroneck Avenue, White Plains, NY 10601. &quot;Chef and Owner, Qi Ma aims to please. Always expect fresh, Manhattan quality sushi.&quot; Zagat 2004   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
  Sushi Nanase Restaurant &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot;
 914-285-5351  
      Click to read review 
Sushi Nanase, serving Japanese food, is located at 522 Mamaroneck Avenue, White Plains NY 10602.
 The word is Super fresh incredibly good sushi. However, don&apos;t arrive late for your reservation. 
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
  Take Sushi
 914-761-3440  
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Yonkers, City of (Westchester) 
  All Yonkers Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    East Harbor &quot;Chinese&amp;Japanese&quot; 
 914-961-0100  
      Click to read review 
East Harbor, serving Chinese food and sushi with a selection of Vegetarian dishes, is located at 1560 Central Park Avenue, Yonkers, New York 10710.
 The word is Great sushi and the Chinese take-out is the best!
   
 Also in Cuisine 
 Chinese Food 
 Vegetarian Food 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
  Nagoya &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot;
 914-771-8889  
      Click to read review 
Nagoya Japanese Restaurant, serving sushi and traditional Japanese food, is located at 1771 Central Park Avenue, Yonkers, NY 10710 in Westchester County.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
  Sun Xing Garden &quot;Chinese&amp;Japanese&quot;
 914-237-8161  
 Sun Xing Garden, serving Chinese&amp;Japanese food, is located at 1288 Midland Avenue, Yonkers, NY 10704 in Westchester County.
 The word is Most agree that this tiny restaurant makes some of the &quot;best Chinese and Japanese in Lower Westchester&quot;, but do takeout.
   
 Also in Cuisine 
 Chinese Food 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Yorktown Heights (Westchester) 
  All Yorktown Heights Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
  Hanako Sushi &quot;Japanese&amp;Sushi&quot;
 914-245-9016  
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
  Okinawa Japanese Restaurant &quot;Hibachi&amp;Sushi&quot;
 914-962-8188  
 Okinawa Japanese Restaurant, serving sushi and Hibachi, is located at 48 Triangle Center, Yorktown Heights, NY 10598 in Westchester County.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Hudson (Columbia) 
  All Hudson Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Wasabi 
 518-822-1888  
 Wasabi, serving Japanese cuisine, is located at 807 Warren Street, Hudson, NY 12534, Columbia County, in the upper-Hudson Valley.
 The word is Delicious food at reasonable prices at this cute Japanese on Warren Street. &quot;Everything we had was excellent&quot;, the &quot;food was great and the fish is fresh&quot;. Wasabi also offers a &quot;good selection of hot dishes&quot;.
   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Poughkeepsie (Dutchess) 
  All Poughkeepsie Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Akari Sushi&amp;Japanese 
 845-471-1773  
 Akari Sushi&amp;Japanese Food is located at 35 Main Street, Poughkeepsie NY 12601, in one of the River Towns of the Hudson Valley.
 Restaurant Features 
BYO
Outdoor Dining


 The word is This small and quaint restaurant is &quot;a local favorite among Culinary Institute of America students&quot;. Locals agree that Akari is absolutely the best sushi restaurant in our area&quot;; Akari is &quot;amazing&quot; serving &quot;incredibly fresh fish&quot;, all offered at a &quot;good value.
   
 Also in Feature 
 Outdoor Dining 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
    Bull&amp;Buddha 
 845-337-4848  
 Bull and Buddha, serving Asian Fusion cuisine, is located at 319 Main Street, Poughkeepsie, NY 12601, Dutchess County in the mid-Hudson Valley. The restaurant is located in a newly restored building in the heart of Poughkeepsie&apos;s revitalized Main Street.
 Restaurant Features 
Night life
Outdoor Dining


 The word is The decor is attractive and chic with a great bar and cozy booth seating; the food and service need to improve, especially the service, but you can go for the great night life scene in Poughkeepsie.
   
 Also in Cuisine 
 Asian - Pan Asian&amp;Asian Fusion 

 Also in Feature 
 Outdoor Dining 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Red Hook (Dutchess) 
  All Red Hook Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Hana Sushi 
 845-758-4333  
 Hana Sushi, serving Traditional Japanese food and sushi, is located at 7270 South Broadway, Red Hook NY 12571, Dutchess County in the Hudson Valley.   
 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants 
 
 
 
 
 
  Rhinebeck (Dutchess) 
  All Rhinebeck Listings   featured Japanese&amp;Sushi   
 
 
 
    Edo Sushi 
 845-835-8402  
 Edo Sushi, serving Traditional Japanese food and sushi, is located at 1094 Route 308, Rhinebeck, NY 12572 in Dutchess County.
 The word is Locals say Edo is the best sushi in the area, serving &quot;excellent super fresh sushi and sashimi&quot; and the &quot;Edo Roll is delicious&quot;.
   
 Also in Location 
 Hyde Park 

 Also in Category 
 Hudson Valley - Restaurants
	</body>
</document>
