<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009467" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20080831083205AA5JEA4" time="2012-07-13-02:50" support="2" score="0.002342125485166933" bingtitle="When it comes to take-out , what is best choice if someone is on a ..." webtitle="When it comes to take-out , what is best choice if someone is on a diet? are noodles like better than pizza..? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="000644" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000440" bing-rank="190"/>
	<description>Cars &amp; Transportation; Computers &amp; Internet ... I wouldn&apos;t pick noodle because they are starch ... is even better. Get a salad at your fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Health &gt; Diet&amp;Fitness &gt; Resolved Question 
 Jonathan S Member since: August 30, 2008 Total points: 311 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
When it comes to take-out , what is best choice if someone is on a diet? are noodles like better than pizza..?
 hamburger etc? 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Addicted to Diet Coke Member since: June 15, 2006 Total points: 10,302 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 rice or vegetable dishes are good. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 100% 1 Vote 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (5)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by complica... Member since: May 02, 2008 Total points: 6,988 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 The best choice is to get a thin and crispy crust, with your choice of meat and tons of veggies.

For example&quot;Can I have a medium thin crust, ham and veggie lover pizza&quot;

that is great because there isn&apos;t ton&apos;s of fats (meats) but still protein, not tons of breads but some, and then lots of veggies. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by jewelz14... Member since: July 10, 2008 Total points: 2,117 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 take out noodles are a no no because they are made with lots of oil, and takeout pizza has a very thick crust, and lots of grease, the burger without the bun would be healthy, and make sure to skip fatty condiments like mayo and use mustard, also salads with grilled chicken are healthy, hope that helps 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by ♥Casey♥ Member since: August 05, 2007 Total points: 2,247 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I wouldn&apos;t pick noodle because they are starch and oily. Pizza is okay, but it has lots of grease, if you pick pizza, eat only 1 or 2 slices and save the rest for later. The hamburger is healthy because it is made with beef and beef is good source of protein. I&apos;d pick the burger. :) 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Jenny Member since: August 31, 2008 Total points: 394 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Take out food is notoriously high in bad saturated fat and sugar - both of which will mess up a diet.

My advice: avoid take out food. It&apos;s all refined processed junk anyway, unbelievably unhealthy.

 http://www.scrumptiouslyrealnutrition.co… 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by recycle b Member since: August 10, 2008 Total points: 23,404 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Noodles are high in Carbs- a little portion of protein such as hamburger is even better. Get a salad at your fast food restaurant. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 
Discover Questions in Diet&amp;Fitness 

 Hey i was wondering what can i do to get a flat belly in 1 week? I need help building tone muscles, please help? How could I eat healthier? Please all help is needed? How can I stay motivated to able lose weight? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Health 
 Alternative Medicine Dental Diet&amp;Fitness Diseases&amp;Conditions General Health Care Men&apos;s Health Mental Health Optical Other - Health Women&apos;s Health 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
