<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009214" url="http://www.freshpatents.com/Paper-cutting-device-and-printer-dt20070201ptan20070022858.php" time="2012-07-13-02:36" support="1" score="0.0008617221103509689" bingtitle="Paper Cutting Device And Printer - Freshpatents.com: Patent ..." webtitle="Paper Cutting Device And Printer">
			<query id="000804" bing-rank="175"/>
	<description>... the printer is used for printing receipts and is installed on a low shelf below the counter in a fast food restaurant ... closing the operable cover unit places ...</description>
	<body>
		Free Services  
 MONITOR KEYWORDS 
Enter keywords&amp;we&apos;ll notify you when a new patent matches your request (weekly update).
 ORGANIZER 
Save&amp;organize patents so you can view them later.
 CUSTOM RSS 
Create custom RSS feeds. Track keywords without receiving email.
 ARCHIVE 
View the last few months of your Keyword emails.
 POPULAR PATENTS 
Most popular patents recently. Top 40.
 COMPANY PATENTS 
Patents sorted by company.

 
 
   Info     Monitor Keywords     Archive     Organizer     Account  |   Prev - Next 
   SEARCH FreshPatents:       Monitor Keywords  |  Custom RSS 

Paper cutting device and printer 
 

 Abstract: A paper cutting device comprising a fixed blade, a movable blade, a movable blade drive mechanism for moving the movable blade, wherein the movable blade and the fixed blade are disposed in substantially perpendicular positions. ...

 Agent: Edwards&amp;Angell, LLP - Boston, MA, US
 Inventors: Motoyoshi Shirotori , Hironori Maekawa 
 USPTO Applicaton #: #20070022858 - Class: 083624000 (USPTO)

 


The Patent Description&amp;Claims data below is from USPTO Patent Application 20070022858, Paper cutting device and printer.

   
 


BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION

[0001] 1. Field of Technology

[0002] The present invention relates to a paper cutting device for cutting
 printed recording paper, and to a printer in which this paper cutting
 device is incorporated.

[0003] 2. Description of Related Art

[0004] Printers that print to a long tape of recording paper wound into a
 roll on a core (that is, roll paper) commonly have a paper cutting device
 disposed near the paper exit for cutting the paper to a certain length
 after the paper is printed. One type of such paper cutting device is a
 scissors-like device comprising a fixed blade and a movable blade.
 Japanese Unexamined Patent Appl. Pub. H8-309689 teaches a scissor-type
 paper cutting device, and Japanese Unexamined Patent Appl. Pub. H9-254474
 teaches a printer comprising a scissor-type paper cutting device.

[0005] The paper cutting device of the printer taught in Japanese
 Unexamined Patent Appl. Pub. H9-254474 has the fixed blade mounted on an
 operable cover that opens and closes the storage compartment where the
 roll paper is held, and disposes the movable blade on the printer chassis
 side. When the operable cover opens, the fixed blade separates from the
 movable blade and thus opens the paper path from the roll paper
 compartment past the printing position and paper cutting position to the
 paper exit. As a result, the roll paper can be easily replaced. When the
 operable cover then closes, the movable blade and fixed blade are
 positioned so that the paper can be cut.

[0006] In a scissor-type paper cutting device the fixed blade and movable
 blade are disposed in opposing positions either vertically or
 longitudinally (in the front-to-back direction) to the printer, and are
 supported so that the cutting edges touch at a point. The movable blade
 is driven to pivot from the side of the paper at which cutting starts,
 and the paper is cut at the position of the paper between the blades by
 gradually moving the point of contact between the two blades from the
 paper edge where cutting starts (the side where the movable blade pivots)
 to the edge where cutting ends (the distal end of the blade).

SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION

Problem to be Solved

[0007] The fixed blade and movable blade are both substantially flat
 knives. A scissor-type paper cutting device cuts by driving these knives
 to intersect while overlapping through the thickness of the blades like
 regular scissors. As a result, a scissor-type paper cutting device must
 have enough space to house both of these blades in either the vertical or
 the longitudinal direction of the printer, that is, the direction in
 which the fixed blade and movable blade oppose each other. Space is also
 needed for the movable blade to pivot in either the vertical or the
 longitudinal direction of the printer. This space must be provided in
 either the vertical or longitudinal direction of the printer, and
 therefore limits where the paper cutting device can be located in the
 printer. As a result, there is limited freedom positioning a scissor-type
 paper cutting device in the printer, and increasing the size of the
 printer is unavoidable.

[0008] More particularly, if the paper exit faces the front or the back at
 the top of the printer, the printed paper will be discharged from the
 front or the back. The fixed blade and movable blade must therefore be
 disposed in opposition vertically to the paper exit in order to cut the
 paper, and incorporating this type of paper cutting device increases the
 height of the printer.

[0009] When the printer is used for printing receipts and is installed on
 a low shelf below the counter in a fast food restaurant, for example, the
 printer must be short. In addition, the paper exit must be disposed
 facing forward at the top part of the printer so that the operator can
 easily remove the printed paper from the front of the printer. Satisfying
 these needs is not possible by using of the prior art, however.

[0010] An object of the present invention is therefore to provide a
 scissor-type paper cutting device that is compact and affords freedom in
 positioning the paper cutting device.

[0011] A further object of the invention is to provide a printer in which
 a scissor-type paper cutting device is incorporated without increasing
 the printer dimensions.

[0012] To achieve these objects, a paper cutting device according to the
 present invention comprises a fixed blade, a movable blade, and a movable
 blade drive mechanism for moving the movable blade, and the movable blade
 and the fixed blade are disposed in substantially perpendicular
 positions.

[0013] By placing the fixed blade and movable blade substantially
 perpendicularly, one blade can be disposed substantially horizontally and
 the other can be disposed substantially vertically. Compared with a
 conventional arrangement in which both blades are disposed in parallel
 planes, i.e., in opposition vertically or longitudinally (that is, in the
 front-to-back direction), there is greater freedom in positioning the
 blades. More specifically, the blades can be easily located without
 wasting space when both blades are assembled into a printer. A compact,
 space-efficient paper cutting device can therefore be provided.

[0014] In this paper cutting device the movable blade and the fixed blade
 touch at the end where paper cutting starts; and the movable blade drive
 mechanism causes the movable blade to pivot on the end portion at the
 side where paper cutting starts so that the contact position between the
 fixed blade and the movable blade moves from the end where paper cutting
 starts to the end where paper cutting ends.

[0015] In a conventional scissor-type paper cutting device the fixed blade
 and movable blade are disposed side by side overlapping in opposition
 through the thickness of the blades like a pair of scissors, and touch at
 a point on the end where cutting starts. When cutting paper, the point of
 contact between the blades moves from the end where cutting starts to the
 end where cutting ends. In order to cut reliably with this arrangement,
 the fixed blade and movable blade must contact at a point. To achieve
 this, both blades must have a slight curvature overall in order to easily
 assure contact at a point. This is the same with regular scissors.

[0016] This invention, however, pushes both blades together from
 substantially perpendicular directions to contact at a point. As a
 result, a flat fixed blade and a flat movable blade can be used and made
 to contact at a point at a suitable contact angle to cut the paper. The
 manufacturing cost can therefore be reduced because a step to impart
 curvature to both blades is not needed. Precise positioning is also not
 needed when assembling the blades, and the manufacturing cost can
 therefore be reduced and the manufacturing quality can be improved.

[0017] Further preferably, the fixed blade can move substantially
 perpendicularly to the movable blade, and is urged by an urging member
 toward the movable blade. When the movable blade pivots to contact the
 fixed blade at a point and the fixed blade is completely stationary, the
 movable blade may strike and bite into the fixed blade as a result of
 assembly deviations and change over time. This damages both blades, can
 result in the movable blade locking, and may result in damage to the
 paper cutting device. To avoid this in the prior art, the shape of the
 blades must be produced with high precision and the movable blade drive
 mechanism must drive the movable blade with high precision in order to
 prevent such problems due to error and aging. When the blades start to
 collide in the present invention, however, the fixed blade moves
 substantially perpendicularly to the movable blade and can retract while
 being returned to the original position by the urging member. The blades
 can thus be easily prevented from biting, and a smooth paper cutting
 action can be assured. High precision is also not needed in the movement
 of both blades, and the manufacturing cost can therefore be reduced.

[0018] Yet further preferably, the urging position where the urging member
 applies force to the fixed blade is offset to a position outside of the
 end-of-cutting end of the fixed blade. If the urging position of the
 fixed blade is located between the end where paper cutting starts and the
 end where paper cutting ends, the paper cutting position of the blades
 (where the blades contact) shifts from before to after the urging
 position as the movable blade pivots in contact with the fixed blade, and
 the angular moment of contact with the fixed blade reverses around the
 urging position in a seesaw motion. The angular moment of the movable
 blade to the fixed blade therefore reverses as the paper cutting position
 passes the urging position, the fixed blade therefore pivots slightly and
 rocks, and the cutting line shifts. In at least one embodiment of the
 present invention, however, the direction of the angular moment does not
 change, this problem therefore does not occur, and the recording paper
 can be cut in a clean line without interruption.

[0019] A printer having a paper cutting device according to this invention
 has an operable cover unit attached openably and closeably to the
 printer; and a paper cutting device comprising a fixed blade affixed on
 the printer chassis side, a movable blade disposed to the operable cover
 unit side, and a movable blade drive mechanism disposed to the operable
 cover unit side. The paper cutting device has a fixed blade, a movable
 blade, and a movable blade drive mechanism for moving the movable blade,
 with the movable blade and the fixed blade disposed in substantially
 perpendicular positions.

[0020] In the printer according to the present invention the movable blade
 and the fixed blade touch at the end where paper cutting starts; and the
 movable blade drive mechanism causes the movable blade to pivot on the
 end portion at the side where paper cutting starts so that the contact
 position between the fixed blade and the movable blade moves from the end
 where paper cutting starts to the end where paper cutting ends.

[0021] A printer according to another embodiment of the invention has an
 operable cover unit attached openably and closeably to the printer; and a
 paper cutting device comprising a movable blade disposed on the printer
 chassis side, a fixed blade affixed on the operable cover unit side, and
 a movable blade drive mechanism disposed to the printer chassis side. The
 paper cutting device has a fixed blade, a movable blade, and a movable
 blade drive mechanism for moving the movable blade, with the movable
 blade and the fixed blade disposed in substantially perpendicular
 positions.

[0022] A paper cutting device having a fixed blade and a movable blade
 disposed substantially perpendicularly to each other is assembled in the
 printer according to the present invention. Compared with a paper cutting
 device having the blades disposed opposite each other, the paper cutting
 device of this invention affords greater freedom positioning the blades.
 The blades can therefore be located without wasting space when assembled
 in the printer, thus affording a small printer. A printer comprising a
 paper cutting device according to the present invention therefore
 requires less installation space, and can therefore be installed where
 space is limited.

[0023] In a printer according to the present invention the fixed blade is
 disposed to either the operable cover unit side or the printer chassis
 side, and the movable blade and movable blade drive mechanism are
 disposed to the other side. As a result, opening the operable cover unit
 opens the path from the roll paper compartment past the printing position
 and paper cutting position to the paper exit. The roll paper can
 therefore be easily replaced. Furthermore, closing the operable cover
 unit places the movable blade and fixed blade at positions where the
 recording paper can be cut.

[0024] The operable cover unit of a printer according to the present
 invention can pivot on a bottom end part of the operable cover unit from
 a closed position where the operable cover unit is substantially vertical
 to an open position where the operable cover unit is open a predetermined
 angle to the front or to the back of the printer. The movable blade of
 the paper cutting device is disposed substantially vertically extending
 widthwise to the printer at a top end portion of the operable cover unit
 with the cutting edge facing up, and the fixed blade of the paper cutting
 device is disposed substantially horizontally extending widthwise to the
 printer at a top end portion on the printer chassis side opposite the top
 end portion of the operable cover unit.

[0025] Because the paper cutting device requires less space vertically,
 increase in the height of the printer resulting from incorporating the
 paper cutting device of the present invention can be suppressed and a
 shorter printer can therefore be provided than with the prior art.
 Furthermore, the paper exit can be located at the top part of the printer
 so that the paper can be removed from either the front or the back.

[0026] Yet further preferably, the fixed blade can move in a direction
 substantially perpendicular to the movable blade, and is urged by an
 urging member toward the movable blade.

[0027] The urging position where the urging member applies force to the
 fixed blade is offset to outside of the end-of-cutting end of the fixed
 blade.

[0028] Yet further preferably, the printer also has a fixed blade
 retraction mechanism for retracting the fixed blade in a direction away
 from the movable blade (toward the inside of the printer) in resistance
 to the urging force of the urging member in conjunction with opening the
 operable cover unit.

[0029] When the operable cover unit is opened in a conventional
 arrangement the fixed blade attached to the top part of the printer
 chassis is exposed. By retracting the fixed blade by means of the fixed
 blade retraction mechanism, the exposed fixed blade can be moved away
 from contact with the user&apos;s fingers.

[0030] A printer according to the present invention can also use an
 arrangement having a fixed blade mounting plate to which the fixed blade
 is attached, and a pivot plate for supporting the fixed blade mounting
 plate. The pivot plate is attached to the printer chassis pivotably in
 the front-to-back direction of the printer around a bottom end portion of
 the pivot plate, the fixed blade mounting plate is attached at a top
 portion of the printer rockably in a direction substantially
 perpendicular to the movable blade, the urging member urges the fixed
 blade mounting plate, and the fixed blade retraction mechanism comprises
 an engaging portion affixed to the operable cover unit and an engaged
 portion attached to the pivot plate rendered so that opening the operable
 cover unit causes the engaging portion to push the engaged portion, thus
 causing the pivot plate to unconditionally pivot so that the fixed blade
 mounting plate attached to a top portion of the pivot plate moves in a
 direction away from the movable blade.

[0031] Opening the operable cover unit thus causes the fixed blade to
 retract automatically.

[0032] A scissor-type paper cutting device according to at least one
 embodiment of the present invention disposes the fixed blade and movable
 blade substantially perpendicularly to each other so that the cutting
 edges meet perpendicularly. Compared with a conventional scissor-type
 paper cutting device in which both blades are disposed in opposition
 vertically or the front-to-back direction of the printer and the blades
 overlap in the thickness direction like regular scissors, there is
 greater freedom positioning the blades and the paper cutting device can
 be rendered compactly without wasting space.

[0033] Furthermore, because the blades contact substantially
 perpendicularly, the blades can be disposed to contact at a point with a
 suitable contact angle without imparting a curve to the fixed blade and
 movable blade. Both blades can therefore be easily manufactured, the
 manufacturing cost can be reduced, and manufacturing quality can be
 improved.

[0034] Because the blades can be positioned with a great degree of freedom
 when assembling this paper cutting device in a printer according to the
 present invention, the paper cutting device can be rendered efficiently
 without wasting installation space, and increase in the printer size
 resulting from incorporating a paper cutting device can be suppressed,
 thus affording a small printer.

[0035] Furthermore, because the fixed blade and movable blade contact from
 substantially perpendicular directions instead of causing the edges to
 overlap through the thickness direction as in regular scissors, the
 blades will not cross, which would prevent the operable cover unit from
 being opened if the movable blade stops while cutting the paper. The
 blades can therefore be easily disposed so that the operable cover unit
 can still be opened even when the movable blade stops while cutting the
 paper.

[0036] Furthermore, because the fixed blade that is affixed to the printer
 chassis retracts automatically when the operable cover unit opens,
 accidents caused by the user&apos;s finger touching the movable blade when the
 operable cover unit is open can be prevented.

[0037] Other objects and attainments together with a fuller understanding
 of the invention will become apparent and appreciated by referring to the
 following description and claims taken in conjunction with the
 accompanying drawings.

BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS

[0038] FIG. 1 is an oblique external view showing a printer applying the
 present invention.

[0039] FIG. 2 is an oblique external view showing the printer with the
 operable cover open.

[0040] FIG. 3 is a schematic view showing the internal arrangement of the
 printer.

[0041] FIG. 4A is an oblique view of the printer chassis and operable
 cover unit of the printer.

[0042] FIG. 4B is a plan view of the printer chassis and operable cover
 unit of the printer.

[0043] FIG. 4C is a side view of the printer chassis and operable cover
 unit of the printer.

[0044] FIG. 5A is an oblique view of the paper cutting device of the
 printer when the paper is partially cut.

[0045] FIG. 5B is a plan view of the paper cutting device of the printer
 when the paper is partially cut.

[0046] FIG. 5C is a side view of the paper cutting device of the printer
 when the paper is partially cut.

[0047] FIG. 6A is an oblique view of the paper cutting device of the
 printer when paper cutting is finished.

[0048] FIG. 6B is a plan view of the paper cutting device of the printer
 when paper cutting is finished.

[0049] FIG. 6C is an oblique view of the paper cutting device of the
 printer when paper cutting is finished.

[0050] FIG. 7A is an oblique view of the fixed blade retraction mechanism
 of the printer.

[0051] FIG. 7B is a side view of the fixed blade retraction mechanism of
 the printer.

DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS

[0052] A preferred embodiment of the present invention is described below
 with reference to the accompanying figures.

[0053] FIG. 1 is an oblique external view of a thermal printer according
 to the present invention, and FIG. 2 an is oblique view showing the
 printer when the operable cover unit is open.

[0054] A thermal printer 1 according to this embodiment of the invention
 has a printer chassis 2 with an operable cover unit 3 attached at the
 front. An operating panel unit 4 is disposed to a front corner of the
 printer chassis 2. A paper exit 5 extending widthwise to the printer is
 formed at the top part of the operable cover unit 3 at the front of the
 printer.

[0055] The printer chassis 2 is covered by a box-like printer case 6 that
 has a long depth front to back and is open at the front and bottom sides.
 An operable cover case 7 that defines the printer front is attached at
 the front of the operable cover unit 3. Operating an operating lever 8
 located at the operating panel unit 4 releases a cover lock not shown,
 thereby releasing and causing the operable cover unit 3 to swing forward
 and open a predetermined angle pivoting on the bottom end part of the
 operable cover unit 3. Opening the operable cover unit 3 opens a path
 from the roll paper compartment 9, passed a printing position determined
 by the thermal print head 16 and platen roller 15, a paper cutting
 position determined by the fixed blade 21 and movable blade 22 (see FIG.
 3), and to the paper exit 5. This exposes the roll paper compartment 9
 formed inside the thermal printer 1, and enables easily replacing the
 roll paper 10.

[0056] A state indicator group 4a of LEDs, for example, a feed button 4b,
 and a power switch 4c are provided on the front of the operating panel
 unit 4.

[0057] FIG. 3 is a schematic view of the inside of the thermal printer 1.
 A roll paper compartment 9 is formed inside the thermal printer 1
 surrounded by a curved paper guide bottom 12, paper guide top 13, and
 paper guide front 14 each extending widthwise to the printer and
 generally conforming to the shape of the roll paper 10. The roll paper 10
 is held so that it can rotate freely inside the roll paper compartment 9,
 and the tape of recording paper 10a that is delivered from the roll paper
 10 is pulled to the front past the printing position between the platen
 roller 15 and thermal print head 16, and is moved to the front of the
 printer from the paper exit 5 disposed in front of the printing position.

[0058] The paper exit 5 is formed between the front edge 6b of the case
 top 6a part of the printer case 6 and the curved top portion 7a of the
 operable cover case 7 disposed below front edge 6b. A scissor-type paper
 cutting device 20 is located in front of the paper exit 5.

[0059] The paper cutting device 20 has a fixed blade 21 disposed on the
 printer chassis 2 side, and a movable blade 22 and movable blade drive
 mechanism 23 disposed on the operable cover unit 3 side. The fixed blade
 21 is disposed substantially horizontally widthwise to the printer with
 the cutting edge 21a facing forward. The movable blade 22 is disposed
 substantially vertically widthwise to the printer with the cutting edge
 22a facing up at a position substantially directly below the cutting edge
 21a of the fixed blade 21. When the recording paper 10a is conveyed
 between these cutting edges 21a and 22a (the paper cutting position), the
 movable blade 22, which is on the bottom, is pivoted upwards so that the
 cutting edges 21a and 22a close together widthwise to the printer and cut
 the recording paper 10a located therebetween.

[0060] The paper guide front 14 that is part of the roll paper compartment
 9, the platen roller 15, and the movable blade 22 of the paper cutting
 device 20 are thus disposed to the operable cover unit 3. As a result,
 when the operable cover unit 3 is opened from the closed position 3A to
 the open position 3B, the roll paper compartment 9 is opened as shown in
 FIG. 2, and the paper transportation path is opened from the roll paper
 compartment 9 to the paper exit 5 past the printing position and the
 paper cutting position. The roll paper 10 can therefore be easily loaded
 and set. When the recording paper 10a is then pulled out from the roll
 paper 10 in the roll paper compartment 9 and the operable cover unit 3 is
 closed, the paper transportation path is completed and the recording
 paper 10a is automatically threaded through the paper transportation
 path.

[0061] FIGS. 4A to FIG. 4C are an oblique view, a plan view, and a side
 view showing the main parts of the printer chassis 2 and operable cover
 unit 3 with the printer case 6 and operable cover case 7 removed and the
 paper cutting device 20 in the position before starting to cut the
 recording paper 10a.

[0062] FIGS. 5A to FIG. 5C are a similar oblique view, plan view, and side
 view when the paper cutting device 20 has partially cut the recording
 paper 10a, and FIGS. 6A to FIG. 6C are a similar oblique view, plan view,
 and side view when cutting is finished.

[0063] The paper cutting device is described below referring to these
 figures.

[0064] The printer chassis 2 has a base panel 31 defining the printer
 bottom, right and left side panels 32 and 33 rising vertically from the
 base panel 31 with a specific gap therebetween, and a head mounting panel
 34 disposed across the gap between the top portions of the side panels 32
 and 33. The thermal print head 16 is mounted to the bottom of the head
 mounting panel 34. Pivot plates 35, 36 are oriented vertically to the
 printer chassis 2 and are disposed to the outside of the right and left
 side panels 32 and 33. The bottom end portions of the pivot plates 35, 36
 are supported on support pins 37 and 38 (only support pin 37 is shown in
 the figures) at the front bottom end portion of the side panels 32, 33 so
 that the pivot plates 35, 36 can pivot in the longitudinal (front to
 back) direction of the printer chassis 2.

[0065] Pivot plate 35 has an inclined portion 35a extending at a slope
 upward and toward the back from the support pin 37, and a vertical
 portion 35b extending substantially vertically from the upper end of the
 inclined portion 35a. Two oblong holes 35c and 35d are formed at two
 vertically separated positions in the vertical portion 35b. Guide pins 39
 and 40 affixed to the side panel 32 are inserted in these oblong holes
 35c and 35d so that the pins can slide, thus limiting the pivot range of
 the pivot plate 35 in the longitudinal direction. The other pivot plate
 36 is comprised in the same way and further description thereof is thus
 omitted.

[0066] The top ends of the right and left pivot plates 35, 36 are
 positioned above the head mounting panel 34, and a rectangular fixed
 blade mounting plate 41 is disposed horizontally widthwise to the printer
 between the pivot plates 35, 36. Oblong guide holes 41a and 41b extending
 longitudinally to the printer are formed in the fixed blade mounting
 plate 41 at both sides width wise to the printer. The fixed blade
 mounting plate 41 also has a tab projecting to the back of the printer
 from the right rear side portion of the fixed blade mounting plate 41,
 and another oblong guide hole 41c is formed in this tab. Guide pins (not
 shown in the figure) are formed on the underside of the case top 6a of
 the printer case 6 that is attached to the printer chassis 2, and these
 guide pins are inserted from above into these guide holes 41a to 41c.
 These guide pins limit longitudinal movement of the fixed blade mounting
 plate 41.

[0067] Except for the portion where guide hole 41c is formed, the back
 edge portion of the fixed blade mounting plate 41 is bent perpendicularly
 downward to form bent portion 41d. A fixed blade pressure spring 42 is
 disposed in the compressed state between this bent portion 41d and a
 spring catch 33a formed at the top of the side panel 33 at the back side
 of the printer opposite the left side of the bent portion 41d (the
 opposite side from the guide hole 41c). The fixed blade mounting plate 41
 disposed between the right and left pivot plates 35, 36 is thus
 constantly urged forward (toward the movable blade 22) with a
 predetermined spring force by the fixed blade pressure spring 42. A fixed
 blade 21 is fixed to the front underside edge portion of the fixed blade
 mounting plate 41 widthwise to the printer with the cutting edge 21a
 horizontal and facing forward.

[0068] The operable cover unit 3 attached at the front of the printer
 chassis 2 comprises a front panel portion 51 extending widthwise to the
 printer, and narrow side panel portions 52 and 53 formed by bending the
 right and left edges of the front panel portion 51 perpendicularly toward
 the back of the printer. The front of the front panel portion 51 slopes
 slightly from the bottom to the top towards the back of the printer. The
 movable blade 22 of the paper cutting device 20 is disposed here with the
 cutting edge 22a widthwise to the printer and facing up. A support stud
 54 is affixed at the top right corner of the front panel portion 51 (on
 the same side as side panel portion 52), and the movable blade 22 can
 pivot vertically on this support stud 54 along the front of the front
 panel portion 51. The end portion 22b of the cutting edge 22a of the
 movable blade 22 on the side where cutting starts is disposed in front of
 and in contact with the end portion 21b of the cutting edge 21a of the
 fixed blade 21 on the same side.

[0069] The movable blade drive mechanism 23 for causing the movable blade
 22 to pivot vertically comprises a drive motor 24 attached to the front
 panel portion 51, a worm 26 that is driven by the drive motor 24 through
 intervening speed reducing gear train 25, and a worm wheel 27 meshing
 with the worm 26. A drive pin 28 is affixed to the worm wheel 27, and
 this drive pin 28 is inserted slidably to a long narrow guide pin hole 29
 formed in the movable blade 22.

[0070] Starting from the positions shown in FIG. 4A to FIG. 4C, when the
 drive motor 24 turns causing the worm wheel 27 to rotate in the direction
 indicated by arrow 27a, the movable blade 22 linked by intervening drive
 pin 28 moves circularly upward pivoting on the support stud 54 at the
 right end of the movable blade 22. The cutting edge 22a of the movable
 blade 22 is positioned with the end portion 22b where cutting starts in
 contact with the cutting edge 21a of the fixed blade 21. As a result, as
 the movable blade 22 pivots upward, the point of contact between the
 cutting edge 22a of the movable blade and the cutting edge 21a of the
 fixed blade moves from the end where paper cutting starts to the end
 where paper cutting ends.

[0071] The cutting edge 21a of the fixed blade 21 is inclined so that it
 projects slightly toward the front of the printer (towards the movable
 blade 22) from the end where paper cutting starts to the end where paper
 cutting ends. The cutting edge 22a of the movable blade 22 faces upward
 and extends widthwise to the printer. As a result, the cutting edge 22a
 of the movable blade 22 pushes the fixed blade 21 slightly toward the
 back of the printer as the movable blade 22 pivots. This applies a force
 suitable for cutting to the point of contact between the two blades. The
 entire fixed blade 21 can move along a curved path in the front-to-back
 direction of the printer by means of the fixed blade mounting plate 41
 disposed between the right and left pivot plates 35, 36 pivoting on the
 support pins 37 and 38, and is constantly urged to the front of the
 printer by the fixed blade pressure spring 42. The cutting edges 21a and
 22a therefore always contact at a point, and as the movable blade 22
 pivots this contact point moves from the end where paper cutting starts
 to the end where paper cutting ends. As the point of contact between
 these cutting edges 21a and 22a thus moves, the portion of the recording
 paper 10a at this contact position is cut widthwise to the printer.

[0072] The fixed blade pressure spring 42 in this embodiment of the
 invention urges the fixed blade 21 at a position offset to the outside
 from the end of the cutting edge 21a of the fixed blade 21 where paper
 cutting ends. Forces denoted by arrows F1 and F2 in FIG. 5A and FIG. 6A
 act on the fixed blade 21. F1 is the pushing force of the movable blade
 22, and F2 is the urging force of the fixed blade pressure spring 42. If
 the urging position of the fixed blade 21 (the position of F2) is located
 between the end where paper cutting starts and the end where paper
 cutting ends instead of outside the cutting range as in this embodiment
 of the invention, the direction of the angular moment of forces F1 and F2
 acting on the fixed blade 21 reverses before and after the urging
 position as the point of contact moves along the cutting edges 21a and
 22a, and the fixed blade 21 may shift in the front-to-back direction
 around this urging position or the point of contact between the blades.
 If the fixed blade 21 thus shifts while cutting the paper, problems such
 as the paper not being cut in a clean straight line may occur. Change in
 the force of contact between the blades may also prevent cutting the
 paper properly. This embodiment of the invention prevents such problems
 by rendering the urging position outside the cutting range.

[0073] This embodiment of the invention also comprises a fixed blade
 retraction mechanism for retracting the fixed blade 21 toward the back of
 the printer in resistance to the urging force in conjunction with opening
 the operable cover unit 3. The fixed blade retraction mechanism according
 to this embodiment of the invention is described with reference to FIG.
 7A and FIG. 7B.

[0074] FIG. 7A is an oblique view when the operable cover unit 3 is open,
 and FIG. 7B is a side view of the same. The fixed blade retraction
 mechanism 70 according to this embodiment of the invention comprises an
 engaging pin 71 affixed to the bottom end portion of the side panel
 portion 52 on the right side of the operable cover unit 3, and an
 engaging spring 72 disposed to the bottom end portion of the right side
 pivot plate 35 supporting the fixed blade 21.

[0075] The engaging pin 71 projects horizontally widthwise to the printer
 at a position offset slightly to the back of the printer from the pivot
 point 3a of the side panel portion 52. The engaging spring 72 slopes from
 the bottom end portion of the pivot plate 35 toward the bottom and front
 of the printer, and the bottom end portion of the engaging spring 72 is
 bent back toward the back of the printer, forming a bent portion 72a that
 is pushed from below by the engaging pin 71. The engaging pin 71 contacts
 the bent portion 72a at a position towards the front of the printer from
 the support pin 37 of the pivot plate 35.

[0076] When the operable cover unit 3 opens from the closed position shown
 in FIG. 4A to FIG. 4C, the engaging pin 71 moves circularly upward around
 pivot point 3a, thus pushing up on while sliding along the bottom part of
 the bent portion 72a of the engaging spring 72 as shown in FIG. 7A and
 FIG. 7B. As a result, the pivot plate 35 is forcibly pivoted downward
 around support pin 37, and the fixed blade 21 supported by the fixed
 blade mounting plate 41 at the top of the pivot plate 35 retracts and
 moves away from the paper exit 5.

[0077] When the operable cover unit 3 is completely open as shown in FIG.
 7A and FIG. 7B, the cutting edge 21a of the fixed blade 21 is at a
 position retracted sufficiently from the front edge portion (near front
 edge 6b) of the case top 6a of the printer case 6 defining the paper exit
 5. Accidents such as the operator cutting his finger on the cutting edge
 21a of the fixed blade 21 when replacing the roll paper 10 with the
 operable cover unit 3 open can therefore be prevented.

[0078] The fixed blade 21 is disposed substantially horizontally on the
 printer chassis 2 side while the movable blade 22 is disposed
 substantially vertically on the operable cover unit 3 side in this
 thermal printer 1. That is the movable blade and fixed blade are
 positioned in planes substantially perpendicular to each other. Only
 enough space to render the fixed blade 21 horizontally is therefore
 needed at the top of the printer chassis 2 where the printer chassis 2 is
 installed. Compared with an arrangement in which the fixed blade 21 and
 movable blade 22 are opposed vertically to the printer, this invention
 minimizes the increase in printer height required to provide a paper
 cutting device, and therefore affords a short, compact thermal printer 1.

[0079] This thermal printer 1 can alternatively be rendered with the
 movable blade 22 disposed substantially horizontally on the printer
 chassis 2 side, the movable blade drive mechanism 23 also disposed on the
 printer chassis 2 side, and the fixed blade 21 disposed substantially
 vertically on the operable cover unit 3 side.

[0080] Furthermore, because the cutting edges 21a and 22a contact
 substantially perpendicularly, the fixed blade 21 and movable blade 22
 can be formed with no curvature and disposed so that the cutting edges
 contact at a suitable contact angle. This simplifies knife manufacture,
 and therefore enables reducing the production cost and improving
 manufacturing quality.

[0081] Furthermore, because the fixed blade 21 and movable blade 22
 contact substantially perpendicularly instead of contacting with the
 cutting edges 21a and 22a overlapping in the blade thickness direction,
 the operable cover unit 3 is not rendered unopenable as a result of the
 fixed blade 21 and movable blade 22 crossing with one on top of the other
 when the movable blade 22 stops in the middle of cutting the recording
 paper 10a, for example.

[0082] Yet further, because the fixed blade 21 affixed to the printer
 chassis 2 retracts in conjunction with opening the operable cover unit 3,
 accidents such as the operator&apos;s finger being cut by the cutting edge 21a
 of the fixed blade 21 when the operable cover unit 3 is open can be
 prevented.

[0083] The invention has been described using a thermal printer by way of
 example, but the invention can obviously be applied to other types of
 printers, including inkjet printers and dot impact printers. [0084]
 Although the present invention has been described in connection with the
 preferred embodiments thereof with reference to the accompanying
 drawings, it is to be noted that various changes and modifications will
 be apparent to those skilled in the art. Such changes and modifications
 are to be understood as included within the scope of the present
 invention as defined by the appended claims, unless they depart
 therefrom.




You can also Monitor Keywords and Search for tracking patents relating to this Paper cutting device and printer patent application.
###
 

 

 How KEYWORD MONITOR works... a FREE service from FreshPatents 
1. Sign up (takes 30 seconds). 2. Fill in the keywords to be monitored.
3. Each week you receive an email with patent applications related to your keywords.  
 Start now! - Receive info on patent apps like Paper cutting device and printer or other areas of interest.
###




###

 Design/code©2012 FreshContext LLC/Freshpatents.com.
Patent data source: patents published by the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO)
Information published here is for research/educational purposes only (and in conjunction with our Keyword Monitor) and is not meant to be used in place of the full USPTO patent document/images or a comprehensive patent archive search. Complete official applications are on file at the USPTO and may contain additional data/images. FreshPatents.com is not affiliated with or endorsed by the USPTO or firms/individuals or products/designs/ideas related to listed patents and there may be applicable trademarks or servicemarks within the documents. FreshPatents.com Support - Terms&amp;Conditions 
Thank you for viewing the Paper cutting device and printer patent info.
- - - AAPL - Apple , BA - Boeing , GOOG - Google , IBM , JBL - Jabil , KO - Coca Cola , MOT - Motorla 

Results in 0.6052 seconds

 
Other interesting Freshpatents.com categories:
 Exxonmobil Chemical Company , Intel , 
g2
	</body>
</document>
