<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009667" url="http://www.freewtc.com/products/plastic-serving-tray-67441686-56238.htm" time="2012-07-13-03:03" support="2" score="0.0016837453662030858" bingtitle="Plastic Serving Tray NTT-1 - Free World Trade Center" webtitle="Plastic Serving Tray NTT-1">
			<query id="001332" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="001340" bing-rank="52"/>
	<description>Plastic Serving Tray NTT-1 specifications ... It is widely used in fast food restaurant, and the dining-room of ... Place Of Origin: China: Brand Name: NICETY: Price Terms</description>
	<body>
		Start Products Yellowpages Buyers My Center 
 Home &gt; Product Catalogue &gt; Home Supplies &gt; Kitchenware &gt; Kitchen Accessories &gt; Cooking&amp;Serving Utensils 
Plastic Serving Tray
 Inquiry the manufacturer of Plastic Serving Tray Our new researched plastic serving tray is made out of the special type of PP material.
It has high temperature resistance (it doesn&apos;t disfigure in boiling water), low temperature resistance (it doesn&apos;t crack in chill and freezing weather). Four kinds of models and many colors are available for choosing. It is widely used in fast food restaurant, and the dining-room of the school and enterprise.

Packing:
Carton size: 410 x 300 x 15mm 
   view large photo of Plastic Serving Tray
 
Sales Terms&amp;Specifications:

 Model No. NTT-1 Place Of Origin China Brand Name NICETY Price Terms FOB / CIF / EXW(Factory Price) Terms Of Payment T/T, L/C Supply Ability 1,200pcs/day Delivery Lead Time in 10 days 
 
Relative Products

 
 Tea Strainer 
 Features:1) Diameter: 6cm, 6.5cm, 7cm, 7.2cm, 7.5cm, 8cm, 8.2cm, 9.2cm, 9.6cm2) Made of stainless steel wire or steel wire O 
 gn31 turner 
 description:stainless steel with Imitates the ceramicsWe can provide all kind of a set of cx - ice cream spoon, shisk, grater, k 
 KITCHEN TOOLS 
 many style of kitchen tools set for your selectionwith perfect quality, elegant design&amp;and competitive price material: stain 
 Odd Sided Grater 
 We are a leading manufacturer and exporter of household products in P. R. China, set up in 1982, having more than 500 workers. M 
 Rose - Kitchen Tool Set 
 Krish Exports best Quality ProductsItem - Rose - Kitchen Tool SetSize - 9 InchDifferent Weight, Designs ara available.Pleas 
 kitchen tool set 
 Name:kitchen tool setSpec:DM071268Detai:Material: 18/0Thickness: 1.0mmPacking: color boxG/N.W.: 20/19KG 
 Spatula 
 spatula 
 Stainless Steel Kitchen Utensils 
  Rads are manufacturing Stainless Steel Utensils. Quality is the biggest objective that we have achieved. We server you wi 
 Kitchen Star 
  Kitchen Star Platinium PlusThe Silicone Polyester QualityWouldnt it be great to have a complete set of professional qualit 
 Colander Alpha 
 Stainless steelGrade 41/1Finishing mirrerHandel pipeThikness 0.5 mmWaight 0.350 gTorlernce weight 5%(+ -) 
 Plastic Tray 
 These fun party trays, bowls and boxes can be decorated with full color graphicsusing custom decals that are added during the mo 
 grater 
 Features:1) Stainless steel material2) Non-slip handle and base 
 ©2001 - 2012 Free World Trade Center
	</body>
</document>
