<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009804" url="http://www.ourbroker.com/foreclosures/can-you-refinance-your-loan-under-the-obama-mortgage-relief-plan/" time="2012-07-13-03:12" support="1" score="0.0005004189968000007" bingtitle="Can You Refinance Your Loan Under The Obama Mortgage Relief Plan ..." webtitle="Can You Refinance Your Loan Under The Obama Mortgage Relief Plan?  : Real EstateMortgageForeclosureNewsCommentary">
			<query id="001044" bing-rank="199"/>
	<description>With rates today near 5 percent — about as ... it automatically disqualifies vast numbers of ... months at the new interest rate and payment. ___ If you successfully make the ...</description>
	<body>
		Friday, July 13th, 2012
 
 Home Advertising Contact Notices Privacy Site Map Staff Trademark RSS 
 
 Buyers Closing Contracts Featured Foreclosures Investing Jobs Library Mortgages News Rent Sellers Toxic Loans 
 
 Can You Refinance Your Loan Under The Obama Mortgage Relief Plan? 
 March 8th, 2009 By Peter G. Miller 
 Filed Under: Foreclosures Tags: 105 percent • 125 percent • 5 percent • afford • affordability • equity • foreclose • foreclosure • forelcosure • HAMP • investor • job • loss • modification • mortgage • Obama • owner • paperwork • plan • program • value 
The 2009 Obama foreclosure relief plan has two parts, first there is modification help for those who face foreclosure and, second, there is also a refinancing program for those with loans which are no longer affordable.

Under the details of the plan we can see how the refinancing program works, who qualifies and who does not.

In basic terms, loans become unaffordable when borrowers are no longer able to make payments or when payments consume so much monthly income that owners are effectively pauperized. In many cases, but not all, there is an instant solution to the affordability problem, namely refinancing at a lower rate.

 Rates 

With rates today near 5 percent—about as low as they’ve been in 50 years—refinancing makes great sense. However, many homeowners cannot refinance because the value of their home is worth less than the remaining principal balance of their mortgage. You can describe such owners as underwater, upside down or simply in steep trouble.

The obvious reason for upside down owners is that properties were bought with little or nothing down and then home values fell. However, there is a second reason why many owners are underwater: They have“negatively amortizing”loans, toxic mortgages where the owners make low monthly payments during start periods. Such payments are very affordable—and they are also a trap. Why? Because the payments are so small they do not even cover interest costs. The result is that unpaid monthly interests costs are added to the loan balance. That’s right, the size of the loan grows each month.

You can imagine what happens when start periods end: The loan balance is larger so monthly payments soar. Sometimes they double. Now the owner must sell but can’t because local home values have fallen. They also can’t stay because the monthly payments are not affordable. The usual results of this dilemma are foreclosure, bankruptcy and simply walking away from the house.

 Upside Down Buyers 

The Obama plan tries to deal with upside buyers. It says that if you have negative equity you can refinance with help from the government. It also says your negative equity can be no more than five percent.

“Eligible loans,” says the White House,“will now include those where the new first mortgage (including any refinancing costs) will not exceed 105% of the current market value of the property. For example, if your property is worth $200,000 but you owe $210,000 or less you may qualify. The current value of your property will be determined after you apply to refinance.”

 The States 

This is a huge limitation because it automatically disqualifies vast numbers of borrowers in California, Arizona, Nevada, Florida, Michigan, Ohio, Indiana, Illinois, Pennsylvania and other jurisdictions which have seen massive price declines.

To apply for a Home Affordable Modification, says the government, you must:

___ Be an owner-occupant in a one to four unit property. No investors.

____ You must have an unpaid principal balance that is equal to or less than $729,750 (for one unit properties and higher for two to four unit properties (consult your servicer),

___ You must have a loan that was originated before January 1, 2009,
 
___ Your mortgage payment (including taxes, insurance, and home owners association dues) cannot be more than 31% of your gross (pre-tax) monthly income.

___ You must have a mortgage payment that is no longer affordable, perhaps because of a significant change in income or expenses.

 Hardship 

Notice the last item. The refinancing is intended only for those with financial hardships.

The government says that“responsible borrowers who are struggling to remain current on their mortgage payments are eligible if they are at risk of imminent default, for example, because they have had or will soon have a significant increase in their mortgage payment that they cannot afford. If you have had or anticipate a significant increase in your mortgage payment or have had a significant reduction in income, contact your servicer. If you meet the minimum eligibility criteria for a Home Affordable Modification, your servicer is required to evaluate your loan to see if you are at risk of imminent default.”

 How It Works 

Okay, let’s say you’ve lost your job, your spouse has died or medical bills are piling up. If you can refinance under the program how will you benefit?

The government explains the program this way:

Your loan servicer—the kindly folks who collect your monthly payments—must determine that your loan meets the minimum eligibility criteria (owner occupied, originated before January 1, 2009, is equal to or less than $729,750). If yes:

___ Obtain sufficient income information to determine if your monthly mortgage payment is more than 31% (approximately 1/3) of your gross or pre-tax monthly income. (Your servicer may initially accept verbal information about your income, but eventually you will need to provide proof of income in the form of tax returns and pay stubs). If yes:

___ Add past due charges (interest, taxes, insurance and costs that your lender paid to other parties on your behalf—but not late fees, those must be waived) to the loan balance.

___ Determine how much of an interest rate reduction will be required to get your mortgage payment down to a point where it is about 31% of your gross monthly income.

___ Apply a test to determine if the cost of the modification (including the government’s incentive payments) is less costly for the investor than a foreclosure. If yes:

___ Put you on a trial modification for three months at the new interest rate and payment.

___ If you successfully make the payments and are current at the end of the trial period, your servicer will execute a permanent modification agreement that will lower your interest rate to a fixed rate for five years. (Notice that the government defines permanent as five years ….)

___ The modification payment will also include a monthly amount to be set aside (escrowed) to pay taxes and insurance when they become due. This escrow is required even if your prior loan was not escrowed.

For details and specifics, contact your loan servicer. Your monthly mortgage bill or payment book will have contact information. In addition, local real estate attorneys, community housing organizations and state attorneys general can also provide assistance.
_______________________
 Copyright 2009 Peter G. Miller . All Rights Reserved. Use of this material without permission is illegal, however up to 300 words of this material may by reproduced online PROVIDED credit is given to the author AND a plainly-visible link is provided to my home page, OurBroker.com 
 
 
 
 
 
 Tweet 
 
Technorati Tags: 105 percent , 125 percent , 5 percent , afford , affordability , equity , foreclose , foreclosure , forelcosure , HAMP , investor , job , loss , modification , mortgage , Obama , owner , paperwork , plan , program , value 
 Related Links 
 Facing Foreclosure? How The Obama Plan Can Help FHA“Short Refinance”—Is This The Way To Reduce Foreclosures? How Can I Get Foreclosure Refinancing? Controversy Brews Over Latest Obama Mortgage Write-Off Plan Feds Start New Short Sale&amp;Deed-in-lieu of Foreclosure Options Mortgages: Feds OK 230,000 Modification Trials Mortgages: Do It Yourself Loan Modifications Can I Bargain With A Lender During Hard Times? Mortgage Loan Relief For BP Spill Victims 100 to 1—Obama Mortgage Modification Plan Tops Bush What Paperwork Do You Need To Get A Mortgage? Chase OKs 138,000 Trial Mortgage Modifications 
 
Post a Response
 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 
 CAPTCHA Code * 
 
 To leave a comment please enable JavaScript in your browser settings! 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via e-mail 
 
 
Widely Read
 
 How To Get A Successful Loan Modification (With Obama Update) How To Read The New HUD-1 How To Read The New Good Faith Estimate Forms Judge To Lenders: Show Me The Note FHA, VA&amp;Conventional Mortgage Loan Limits How To Get A New Job Using Google AdWords How To Write Your First Resume (With Sample) A Basic Guide To Real Estate, Mortgages&amp;Taxes Mortgage Surprise? What Mortgage Surprise? Who Should We Blame For The Mortgage Meltdown? Is It Time To Take The Tilt Out Of Bankruptcy? 
 
 
 
Related Sites

 ChefsOnTheRoad.com Consumer Financial Protection Bureau Content That Works Deadline News DollarCollapse.com FHA Loan Pros Future Military Homeowners HSH—Mortgage Rates Huffington Post Jesse&apos;s Cafe American MakingHomeAffordable Mortgage News Clips Negretes Notaries OurBroker Real Estate&amp;Loan News Patrick.net Professional Development Institute (PDI) Real Estate Professional Magazine Realty Times RealtyTrac.com RightWorx.com—Make Military Pay Tax Free 
 
 
 Custom Search 
First-Time Home Buyer Library
 
 Conventional Mortgage Basics FHA Mortgage Basics VA Mortgage Basics Must Buyer Brokers Be “Exclusive”? How Do We Get Rid of the FHA Mortgage Insurance Premium? What Is Title Insurance? What Is A Title Insurance “Re-Issue” Rate? Can I Make Big Money Buying and Selling Mortgage Notes? What&apos;s A Seller Contribution In Real Estate? Can I Re-Use My VA Entitlement? Does A Mortgage Pre-Approval Letter Guarantee Financing? How Does A Reverse Mortgage Work? 
 
Fixed-Rate Mortgage Trends
 

 
OurBroker News
 Google News unavailable
 
Recent Comments

 Thank you Peter for asking some questions about this program instead of uncritically reciting the press announcement, which is ...
 James | 11Jul12 | More As difficult and awkward as the situation is, the Teutuls at least had the courage to sit down and start ...
 custom choppers | 25Jun12 | More Mortgage rates will inevitably rise, that much is true. The low rates are also a problem because it just makes ...
 Tim Richmond | 19Jun12 | More I suspect that all states are unique. Some have been substantially impacted by delayed foreclosures and will be impacted again ...
 Peter G. Miller | 19Jun12 | More Do you think Georgia is a good barometer to use for the rest of the states? Their sudden jump concerns ...
 Tim Richmond | 19Jun12 | More EVERYTHING COULD BE SOLVED IF SR. GOT OFF HIS BUTT AND BECAME &quot;INVOLVED&quot; IN THE SHOP, INSTEAD OF TELLING EVERYONE ...
 RALPH EARNHARDT | 22May12 | More Selling a house at auction is the purest form for finding value. It is usually sold as is where is ...
 Jerry Wilkins | 15May12 | More I feel the broker seller along with the buyer is a wider bridge a better relationship than auctions. Auctins have ...
 Frank Galante | 14May12 | More I understand that banks take a risk lending you money. But to say if you don&apos;t put 20% down ...
 Tim | 9May12 | More Like father like son. Hot tempers and big egos. Before they were TV stars they were family. Of anyone that ...
 Tim Horton | 23Apr12 | More 
 
  ©Copyright OurBroker.com 2012. All Rights Reserved.  Powered by Geeks2020.com • Site Admin
	</body>
</document>
