<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009529" url="http://www.menuism.com/restaurants/relish-modern-tapas-mason-269253" time="2012-07-13-02:55" support="2" score="0.002437539471245395" bingtitle="RELISH Modern Tapas - Reviews &amp; Menu - Mason 45040" webtitle="RELISH Modern Tapas - Reviews&amp;Menu - Mason 45040">
			<query id="001283" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="001314" bing-rank="154"/>
	<description>... at Relish is a dining discovery - choose a selection ... dinner” and drinks, I had to stop by a fast food restaurant ... The problem came when we went to pay the bill ...</description>
	<body>
		Menuism - Restaurant and dish reviews 
 Explore Restaurant Reviews&amp;Menus 
 Restaurants Near Me Make Online Reservations Order Delivery&amp;Takeout Restaurant Week Directory Popular Cities Popular Chains What&apos;s Menu ism ? Monthly Review Contest 
 Remember Personal Dining Journal 
 My Favorites My Try List My Photos Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 
 Learn Foodie Education Blog 
 Food Primers Exclusive Interviews 
 
 FIND AROUND GO 
 Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 

 Not a member? To save, rate, and share reviews, sign up! Already a member? Log in (OpenID) Connect with Facebook 
 
 larger map / directions 
 
 - Actions - Write a Review Add to Try List Add to Favorites Suggest Corrections Upload Pics 

 - Pages - The Restaurant Map/Directions 
 Mason Restaurants » Tapas » RELISH Modern Tapas Share | 
RELISH Modern Tapas
 
 2.5 star rating           
  2.5 rating over 3 reviews 
 (513) 204-6925 

 5947 Deerfield Cir ( ) 

 Mason , OH 45040-2548 

 View Nearby Businesses» 
 Send to Phone Email Listing Print Listing   
 Reserve Online View Menu Website Read Reviews (3) View Map/Directions 
 
 Information From the Restaurant Offers 
 
 Tags: Tapas, Small plates, Cincinnati, OpenTable, Reservations, Casual Elegant, Fusion, and Good for groups Stats: 
 1 user wants to eat at RELISH Modern Tapas 
 
 
 From OpenTable:  
Relish Modern Tapas is an oasis of new age tapas - an eclectic collection of familiar dishes in small plates infused with flavors from cuisines around the world. Eating at Relish is a dining discovery - choose a selection of gourmet quality dishes in small plates and share with friends and family for an enjoyable dining experience in a relaxed and contemporary space.
Private Party Facilities: We offer a private dining area for your party needs. Just contact our chef for your requirements - you may order from our menu or have our chef design a special menu for your event. In addition, a chef&apos;s table by the kitchen which can accommodate up to 5 adults is available on reservation. See the kitchen staff in action, and enjoy a chef&apos;s choice menu from our executive chef

 
 Do you own RELISH Modern Tapas? Contact us to connect with your diners. 
 
 Suggest Corrections/Menu 
 
Reviews for RELISH Modern Tapas
 Write a review 
 3 reviews First reviewed by nomorespam2000 
 
 4 helpful votes over 1 review 
 nomorespam2000 
 1 Restaurant Review +4 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 RELISH Modern Tapas nomorespam2000 
 January 29, 2009 
 1.0 
 1.0 star rating           
 +4 0 +4 4 Votes   
It&apos;s not all that...
 
The idea of tapas is lost here. How can you charge family-style entree prices for such a small serving? After dining at Relish and spending so much for my“dinner”and drinks, I had to stop by a fast food restaurant just to feel full.

It seems obvious to me that the restaurant owner&amp;/or staff has written the other reviews I have read for this“resto.”

It is also blatantly obvious that the kitchen staff might have some, let’s say“proper immigration credentials.”
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply 
 0 helpful votes over 1 review 
 lovetodine99 
 1 Restaurant Review 0 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 RELISH Modern Tapas lovetodine99 
 April 13, 2009 
 5.0 
 5.0 star rating           
 0 0 0 0 Votes   
Love this place!
 
While this is a little pricey, what tapas place isn’t? It’s gourmet food so you pay for it. The soups are out of this world, martinis are heaven, flatbread is to die for. Meat and seafood tapas offerings are sometimes a miss–like the chorizo and medjool dates that turned out to be glorified meatballs whee you really didn’t get much taste of either of the main ingredients. But most offerings are wonderful, with a special spin that is worth trying. Current favorites are the Asian Spicy Shrimp, Ribs, Paella, and the Shrimp and Chorizo.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply winbaxsu 
 from Citysearch 
 
January 19, 2011
 
 1 star rating           
 
I didn&apos;t Relish the experience
 
I brought 9 friends to Relish on Saturday evening. The food was good, with a beautiful presentation. The service was fine (I think our waiter was new). The problem came when we went to pay the bill. One person had a groupon. One had…

 read full review» 
 Read 3 reviews on Citysearch» 
Best Dishes at RELISH Modern Tapas
 
Thinking about visiting RELISH Modern Tapas? Check out the full RELISH Modern Tapas menu to decide if the menu items&amp;prices meet your expectations. When available, we&apos;ll provide pictures, dish ratings, and descriptions of each item. RELISH Modern Tapas prices and menu items may fluctuate by location or over time, so use the following menu information as a reasonable guideline as to what is currently being served at the restaurant.
 
 Sort: Top Rated Most Popular 

No menu items or dish reviews have been added for this restaurant.
Be the first food lover to add a dish.
 
Menuism intends to provide as accurate information as possible. RELISH Modern Tapas prices and menu items are known to fluctuate. The information above has been provided by Menuism users or 3rd party data sources. If you represent RELISH Modern Tapas you are invited to feed us with more accurate information by contacting us.
 
 Air Authority Reliable Handyman Solutions, Inc. Reed M. Douglas PhD&amp;Associates Goddard School Shorten&amp;Ryan Funeral Home Inc The Learning Place Pre School&amp;Pre Kindergarten Air Authority Baysore&apos;s Flower Shop Kiddie Academy Child Care Lrng Zoom&apos;s Nail&amp;Spa 
 RELISH Modern Tapas is located near the cities of Kings Mills, Wetherington, Uninc Warren County, Landen, and Liberty Township. People found this by searching for: Relish Tapas Mason, Tapas Paella Restaurant At Ohio, Relish Restaurant Mason Ohio, Relish Mason, Relish Modern Tapas, Relish Modern Tapas Mason Ohio Menu, Relish Restaurant Cincinnati, Relish In Mason, and Tapas Restaurant Cincinnati Menu. 
Featured in Mason
 
 4.5 star rating           
 Sun Garden Restaurant 
 4.25 star rating           
 Cazadores Mexican Restaurant 
 3.5 star rating           
 China City Buffet 
 5.0 star rating           
 Chubby&apos;s Pizza 
 3.0 star rating           
 Mama Vita&apos;s 
 0.0 star rating           
 LaRosa&apos;s 
 0.0 star rating           
 La Rosa&apos;s 
 0.0 star rating           
 LaRosa&apos;s Pizzeria 
 0.0 star rating           
 LaRosa&apos;s 
 0.0 star rating           
 Antonio&apos;s Ristorante Italiano 
 Upload Pics Photos
 
Nearby Restaurants
 Deerfield Commons Retirement Abuelo&apos;s Mexican Food Embassy Brazenhead Pub Papa John&apos;s Pizza 
Link to RELISH Modern Tapas
 
Copy the link below and paste onto your website or blog to display badge.

 Copy 
 
 Follow Menuism around the web Find us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter Find us on Google+ 
 
 Learn More
 Advertise About
Advertise
FAQ
Privacy
Terms of Use 
 Take Action
 Link to Menuism / Badges and Widgets 
 Browse
 Restaurant Week Restaurant Locations Popular Cities Sitemap 
 
 ©2006 - 2012 Delta Beans, LLC
 Contact Menuism 

Some Images and Data provided by Citysearch .
	</body>
</document>
