<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009610" url="http://www.copykat.com/2010/04/08/kfc-buttermilk-biscuits/" time="2012-07-13-03:00" support="4" score="0.006511613425754144" bingtitle="KFC Buttermilk Biscuits Recipe | CopyKat Recipes | Restaurant Recipes" webtitle="KFC Buttermilk Biscuits Recipe | CopyKat Recipes | Restaurant Recipes">
			<query id="001218" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="001213" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000673" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000678" bing-rank="31"/>
	<description>Restaurant Style Biscuits Red Lobster Cheddar Bay Biscuits II – make these cheesy ... Keep in mind much of the sausa... Anonymous</description>
	<body>
		You loved it at the restaurant, now make it at home Try It Out 
 
 Search from over 1500 recipes... 
 Home About Contact Press Contests Links to Love Dining Out At Home Recipe Box Videos 
 This recipe is filed in 
 Bread Recipes CopyKat Recipes 
 and has these ingredients 
 biscuits Fast Food Recipes 
 
KFC Buttermilk Biscuits
 April 8, 2010 13 Comments 
Share the recipe
 Tweet Print Add this recipe to ZipList! Next Recipe&gt; &lt;Previous Recipe 
KFC Buttermilk Biscuits have to be one of my guilty pleasures. The KFC Buttermilk Biscuits are soft, billowy, and have a crunchy top. You know, you don’t have to leave home to make biscuits just like the KFC Buttermilk Biscuits. What I really like about making these KFC Buttermilk Biscuits at home means I can make them for breakfast, which I can’t do during the morning. This is one of the few recipes that I actually use self rising flour. I like the self rising flour in the KFC Buttermilk Biscuits because commercial self rising flour has a really nice consistency in flour. I do add a couple of secret weapons in my version of the KFC Biscuits.
 
 

In addition to the self rising flour, I also like to use, some sugar, for sweetness, and some cream of tartar to give these biscuits an additional lift. I think one of the qualities I like most about the KFC Buttermilk biscuits is how high, light, and fluffy they are. If you have never tried using buttermilk before in your biscuits, you should really give it a try, buttermilk gives your baked goods a fabulous tang, with the addition of sugar, and you get a really balanced flavor in the KFC Buttermilk Biscuits.

KFC Buttermilk Biscuits

2 1/2 cups self rising flour
1 cup buttermilk
1/2 cup chilled butter (you can use shortening)
2 tablespoons of butter melted (to top biscuits with)
2 1/2 teaspoons sugar
1 teaspoon cream of tartar
 
Preheat your oven to 425 degrees. Cut butter into small cubes, if you use shortening chill it so you cut into small pieces. It is important to cut the butter into small pieces so it will make it easier to cut the butter into the flour. In a medium sized bowl combine self rising flour, sugar, and cream of tartar. Add in cubed butter, and work butter into the flour until it reaches a large sand grained texture. Add buttermilk, and stir long enough to stir buttermilk into the dough.
 

On a floured surface turn dough out of the bowl, and shape flour into a round shape, use a rolling pin to gently roll out dough to about 3/4 of an inch thick. Use a biscuit cutter to cut out biscuits and place on an ungreased cookie sheet. Brush tops of biscuits with the 2 tablespoons of melted butter. Bake biscuits for 12 to 15 minutes.

 
 Add this recipe to ZipList! 
 
Buttermilk Biscuits – make these fresh anytime. These are easy to make, and you can’t beat fresh bread baking in the oven. 
Crazy Biscuits – biscuits are tasty when made from scratch, these biscuits are so good you will be crazy for them. 
Restaurant Style Biscuits 
Red Lobster Cheddar Bay Biscuits II – make these cheesy garlicky biscuits at home. 
Churches Honey Biscuits 
 
 http://recipes.latestrend.com/general/kfc-buttermilk-biscuits-recipe-copykat-recipes/ All type of RECIPES!..»KFC Buttermilk Biscuits Recipe | CopyKat Recipes 
[...] biscuits. You can make biscuits just like they do with this recipe . Go here to read the rest: KFC Buttermilk Biscuits Recipe | CopyKat Recipes Thursday, April 8th, 2010 at 22:24 RSS feed for comments on this post Leave a comment | [...]
 http://frantasticfood.com Fran 
Well, that looks easy enough. Sounds like the perfect side to eggs this weekend.
 munkee 
Schwans has cheap biscuits like KFCs without the hassle. Very addictive.
 Marcy Powell 
I just made the KFC Buttermilk biscuits and they were the biggest flop I have ever had. Usually all the recipies I try turn out great. Everyone loves my cooking and baking. This recipie is one I would never recommend or make again. Thanks Marcy
 http://www.copykat.com Stephanie 
Marcy, I am really sorry that this recipe flopped for you. I am curious, did you use self rising flour?
 Casey 
I usually enjoy all of your recipes, however, this one I did not. They were not like the KFC biscuits I have had. Will not be making these again.
 Bree 
Does anyone have a recipe for KFCs coleslaw?? Thanks, Bree
 Sandra 
I would give the moon for a recipe from Jack’s Restaurant biscuits 
 marissa 
i think tat it is kool and it tasted really nice wen i tried it soooooo………..i think um…u can try it
 cjletsid 
biscuits are not easy to make, even for everyday bakers. My mom taught me when I was very young and it took me years to perfect her biscuits. You can not over knead or under knead. You have to use the right flour and sifting is very important. If they flop for you, you most likely did something wrong whether you want to hear it or not.
 Stephanie Manley 
The recipe is here, Better than KFC Coleslaw.
 Stephanie Manley 
It seems like baking is often more than just following directions. Lots of practice also helps!
 Techchef 
Thanks for the recipes (this one and the Fried Chicken) but the video on the side that starts automatically is very annoying..
 
 CopyKat.com&apos;s Dining Out at Home Cookbook Recipes for the Most Delicious Dishes from America&apos;s Most Popular Restaurants Buy on Amazon I’d definitely recommend adding Dining Out at Home to your collection. It’s a great way to add some variety into your meals at home and give you the feeling of dining out even when you stay in. FrugalNovice 
 
Welcome to CopyKat Recipes
 
CopyKat.com is the creation of Stephanie Manley. Stephanie started publishing recipes on the web in 1995 as a means to capture her family recipes in a format that they would not be thrown away. Over the years she has developed many recipes that
taste just like restaurant recipes.
 read more 
10 FREE Copykat Recipes
 Want 10 free Copy Cat recipes? 
Sign up for the Free newsletter. Policy: We won&apos;t share your email with any 3rd party and won&apos;t send you any spam 
 
Categories

 52 Weeks of Cream Cheese (22) Appetizer Recipes (211) Book Review (1) Bread Recipes (114) Cake Recipes (34) Candy Recipes (26) Casserole Recipes (121) Chicken Recipes (92) Contest (4) Cookie Recipes (60) Copycat Restaurant Recipes (713) CopyKat Recipes (903) Dessert Recipes (322) Dips/Sauces (122) Drink Recipes (68) Favorite Recipes (82) Giveaway (5) Holiday Recipes (8) Main dish Recipes (202) Meat Recipes (63) Menu Plan (23) Miscellanous (52) New (4) Pasta Recipes (89) Reader&apos;s Recipes (194) Salad Dressings (56) Salad Recipes (100) Seafood Recipes (84) Side Dish Recipes (81) Snack Recipes (62) Soup Recipes (122) Tweet (16) Video (32) 
 
Recent Posts

 Bacon Beer and Cheese Cupcakes Star Pizza Roasted Garlic and Goat Cheese Red Lobster Shrimp Nachos Quick and Easy Broccoli Rice Casserole Outback Steakhouse Green Beans Video 
 To place this on your site, select the code below and then press &quot;Ctrl+C&quot; to copy 
Video
 Panera&apos;s Broccoli Cheese Soup Broccoli Rice Cheese Casserole Outback Steakhouse Green Beans Red Lobster Cheddar Bay Biscuits Chocolate Pretzel Bites More Videos 
Recent Comments

 What&apos;s the best way to reheat... Arpy Jul 13, 2012 I worked at sonic in highschoo... Tomara Armstrong Jul 12, 2012 you needed to scroll down a l... Dmchensky Jul 12, 2012 my son had this when we went o... Sweetheart4270 Jul 12, 2012 ummm, the temp of the oven to... Lenriz Jul 12, 2012 
 (C) 2011 CopyKat Recipes | Restaurant Recipes WordPress Design by Blog Design Studio
 Graphic Design by Lakia Ross Creative 
Please note, no restaurant recipes are actually used, these recipes have been inspired by the restaurant originals. Unless otherwise noted, all recipes have been created by CopyKat.com.
	</body>
</document>
