<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009711" url="http://smallbusiness.chron.com/make-restaurant-concept-statement-25816.html" time="2012-07-13-03:05" support="1" score="0.0022650274481200838" bingtitle="How to Make a Restaurant Concept Statement | Small Business ..." webtitle="How to Make a Restaurant Concept Statement | Small Business - Chron.com">
			<query id="001062" bing-rank="74"/>
	<description>Subscribe; Subscriber Services; Make a Payment; MyChronRewards ... For example, if you plan to open a fast food restaurant with a menu based on traditional Thai ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to main content. 
 Subscribe Subscriber Services Make a Payment MyChronRewards 
 Chron.com chron.com Web Search by YAHOO! Businesses 
 Home News Sports Business Entertainment Life Travel Blogs Opinion 

 Jobs Homes Cars Classifieds Coupons 

 Index 
 Close [X] Quick links to the best of chron.com | Still can&apos;t find it? see Site Index 
 Don&apos;t miss: Recent Headlines 
 
 Houston&amp;Texas Houston weather Houston traffic Nation&amp;world Politics Health News bizarre Deaths Hurricanes 9/11 anniversary 
 
 Ultimate Astros Rockets Texans Dynamo Colleges High school Golf Outdoors More sports 
 
 FuelFix.com Markets Houston stocks World markets Your portfolio Currency Small business Tech Homes Commercial real estate Press releases 
 
 29-95 Restaurants Alison Cook Music Movies Bars Arts&amp;Theater 
 
 Mom Houston Houston Belief Health Gardening Pets Gloss Food Books Horoscopes Comics&amp;games Weddings&amp;celebrations 
 
 Texas Travel Travel New Orleans Travel Louisiana Flight tracker 
 
 City Brights Newswatch Celebrity Buzz SciGuy Tubular NFL: John McClain Sports Justice TechBlog Texas on the Potomac Mom Houston 
 
 Nick Anderson cartoons Bill King columns Editorials Op-ed columns Letters to the editor 
 
 Advanced search Browse job categories Career Rescue Houston&apos;s Hiring Work&amp;Career Advice 
 
 New Homes Rentals Farms&amp;Ranches Second Homes Research Mortgages Commercial Real Estate 
 
 Research&amp;Reviews Build a New Car Find Dealers 
 Small Business by Demand Media 
 Running a Business | Money&amp;Debt | Managing Employees | Finances&amp;Taxes | Accounting&amp;Bookkeeping | Setting Up a New Business | Business Models&amp;Organizational Structure | Types of Businesses to Start | More» 
 
 » Business Communications&amp;Etiquette » Human Resources » Business Planning&amp;Strategy » Advertising&amp;Marketing » Business&amp;Workplace Regulations » Business Technology&amp;Customer Support 
 
 Small Business » Business Technology&amp;Customer Support » Customers » How to Make a Restaurant Concept Statement 
 
How to Make a Restaurant Concept Statement
 by Devra Gartenstein, Demand Media 

 
A buffet restaurant concept offers customers a bounty of choices.

Thinkstock/Comstock/Getty Images
 
 Related Articles 

 What Is a Bakery Concept Statement? Important Points in a Concept Statement What Is a Design Concept Statement? Example of a Product Concept Statement Basic Income Statement for a Restaurant What Is a Statement of Purpose for a Restaurant? 
 
Opening a restaurant involves much more than simply knowing how to cook. Successful restaurants depend on creating a space where customers want to linger, and a menu that communicates a unique and appealing identity. In addition, a restaurant&apos;s concept must be built on a viable business model; you can&apos;t offer high end meals for fast food prices and stay in business for long. A concept statement is a document that provides information about how a restaurant will create a brand, attract clientele and make enough money to survive.
 
Step 1

Describe the type of food you&apos;ll be preparing in your restaurant. Choose a culinary theme that&apos;s broad enough to allow you to innovate but narrow enough for customers to easily understand. For example, &quot;American food&quot; is too broad, &quot;my grandmother&apos;s recipes&quot; is too narrow, while &quot;southern comfort food&quot; provides both identity and wiggle room. Explain the possibilities and limitations associated with your concept, as well as your unique qualifications for creating a menu based on the type of food you describe.
 
Step 2

Describe the ways that your restaurant&apos;s decor will work in synergy with your menu&apos;s theme. For example, if you plan to open a fine dining restaurant, you should use fine linen and attractive plates. If you&apos;re opening a local foods restaurant, select decor inspired by local agriculture, such as vintage produce signs. Include information about how you&apos;ll decorate the outside of your restaurant as well, with details about signage, awnings and an exterior scheme.
 
Step 3

Identify the target market for your restaurant&apos;s concept and explain how your idea will appeal to this core group of customers. Include applicable demographic information such as gender, income level, race, ethnicity and geographic location. For example, if you plan to open a fast food restaurant with a menu based on traditional Thai street food, you might focus on attracting your local Thai community as well as people who work in close proximity to your restaurant, who may need something quick for lunch.
 
Step 4

Describe the way your restaurant&apos;s business model will earn revenue and make a profit. Provide specifics about particular menu items as well as general information about margins for different types of expenses such as ingredients and labor. Use this part of your restaurant concept statement to demonstrate that you have a clear idea of whether your operation will channel most its resources into food, staffing or atmosphere.
 
Things Needed

 Menu Ingredients price list 
 
References

 GEC Consultants: Develop Your Restaurant&apos;s Concept First State of Illinois: Restaurant Start-up Profile Food Service Warehouse: Creating a Restaurant Concept 
 
About the Author

Devra Gartenstein has owned and run a variety of food businesses for more than 20 years. She has published two cookbooks:&quot;The Accidental Vegan&quot;and&quot;Local Bounty&quot;. Gartenstein holds Master of Arts degrees in philosophy and English literature.
 
Photo Credits

 Thinkstock/Comstock/Getty Images 
 
More Articles

 
How to Change a Restaurant Concept While the Business Is Running
 
What Is a Concept Description in Terms of a Restaurant Business?
 
Restaurant Catering Concepts&amp;Business Ideas
 
The Everything Guide to Starting&amp;Running a Restaurant
 
 
People Also Viewed

 What Expenses Can Go Onto Profit&amp;Loss in a Restaurant? Top Restaurant Sales Techniques How to Make Projections for a Restaurant How to Start a Dessert Restaurant How to Make a Statement Balance Column in Excel Steps to Opening a Restaurant 
 
Related Topics

 How to Start a Customer Service Consulting Business How to Provide Customer Support What Is Metrics-Based Customer Support? More Business Technology&amp;Customer Support Business Technology Planning 
 
 
The Web&apos;s 6 Most Influential Tech Bloggers
 
America&apos;s 9 Most Tech-Friendly Cities
 
Phone Pas: 9 Places You Should Pocket Your Cell Phone
 
10 Highest Valued Tech Companies
 
9 Gadgets You Can&apos;t Live Without
 
 Small Business Index Powered by Demand Media 
Chron.com

 Home Houston&amp;Texas Nation&amp;World Business Sports Entertainment Life Corrections Blogs Weather 
 
 City Brights Traffic 

Topics

 Small Business MomHouston.com HoustonBelief.com 29-95.com 
 
Neighborhoods

 Aldine Alief Baytown Bellaire Clear Lake Conroe Cy-Fair East End Fort Bend Heights Katy 
 
 Kingwood Lake Houston Magnolia Memorial Montrose Pasadena Pearland Spring Tomball West U The Woodlands 
 
Marketplace

 Jobs Homes Cars Coupons Classifieds Place a classified ad Place a retail ad 

Other Editions

 Home Delivery iPad iPhone Android Mobile RSS Feeds e-Edition 
 
Local Services

 Air Conditioning Contractors in Houston Car Dealerships in Houston Cleaning Services in Houston Family Doctors in Houston Furniture Stores in Houston Injury Attorneys in Houston New Car Dealer in Houston Real Estate Agents in Houston Real Estate Attorneys in Houston Restaurants in Houston 
 
Services

 Help/Contact us Business directory Legal notices Privacy policy Terms&amp;Conditions Employment opportunities Advertise with us Buy a banner ad 
 
©2012 Hearst Communications Inc.
 Hearst Newspapers RSS My Yahoo!
	</body>
</document>
