<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009195" url="http://www.theage.com.au/news/Fashion/A-waifs-progress/2005/03/12/1110567739584.html" time="2012-07-13-02:35" support="3" score="0.000940394983607011" bingtitle="A waif&apos;s progress - Fashion - www.theage.com.au" webtitle="A waif&apos;s progress - Fashion - www.theage.com.au">
			<query id="000854" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000228" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="001451" bing-rank="230"/>
	<description>... holy kind of meal, promiscuously mass-marketed? Tom Sachs thought so, which is why he photographed her tossing burgers in a fast-food restaurant. ... she was a receptacle of ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to The Age Online. Skip directly to: Search Box , Section Navigation , Content . Text Version .
 NEWS | JOBS | REAL ESTATE | CARS | FINANCE | MOBILE | DATING | TRAVEL | WEATHER 
   network map | member centre   
 
 ARTS BOOKS EPICURE FASHION FILM MUSIC PEOPLE TV&amp;RADIO 
 
 A waif&apos;s progress 
 March 12, 2005 
 
Page Tools

 Email to a friend Printer format 
 
Telephone bidders sit under a Lucian Freud portrait of a pregnant and naked Kate Moss, entitled Naked Portrait 2002 during the auction at Christie&apos;s, London.
 Photo: AP 
 
 Kate Moss is feted as much for her wild nights out,
stints in rehab and unruly lovers as her looks.
How is it, asks Peter Conrad, that a scrawny girl with bandy legs,
crooked teeth and a wonky eye emerged as an iconic beauty of our
age? 

Beauty is the most devoutly ideal of human notions, and also the
harshest and most heartless.

Why should we expect our quirky faces and baggy physiques to
match some lofty aesthetic standard? Yet we have always done so,
conferring an almost supernatural status on those who resemble the
ideal. In his recent History of Beauty , Umberto Eco tracks
this infatuation through the centuries. His first illustration is a
battered Roman bust. The woman it represents lacks arms, and has
been broken apart below the breasts, but in every other way
embodies perfection: alabaster flesh, a nose designed by a slide
rule, sculpted hair that deliciously tickles her bare shoulders, a
pouty half-open mouth, eyes obligingly left blank so they can
reflect whatever we project into them. Two thousand years later,
Eco&apos;s book ends with Herb Ritts&apos;s photograph of Kate Moss from the 1994 Pirelli calendar.
 
She is naked on a tropical beach, with a looped shell necklace
arranged to cover her nipples and dangle into her groin; though her
skin is tanned, not whitely marmoreal, she has the same ripe mouth
as the Roman figure, and the same wayward serpentine hair. But she
has not lost her lower body, which curves out of the frame - her
bare bottom retouched to look curvier - as an enticement to
fantasy.

The Roman sculptor carved a goddess. Today, the divine image is
invested in one of those flighty beings we call supermodels. Does
Moss, placed at the end of Eco&apos;s aphrodisiac anthology, represent
the high point of civilisation? Or is she perhaps - with her wild
parties and cocaine comas, her fags, booze, bouts in rehab and
line-up of unruly lovers - an augury of its end? The goddess may
look delectable, but her behaviour is diabolical.
The talent scout who first spotted Moss in 1987 admired her
&quot;translucency&quot; and her &quot;ethereal look&quot;. Naomi Campbell in her
novel, Swan , renamed her Celestia. In January, her
boyfriend, rock singer Pete Doherty - a crackhead who has been
jailed for burglary - paid tribute to Kate&apos;s &quot;beautiful soul&quot;.

But what religion does this supernatural creature serve? She has
spent her life, ever since she began modelling at the age of 14, as
an evangelist for consumerism, selling Calvin Klein underpants,
peekaboo outfits by Versace or Galliano, and perfumes called
Obsession and Opium. Undersized, dangerously thin, she is a
mannequin or a manikin, less a human being than an animated dummy
from a shop window, festooned with price tags. No wonder she spends
so much of her time behaving unbeautifully, grimacing as she puffs
a fag, swigs a drink, gives paparazzi the finger, and spits out
expletives in her harsh south London accent. Her rampages are an
attempt to claim back a reality that the fashion business has
stolen from her.
 
British model Kate Moss in 2002.
 Photo: Reuters 
 
The goddess, tired of heaven, wants to ground herself. Moss&apos;s
idea of bliss, she once said, is to watch EastEnders while
eating baked beans on toast. In the idyll, she will probably stub
out her cigarette in the red puddle of beans and reach for her hip
flask of undiluted vodka. As she once succinctly put it: &quot;F... all
the mixers.&quot; Her way of gauging her own celebrity combines
disenchanted scorn with helpless nostalgia. &quot;I must be famous,&quot; she
said in 1993, &quot;because I&apos;ve been in the Croydon
Advertiser . You normally only get in there if you&apos;ve stolen
something or you&apos;re having a jumble sale.&quot;

Moss&apos;s modelling sells a standard of beauty which anorexic
teenagers ruinously mimicked during the 1990s. But although beauty
becomes a collective dream, available to anyone who can afford the
clobber or put themselves on the punitive diet, it begins as the
possession of a single, quirky individual. Oddity and strangeness
have always been part of its appeal. The adolescent Moss, when she
caught the eye of an agent in a queue at JFK airport on her way
back from a family holiday, had bandy legs, a wonky eye and crooked
teeth; she was short and scrawny, although the most expensive
bodies then belonged to strutting lionesses like Linda Evangelista
and Cindy Crawford or sportive Valkyries like Elle Macpherson and
Claudia Schiffer.

The first agency to take her on, impatiently wondering how long
it would take her to grow into her features, doubted that she&apos;d
ever get beyond ad campaigns for the British chemist chain Boots.
She could at best be used to sell dandruff shampoo. But lingerie,
or the alluring odour bottled by Chanel under the name of Coco
Mademoiselle? It seemed unthinkable. More perceptive observers
suspected that, being hard to categorise, she would create a
category of her own. For a photographic session in 1992, Michael
Roberts got Moss to drape herself in feathered Indian regalia,
portraying her as an androgynous tribal outcast. BBC presenter Joan
Bakewell remarked that her face looked Asiatic, as abstract as a
memorial on an Egyptian tomb. A burial chamber was perhaps the
place for it: you could see the skull beneath the skin, and watch
the wasting process in action as she chain-smoked. Her appeal was
perverse, unsettling. She looked like a child, yet her eyes
betrayed a ghoulish elderly wisdom. Last year, at a party given by
designer Alexander McQueen, she wore a dress decorated with
grinning death&apos;s heads; it suited her.

Her performances before the camera were bracingly, abrasively
ironic. In some photographs by Karl Lagerfeld, she seems to despise
the accessories she is meant to be recommending, and swings a
handbag as if about to hurl it away. When Calvin Klein dressed her
in male underpants and made her straddle the muscular Mark
Wahlberg, she laughed at his &quot;slaggy styling&quot;. The lush, sultry
vixens of the previous generation breathed their commercial slogans
with a fierce intensity. Moss voiced the mantras inside jeering
quotation marks. Once, arriving hours late for an engagement, she
surveyed the fretting stylists, fuming photographers and alarmed
accountants whose morning she had ruined, and impenitently greeted
them with L&apos;Oréal&apos;s tag line. &quot;Because I&apos;m worth it,&quot; she
shrugged.
At the same time, unlike the haughty Naomi Campbell, she knew
perfectly well that she wasn&apos;t worth it. In 1999, she counted her
assets, which by then totalled£15 million ($36 million), and
lisped a confession: &quot;I s&apos;pose I think I don&apos;t deserve it.&quot; She
remained unfragrant. Journalist Jefferson Hack, who fathered her
daughter, chatted her up by telling her that she smelled of wee.
Only Moss would have taken that as a compliment.

Her earliest collaborations with the photographer Corinne Day
presented Moss as a child of nature. She scampers naked on a beach,
hiding her private parts behind a straw hat and naughtily giggling.
Fashion is about renewal and the rites of spring, since what it
sells is the promise of agelessness. It therefore makes a fetish of
freshness and innocence. These are the values it prizes, yet it is
duty-bound to ravage them, because they are merely a teasing
commercial ploy. Moss therefore soon found herself cast in
scenarios that sullied her. In a photograph by Vinoodh Matadin, she
is Lolita or Tennessee Williams&apos;s Baby Doll on her wedding day. She
wears a bridal veil, but rather than vouching for virginity, it is
thrown back to expose her naked body; she lets her bouquet of white
roses droop, the thorns scratching her pubis. And, fixing us with a
gaze of sensual stupefaction, she sucks her stubby phallic
thumb.

In one Obsession advertisement for Calvin Klein, she lies on a
couch, her nude rump in the air, pitifully thin and dangerously
vulnerable. The session, as she recalled in 1995, was a war of
wills between Moss and the photographer Mario Sorrenti, her
boyfriend at the time. &quot;Mario was like, &apos;You have to be naked, man,
it&apos;s about purity, you have to be pure&apos;, and I&apos;m like, &apos;What&apos;s the
difference if I have a pair of knickers on?&apos;&quot; Sorrenti&apos;s definition
is intriguing: purity is a pair of bare, upraised buttocks. Moss
fought valiantly to retain her knickers, but admitted that &quot;at the
end of the day, he had the control&quot;. Klein made matters worse by
burbling that Moss &quot;had this childlike, womanlike thing - a kind of
sexiness that I think is very exciting&quot;. Once again, you wonder
where the superego was: should we brag about being titillated by
the eroticism of a child? Klein went on to rhapsodise about Moss&apos;s
grunginess: &quot;It&apos;s very real and modern when a woman&apos;s hair looks
dirty, when it sticks together a little.&quot;

These philosophers of fashion, dealing with the ineffable, have
an odd way of seeing the world. For them, purity is a pertly
available bum, and modernity can be equated with greasy hair.
Either way, Moss found herself being soiled, even when, in 1993,
for an Esquire layout photographed by Thierry Le
Gouès, she allowed herself to be painted gold. The
magazine&apos;s cover celebrated her as a &quot;Golden Girl&quot; and praised her
for having &quot;conquered the world&quot;, but the gimmick remained
vindictive, lethal: it quoted, after all, from the Bond film Goldfinger , in which a girl is suffocated when her pores
are blocked by that expensive epidermis of pigment.

The men who photograph Moss seem to compete with each other to
devise ways of tormenting her, or of enticing her to degrade
herself. During her romance with Johnny Depp, she made a trip to
Nashville to appear in a Johnny Cash video. She reminisced about
this misogynistic farrago in 1994: &quot;I&apos;m his girlfriend but I don&apos;t
want to be his girlfriend any more, so he ties me up in this chair
and shoots me and then buries me. It&apos;s kind of twisted.&quot; Models are
toys for overgrown boys, who reserve the right to destroy their
fragile playthings.

The street-smart Moss is aware that her job involves a
hypocritical harlotry. Gianni Versace acknowledged the fraudulence
of the transaction: &quot;How can a piece of fabric be sexy? It&apos;s the
woman wearing it who makes it so.&quot; The designers and advertisers
help themselves to Moss&apos;s musky charisma, and deceive the customers
into believing that this is what they can buy. Moss has been
involved in the mercantile routine for so long that she&apos;s not quite
sure whether she is selling or being sold. In a 1994 interview, she
blurted out an inadvertent, indiscreet truth: &quot;Clothes sell
sex.&quot;

She at once reversed the terms and gave the official version:
&quot;Sex sells clothes.&quot; Both propositions are correct, though neither
is especially agreeable. The models perambulating down the catwalk
resemble a parade of nubile talent laid on for the clients of a
brothel (even if the prospective purchasers in the front rows are
not lecherous men but middle-aged female journalists with lifted,
adamantine faces). Helmut Newton made the connection in 1981 when
he stripped the models at a Paris fashion show down to their spiky
heels. Versace sold fabric, but his models touted flesh.

Moss, while profiting from the pretence, takes sarcastic
pleasure in exposing it. Hence the ridicule she directs at her own
glossy effigy on billboards 12 metres high. &quot;I don&apos;t see myself any
more,&quot; she said in 1998. &quot;I just see an image of what someone&apos;s
trying to advertise, and that&apos;s sad.&quot; A journalist from The Face
watched in 1999 as a stylist over-zealously combed Moss out and
dislodged one of her hair extensions. &quot;It&apos;s all fake,&quot; she said,
&quot;I&apos;m all fake.&quot;

Disillusionment has pushed her towards a campaign of subversion.
When she met Fidel Castro in 1998, he hailed her as a colleague:
&quot;You are some kind of revolutionary yourself.&quot; Ironic and
self-disparaging as always, she replied: &quot;Maybe because I&apos;m small.&quot;
But there is an angry Napoleonic ambition in her, a desire to see a
world of pomp and privilege turned upside down. Her one-time
fiancéJohnny Depp used to trash hotel rooms; Moss more
ingeniously engaged an Art Deco suite at Claridge&apos;s for her 30th
birthday celebrations last year, invited her friends to come
dressed as characters from F. Scott Fitzgerald&apos;s The Beautiful
and the Damned , and - making herself scarce - let them get on
with the business of disgracing themselves, which they did with
gusto. The Daily Mail described journalist and broadcaster
Janet Street-Porter as legless, designer Stella McCartney spewing
abuse at her sister, and Sadie Frost, Jude Law&apos;s ex, letting a boob
escape from her dress, while participants in a polymorphous gang
bang called for a supply of condoms.

During the late 1990s, Moss used to do a patriotic impersonation
of Cool Britannia, posing in a T-shirt emblazoned with the Union
Jack. The revels she hosted at Claridge&apos;s suggested that she might
now be planning the dissolution of a society corrupted by drink,
drugs and easy money. She likes to think of herself as a queen of
the night, and relishes her nickname, Dracula. She even seems to
take the sulphurous whiff of damnation seriously. While being
detoxed at the Priory clinic in 1998, she arranged for the exorcism
of her London house: &quot;A priest came over and then a Thai lady came
over. Prayers in every room.&quot; By now, the demons are back in
residence: photographers saw her sneak off to a party recently,
carrying her vodka in a plastic bag.

Short of self-destruction, what future does Moss have, now
companies like Chanel - noting her age and flinching from her
tabloid reputation - hesitate before they renew her contracts? She
apparently fancies singing: rock music is a career open to the
talentless. She has taken acting lessons to prepare for a part in a
television adaptation of Jilly Cooper&apos;s bonkbuster Polo. It&apos;s
unclear why she needs tuition, as she is playing herself: who else
could she be?

She seems anxious to be remembered as an artists&apos; muse, not
merely as the bait hired by advertisers for the rag trade. In 2000, Vogue commissioned seven young artists to produce their
own versions of her. Gary Hume drew her, then beamed his sketches
onto her body, so she wore his drawings like a costume, or a second
skin. Sarah Morris photographed her sucking Coca-Cola through a
straw, then digitalised the print so that Moss was broken up into a
grid of bite-sized squares, ready for our eyes to make a meal of
her all over again. Sam Taylor-Wood posed her in a church portico,
veiled her head, and positioned a crystalline tear in the corner of
an eye that looked up to heaven: impersonating a Victorian Madonna,
Moss the profane icon regained sanctity. Marc Quinn cast her in
plaster and used the mould to make an ice sculpture, which
vaporised with agonising slowness over the next six months. Quinn
thought the spectacle was &quot;eucharistic&quot;: as Moss evaporated,
visitors to the gallery breathed her in. Or does she constitute a
greasier, grosser and less holy kind of meal, promiscuously
mass-marketed? Tom Sachs thought so, which is why he photographed
her tossing burgers in a fast-food restaurant.

Perhaps it was the experience of working with Quinn, Taylor-Wood
and the others that made Moss think about being painted by Lucian
Freud. She whispered her wish in Jefferson Hack&apos;s magazine, Dazed and Confused ; Freud saw the article and invited her
to sit for him - or rather to lie naked on a tousled bed during
nocturnal sessions that lasted several months. The painting
disappeared into an American collection without ever going on
public display. Its owner, however, decided to offload it and, on
February 9, after a brief American tour to tantalise wealthy
bidders, it was auctioned at Christie&apos;s. Moss, who&apos;d made an
unsuccessful bid for it in 2002, failed once again to acquire the
painting, which sold to an unnamed bidder for£3.93 million
($9.52 million).

It&apos;s no surprise she covets Freud&apos;s work. The painting is a
vindication of her, something to be salvaged from a life that so
far has largely been frittered away on selling people things they
don&apos;t need but can&apos;t do without. Moss was proud of the time she
invested in modelling for it. Freud&apos;s minute, pernickety attention
atoned for the dismissive blink rate of all those cameras that had
looked at her without seeing who she was.

And whereas the ad campaigns treated her body as a bland,
silvery, monochrome surface, Freud&apos;s application of paint made it
seethe with life. She was pregnant at the time; her belly swells,
her breasts are plump, and rivers seem to run through her. Lolling
on her pillow, her head matters less than her distended midriff and
her elongated lower limbs. Her face, in all those photographs,
constituted a brand. But Freud ignored her lucrative personal
mystique. He was interested in Moss, he said, merely as an animal
(by which he meant that she was a receptacle of organic vitality,
and maybe also a dwelling for the anima, the soul that boyfriend
Pete Doherty praises); he did not identify her, but anonymously
entitled the painting Naked Portrait .

Moss recently turned 31. The beauty she sells when modelling is
leaking away like Quinn&apos;s ice. Her nocturnal antics accelerate this
inevitable loss. To live so fast is to anticipate death; at school,
she had &quot;a period every week&quot; to ensure that she escaped sports.
Her new best friend is Marianne Faithfull, a worn and weathered
relic of the 1960s who serves as her memento mori. Beauty like
Moss&apos;s is as disposable as last season&apos;s dress - or will it survive
thanks to the homage of an artist who, indifferent to her
celebrity, didn&apos;t even record her name? The catalogue for
Christie&apos;s sale boldly likened Freud&apos;s picture to Titian&apos;s Venus of
Urbino and to Manet&apos;s flagrant Olympia. Moss has spent her life in
nightclubs, airports and recuperative clinics, but she may spend
eternity in an art museum.
 
 Get The Age home delivered for as little as $2.70 a week *
 
 Top of Page 
 
Page Tools

 Email to a friend Printer format 
 
Our Advertisers
 Search 
 SPONSORED BY:
 
 Film 

 Their own beat Irons makes fist of supporting role Gentleman Jeremy 
 
 Music 

 Philosopher of contradictions Fine-tuning the bluegrass sound Back to his roots 
 
 TV&amp;Radio 

 Ratings Rewind The perfect TV age 
 
 Arts 

 The Goodies - still alive on stage War begins at home Cosi Fan Tutte 
 
 Epicure 

 A shy squire squares off Back on the crawl Almost French 
 
 Fashion 

 Staying afloat Mary raises fashion stakes Festival program 
 
 Books 

 Hang-ups: essays on painting Kafka on the shore Machiavelli: a man misunderstood 
 Get the freshest entertainment news by email . 
 Jobs @ MyCareer Cars @ Drive Homes @ Domain 
 
NEWS

 breaking national world business technology sport realfooty entertainment science 

 video photo galleries 

COMMENTARY

 opinion editorials letters your say cartoons 

TIME OUT

 oddspot crosswords weather tv guide 

SECTIONS

 Travel Money Employment Property Motoring Education 

CLASSIFIEDS

 place an ad adonline real estate cars jobs announcements other classifieds 

EDITIONS

 am today last 8 days text rss version mobile&amp;pda 

SERVICES

 member centre age store subscriptions overseas sales advertise archive photosales about the age The Age@150 

 site map contact us 
 
 Home &gt; Entertainment &gt; Fashion &gt;Article
 Search Search Tips 
  Add theage.com.au to your rss feeds 

 National | World | Opinion | Business | Technology | Sport | Entertainment 

 Subscribe | Privacy | Contact Us | Conditions | Member Agreement | 

Copyright©2005. The Age Company Ltd.
	</body>
</document>
