<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009283" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/North-Miami/Avanti-International-Hotel--Restaurant-Supply-Incorporated" time="2012-07-13-02:40" support="1" score="0.0011052351830009503" bingtitle="Avanti International Hotel &amp; Restaurant Supply Incorporated - Fast ..." webtitle="Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated - Fast Food Restaurant  North Miami, FL 33168">
			<query id="000303" bing-rank="20"/>
	<description>Avanti International Hotel &amp; Restaurant Supply Incorporated a Fast Food restaurant ... Avanti International Hotel &amp; Restaurant Supply Incorporated listing. Please enter the ...</description>
	<body>
		0 Friend Requests Friend Requests 0 Messages Send a New Message Messages 0 Notifications Notifications 
 
 Find Friends Login 
 or login with: User Pages Photos Events Videos Polls Forum Threads Restaurant Search Results For User Search Results For Pages Search Results For Photos Search Results For Events Search Results For Videos Search Results For Polls Search Results For Forum Threads Search Results For Restaurant 
 Places Deals Recipes Photos Members Blog 
 
 Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Avanti International
Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply
Incorporated

 
Average User Rating
 
5
 
Average
 
Sponsored Link


 
(305) 688-4648

 http://www.avantiinc.com/ 
 FL &gt; North Miami &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated
 Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated is a Fast Food restaurant located at 650 Nw 123rd St in North Miami, FL 33168. Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 5 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated
 
 
 
All Reviews for Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated


 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   0

 
Comments
 
 
Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated News
 ASEAN: Genting Berhad Upgraded to Must Own International In the United States, Resorts World Casino New York City (“RWNYC”) marked its ... as the mixed-use development will be called, will include hotel, convention, entertainment, restaurant, retail, residential and commercial facilities. Starbucks reveals strawberry frappuccino contains crushed bugs In 1999, Starbucks experimented with eateries in the San Francisco Bay area through a restaurant ... introduced a brand new line of instant coffee packets called VIA &quot;Ready Brew&quot;, in March 2009. It was first unveiled in New York City with subsequent ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing New York Restaurants, Dentists, Bars, Beauty Salons, Doctors New York - User Reviews and Recommendations of Top Restaurants, Shopping, Nightlife, Entertainment, Services and More at Yelp Global Restaurant Equipment&amp;Supplies - Fast Food Restaurant ... NEW YORK, NY — Food safety ... Even in a year when global food prices hit record highs and both restaurant menus and retail food labels got a new look, the safety ... Citysearch City Guides by State Citysearch®: Search City Guides by State. ... Partner Sites: Ask Kids - Bloglines - Expedia - Hotels - Hotwire - Insider Pages - Los Angeles, CA City Guide - Reviews and Recommendations by Citysearch The Citysearch® Guide to Los Angeles, CA. Los Angeles, CA restaurants, bars, night clubs, hotels, shops, spas, events, attractions, yellow page listings and more. Darden Restaurants - A Leader in the Full-Service Restaurant Industry The Darden family of restaurants features some of the most recognizable and successful brands in full-service dining: Red Lobster, Olive Garden, LongHorn Steakhouse ... 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 82° 
Fri
 
 77° - 88° 
Sat
 
 81° - 90° 
Sun
 
 81° - 86° 
 
Address
 
Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated

650 Nw 123rd St

North Miami, FL 
 
33168
 
Telephone
 (305) 688-4648 
Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated
 
 Rating :  5 out of 10 based on 5 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated Photos
 
 Fast Food 
 
 Local Places
 
 Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Global Restaurant Equipment&amp;Supplies 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Popeye&apos;s Chicken&amp;Biscuits 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Brazil International Group 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Miami Restaurant Equipment Rpr 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Checkers Drive-In Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Ambrosino Gallery 
Cuisine: Tourist Attractions Museum of Contemporary Art at North Miami 
Cuisine: Tourist Attractions Crown Wine Spirits 20 
Cuisine: Wine Shop 
 

See all North Miami Tourist Attractions 
See all North Miami Wine Shop 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated Coupons 

 Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated North Miami 

 Avanti International Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supply Incorporated Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 North Miami Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | P | R S | T | V | W 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
