<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009805" url="http://www.reefcentral.com/forums/showthread.php?t=1521955" time="2012-07-13-03:12" support="1" score="0.001730311420594501" bingtitle="Starphire Glass... Is it worth it? - Reef Central Online Community" webtitle="Starphire Glass... Is it worth it? - Reef Central Online Community">
			<query id="001185" bing-rank="100"/>
	<description>Can you really tell a differance ... Again, I didn&apos;t buy into it and order my 120&quot; tank with regular glass. ... Thats right...until you get near .5 inches...its a waste of ...</description>
	<body>
		Blogs Recent Entries Best Entries Best Blogs Blog List Search Blogs 
 

 
   Reef Central Online Community &gt; General Interest Forums &gt; Reef Discussion Starphire Glass... Is it worth it? 
 
 User Name Remember Me? Password 
 
 
 Register Blogs FAQ Calendar 
 
 
 Notices Welcome to ReefCentral.
Because of the sheer size of our forum, we&apos;ve been forced to limit selling and trading to members who&apos;ve met a couple of criteria. (If you&apos;re seeing this message, you haven&apos;t met them yet.) Please take a moment to acquaint yourself with our selling/trading rules to help make your stay a long and rewarding one.

 Selling and trading on ReefCentral. Please join us in congratulating our July 2012 TOTM winner, Tony Brazao (Tony B) .
You can see and comment on his amazing tank, right here .
Cheers 

 
 Go to Page... 
 
 

   « Previous Thread | Next Thread » Thread Tools 
 
 12/01/2008, 09:29 PM  # 1 MightyNano Registered Member  
 Join Date: Sep 2007 Location: Pelham AL Posts: 7 Starphire Glass... Is it worth it? Can you really tell a differance? does anyone have any pic&apos;s of their tanks with and wo starphire?


   
 
 MightyNano View Public Profile Find More Posts by MightyNano 
 
 12/01/2008, 09:47 PM  # 2 TheMcs Registered Member  
  
 Join Date: Sep 2004 Location: Broken Arrow, OK Posts: 2,276 The only difference I&apos;ve seen is when viewing close up at an angle. Float glass is distorted, starphire is still fairly clear. Head on there&apos;s not much difference to see. I&apos;ve never owned starphire, only looked through a few dozen. Maybe some owners of both types of glass will pitch in.


 __________________
Evaporation and top off don&apos;t count as water changes...

Current Tank Info: 185g Deep Sea display, 2x 40g frag tanks, 90g fuge, 60g sump (400+ gal system)   
 
 TheMcs View Public Profile Find More Posts by TheMcs 
 
 12/01/2008, 10:01 PM  # 3 blakeorme Registered Member  
  
 Join Date: Aug 2008 Location: Columbus, OH Posts: 301 The biggest difference I noticed was when looked length way through the glass. On regular glass its almost too dark to see through a 4ft. tank, with starphire you can see all the ay through very easily. Obviously, this is an exaggerated test, but it does show you how clear the glass is.


 __________________
What is that blue light??

Current Tank Info: 150gal. 48x30x24   
 
 blakeorme View Public Profile Find More Posts by blakeorme 
 
 12/01/2008, 10:42 PM  # 4 TheH Registered Member  
  
 Join Date: Mar 2008 Location: Bellevue, WA Posts: 1,276 It depends on how thick the glass is. I&apos;ve heard that the difference becomes very clear around the 0.5&quot; mark.


   
 
 TheH View Public Profile Visit TheH&apos;s homepage! Find More Posts by TheH 
 
 12/01/2008, 10:55 PM  # 5 whosjohnny Premium Member  
  
 Join Date: Dec 2004 Location: Anaheim Hills, CA Posts: 598 Starphire prices has just skyrocketed recently due to demand. However, I not going to jump on to the bandwagon until a couple of years down the road. I personally think, the bigger deal is going to be how well you clean your glass on a regular basis and your maintenance and patience in good husbandry.

Starphire is just another technology that just makes you want to spend more -- yes, it&apos;s more clear and I would only order it with rimless top. =P Again, I didn&apos;t buy into it and order my 120&quot; tank with regular glass. All the money I saved is going toward getting frags and more coral colonization. Maybe when I build my 600G or 1000G in the big mansion, I&apos;ll consider Starphire. =)


 __________________
I wish I could live 1,000 years and get 1,000 PhDs. I have an infinite appetite to understand life.

Current Tank Info: 300G glass 10 foot x 2&apos; x2&apos;, 9 foot sump w/ 3&apos; fug 4&apos; frag, EuroReef CS12-2, Geo Reactor 624 30&quot;, 2x 250W DE MH, 3x 150W DE MH, RKE, 135G FOWLR w/ 50G sump ASM-G3, 50G QT w/15G sump, 12G Nano, 60G turtles.   
 
 whosjohnny View Public Profile Find More Posts by whosjohnny 
 
 12/01/2008, 11:05 PM  # 6 Mark426 Registered Member  
 Join Date: Dec 2005 Location: South Carolina Posts: 1,359 Quote:
	</body>
</document>
