<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009702" url="http://www.rr.com/local/TX/Corpus_Christi/4413073" time="2012-07-13-03:05" support="1" score="0.0004105076926602267" bingtitle="Local - Road Runner" webtitle="Local - Road Runner">
			<query id="000711" bing-rank="200"/>
	<description>Auto Racing; Soccer; Golf; Boxing | Game Tickets ... Antonio Zoo has revamped the east side of the park ... group called on it and 21 others to remove the fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Make RR my Homepage Download Toolbar MyServices Support Live Chat Search Enhanced by Google 
 News 
 Economy Politics Going Green Good News 
 Local TV 
 VideoStore 
 Entertainment 
 Summer Movie Guide Radio |   Concert Tickets Theater Tickets Celeb Style VideoStore Music Choice 
 Sports 
 Olympics NFL Baseball NBA NCAA Basketball NHL Tennis NCAA Football Auto Racing Soccer Golf Boxing |    Game Tickets 
 Finance 
 Mortgage Personal Finance Banking Center Investing Stocks Checking&amp;Savings Retirement 
 Shopping Games 
 Home Download Games Online games GamePass! Video Games All Games Crossword Play Four Sudoku Word Search 
 Autos Travel Dating Jobs Video 
 Video Store 
 
     
 
 
 More From Road Runner: ESPY Photos Kristin Chenoweth Tour de France Weather Forecast Rolling Stones Play Sudoku 
 
Local Weather
 »Extended Forecast 
 
Best Gas Prices

 Regular Mid Grade Premium Diesel 
     Last Updated 
Local Events
 
 Music Sports Family 
 Search Tickets 
 Search Corpus Christi (edit) 
 The Spurs set their summer league roster 

The San Antonio Spurs today announced their roster that will participate in the 2012 NBA Summer League, which runs from July 13-22 in Las Vegas. This year’s roster...

 »Read More 
 
 After 1,111 games, NBA legend Tim Duncan re-signs with the San Antonio Spurs 

Tim Duncan has been resigned with the San Antonio Spurs.“Tim Duncan has established himself as one...

 »Read More 
 
 Aztex clinch playoff berth 

The Austin Aztex clinched their place in the PDL playoffs on Sunday with a late goal securing a 1-0 win over the El Paso Patriots in El Paso.“We are in the playoffs now...

 »Read More 
 
 Obesity in San Antonio 

San Antonio is a diverse city that offers something for everyone. It has rich culture and history, vibrant parks, fun family theme parks and affordable cost of living. The City of...

 »Read More 
 
 Scoreless draw keeps Dallas streaks going 

It was a surprisingly tight match at FC Dallas Stadium as Dallas welcomed the San Jose Earthquakes, with neither side able to break through in a scoreless draw. Schellas Hyndman...

 »Read More 
 
 Your sunscreen choice could be providing you more harm than sunburn protection 

Are you getting burned by the sunscreen you use? Millions of people depend on sunscreen and expect protection from harmful ...

 »Read More 
 
Corpus Christi Caller-Times
 
 
 
 Windstorm rally set for Friday, rain or shine 

A rally against windstorm rate hikes Friday morning is set to go off, rain or shine.

 »Read More 
 
More News
 
 Corpus Christi-Nueces County health district can&apos;t confirm human West Nile virus case 

A Calallen woman was diagnosed with the mosquito-born illness last month by her doctor

 »Read More 
 
 Freer woman dies after stabbed in domestic dispute, police say 

The 33-year-old was stabbed repeatedly in the upper chest, police said

 »Read More 
 
 Man sleeping in restaurant reaches for knife, Corpus Christi police say 

Police had trouble waking a man about 11:45 p.m. Wednesday in a fast-food restaurant

 »Read More 
 
Local Reviews

 Restaurants Nightlife Entertainment 
 
Jobs Near You
 
Search Jobs
 Search 
 Business Jobs Computer Jobs Construction Jobs Customer Service Jobs Education Jobs Engineering Jobs Food&amp;Beverage Jobs Healthcare Jobs 
 
 Maintenance Jobs Management Jobs Non-Profit Jobs Office Jobs Part Time Jobs Restaurant Jobs Retail Jobs Sales Jobs 
 
 »Find More Jobs 
 
Odd Stories
 
 Stray dog dispute heads for Portland courtroom Hoax shooting suspect appears in Montana court Cop accused of stealing driver&apos;s iPhone from wreck 
 
Entertainment
 
 Arnold&apos;s back with &apos;Expendables&apos; at Comic-Con Future &apos;Assassin&apos;s Creed&apos; games may not leap ahead &apos;Wreck-it Ralph&apos; ventures into old arcade games 
 
Sports
 
 Kite has record-breaking 28 in 9 at US Senior Open 9 dead in Mont Blanc summer avalanche Column: Paterno loses the benefit of the doubt 
 Search Enhanced by Google 
 Home Mail Video TV Listings Radio 
 
 Channels News Sports Shopping Games Entertainment 
 
 Benefits Download IE Download Toolbar Premium Services more... 
 
 Road Runner Help 24x7 Live Chat Support Password Reset Self Care FAQs Web Mail Support 
 
   Security Abuse Tutorials Feedback Contact Us More ... 
 ©2012 Time Warner Cable Inc. All Rights Reserved. | Advertise with Us | Terms of Use | Web Privacy Policy | Your California Privacy Rights | TWC Subscriber Policies 
Time Warner Cable is a trademark of Time Warner Inc. Used under license. Road Runner is™and©Warner Bros. Entertainment Inc.
(s12)
	</body>
</document>
