<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009451" url="http://blog.vovici.com/blog/?month=6" time="2012-07-13-02:48" support="3" score="0.0034059886145590503" bingtitle="June | Survey Research &amp; Enterprise Feedback Management | Voice of ..." webtitle="June | Survey Research&amp;Enterprise Feedback Management | Voice of Vovici Blog">
			<query id="000260" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000328" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000072" bing-rank="193"/>
	<description>For B2C research, e-commerce sites and mail-order ... passenger seat with an extendable diner&apos;s tray or ... wash right after the drive-thru window of the fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Your email: 

     
 
Welcome to the Listening Post!

Your single source for everything Voice of the Customer (VoC) and Customer Experience (CxP). And, don’t forget you can follow us on twitter @vovici , or come check us out on Facebook and join the Vovici Network on LinkedIn .
   

 
 Current Articles |   RSS Feed 
 
 I Have Executive Sponsorship... Now What? 
 Posted by Nancy Porte on Thu, Jun 28, 2012 Tweet   
 When you begin setting up a Voice of the Customer (VoC) program for your organization, one of the most important steps is to find Executive Sponsorship. Without it, the program may have a difficult time succeeding–or worse, getting off the ground at all!

But what happens after you find that valuable executive who agrees to sponsor, support, and advocate for the program? Chances are the next step will be to set up the program governance. This is an essential step for a couple of reasons.

First, a Voice of the Customer program is a major enterprise undertaking–it is a combination of projects that bring about significant business and process improvements. As the program progresses, it needs to have linkage mechanisms that ensure alignment with stated business objectives. These mechanisms provide oversight to the program during the initial setup phase, as well as during execution. Most importantly, linkages help adjust the program to maintain alignment as the business strategies evolve.

There are many models for Voice of the Customer program governance. Following is one model that has worked for many organizations:

 Executive Sponsorship (direction&amp;oversight)

 Set program strategy and objectives Resource Customer Experience Program Management Office (PMO) Receive bi-weekly status updates from Customer Experience Team 
 Executive Team (alignment&amp;advising)

 Set strategy and ensure that customer experience measurements drive results Develop VoC program with VoC Program Management Monitor CSAT for their functional areas with responsibility for making improvements within those areas Determine cross-functional initiatives and provide resources for those customer experience initiatives Meet quarterly to review CSAT reports, monitor functional progress, and assign cross-functional projects 
 VoC Program Manager (management&amp;integration)

 Develop regular (monthly/quarterly) dashboards for the Executive team Define customer experience metrics for the company Develop customized VoC reports for different functional and project-based groups across the company Maintain list of top customer issues across the company Lead multi-disciplinary customer experience team and initiatives Make recommendations for improvements within different groups based on VoC analysis Track progress of VoC improvement programs across the company Train and coordinate VoC advocates across the company 
 

Once the governance structure has been defined, the next step is getting organized. Because of its organizational reach and responsibilities, a VoC program is not a single structure, but a series of integrated structures. Besides the PMO, there will need to be a multi-disciplinary team that reviews VoC data and analysis (we call ours the Vovici Customer Insight Team). In our case, they actively participate in identifying and solving customer process issues, and represent members from the sales, marketing, customer support, and product development teams. They also serve as internal advocates for the VoC program.

Establishing a governance framework is one of the most significant efforts for a successful VoC program. This framework helps support the long-term success of the program because it provides for alignment to business strategies, establishes clear decision making authority, and provides effective oversight and leadership.
 0 Comments Click here to read/write comments Tags:  Customer Relationship Management , Voice of the Customer , Customer Experience , Customer Loyalty , Customer Journey Mapping , Customer Experience Professionals , Customer Satisfaction , Customer Experience Management 
 Asking for Demographic Information can be Tedious, but Important 
 Posted by Sean Mahoney on Tue, Jun 26, 2012 Tweet   
 To see how opinions vary between different groups in your survey audiences, it is important to be able to compare and cross-tabulate sub-groups. To do this, you should use demographic and firmographic questions to profile respondents and their organizations. Firmographic means the characteristics of an organization, such as employee size, revenue size, industry, number of locations and location of headquarters.

Below are some sample demographic survey questions, many adapted from the U.S. Census.



 Question on gender: 
What is your sex?

 Male Female 

 Question on age: 
In what year were you born?           

 Question on marital status: 
What is your marital status?

 Now married Widowed Divorced Separated Never married 

 Question on education: 
What is the highest degree or level of school you have completed? If currently enrolled, mark the previous grade or highest degree received.

 No schooling completed Nursery school to 8th grade 9th, 10th or 11th grade High school graduate–high school diploma or the equivalent (for example: GED) Some college credit, but less than 1 year 1 or more years of college, no degree Associate degree (for example: AA, AS) Bachelor&apos;s degree (for example: BA, AB, BS) Master&apos;s degree (for example: MA, MS, MEng, MEd, MSW, MBA) Professional degree (for example: MD, DDS, DVM, LLB, JD) Doctorate degree (for example: PhD, EdD) 

 Question on employment status: 
Are you currently...?

 Employed for wages Self-employed Out of work and looking for work Out of work but not currently looking for work A homemaker A student Retired Unable to work 

 Question on employer type: 
Please describe your work.

 Employee of a not-for-profit, tax-exempt, or charitable organization Employee of a for-profit company or business or of an individual, for wages, salary, or commissions Local government employee (city, county, etc.) State government employee Federal government employee Self-employed in own not-incorporated business, professional practice, or farm Self-employed in own incorporated business, professional practice, or farm Working without pay in family business or farm 

 Question on housing: 
Is this house, apartment, or mobile home–

 Owned by you or someone in this household with a mortgage or loan? Owned by you or someone in this household free and clear (without a mortgage or loan)? Rented for cash rent? Occupied without payment of cash rent? 

 Question on household income: 
What is your total household income?

 Less than $10,000 $10,000 to $19,999 $20,000 to $29,999 $30,000 to $39,999 $40,000 to $49,999 $50,000 to $59,999 $60,000 to $69,999 $70,000 to $79,999 $80,000 to $89,999 $90,000 to $99,999 $100,000 to $149,999 $150,000 or more 

 Question on ethnicity: 
Please specify your ethnicity.

 Hispanic or Latino Not Hispanic or Latino 

 Question on race: 
Please specify your race.

 American Indian or Alaska Native Asian Black or African American Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander White 

Because these types of questions can be rather tedious it is best to place them near the end of the questionnaire whenever possible. Sometimes though, one or two demographic questions must be moved to the screener in order to appropriately route respondents.

If you can, try to pre-populate material from CRM systems into your survey before getting started so that respondents can update information rather than re-entering it. When integrating with CRM data, make sure to ask the questions in your survey the same way it is reported by your CRM system. If you are comparing your survey results to other data, such as U.S. Census estimates, make sure to use similar categories and questions as your sources.
 0 Comments Click here to read/write comments Tags:  Customer Relationship Management , Customer Satisfaction Surveys , Customer Service Surveys , Employee Satisfaction Surveys , Survey Research , Voice of the Customer , Customer Satisfaction , Customer Experience Management , Survey Best Practices , Voice of the Employee , VoE 
 When it comes to surveys what is the&quot;right length&quot;? 
 Posted by Sean Mahoney on Mon, Jun 04, 2012
	</body>
</document>
