<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009762" url="http://www.retailwire.com/discussion/9943/wendys-tests-drive-thru-only-stores" time="2012-07-13-03:09" support="2" score="0.0014329269457388728" bingtitle="RetailWire Discussion: Wendy&apos;s Tests Drive-Thru-Only Stores" webtitle="RetailWire Discussion: Wendy&apos;s Tests Drive-Thru-Only Stores">
			<query id="000919" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000928" bing-rank="135"/>
	<description>... themselves as being too busy to get out of their cars to order inside one of its restaurants. ... drive-thru lane at the typical fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Sponsorships/Ads |  About Us |  
 Company Staff Releases 
 Contact Us 
 Most recent discussions Browse discussions by
popular tags Submit a discussion topic 
 
 Browse Business Tips Sponsor Your Own Tip 
 
 See all panelists, A-Z Find a consultant for your business Submit a query to the panel See all BrainTrust resources 
 
 Retail Industry News Twitter Feeds Research Whitepapers Webinars Press Releases 
 
 Also see... 

Discussion Options:

 Submit a discussion topic Browse discussions by
popular tags Most recent discussions 
 
Latest Discussions:
 [17 Comments] Supervalu Exploring &apos;Strategic Alternatives&apos; [11 Comments] Michael Vick&apos;s Comeback Continues with Clothing Line [16 Comments] Teens Need Not Apply 
 Search for more... 
 
BUSINESS TIPS
 SellCheck:
Effective Promotional POS How to Evaluate the Effectiveness of Promotional POS CrossView:
Cross-Channel Shopper Experiences How Top Retailers Are Mobil-izing Gillette:
Men&apos;s Shaving Category A Major Growth Opportunity in Men&apos;s Shaving ... with Style SymphonyIRI Group:
Shopper-Centric Execution For Non-Foods New Products, Performance is Prized AT&amp;T:
Mobile Productivity Solutions Drawing a Mobile Strategy Roadmap P&amp;G:
Feminine Care Category The Value of a Unifying Brand Experience for Feminine Care Duracell:
Battery Category Creating Olympic In-Store Excitement Nestle Purina:
Winning Pet Care Shopper Loyalty Six Essential Principles Retailers Don&apos;t&quot;Get&quot;About Pet DemandTec:
Revolutionary Decisions A Revolution in Decision Making: Segmentation Plus Merchandising Optimization MarketingLab:
iShopper Marketing Evolution Acquisition and Retention: Finding the Balance Register/Log In Handle: Password: Keep me logged in Forgot your handle or password? 
 Click here to recover them via email. NEW TO RETAILWIRE? 
 CLICK HERE TO REGISTER 
It&apos;s quick, simple and FREE. Enter Email Address: 

Please add support@retailwire.com
to your spam filters. 

Credentials have been sent to the email address you provided. Please check your inbox. 

The email address you provided
was not found in our database. Home » Discussion Articles »Discussion Your Full Name: Your Email Address: Recipient Email Addresses
(one per line, up to 5): Optional Message For Recipient(s): Discussion Articles [0 comments] Wendys International · Eating Out · Store Design 
Wendy&apos;s Tests Drive-Thru-Only Stores
 June 21, 2004 
 Tweet 

 



 
 
By George Anderson

Wendy&apos;s knows many American consumers think of themselves as being too busy to get out of their cars to order inside one of its restaurants. One need only look at the long lines 
 in the drive-thru lane at the typical fast food restaurant, while inside only a few customers do their ordering the old-fashioned way.

That&apos;s why the number three hamburger chain is testing drive-thru and walk-up window only stores. The chain plans to have 13 in operation before the end of the year.

Tom Mueller, Wendy&apos;s North American chief operating officer, told Reuters , &quot;We spread them out in different markets and different types of demographic areas. The response 
 has been very positive.&quot;

Mr. Mueller says Wendy&apos;s generates up to 70 percent of its sales with drive-thru transactions.

 Moderator&apos;s Comment: What are your thoughts on Wendy&apos;s test of drive-thru and/or walk-up window only restaurants? 

 Personally speaking, we&apos;d miss the restaurants if they went away. We&apos;ve always found the 10 minutes spent going inside to get our Wendy&apos;s order more worthwhile 
 than waiting 15 minutes in the drive-thru lane. - 
 George Anderson - Moderator 

 Wendy&apos;s builds drive-through-only stores in test - Reuters/USA 
 Today 
 Discussion Questions 

 
 Display my name, title&amp;company 
 Display my handle only
 
 
 You may publish this comment 
 I agree to the RetailWire
       &quot; Golden Rule &quot; 
 
While we value unfettered opinion, we urge you to show respect and courtesy for people or companies about whom you comment.
 Keep in mind that this is a public, professional business discussion. RetailWire reserves the right to edit or refuse the
 publication of remarks that we deem unsuitable. We may also correct for unintended spelling and grammatical errors.
 

 THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENT 
Before posting, comments are first edited
 for spelling, grammar and appropriateness.
 Although we strive to publish all comments,
 we regret that it&apos;s not possible in all cases.
 You may contact us with questions.
 
Use the form above to add your comments.
 Search RetailWire
 Follow Us...
 
 RetailWire&apos;s
Getting Started video! 
 View this quick tutorial and learn all the essentials...
 HOME | DISCUSSIONS | BRAINTRUST PANEL | BUSINESS TIPS 
 Retail Industry News | Twitter Feeds | Research | Whitepapers | Webinars | Press Releases 
 Sponsorships/Ads | About Us | Staff | Releases | Contact Us 
 Privacy Pledge | Disclaimer and Terms of Use | Advanced Search | Register 
 ©2012 RetailWire LLC. All rights reserved. No part of the contents of this website may be reproduced
or transmitted in any form or by any means except as may be expressly permitted in writing by the copyright owner.
 0.406s·0·retailwire-com-v2-4-16·req 1 
 sp 
 Email Marketing Solutions&amp; Shopping Cart Abandonment 
 
 
Not registered? You&apos;re missing out on...

 Our top-quality eNewsletters! Participating in our great Discussions! Skads of free whitepapers and reports! 

And as a special THANK YOU for registering,
 you&apos;ll get a free, instant download of...
 The latest RetailWire Digest:

 Clicks &apos;n Bricks 
A round-up on four of our
 best discussions on the
 cross-channel revolution.
	</body>
</document>
