<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009296" url="http://www.43things.com/entries/view/5231659" time="2012-07-13-02:40" support="1" score="0.0010471799564514984" bingtitle="I tried! by Leezel on pay for the person behind me on 43 Things" webtitle="I tried! by Leezel on pay for the person behind me on 43 Things">
			<query id="001039" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>pay for the person behind me ... be pretty easy to do in a drive-thru at a fast-food restaurant ... register, the woman in front of me told the cashier ...</description>
	<body>
		Zeitgeist Login with
Facebook    Log in  or  Sign up 
 

 Sponsored Links 
 How To Stop Foreclosure 

 www.how-to-refinance-mortgage.info/    Change Lender In 3 Weeks! Avoid Three Common Mistakes.
 
 Pay People 

 www.ask.com/ Pay + People    Get Pay People Search for Pay People 
 
 Pay your network easily 

 www.tipalti.com/    Wide range of payment methods. $0 cost to payer. 1 line of code.
 
 Leezel will be at Comic Con this weekend!
 pay for the person behind me I tried! 
I was standing in the line at the post office. I had some packages with me to mail out. There was a guy after me who had a letter. As I put my things on the scale, I told him, casually,“go ahead, I’ll pay for your letter, it’ll be faster that way.”
He turned me down in the nicest way possible. He smiled, and told me he couldn’t take my money.
Boo.
 
 Jun 20, 2011, 10:50PM PDT | 7 cheers 

 
Comments:
 
 TechKat 
 
I bet this would be pretty easy to do in a drive-thru at a fast-food restaurant…first of all, they don’t know who you are…and secondly, they can’t do anything about it because you already paid for their food and drove away.
 
 Jun 20, 2011, 11:51PM PDT | Respond to this 1 cheer 
 
 Josh ...and life just rolls on like a river.
 
 I recently had someone... 
 
...do this to me. I was attending an accupressure class, and I went down stairs to a little shop to get a bottle of water because the instructor said we needed to stay well hydrated for the accupressure to be affective. As I was standing in line for the register, the woman in front of me told the cashier to get my water, too. At first I resisted, but she asked a second time and I let her. It made us both smile.
 
 Jun 30, 2011, 10:11AM PDT | Respond to this 10 cheers 
 
 Lanie the winds of change are blowin
 
I have a good friend that does this frequently. I’ve always wanted to do this myself, but havent had the nerve to follow through. Maybe I will try Techkat’s suggestion and give it a try at the drive-thru!
 
 Apr 11, 01:07PM PDT | Respond to this 1 cheer 
 
 Add a comment 
Leezel has gotten 7 cheers on this entry.

 sitruunapuu cheered this 6 months ago Thara43Things cheered this 10 months ago TroegPerdo cheered this 11 months ago Alexis Sogl cheered this 11 months ago xELx cheered this 12 months ago Josh cheered this 12 months ago TechKat cheered this 12 months ago 
 
 See all of Leezel&apos;s entries 

 See everyone with this goal 
 
 
 I want to: 
The world wants to...
 paint more InshaAllah memorize the Quran learn martial arts how to make a friendster layout using my picture? be loved ComicMedal wants to drink less alcohol be a vegetarian for a week stop being lazy get up on time Learn to cook Do NaNoWriMo play sims online learn to pick a lock Let go of the past Design and build my own house KatyLove wants to Grow in Christ be a good daughter go green grow my own vegetables Learn to play keyboard run with the bulls in Pamplona stop eating fast food learn fencing learn to sail a sailboat do yoga visit every MLB stadium See Pearl Jam live 
 City Hall 
 FAQ Guidelines Contact Us Tools 
 iPhone App RSS API About Us 
 Our blog Press coverage Terms of Use Follow @43things Copyright©2004 - 2012 Robot Co-op 
 
 43 Things Login 
 Username: Password: Remember me   Forgot username or password? 
 or Join 43 Things
	</body>
</document>
