<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009175" url="http://www.careerleak.com/fast-food-careers/" time="2012-07-13-02:34" support="1" score="0.0008438519117048277" bingtitle="Fast Food Careers | Job Reviews" webtitle="Fast Food Careers | Job Reviews">
			<query id="001358" bing-rank="126"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant Industry Facts. There are more ... registers and computerized order ... Fast Food Restaurant Industry Employment Statistics. Number of employees: 3,426,126 ...</description>
	<body>
		[ Close ] 
You are using Internet Explorer 6 which is over 10 years old. The Web has advanced, your browser has not! Please upgrade your browser to increase safety and your browsing experience. Choose one of the following links to download a browser: Firefox Safari Opera Internet Explorer 
 
 About CareerLeak Contact Us 
 Thursday, 12 July 2012 Loading 
 CareerLeak Home Job Reviews Know Before You Apply 
 Job Reviews by Employer Job Reviews by Industry 
 Accounting Admin Charity&amp;Non-Profits Construction Consulting Education Engineering Fast Food Financial Services&amp;Banking Government&amp;Civil Service Grocery Healthcare Health&amp;Fitness Hospitality Human Resources Information Technology Insurance Manufacturing&amp;Distribution Military News&amp;Media Pharmacy Restaurant Retail Services Technology Telecommunications Transportation Other 
 Job Reviews by Job 
 Salaries What Others Get Paid CareerLeak Blog Your Job Search Starts Here 
 See Our Guides Now You Know 
 How To Research Employers How To Negotiate Your Salary How to Follow Up on a Job Application 
 Blog Categories 
 Company Articles Interviews Jobs and Education Resumes 
 
 Job Search Find the Job You Want 

 Login 
 
 Username 
 

 Password 
 

 Remember Me 
 
 Forgot your password? Forgot your username? Create an account 
 
 
 
 Sign Up 
 Home Job Reviews 
Fast Food Jobs
 
 Fast food restaurants, also known as quick service restaurants, represent one of the largest sectors of the food industry. Fast-food restaurants range in size from a single establishment to huge franchised corporations such as McDonalds. The top companies are McDonald&apos;s Corporation, Pizza Hut, Inc., YUM! Brands Inc., The Wendy&apos;s Company, Burger King and Chick-fil-A. The United States is the world&apos;s largest fast food market.

International fast food companies, including YUM! Brands and McDonald&apos;s have been more successful than other fast food companies because explosive growth in emerging markets has offset rising costs and a slowdown in sales in the United States. Some companies such as Domino&apos;s and Sonic use new marketing campaigns and product innovation to increase growth and profitability. Many fast food companies are trying to increase revenue by offering high-margin and nontraditional menu items.

 
Fast Food Employment - Employer Reviews

 A&amp;W;Careers Burger King Careers Chick-Fil-A Careers
	</body>
</document>
