<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009375" url="http://www.logicsblog.com/index.php/roach_coach_meets_food_truck" time="2012-07-13-02:44" support="17" score="0.052093356671489684" bingtitle="Roach Coach meets Food Truck | Logic Talk" webtitle="Roach Coach meets Food Truck | Logic Talk">
			<query id="000536" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000348" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="000224" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="001479" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000598" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000881" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000661" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000806" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="001007" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000850" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="001133" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="001415" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000787" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="001447" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000724" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000099" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="001509" bing-rank="170"/>
	<description>... PM to 12:45 PM) would offer a menu board mounted to the left of the food order ... well, just about the same as a fast food restaurant ... Jewish Gift Cards; Orange County ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About Logic Logic&apos;s Bio Archives Contact 
 Tuesday, March 22, 2011 
 Roach Coach meets Food Truck 

 

 Is there nothing new in our society today? 
As a society Americans decade after decade merely reinvent the things that currently exist.


 
 Meet Logic 
 About today’s article 
Logic is going to share how the mobile food truck (catering truck) we know as the roach coach, came to be the popular and highly publicized fine food vehicles delivering items to customers from basic food dishes to designer and even exotic foods, created and prepared by chefs on board them today.


 Growing up around the Roach Coach 
As a child growing up in Orange County, within Southern California with my family and where my dad began an aerospace machine shop and manufacturing company in one of hundreds of 1200 to 3600 square feet Fullerton warehouse style buildings, known as the industrial area in our city, each unit came with a small front office and a giant pulls up door that opened up to an alley between these rows of buildings, and this setting is when I first meet the roach coach, a small Chevy or Ford truck cab, ran by a really nice older man (all people are old to a 7 year old boy) that had a rectangular enclosed diamond patterned stainless steel box called a food unit on the back of it, all made of stainless steel.


 
 The year was 1973 
It was the morning break time when a really cool sounding horn began blasting its tune in the alley outside that giant pull up warehouse door. At the age of 7 I did not know this sound until an employee working at my fathers new company described the sound being played out of this truck as an ice cream truck for adults, when we stepped outside there was this truck parked in the center of the alley way and a man emerged out of the trucks cab wearing one of those change machines (cash only credit cards were rare to have then) just like the neighborhood ice cream truck driver did. The man raced around from the driver’s side skipping the door behind the driver’s side of the truck cab and swinging up and opening the rear door first then racing around to the passenger side door and swing up and out this slightly larger door then the one on the rear of the truck.


 What was behind those 3 stainless steel doors? 
Describing these three stainless steel doors goes like this.
Each of these 3 doors swung up creating a shaded area for customers to view the catering trucks offerings. The door behind the driver’s side of the cab of the truck was where the man stored additional supplies, this door was never viewable by the customers, but none the less a very important door, it is where the cooler and warmer units were operated and maintained from.

 Time to meet the fun food 


 What was this roach coach offering? 
Behind the other two doors are where customers would come out or around too and see what was being offered, for all of us very hungry, hard working, laboring workers that mostly began their days before sunrise around 5:00 AM in the morning each day. The door behind the truck cabs passenger side was where the cold and room temperature items were located like, the soda dispensers, snack foods, cold sandwiches, chips, cookies, donuts, fruits, and candy bars were located on more stainless steel shelves. Below these 2 or 3 shelves there was a stainless steel trough filled with some fruit juices, plain and chocolate milks and scoop yourself shaved ice for your soda cups that this man also offered in 2 sizes.


 Behind the rear stainless steel door 
In the rear of the catering truck is where the hot items were offered.
The rear offered up coffee, hot water, and hot foods located behind a pair of acrylic (clear plastic) doors. The hot food choices were burritos, hot sandwiches, breakfast sandwiches, hamburgers, and hot dogs to mention a few.

 Scheduling the break and lunch times around the demands of the catering trucks schedule. 


 Small roach coach stops had to take what they could get and we did. 
Catering truck arrived for our AM break, lunchtime each weekday leaving us to fen for ourselves for our afternoon or PM break and nothing was offered for our nightshift, they still had to bring their meals to work with them.


 Father’s business grew and so did our demand for a bigger roach coach 
Moving on up required a larger space, more employees and a more sophisticated food catering operation.
From one industrial rental unit of 1200 square feet in all and 1 or 2 employees and family members in 1973 to many of these rented industrial units all stead out across the industrial complexes of southeast Fullerton 1979 utilizing more then 50000 square feet and nearer 50 employees spread out across several locations the demand to place most manufacturing operations under one roof in a company owned building was needed and along with this major move from Fullerton to Placentia a neighboring city with more space at the time worked out well for us.

 From Roach Coach to a Food Catering Truck with a cook and a kitchen. 


 Welcome to the 80’s 
It was 1980, a new decade and a growing commercial and defense manufacturing company was on the move.
The food types and the selections along with larger volume food demands came with this great company growth, a larger and more select choice of food services was in great need and from our location in Placentia up on a hill from the city boarder line to Anaheim and the home to Disneyland we could look out from the now larger aerospace complex and since we began work early in the mornings before sunrise we would see these lights just down the hill and in the city of Anaheim.


 
 Orange County Food Service moves and changes it business type. 
We will share why these people are shutting down near the end of this article.
Those bright lights were coming from the 10 acre operations center where the new style catering trucks were stationed, prepared, maintained, stocked up and where drivers and cooks mingled each day or night with one another, the company was Orange County Food Service that now is relocated in our city of Placentia, but under a new name and business type, the type is food vending.


 
 We discovered better food and a mobile kitchen 
What a time it was business was doing great, growth was being managed and that growth included the addition of a larger and fancy catering truck.
The first day this giant mostly all stainless steel van pulled up through the custom gates in the new alley of our new facility was a day that I will always remember. It was 8:45 AM or AM break time.
With the arrival of this new large van style catering truck (similar to a motor home or RV) came a new horn to make us all aware over the loud sounds that a manufacturing and machining operation creates that food and drink had arrived and all were invited through this cool sounding horn to join in and have some fresh, warm or cold foods, drinks, snacks, even cigarettes if you wish. 

 Sun Eight Co, Inc. 
Precision Machining
Circa 1973 to 1998
Father’s company continued business in Placentia beginning in 1979/1980 with a larger catering truck service that began serving us just before our relocation from Fullerton to Placentia and continued with us until my father sold this company in 1998, though the new owners more then likely still continued with Orange County Food Service for years to come.

 
 1980 catering truck 
How the van style Catering Trucks were laid out
The driver has direct access to the cooking work area from the driver’s compartment, same as a motor home offers.
The giant motor home style vans had all of their offerings behind 2 stainless steel doors on the passenger side of the van, each has a smoked glass window built into them, so the cook could see out while in transit and to add some aesthetics to the overall van the doors each opened up and out creating a shaded patio area. These two doors each had a handle and swung up on shock absorbers from about waist high to well above the average persons head.


 Honk if you are hungry 
When the catering truck arrived it sounded the horn, the driver would exit the van from the drivers side, open the two massive swing up doors then open up a small 2 foot square table to allow the people to lay down their selections before paying for them, the driver also wore a change machine (same as the catering truck drivers in 1973) on his belt and carried cash bills in an apron.  


 Food made to order 
Upon arrival
The cook remained inside the van on his or her feet ready to take menu orders from the customers that called out food by numbers or by name sometimes even taking special requests or customizing of the regular menu items.
One person favorite around the AM break time for me was a breakfast burrito that had scrambled eggs, strips of bacon and potato in it. Eggs on a plate with ham, sausage, or bacon with 2 slices of toast were a common AM break favorite for many fellow employees.


 Daily specials hot off the grill 
Lunchtime (12:15 PM to 12:45 PM) would offer a menu board mounted to the left of the food order window (at eye level) and all located on the right hand side of the catering truck near a pear of clear acrylic doors where ready prepared hot foods like hamburgers, breakfast burritos, and hot lunch sandwiches, to mention a few staples of these catering truck offerings were displayed. Specials would be hand written on card stock in red orblack sharing the special or specials for the day.

 Catering Trucks are a fading or even lost art today 


 Why traditional catering trucks dying off? 
Not for the reason you might be thinking, that those latest trend foodie trucks have taken over, that would be a false answer. The true reason for the disappearance on many of the catering services fading away come form the lack of businesses that create products today, at least for the most part.


 Allow me to expand about the dying catering truck.   
While construction is down reducing the requirement for catering trucks it was manufacturers that drove the need for these catering trucks and keep them as a staple in the lives of manufacturing employees since moist all manufacturing plants were/are located in areas of cities that did/do not have a retail center or residents to things needed to operate a successful food store or restaurant. Then there was the time restraint for these hard working men and women to actually get form the manufacturing plant to these nearby eating places and back in time to begin working again, then finally the most important fact, that these workers enjoyed one another and spent their break and lunch times together like a happy family.


 My last meal from a catering truck, roach coach or food truck 
The year was 1992 when I left the family aerospace manufacturing business to join my hide and go seek partner and best friend of over 35 years to begin a computer controller manufacturing and software development business in May 1993.


 
 Do I miss the Roach Coach? 
Yes and No.
 Yes it was fun to hangout with my coworkers 3 times a day, but No the food and in fact all food from a catering or food truck is well, just about the same as a fast food restaurant is to us all today and similar to my favorite fast food chain and weekly experience at Taco Bell.
Trendy as it is to get food from a street corner made by a chef or graduate of a famous cooking school might be for those that have not ever experienced the true catering truck, the end result is that a food truck even wrapped in fancy graphics and exotic dishes being offered will still not replace the full atmosphere and cooking options that a true brick and mortar restaurant offers us all today.

The final thought is that in the end, the food truck is no more then a modern day camouflaged Roach Coach.
Enjoy
 Posted by admin in• Logics Bla Bla Blog Talk 
(0) Comments • Permalink 
Subscribe
 
   Subscribe to my Posts (RSS) 
 Subscribe to Logic Talk by Email
 
 

Search

 
 
 Advanced Search 

Categories

 California Authority Domain Name Investing Logics Bla Bla Blog Talk Marketing Tips 

Most recent posts

 Lady GaGa goes it alone Happy in the Desert New name of Facebook revealed Eyewear Innovations Got Drops? Star Trek Gold and Silver Coins Facts that will Floor U Americans are aging Light Targets Viper Logic Corp. Palm Springs, CA. Personal Domain Names Palm Springs Events Watch Service Palm Springs Linkedin.com/in/logic Cartoon Signs 
 
 
Total Entries: 642
Total Comments: 21
Total Trackbacks: {total_trackbacks}
Most Recent Entry: 07/10/2012 10:11 am
Most Recent Comment on: 09/26/2011 09:32 am
Total Members: 1089
Total Logged in members: 0
Total guests: 13
Total anonymous users: 0
Most Recent Visitor on: 07/12/2012 04:44 pm
The most visitors ever was 231 on 12/04/2010 07:55 pm
 Copyright©2008-2012 Viper Logic Corp., All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
