<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009251" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Solon/Quiznos_499" time="2012-07-13-02:38" support="1" score="0.001242727185875281" bingtitle="Quiznos - Fast Food Restaurant Solon, OH 44139" webtitle="Quiznos - Fast Food Restaurant  Solon, OH 44139">
			<query id="000934" bing-rank="198"/>
	<description>Quiznos is a Fast Food restaurant located at 33411 Aurora Rd in ... Fuckers like to leave the door open and freeze you ... Quiznos Restaurants - maps and store locator</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Quiznos
 
Average User Rating
 
5
 
Average
 
Sponsored Link


 
(440) 498-4900

 http://quiznos.com/ 
 OH &gt; Solon &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Quiznos listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Quiznos to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Social 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Quiznos
 Quiznos is a Fast Food restaurant located at 33411 Aurora Rd in Solon, OH 44139. Quiznos has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 5 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Quiznos
 
 
 
All Reviews for Quiznos


 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Quiznos:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   0

 
Comments
 
 
Quiznos Tips
 Fuckers like to leave the door open and freeze you out
 
Daniel D. 
Quiznos News
 UPDATE: Subway To Open At Hunt Valley Towne Centre A Subway restaurant is opening soon at the ... or in person at the Exxon On-The-Run/Subway at 11235 York Road in Cockeysville. The new Subway is located in the space formerly occupied by Quiznos, another chain sub shop. The Morning Leverage: An Exit ‘Fur’ Hammond Kennedy Freeman Spogli is adding to its restaurant ... News report the firm wrapped up its latest mid-market fund in around four months, roughly the same time it took for fellow Nordic investor HitecVision to close its latest vehicle. Sandwich chain ... Quiznos eyes possible Ch. 11 bankruptcy protection DENVER—Quiznos says a majority of its creditors have agreed to a plan by the restaurant chain to restructure or pay ... to invest $150 million of new equity capital into the chain. The investment would be made up of equity and the conversion of debt ... Baby formula pulled from shelves More taking long holiday trips NEW YORK - More Americans ... massive central bank support. Quiznos may file for bankruptcy DENVER - Quiznos says a majority of its creditors have agreed to a plan by the restaurant chain to restructure or pay ... How a Franchise Can Play the Real Estate Market Beef &apos;O&apos; Brady&apos;s is also putting a new emphasis on site selection. In 2010, it teamed with Site Analytics, a New York-based data company that ... for franchisees needing rent relief. In 2009, Quiznos fielded several teams to help struggling ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Quiznos Restaurants - Sub Sandwich Restaurant Quiznos Restaurants offer toasty sandwiches, fresh salads, and delicious soups. Visit us online for more info your favorite Sub Sandwich, catering services, coupons ... Quiznos Restaurants - maps and store locator Find a Quiznos sandwich restaurant near you. Enter your zipcode and find a quiznos near you. Quiznos - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia Quiznos is a fast casual restaurant franchise based in Denver, Colorado. The company specializes in offering toasted subs, although they may be served untoasted at ... Quiznos Sub Locations - Quiznos Sub Restaurant Locator Are you looking for a filling and healthy meal prepared fast? Find your favorite sub or sandwiches at Quiznos Sub. Use our Quiznos Sub restaurant locator list to find ... Quiznos - Quiznos Restaurants in Houston TX - Houston Restaurants Quiznos sandwich restaurants in Houston serve toasty sub sandwiches food delivery services, and restaurant catering services. Visit Quiznos restaurants online to fine ... 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 88° 
Fri
 
 64° - 84° 
Sat
 
 70° - 84° 
Sun
 
 72° - 88° 
 
Address
 
Quiznos

33411 Aurora Rd

Solon, OH 
 
44139
 
Telephone
 (440) 498-4900 
Quiznos
 
 Rating :  5 out of 10 based on 5 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Quiznos Photos
	</body>
</document>
