<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009422" url="http://qmato.com/restaurant/mediteran-lansing" time="2012-07-13-02:47" support="9" score="0.011395036012179399" bingtitle="Mediteran, Lansing, MI - Qmato" webtitle="Mediteran, Lansing, MI - Qmato">
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000298" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000663" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000658" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="000590" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="001009" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000578" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="000569" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000564" bing-rank="149"/>
	<description>Enter an address or place name ... This is not a &apos;fast food&apos; restaurant so plan on a relaxing visit ... coffee shop and he graciously took care of my order ...</description>
	<body>
		Lansing, MI 
 Address or place name (optional) 
 City, State, or ZIP Enter an address or place name 
 Find my current location No recent locations 
 
 
 Restaurant guide Qmato mobile Share Qmato 

 Sign in Join 
 
 Write a review Favorite Add to list Suggest to… 
 
Mediteran

 4.6 Saving… 4.6 stars from 49 votes

 Balkan , Greek • $$ $$ 
 333 S Washington Sq 
 Lansing , MI 
 517-372-1072 

 www.restaurantmediteran.com 
 
 Overview Large map Write a review 
 
Mediteran serves fresh Balkan and Greek food in a pleasing environment that people report is &quot;lovely&quot;. Their moderately priced menu is considered an excellent value. Visitors notice their great service, and they especially recommend their lunch offering. Some customers were disappointed by poor service.

Known for its excellent value and as an outstanding lunch spot.
 Recommended: spinach pie, insalata caprese, pesto, sandwiches, salads Details: Lunch, dinner, table service, outdoor seating, delivery 
 Meal times 

 Lunch Dinner 
 
 Services 

 Table service Take-out Delivery Catering Reservations accepted 
 
 Features 

 Private room Outdoor seating 
 
 Attire 

 Casual 
 
 Accessibility 

 Wheelchair accessible 
 
 Update or add to this information 
 
 Write a review Directions   
 
Reviews

Sort by: date | rating 
 First reviewed by happygirl19 
 

the cultural experience
 this restaurant is a great place. Food is home made and honestly for just under $7.00 downtown Lansing you cannot get a better food. For all those who have experienced the owner and thought he was rude I have an answer: it is a cultural thing. This guy is from another part of the world, he is not rude, but actually pretty entertaining. He is actually quite humorous and sarcastic.Give a guy a break and appreciate a cultural differences. Apr 23, 2011 • Report this review 
 

My Favorite
 This is my favorite restaurant in Lansing. Great food, lovely setting, Old World service. The owner may seem haughty sometimes but he&apos;s really a sweatheart. The place is certainly a great value. Mar 06, 2011 • Report this review 
 

Thank You, Lucille Belen!
 Reading the reviews, I feel I must stand up for the owner of the Mediteran! I have eaten there often, and can tell you that the restaurant may have been empty at 11:30, but by 12:00, it was filled with loyal patrons from the Capital and from Cooley Law School...who do have reservations! Like them, I respect the fact that they do not try to rush you through so they can have more seatings! The food is worth waiting for!

I have many reasons to thank my dear friend, Lucille Belen...the Mediteran is one of them! It was a favorite of Lucille&apos;s, and for years we delighted in a birthday lunch or dinner to celebrate her birthday, between Christmas and New Years. Sadly Lucille has passed away last spring, but I will continue to enjoy everything about this charming restaurant! KathyPetz • Jan 06, 2011 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

the best of downtown!
 great food and friendly service. yes the owner is a bit abrupt at first (after getting to know him, i dont think he means to be rude...i think its really just his eastern european background). at any rate the food makes up for it by far. also, once you are in there a few times he gets a lot friendlier. i make reservations just because then i dont have to worry about waiting...but i have showed up with no reservation and have been seated promptly. the food is out of this world and quite reasonably priced for what you get. but if you want to be put off by the owner not kissing up to you, its ok because it just means more food and less of a wait for me! :) Jun 24, 2010 • Report this review 
 

Jan 22, 2009 Reservations ?
 I ate at this restaurant twice last summer and enjoyed the food and was never asked for a reservation. I went in Friday thinking it was the same restaurant and was treated rudely about reservations. A sign on the door&quot;Reseravtions Only&quot;would not be to much to ask for.

I never thought this restaurant was higher class than the Greek restaurants on Monroe Street in Detroit, but they seem to want to act as though they are.

A sign out front notifying people of a change in policy isn&apos;t to much to ask??? jbutera • Jan 22, 2010 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Great food, incredible atmosphere and family own
 This restaurant is the best eatery downtown and the most inviting atmosphere in all of Lansing.
Those who went to Sultans after being put off by the&quot;abrupt manner&quot;of the maitre d&apos; should probably not have gone there in the first place.....no comparison.. at Sultans you are a number.... get a life! Dec 21, 2009 • Report this review 
 

Reservations?
 Did anyone ever think that the question of whether one has a reservation is simply so it can be fulfilled properly? Come on people - use your heads! bv2959iii • Oct 14, 2009 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Loved It!
 My friend and I ate at the Mediteran recently not knowing anything about the restaurant. What a pleasant surprise. The food was delicious. We&apos;ll be back. gardenguile • Oct 10, 2009 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Fantastic Owner
 I don&apos;t know how anyone could get bad treatment by the server/owner of the Mediteran. They probably misunderstood him. I&apos;d guess he asked them if they _wanted_ reservations (not if they _had_ reservations). The food is awesome. The best side salad I&apos;ve had anywhere, great pork medallions, and the best chocolate mousse pie I have had in a long time! The owner&apos;s accent is a little strong, so if you&apos;re not sure what he said, just ask. He makes it his job to please you. Jun 05, 2009 • Report this review 
 

Best place ever! Take some advice from me.
 I have eaten at this establishment for over 3 years. Almost every lunch and dinner while I attended law school. The fact is that the owners do not like impolite diners. It is not personal. If he does not seat you, you should have made a reservation. In addition, his kitchen cannot handle a ton of orders, so rather than have you wait and hour for your lunch/dinner, he does not seat you. It&apos;s not personal. There is only one chef: his wife. These disgruntled folks are missing out. Make a reservation and go. The food is outstanding and I would not eat anywhere else in downtown Lansing! May 12, 2009 • Report this review 
 

A true European experience
 I am married to a German and understand the brusque personality. Even though prospective customers may not like it, the host won&apos;t lose any sleep over your opinion either.
We have been guests at Mediteran for several years, always asked if we have a reservation, never have, but always seated if an empty table exists.
The food is plentiful and delicious. It is presented beautifully and the waiter is always pleasant when he serves us (very different than his greeting at the door). Just like the other Germans/Croatians I know, the experience is worth the initial agravation. Americans think that everything revolves around them. Don&apos;t take it personally - it&apos;s not about you, it may be about the others that came first. VaticantToo • May 11, 2009 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Looking for a great dining deal in Lansing?
 Wow - fantastic food, great atmosphere, and a very reasonable price. There are restaurants that you could pay twice as much at and not have near as enjoyable the experience at. From the salad, the homemade bread, and the daily specials (I have yet to have one that I didn&apos;t find exceptionally tasty) the presentation, the quality and the freshness is hard to find in any other restaurant in downtown Lansing near the price of this one. adekoninck • Oct 16, 2008 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

I Wish I Did&apos;Nt Have To Share!
 This is probably the hardest review I have ever had to write.
You want to keep such a wonderful place with such great food and service a secret, but you also wnat them to make a living.
So with that in mind here is my tale.

Thanks to the rating received on restaurantdb.net, I was led to Mediteran.

I could not believe the quality of food and the wonderful atmosphere of this little restaurant.

Mr. Jurkovic and his staff provide wonderful dishes of food that are absolutely fantastic. To feed a family of five with fresh bread, salads, main course with coffee and dessert for under $65.00 was amazing. Food like this anywhere else would have been double.

To tell or not to tell has been my dilemma since dining here. I have spilled the beans so go forth and enjoy all that is Mediteran!

I wish there were more quality restaurants like this in Lansing! AMOUTDOORS • Sep 15, 2008 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Take it with a grain of salt...
 ...not the food, but your greeting! Food is fabulous, but it is true, the owner and host can be a bit abrupt at the door. The restaurant is family owned and operated and they only seat the dining room once during the lunch hour - it isn&apos;t about speed - it&apos;s about quality and enjoying your meal. Even if it doesn&apos;t look full - it will be. My advice: always make a reservation and be prepared for wonderful entrees, breads, soups and desserts. LB2007 • Sep 04, 2008 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Simply Delicious
 LUNCH - Our meal was delicious and service was wonderful. We thought the salad and bread were the best but the entree&apos;s and homemade desert surpassed our expectations. This is not a &apos;fast food&apos; restaurant so plan on a relaxing visit with time to enjoy your mean and ambiance. Reservations are strongly recommended. Most likely, you may not be seated without them. kimrick • Jun 17, 2008 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Food to remember
 Wow! The man who greeted me at this restaurant, the owner&amp;resident artist, was kind, welcoming, friendly, and generous. I stopped in thinking it was a coffee shop and he graciously took care of my order (take out sandwiches) and treated me to a cold drink and good conversation while I waited. The sandwiches were absolutely the best I have had in years. They were a gourmet experience. He even threw in a few bars of chocolate as a surprise. I loved my food, enjoyed the restaurant, and thought the service was terrific. PabloPicasso • Jun 04, 2008 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Oh Oh...
 So here goes,,,, a friend topld me about the place and I being who I am decided to stop in and try it. I showed up on a typical lunch hour. I was greeted not by&quot;welcome in&quot;or&quot;how are you today&quot;but simply... Do you have a reseravation? I replied no. The&quot;whoever he was&quot;quickly set the menus he had piked up aside and walked away. There were empty tables... he gave no explanation as to how to even make reseravtations. I quickly turned, placed my tails between my legs and walked away to Sultans. There they welcomed me with open arms and a credit card machine. No soup for me. di3d2002 • May 22, 2008 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Wonderful Dining Experience
 We visited this restaurant because we have always wanted to try Balkan food. Previous descriptions of food from Eastern Europe had often seemed somewhat unappealing (rich but bland, etc.) so I did not know what to expect. However, this dining experience absolutely exceeded all my expecations. The service was very kind and attentive without being intrusive. I am sorry to hear that others had negative experiences in this area - we were not asked for a reservation, and were respectfully treated. The atmosphere was very pleasant and comfortable, and every single piece of food that was placed in front of us was delicious. I recommend the sampler platter for dinner, from which you can try all of the &apos;Balkan specialities&apos;. Every one is outstanding (there is a danger of overeating, since you will want to finish all of them), and the cucumber dip enhanced every flavor further. The salad was intricate and all the ingredients were amazingly fresh. Lastly the dessert was delicate and flavor-rich (a type of mocha torte). It should be noted that the amount of food received for a very reasonable price is just one more reason to visit restaurant Mediteran. Highest recommendation. Natasha2000 • Apr 26, 2008 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Dinner in Downtown Lansing
 I have never been asked for a reservation at this place at dinner or lunch, weekday or on Saturdays. I think the reviewers above may be stretching the truth.

The food is unique - I would recommend trying the daily special whenever you are there.

Tip: if you have not tried the spinach pie here, please do. It is the best I&apos;ve ever had. EastLansingFood • Apr 26, 2008 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Reservations -- for this place?
 I was able to try this establishment once&amp;really enjoyed it -- then when a couple co-workers and I went back same story as several other reviewers ... the&quot;gate keeper&quot;said&quot;reservation?&quot;and when we said no, he told us to leave.

This is not a high class establishment&amp;most of the tables were EMPTY!

I&apos;ll never go back. laurenloo • Mar 28, 2008 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Where&apos;s the customer service??
 Three of us also walked into the restaurant with a $100 gift certificate ready to spend, spend, spend and were greeted by the same rude server (owner???) that I see others have encountered, who asked if we had a reservation. When we said no, he said no and turned on his heel and left us standing there. We were dumbstruck and stood there a moment, hoping for, I don&apos;t know what. Maybe some customer service?? Maybe a suggestion of&quot;I&apos;m sorry, but the wait will be over an hour, can I make a reservation for you for later?&quot;Something, anything. But we basically got slapped. Although I&apos;ve heard the food is good, the insolence is unacceptable. I can&apos;t even rate the food or ambience because I didn&apos;t get past the door. I&apos;m going down the street to Tavern on the Square where I&apos;m always greeted with a smile and the service is excellent...as is the food. Oldtownbrewcrew9 • Mar 26, 2008 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Great food Downtown!
 I have never had a bad experience with this restaurant or food that was anything less than fantastic. Excellent eastern European lunch menu including everything from spinach pie to cevapi!. Salad and fresh bread with every meal and quite a classy environment. Fine dining downtown with many choices for under $10 per meal! arturo420 • Feb 17, 2008 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Probably the best restaurant in the area
 I saw that Meditaran had good reviews on DB, so my husband and I went to try it out last night. This is the cutest restaurant- beautifully decorated Christmas trees are everywhere and it is just so cheery and festive without being cheesy. The service was great and the food was amazing. Think enough homemade food to feed 4 people for 19.50. Our dinner even came with a fruit arrangement and dessert, which we had no idea until the waiter brought it out. Definitely give this place a try! Yummfood • Nov 28, 2007 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

The most rude and degrading host ever!!
 I have previously dined at Mediteran- and enjoyed it. A friend and I went there to have lunch today, and was greeted with&quot;Reservation?&quot;by the host. We responded&quot;no&quot;. His response was&quot;No&quot;and walked away leaving us standing in the doorway- There is nothing posted&quot;reservations only&quot;and a few tables with no&quot;reserved&quot;signs on them. I understand having reservations and if I had known I would have made one- but the manner in which we were treated was horrible and embarrassing. Be sure of one thing- although the food is fabulous, my friend and I will not ever grace this establishment again. dwntwnpeople • Jun 19, 2007 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

The BEST Place for First Date
 Based on the review here, I tried this place out, and from the outside I wondered if I was even at the right location. I always figured it was the place that spelled&quot;Mediteranian&quot;wrong, but looks were deceiving. This is the best restaurant in Lansing. Period. Their lunch specials are increadible. You can satisfy two people for lunch for less than $15. I have never been less than *astounded* at how good the food is. Bean soup on Fridays is my favorite, and I figured that since the spinach pie was so cheap that it wouldn&apos;t be as good, I was wrong, and it turned out bigger than my outstretched hand.

There was one time the service was unattentive, but other times they will outright GIVE you a tiramisu to finish your meal. It&apos;s a bit of a crapshoot in this respect, but overall it&apos;s a great place I recommend to friends. malavidava • Mar 16, 2007 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

What a surprise!
 I had walked by this restaurant dozens of times, but had never ventured in until recently. Boy was I surprised! I was expecting a small take-out type place as is the usual downtown, but the place is decorated very nicely, and while I assume you can get takeout, its really a very nice dine-in restaurant.

The service was excellent. The waiter brought us some homemade bread right away which was very good, and the rest of the meal didn&apos;t dissapoint. The menu has a number of sandwiches for the lunch crowd, and a variety of Eastern-European themed dishes for dinner. The prices are reasonable for the portions you get.

I&apos;ll deifnitely be back! Slick99 • Aug 18, 2006 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Fabulous Food
 The Mediteran is one of the best restaurants in downtown Lansing. The service is always good and the daily specials are fabulous. We also enjoy the fact that is is a family-run establishment. We dine in at least once or twice a week.

I would highly recommend it to anyone and hope that they never move from their current location. happygirl19 • Jun 19, 2006 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
More information
 
 www.restaurantmediteran.com Read more on TripAdvisor and Foursquare Search Google or Bing 

Know more? Update or add to this information 

Or, let us know if this restaurant has closed 
 

 
Similar cuisine
 
 Zeus&apos; Coney Island 

Greek • $ $$$ 
 Georgio&apos;s Gourmet Pizzeria 

Greek • $ $$$ 
 Olympic Broil Restaurant 

Greek • $ $$$ 
 Bell&apos;s Greek Pizza 

Greek
 
 
Nearby guide
 
 Vegetarian friendly Best for dinner Best for lunch Tasty takeout Meal with the kids Most popular Hidden gem Best for breakfast Authentic cuisine Good food, good value 
 
 Add a restaurant About Blog Mobile Contact Sitemap Terms and Privacy policy 

Copyright©2012 RestaurantDB.
 This page was served to you in 0.439 sec.
	</body>
</document>
