<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009548" url="http://www.losangeles.com/restaurants/woodland-hills.html" time="2012-07-13-02:56" support="3" score="0.0032855057078052903" bingtitle="Woodland Hills Restaurants | Los Angeles Restaurants | LA Dining ..." webtitle="Woodland Hills Restaurants | Los Angeles Restaurants | LA Dining&amp;Reservations">
			<query id="000296" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="001396" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="001017" bing-rank="207"/>
	<description>A guide to restaurants in Woodland Hills. Book tables online and read reviews.</description>
	<body>
		Free! 
 List your event | List your business | View categories 
 
 Sign in | Register | Mail 
 
 Restaurants | Hotels | Attractions | Nightlife | Events | Tickets | Real Estate | Jobs | Directory 

 
 
Woodland Hills Restaurants
 VIEW BY: 
 Cuisine Area 
 
 All Cuisine Afghan African American Argentinian Asian Fusion Barbeque Brazilian Breakfast Cafés Burger Joints Burmese Cajun/Creole California Cambodian 

 Caribbean Caterers Chinese Cuban Diners Eastern European Fast Food French Filipino German Global Cuisine Greek Hawaiian Indian/Pakistani 

 Indonesian Italian Japanese Korean Latin American Live Music Malaysian Mediterranean Mexican Middle Eastern Moroccan Noodle Houses Nuevo Latino 

 Pizza Russian Salad Bars Sandwich Shops Singaporean Cuisine Seafood Soul Food Spanish Food Steak Supper Clubs Thai Vegetarian Vietnamese 
 
 Featured Restaurants 
 Downtown L.A. 
 Beverly Hills Brentwood Culver City Fullerton Hollywood 

 Huntington Beach Irvine La Quinta Long Beach Malibu Marina del Rey 

 Newport Beach Pasadena Santa Monica Sherman Oaks Thousand Oaks Torrance 

 Venice West Hollywood West Los Angeles Westwood Woodland Hills Anaheim 
 
As the premier urban district of the San Fernando Valley, Woodland Hills is one of the fastest growing areas of Southern California. By virtue of the rapidly increasing population, this beautiful city is constantly increasing the number of dining and entertainment options. From delicious family-style restaurants to gourmet steakhouses, Woodland Hills has a restaurant for every occasion. While dining in Woodland Hills, it isn&apos;t uncommon to see stars like America Ferrera, Kim Basinger, Dr. Dre, Will Smith or Brad Garrett at a nearby table, since they are some of the area&apos;s most famous residents of both past and present.
 Join other local businesses. Get listed on this page. + Add your business 
 Amaranta Cocina Mexicana 
6600 Topanga Canyon Blvd., Ste. 1029, Canoga Park CA 91303 Mexican/Southwestern. Authentic Mexican cuisine is at this Los Angeles restaurant in Woodland Hills and Canoga Park. Amaranta Cocina Mexicana has a relaxing dining room with river pebble flooring and blown glass lights. Every Thursday features live music from the house band, and monthly tequila tastings are held with over 400 varieties. An intricately-detailed private dining room is available for a cocktail reception or family dinner party. A separate to-go store sells pre-packaged foods for take out, using the same recipes from the restaurant menu. 
 Arnie Morton’s The Steakhouse—Woodland Hills 
6250 Canoga Ave., Woodland Hills CA 91367 Steakhouse. Arnie Morton’s The Steakhouse is a famous chain restaurant known for its luxurious setting and high-grade USDA Prime-aged steaks. This Los Angeles restaurant in Woodland Hills brings out main entrees and fresh produce to dining tables on a signature cart. Private banquet rooms are available for special events, and a full bar with large wine selections are extra amenities for fine dining. Arnie Morton’s The Steakhouse has accolades and glowing reviews from all across the country, including Wine Spectator’s 2008 Award of Excellence. 
 Bistro Ka 
6600 Topanga Canyon Blvd., Ste. 2010A, Canoga Park CA 91303 Japanese. The yakitori grill, sushi bar and well-crafted Japanese cuisine are the main attractions of Bistro Ka. This Los Angeles Japanese restaurant in Canoga Park offers traditional classic food fused with influences from California cuisine. Located in the Topanga Canyon Mall, this is a casual dining place appropriate for all patrons. Despite this, the fashionably modern décor is reminiscent of a more upscale place. Various vegetarian dishes are available, including agedeshi tofu and vegetable tempura. 
 Gyu-Kaku—Topanga Canyon 
6600 Topanga Canyon Blvd., Ste. 1010B, Canoga Park CA 91303 Japanese. Located in the Westfield Topanga Center mall, this Japanese restaurant in Canoga Park offers authentic Japanese BBQ. Barbeque grills are located at every table for diners’personal cooking of fresh beef or other sizzling dishes. The courteous staff can help with any questions on how to use the grills, and a bar is available for sake and beer. 
 Kate Mantilini 
5921 Owensmouth, Woodland Hills CA 91367 American. Kate Mantilini serves traditional American comfort food, fresh seafood, and prime dry-aged steaks. BBQ ribs, chicken pot pie, sandwiches, and New York steaks are popular items that can be seen freshly grilled in the open kitchen for diners to see. This steakhouse in Woodland Hills offers both booth and outdoor patio seating. Sundays feature brunch. 
 Maggiano’s—Woodland Hills 
6100 N. Topanga Canyon Blvd., Woodland Hills CA 91367 Italian. Little Italy is a self-dubbed nickname for Maggiano’s restaurant, where a 300-seat dining room and outdoor patio seating makes this a prime location for hosting events for celebrity-heavy charities or banquets. Located near the Getty Center and Ronald Reagan Library, visitors can stop by Maggiano’s for a family-style Italian meal. This Los Angeles restaurant in Woodland Hills has been a dining destination for stars like Will Smith. Takeout and delivery services are available. 
 Monty’s Steakhouse 
5371 Topanga Canyon Blvd., Woodland Hills CA 91364 Steakhouse. Monty’s Steakhouse offers hearty meals of steak and seafood. This Los Angeles restaurant in Woodland Hills features live jazz and pop music on weekends. Monty’s featured desert is bread pudding, and a stocked bar offers freshly mixed cocktails. The bar lounge is filled with flat screen plasma TVs to catch the most exciting sports games. 
 Profile Bar&amp;Grill 
20969 Ventura Blvd., Ste. 32, Woodland Hills CA 91364 Continental. Fine dining on Continental cuisine, seafood and steaks can be found in Profile Bar&amp;Grill. This Los Angeles restaurant also features a full bar, private room and outdoor patio area. From Sunday through Thursday is a special“Sunset Dinner”meal for $16. Plush booth seats and wooden chairs complement the linen cloth tables, which provide a classy and romantic place to dine. The bar features plasma TVs for the latest sports games, as well as a selection of fine wines. 
 Ruth&apos;s Chris Steak House 
6100 Topanga Canyon Blvd, Suite #1360, Woodland Hills, CA 91367-3627 Situated in the Westfield Shopping Towne Promenade Mall, Ruth&apos;s Chris serves broiled USDA Prime beef, fresh seafood and seasonal specialties. With an award winning wine list and great service, this Woodland Hills restaurant is sure to please each guest. Online reservations suggested. 
 Villa Piacere 
22160 Ventura Blvd., Woodland Hills CA 91364 Californian. Serving delicious and creative cuisine since 1981, the Villa Piacere restaurant also boasts its own brick courtyard that provides an intimate and beautiful setting for any special occasion or banquet. An alcove at the back features a romantic water fountain and lights on the trees, where small weddings have been conducted. This California fusion restaurant in Woodland Hills has been considered to be one of the area’s best-kept secrets. The interior dining area has the feel of a warm and cozy Italian country house. Join other local businesses. Get listed on this page. + Add your business Back to Top Reserve Now for Restaurants on OpenTable.com 
 Opaque 
Dining in the Dark →Reserve Table 
 The Stinking Rose 
A Garlic Restaurant →Reserve Table 
 Locanda Veneta 
Northern Italian Cuisine in Beverly Hills →Reserve Table Advertise | Contact Us | Site Map | List Your Business | List Your Event 
 Copyright 2012 LosAngeles.com: A City Guide 
 by Boulevards . All rights reserved.  Terms of Service   Privacy Policy .
	</body>
</document>
