<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009694" url="http://www.justbestrecipes.com/salad/burger-king-original-zesty-sauce.html" time="2012-07-13-03:05" support="2" score="0.0024776245435595584" bingtitle="» Burger King Original Zesty Sauce - Best recipes on the web" webtitle="Burger King Original Zesty Sauce">
			<query id="000409" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="001154" bing-rank="163"/>
	<description>... diminishing quality and portions of today&apos;s fast food ... Press here to remove it or receive credits for it! ... Condiment/Spread; Salad; Kid-Friendly; Bread; Non-Alcoholic</description>
	<body>
		Burger King Original Zesty Sauce

 Posted in Salad 
 
Burger King Original Zesty Sauce SERVES
 6 
 
I love Burger King&apos;s Zesty dipping sauce, offered with their onion rings... which used to be somewhat palatable (no further comments about the rapidly diminishing quality and portions of today&apos;s fast food restaurant chains...). On each BK visit, I would routinely purchase additional Zesty sauces so I could take a good supply home with me... until the simple solution came when I opened my last remaining packet...&quot;I can make this myself at home!&quot;... And I did...
 
Ingredients for Burger King Original Zesty Sauce:

 
BASIC RECIPE
 1/2 cup real mayonnaise 2 tablespoons tomato ketchup 2 tablespoons creamed horseradish 2 teaspoons prepared yellow mustard 2 teaspoons ranch dressing 1/2 teaspoon cayenne pepper 
SERVE WITH
 onion rings, burgers, sandwiches, crab cakes, batter-fried fish and prawns 
FOR SEAFOOD ADD
 fresh lemon juice, grated fresh lemon zest, minced fresh onion, fresh minced dill or 
 tarragon, chopped sweet pickle 
FOR A SANDWICH SPREAD (choose one or two)
 chopped fresh dill, chopped sweet pickle, minced green onion, chopped hard-boiled egg, minced fresh red pepper 


Preparation of Burger King Original Zesty Sauce:
 
 COMBINE all ingredients in a small bowl using a wire whisk. SERVE and enjoy! STORE in a resealable container in refrigerator for up to 2 weeks. 
 
Nutrition of Burger King Original Zesty Sauce:
 Nutrition Facts
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Serving Size 1 (61g)
 
 
 Recipe makes 6 servings
 
 The following items or measurements
 are not included below:
 
 tomato ketchup Do you have copyrights on this recipe? Press here to remove it or receive credits for it! 
Related recipes :

 
 Cheese Crackers 
Adapted from a recipe at MelayneSeahawk&apos;s LiveJournal.SERVES
 12
 
 , 
 4
 dozen 1 lb sharp cheddar cheese, shredded 
 1/2 cup unsalted butter, softened 
 2 teaspoons worcestershire sauce 
 1 1/2 cups all-purpose flour 
 1&amp;nbs; 
 Chocolate Mousse in Chocolate Cups 
A delightful little dessert. :) from my sister in law Debbie.1
 batch For mousse 
 2 cups heavy cream 
 6 ounces semi-sweet chocolate chips (or double chocolate Ghirardelli) 
 1/4 cup confectioners&apos; sugar 
 1 te 
 Cornbread Waffles 
OMG YUMMM. From Vegan Brunch!8
 waffles 2 cups almond milk 
 1 teaspoon apple cider vinegar 
 1 1/2 cups cornmeal 
 1 cup all-purpose flour 
 1 tablespoon baking powder 
 1/2&amp;n; 
 Mashed Sweet Potatoes With White Cheddar Cheese 
Make sweet potatoes special. From BHG.SERVES
 8 3 lbs sweet potatoes (about 7 medium) 
 1/4 cup butter 
 1 teaspoon salt 
 3 ounces aged white cheddar cheese, shredded 
 1/4 cup bourb 
 Mushroom Polenta 
Polenta con Funghi, in &apos;1,000 Italian Recipes&apos; by Michele ScicoloneSERVES
 6 2 ounces finely chopped pancetta 
 1 small onion, finely chopped 
 2 tablespoons olive oil 
 1 (10 ounce) package white mushrooms, trim 
 
 
Recent recipes

 Chicken Adobo Coconut Macaroon Cookies (Gift Mix in a Jar) Mystery Pie Hamburg Creole Greek Tilapia Pasta with Herbed Ricotta and Pine Nuts Flourless Chocolate Cake Cracker Barrel Like Biscuits! Really! Firehouse Beef Pie Portabella Vegetarian Gravy 
 
Best light recipes

 Cheese, Pea and Pepper Samosas in Non-Alcoholic Grandmother&apos;s Cornbread in Non-Alcoholic Master Mix ( Biscuits or Pancakes ) in Non-Alcoholic Okra Salad in Non-Alcoholic Shrimp and Avocado Tortilla Rounds in Non-Alcoholic The Perfect Corn Chowder in Non-Alcoholic No Bake Cheesecake in Pastry Parmesan Popovers in Seasonings/Spices Banana Nut Bread in Alcoholic Black Velvet in Alcoholic Cheesy Chicken Jack With Cilantro Cream Sauce in Alcoholic Evan&apos;s Champagne Julep in Alcoholic Love Passion in Alcoholic Strawberry and Chicken Salad Trifle in Alcoholic Tuna, Fennel, Avocado, and Tangerine Salad with Citrus Vinaigrette in Alcoholic Blueberry Coffee Cake in After Dinner cocktails Chips Ahoy Chocolate Pie in After Dinner cocktails Piperade for One or Two in After Dinner cocktails Sauteed Asparagus in After Dinner cocktails Shawarma in After Dinner cocktails Sweet Potato Pudding 1 in After Dinner cocktails Polish Horn Cookies in Sangria Festive Rainbow Star Mould in Cocktail Key West Smoked Fish Dip in Cocktail Lower Fat Chiles (Chiles) Rellenos Casserole in Cocktail 
 
 
 
Site Search
 
On FaceBook
 
Tags

 chicken juice peach cake sangria meatloaf pecan pie low carb pasta salad chicken salad eggplant 
 
Popular Categories

 Egg Dish Bread Pastry Sangria Seasonings/Spices Soup/Stew Condiment/Spread Sauce Cake Sandwich Salad Dressing Tea Drinks Alcoholic Stuffing/Dressing Vegetable Salad Frosting/Icing Punch Hot Drink Quick&amp;Easy 
 
Friends

 Free software download 
 
   
 Light Recipes 

Best light recipes on the web
 
 Homepage Categories Best recipes 
 
Other of our best recipes :

 Sea Bass with Oriental Sauce Shiitake-Beef Stir-Fry Salmon Salade Niçoise Buttermilk Roasted Chicken Cajun Lowfat Turkey Meatloaf Country Pork Stew Great Curry in a Hurry Moo Shu Pork Parmesan-Crusted Chicken Breasts Coq au Vin Nouveau Apple, Walnut and Currant Strudel Sauteed Carrots with Rosemary and Lemon Peanut Butter Ice Cream Pie with Fudge Topping Grilled Italian Burgers Blue Cheese and Walnut Toasts Canadian Bacon Fried Eggs with Blue Cheese Fried Chicken and Spinach Salad Grilled Mock Sausage Patties Herbed Beef Stew with Sugar Snap Peas Marinated Eggplant Salad Mediterranean Pita Pizza Pan-Seared Tuna Topped with Fennel Salad Red Wine-Braised Lamb Shanks Roasted Potato Slices with Caviar Santa Fe Tortilla Pizza Asian Cole Slaw with Seared Scallops Lamb and Ratatouille Kebabs Blanquette de Veau Chicken Athena Mustard- and Rosemary-Roasted Game Hens 

 
©  2011 All Rights Reserved • Design by Free CSS Templates .

 Privacy Policy  •  Terms of Use
	</body>
</document>
