<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009559" url="http://fastfood.ocregister.com/2009/02/27/chili-dog-wars-ignite-between-carls-jr-wienerschnitzel/14433/" time="2012-07-13-02:56" support="1" score="0.0010391252176947293" bingtitle="Chili dog wars erupt between Carl’s Jr. &amp; Wienerschnitzel - Fast ..." webtitle="Chili dog wars erupt between Carls Jr.Wienerschnitzel - Fast Food Maven : The Orange County Register">
			<query id="000675" bing-rank="191"/>
	<description>Report: Small firms get worst of credit card deals; Buyer found for $60 million apartment ... entertainment; life; travel; opinion; Real estate; Jobs; Cars; Deals; Classifieds; Place an Ad</description>
	<body>
		REAL ESTATE JOBS CARS DEALS CLASSIFIEDS PLACE AN AD 
 
 SUBSCRIBE E-REGISTER CUSTOMER SERVICE TODAY&apos;S PAPER 
 Orange County Register 

 
 SURF REPORT/CAMS |  WEATHER  | LIVE TRAFFIC 
 
 HOME NEWS SPORTS BUSINESS ENTERTAINMENT LIFE TRAVEL OPINION 
 
 Newsletter RSS Mobile Facebook Twitter 
 Beaches | Best of OC | Blogs | Columns | Comics | Contests | Food | Gift of Giving | Health and Fitness | Home and Garden | Horoscopes | OC Moms | OC People | Outdoors | Pets | Photos | Puzzles and Games | Shopping and Deals | Video «Previous Post Next Post» All Posts 
 Chili dog wars erupt between Carl’s Jr.&amp;Wienerschnitzel 

February 27th, 2009, 8:32 am· ·posted by Nancy Luna, Staff Writer 
 
Carl&apos;s Jr. Jumbo Chili Dog is selling in some SoCal restaurants. (2 for $3)
 
Thanks to a tip from Fast Food Maven reader, Eric , I’ve discovered that Carl’s Jr. has been selling chili dogs in a limited number of Southern California restaurants.

Eric told me he spotted the Jumbo Dogs at a Carl’s Jr. in Norco, Ca. Does this mean the famous chili dog is making a comeback? (Remember, Carl’s Jr. founder Carl Karcher got his start as a hot dog vendor.)

Carl’s Jr. spokeswoman Beth Mansfield confirmed some details about the so-called Return of the Carl’s Jr. Chili Dog:

“Two for $3 Jumbo Chili Dogs are currently being offered  in some markets as an ongoing test. We’ve had a lot of positive customer feedback and will hopefully bring them back on a larger scale soon,”she said.

Carl’s Jr. restaurants in Brea, Yorba Linda, Fullerton and Placentia are the only ones in Orange County currently selling the dogs. ( CLICK HERE FOR a LIST of Carl’s Jr. chili dog locations )

Mansfield declined to comment more about the chili dog’s comeback.

I suspect, Newport Beach-based Wienerschnitzel knows more.

The nation’s largest hot dog chain will launch a new jumbo dog on Sunday dubbed the Big Original Chili Dog. The chain says the new dog is 84% larger than a regular Wienerschnitzel chili dog.

Guess how much it cost? You got it: 2 for $3!
 
The Big Original is 84% larger than a normal Wienerschnitzel chili dog. The cost: 2 for$3. (Additional cost for cheese and onions.)
 
Coincidence?  Of course not.

Wienerschnitzel said it had planned to launch the new dog this spring. But, officials moved up the product’s debut“to counter Carl’s Jr.’s chili dog launch,”the chain said.

“Sources suggest that the new Carl’s Jr. dog will be microwaved,”an aghast Wienerschnitzel marketing rep told me via email.

Now, that is some serious wiener dog smack talk.

I don’t like to let these kind of accusations go without further investigation. So, I called a few Carl’s Jr. restaurants and employees told me their dog is, indeed, microwaved!

So be it.

Let the chili dog wars begin.

 Tell us: If you spot a Carl’s Jr. restaurant selling chili dogs in the next few weeks, please list it here under comments. If you try the chili dogs from both chains, write in and give us your feedback.

 Related stories: 

 Get the latest updates on Menu Changes at your local restaurants, by bookmarking my New on the Menu section. Current updates include new meal deals at Baja Fresh, El Pollo Loco and Starbucks . Carm’s Coneys coming to Orange Jerry’s Wood-Fired Dogs opening new eatery in Irvine Zagat 2007: Best Cheap Eats in O.C. 
 Posted in: Burger Joints • Fast food news • Marketing Buzz • Value Deals • Carl&apos;s Jr. • chili dogs • Wienerschnitzel 

 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 You can follow any responses to this entry through the RSS 2.0 feed. 
 
 You can skip to the end and leave a response. Pinging is currently not allowed. 

 
Reader Comments
Comments are encouraged, but you must follow our User Agreement .
 Keep it civil and stay on topic. No profanity, vulgarity, racial slurs or personal attacks. People who harass others or joke about tragedies will be blocked. 

 

 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
 Name (required) 

 Email (required) 

 Website 
 
 

 

 
 
 Posh Party Box $40 for $100 towards Your Party Box at PoshPartyBox.com ADVERTISEMENT 
Things to do

 
 
 Latest food trends: Register food blogger Nancy Luna recently attended the restaurant industry&apos;s biggest conference in Chicago. Check out her coverage on her Fast Food Maven blog and on her social pages: Facebook and Twitter . 
Recent Posts

 Darden, Olive Garden owner, to buy Yard House for $585 million El Torito Grill closing at Fashion Island Menchie’s celebrates Irvine opening with 2-for-1 froyo deal OC Fair 2012: Your ultimate food guide Taco Bell feeds a small town in Alaska KFC launches new bite-sized fried chicken bites Wendy’s debuts Son of the Baconator 118 Degrees to expand raw food revolution with 2 new locations Updated: The Point set to open in Dana Point Porn star Ron Jeremy talks about his rum venture 
 
Mobile Food Alerts
 Fast Food Text Alerts : Subscribe to free O.C. fast food news alerts. About three to five are sent each week on breaking news, and fast-food deals. Text OCRFASTFOOD to 56654. More OCRegister news alerts. 
Contact the Fast Food Maven
 Follow the Fast Food Maven on Twitter or &apos;Friend Me&apos; on Facebook .
Send tips, reviews, gripes to nluna@ocregister.com . About the blog and blogger .



Nancy Luna, the Fast Food Maven
The Orange County Register
625 N. Grand Ave.
Santa Ana, CA 92711-1626

 

 
Register Food Writers
 
 Paul Hodgins is The Register’s wine columnist. He pens the Booze on a Budget column focusing on beer, wine and Happy Hour news every Tuesday and Friday on the Fast Food Maven blog. Marla Fisher is our Deals Diva blogger . She writes often about restaurant and grocery deals. The Food Frenzy blog gives readers daily reviews on local hidden gems in Orange County. 
 Top Food Stories: 
 Biggest fast-food flops of the 2011 Top Foods You Must try in 2011 Top Money Making Burger Chains My Morning as a Carl’s Jr. Biscuit Maker Sneak peek: Inside Thrifty Ice Cream’s factory Maven tours lettuce fields that serve McDonald&apos;s in California Inside look at McDonald’s bun factory Behind the scenes at In-N-Out’s Baldwin Park food plant 
 
2011 Top Slide Shows
 
 Is this Orange County&apos;s next best burger? Biggest fast-food flops of the 2011 Gourmet waffle shop makes waffle burger Top foods you must try in 2011 The making of an 8-pound Burger Top 10 Best Bars in O.C. (The anti-Yelp edition) Best, worst fast-food mascots 
 The recession is forcing many Orange County restaurants to shutter, and we&apos;re trying to track them all for you. Check out our O.C. Restaurant Closure List for the latest updates. 
 Restaurant Closures 

 Red Robin closing at Irvine Co. retail center Pei Wei in Irvine closes Hometown Buffet, Carl’s Jr. among four restaurant closures Daily Grill closing at Fashion Island Shore House Cafe closes 
 
New Restaurants
 The latest Restaurant Openings in Orange County . 
 The Latest Restaurant Openings 

 Menchie’s celebrates Irvine opening with 2-for-1 froyo deal 118 Degrees to expand raw food revolution with 2 new locations Another Broken Egg Cafe expanding in Southern California MainPlace: New restaurants now open, coming soon New breakfast cafe by Burger Parlor owner set to open in Fullerton Opening alert: Top Chef’s Fabio Viviani planning O.C. restaurant Opening alert: Umami reveals Anaheim opening date 
 
Fast Food Maven Awards
 
 2009 Best Blog, Orange County Press Club Best Food Blog, Just Spotted 2009 O.C. blog awards 2010: Best food blog (3rd Place) Orange County Press Club 2010: Best Transition from Traditional Media-Individual, Orange County Press Club Also, check out my OCR Wiki Page 
 
Fast Food Maven in the News
 
 Chain Leader: National trade &apos;zine interviews the Fast Food Maven Maven talks fast food value wars with CBS2 NPR: Nancy Luna on the future of In-N-Out WSJ: Maven talks burgers with Wall Street Journal 
 
 Food Truck News 

 OC Fair 2012 food truck lineup Food trucks to face off at Costa Mesa cooking contest Guide: Where to find food trucks in Orange County Food trucks 101: How to roll out a crave worthy mobile restaurant Free food prizes at Maven/OC Fair food truck gathering 
 
Audio: Interview with Jack Box
 
 More Deals From OC Deals Blog 

 Krispy Kreme doughnut deal is tomorrow! Buy 1 entree get 1 free at Denny’s 2-for-1 coupon for new Cantina Bowl meal at Taco Bell Buy 1 Mimi’s Cafe breakfast, get 1 free Fundraising for your group at Marie Callender’s 
 
Kids Eat Free
 LIST: Where do Kids Eat Free in O.C. 
Blog Watch

 Destination Irvine/Restaurants EaterLA Fast Food Weblog Food Frenzy McChronicles OC Deals OC Retail Orange County Mexican Restaurants So Good 
 
Tags
 Baja Fresh bankruptcy barbecue bbq Booze on a Budget Breakfast Burger King Carl&apos;s Jr. cheap chic dining Chick-fil-A Chipotle Mexican Grill cupcakes Del Taco Denny&apos;s El Pollo Loco Farrell&apos;s Ice Cream Parlour Fashion Island Financial Five Guys Burgers&amp;Fries food events food reviews Food safety food trucks Fried food frozen yogurt grocery shopping grocery stores happy hour hot dogs Irvine Co. Jack in the Box Jamba Juice John Wayne Airport KFC Kogi BBQ Mobile food new menu Quiznos restaurant remodels Ruby&apos;s Diner Subway Taco Bell upscale dining Wahoo&apos;s Fish Taco Wendy&apos;s 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 Return to Top 
 home news sports business entertainment life travel opinion Real estate Jobs Cars Deals Classifieds Place an Ad 
 
 
ADVERTISE OPTIONS

 Self Service Place an Online Ad Place a Print Ad Place a Classified Ad Media Kit Advertising Contact Info 
 
CONTACT OCREGISTER

 About Us Careers Contact Us Corrections Customer Service Subscribe Today Subscriber Services Site Help Site Feedback 
 
OCR SERVICES

 Archives Buy Our Photos California Lottery Deals OCRegister Fanshop Orange County Businesses Register Insider Register in Education Obituaries Facebook Comments FAQs 
 
NEWS YOUR WAY

 Blogs E-Mail Newsletters E-Register Mobile RSS Article Map Site Map Video 
 
ADVERTISING

 Classifieds Cars Deals Jobs Real Estate Place a Classified Ad View our Media Kit Interactive 
 
PARTNERS

 KDOC-TV MSNBC OC Excelsior Coast Magazine Preferred Destination OrangeCounty.com FreedomPolitics.com Freedom Printing 
 
 
 Privacy Policy | Site Help | User Agreement | Site Map SEO Powered by Platinum SEO from Techblissonline
	</body>
</document>
