<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009407" url="http://asgasgasg.activediner.com/mas-que-perros-colombian-fast-food/restaurant/pembroke-pines/fl/us/profile/902856" time="2012-07-13-02:46" support="2" score="0.000854712171721609" bingtitle="Mas Que Perros Colombian Fast Food Restaurant Overview, 9107 Taft ..." webtitle="Mas Que Perros Colombian Fast Food Restaurant Overview, 9107 Taft St, Pembroke Pines, FL, 33024, (954) 443-6001 - ActiveDiner">
			<query id="001301" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000046" bing-rank="81"/>
	<description>It can seat over 400 patrons! The food was good but I would say not excellent. The portions however is very good for the price you pay. That is certainly the case for the ...</description>
	<body>
		CUISINE OR RESTAURANT   CITY/STATE OR ZIP     
 
 
 Destinations 

 Atlanta Austin Boca Raton Boston Charleston Charlotte Chicago Dallas Denver Detroit Fort Worth Ft. Lauderdale Greensboro (Triad) Hartford Houston Indianapolis Kansas City Las Vegas Los Angeles Louisville Miami Minneapolis Nashville New Orleans New York Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Pittsburgh Portland Raleigh San Diego San Francisco Seattle Washington DC  -------------------------- Browse by Map   
 

 
 Sign Up for Specials 
 

 
 Add Your Restaurant 
 

 
 ActiveDiner Blog 
 
 
Cuisine
 All Restaurants 
 Italian 
 American 
 Chinese 
 Latin 
 Caribbean 
 Japanese 
 Mexican 
 Burger 
 New American 
 
 more... 
 American American Traditional Argentinean Asian Bagel Shop Bakery Banquet/Party Room Bar Barbecue Billiard/Pool Tables Brazilian Breakfast Brewery/Pub/Tavern British/English Brunch Buffet Burger Cafe Cajun/Creole Candy/Dessert Shop Cantonese style Caribbean Casual/Family Catering Cheesesteaks Chicken Children&apos;s Menu Chinese Coffee Shop Country Cuban Dance Floor Darts Deli/Sandwich/Subs Delivery Dim Sum Diner Dinner Dinner Theatre Doughnut Shop Ethnic Setting Fast Food Filipino Food Trucks&amp;Street Vendors French Fun and Games Greek Halal Happy Hour Hong Kong Cuisine Hot Dog Ice Cream/Yogurt Shop Indian Indonesian Irish Italian Jamaican Japanese Juice Bar&amp;Smoothie Shop Karaoke Kids Friendly Korean Late Night Dining Latin Live Entertainment Lunch Meat Shops Mediterranean Mexican Middle Eastern New American Outdoor Seating Pakistani Peruvian Pizzeria Romantic Seafood Smokers Friendly Smoking/Non Smoking Soup&amp;Salad Spanish Sports Bar and Grill Steak House Sushi Bar Take Out/Carry Out Tapas Tex-Mex Thai TV/Satellite Vegetarian Vietnamese Wheelchair Access Wi-Fi/Internet Access Wings 
 
 





 
Dining Specials
 Big Tomato Market Grill 
 - Italian, Pizzeria, Casual/Family, Banquet/Party Room Restaurant in
Pembroke Pines 
0.0|what a terrible place where the managers can&apos;t speak English and the new staff is horrible. the ... Bombay Sizzler 
 - Chinese, Indian, Middle Eastern, Pakistani Restaurant in
Pembroke Pines 
 
 
 


 
 United States &gt; Florida &gt; Pembroke Pines Restaurant Guide 
Mas Que Perros Colombian Fast Food
 (954) 443-6001 
 9107 Taft St, Pembroke Pines, FL 33024 | MAP 
   | Share | Features 
 Latin , Fast Food 

 
 Overview 
   
 Map 
   
 



 UPDATE THIS LISTING 
 
 Cook&apos;in Paris 
 French, Bakery, Casual/Family, Catering Restaurant in
Pembroke Pines 
 Indian Chillies 
 Chinese, Indian, Casual/Family, Buffet Restaurant in
Pembroke Pines 
 JT&apos;s Sports Bar and Grill 
 American, Wings, Sports Bar and Grill, Casual/Family Restaurant in
Pembroke Pines 
   »   See All Pembroke Pines Restaurant Coupons &amp; Deals 
 
 advertisements 




 
Reviews of Similar Restaurants
 Las Vegas Cuban Cuisine   
 Cuban, Latin 
  The restaurant is very nicely decorated and is enormous. It can seat over 400 patrons! The food was good but I would say not excellent. The portions however is very good for the price you pay. That is certainly the case for the Arroz Con Pollo. They 
 
 ... 

   »  Read More:   Pembroke Pines Restaurant Reviews 
 Copyright 1996-2012 ActiveDiner.com All rights reserved.      About Us  |  Contact Us  |  Disclaimer  | Privacy Policy  | Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
