<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009482" url="http://www.opposingviews.com/i/society/crime/video-mcdonalds-cashier-beats-customers-claims-self-defense" time="2012-07-13-02:52" support="2" score="0.0033735427091408933" bingtitle="Video: McDonalds Cashier Beats Customers, Claims Self Defense" webtitle="Video: McDonalds Cashier Beats Customers, Claims Self Defense">
			<query id="001315" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="001291" bing-rank="25"/>
	<description>... cashier and the other jumped over the counter. That’s when the cashier disappeared into the back of the fast-food restaurant ... Video: Bill O&apos;Reilly Worries that &apos;Glee ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In | Sign Up Follow @opposingviews 

 
 Home Entertainment Health Money Politics Religion Society Sports Tech Videos 
 
Video: McDonalds Cashier Beats Customers, Claims Self Defense
 

 Tweet Share on Tumblr By Michael Allen , Sun, October 23, 2011 
Rayon McIntosh, a McDonald’s cashier jailed for beating two irate customers with a metal rod (video below), claims that he was only trying to defend himself. McIntosh was arrested on Oct. 13 after a wild fight inside a McDonald’s in the Greenwich Village neighborhood of New York City.

The fight appeared to have started when two female customers argued and yelled obscenities at the cashier when he questioned a $50 bill they gave him.

One of the female customers slapped the cashier and the other jumped over the counter. That’s when the cashier disappeared into the back of the fast-food restaurant, came back with a metal rod and hit the women repeatedly.

One of the women (whose names were not released) has a fractured skull.

McIntosh told the New York Daily News that the women came in angry and he was just trying to keep things calm when they “attacked for no reason.”

McIntosh was charged with two counts of felony assault and criminal possession of a weapon, while the two women were charged with menacing, disorderly conduct and trespassing. 

McIntosh has a prior record and served time in prison after shooting and killing a high school classmate in 2000.

The owner of that McDonald’s said in a statement that she was “disturbed” by what happened and said that McIntosh is no longer employed there.

 
 

 
 Looking for work? Click here to get a Free Resume Builder 
 

 Top 5 Most Controversial News Stories Daily 
Sign up for the OV Daily Newsletter
 

 

 

 
 Login or register to post comments 
 

 

 Get your daily controversy 
Sign up for the OV Daily Newsletter
 

 

 

   

 

 

 
Most Popular
 
 NBA Rumors: Lakers Trying to Trade for Dwight Howard, Sign Antawn Jamison? Michigan Woman Kept Man’s Dead Body for 18 Months, Watched NASCAR with It Manny Pacquiao vs. Timothy Bradley: Boxing Stars Publicly Side with Manny NBA Rumors: Blazers, Timberwolves, Bulls Working on Big Trade? Video: Rhode Island Police Officer Edward Krawetz Fights for Job After Kicking Woman Anderson Silva vs. Chael Sonnen II: Nevada Athletic Commission Not Accepting Silva&apos;s Apology? NBA Rumors: Warriors, Hornets, 76ers, Nets, Blazers, Pacers, Mavericks Working on Deals MMA News: Jon Jones, Anderson Silva, Chael Sonnen, Chan Sung Jung, Jose Aldo and More Michael Jordan Laughs at Kobe Bryant’s ‘Dream Team’ Comments, Mocks Them Video: Millionaire Michael Marin Kills Self After Guilty Verdict is Read in Court 
   

 
Most Commented
 
 Video: Mitt Romney Used to Impersonate a Police Officer, Pull People Over Video: Police Beat Pregnant Woman Destiny Rios Video: Code Compliance Officer Enters Erica Masters&apos;Home While She Sleeps, Over Long Grass Pacu, Testicle-Eating Fish, Found in Illinois NRA Warns of U.N. Gun Conspiracy to Seize U.S. Guns Morgan Freeman Says President Obama&quot;not America’s First Black President&quot; Video: Rhode Island Police Officer Edward Krawetz Fights for Job After Kicking Woman American Family Association Claims Jesus Supported the Second Amendment Graphic Video: Woman Shot 9 Times in Public Execution by Taliban, Men Cheer Texas Voter ID Law Accepts Gun Licenses, But Not Social Security Cards 
     
 Civility 101 FAQ Terms of use Privacy Policy About Contact OV Badges 
   
©2008-2012 Opposing Views, Inc. All Rights Reserved.

Opposing Views, Inc. and its affiliates are not responsible for the content posted on thie website. Please view full disclaimer under Terms .
	</body>
</document>
