<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009501" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?Seven-Reasons-to-Stop-Drinking-Soda&amp;id=2217680" time="2012-07-13-02:53" support="1" score="0.0007805906035291964" bingtitle="Seven Reasons to Stop Drinking Soda - EzineArticles Submission ..." webtitle="Seven Reasons to Stop Drinking Soda">
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="104"/>
	<description>Drinking a soda won&apos;t kill you (not right away ... vending machine full of sodas, and every fast food restaurant ... science project where you put a tooth in a glass ...</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Health and Fitness » Nutrition Donald Child, Ph.D. 
 Platinum Author |   9 Articles 
 Joined: January 15, 2009 Was this article helpful? 0 0 
Seven Reasons to Stop Drinking Soda

 By Donald Child, Ph.D. 
 
It seems like every public building has a vending machine full of sodas, and every fast food restaurant meal comes with a soda, usually in an extra large size. If it&apos;s true that most of the Standard American Diet (SAD) is full of hidden health risks, it should come as no surprise that soda is also unhealthy.

Here are seven very good reasons not to drink another can of soda:

1. Sugar - Regular soda is full of sugar, and sugar equals ultimately ends up as extra weight around your hips, or as an extra clogging factor in your arteries. Those are not desired outcomes for anyone who is truly interested in optimal health. If you really want to quit drinking sodas, do an Internet search on High Fructose Corn Syrup, a sweetener commonly used in sodas.

2. Formaldehyde - There are many voices claiming that low-calorie sweeteners containing aspartame get converted to formaldehyde, which is toxic to the human body. Others, such as the FDA, say it&apos;s a hoax, that aspartame sweeteners are perfectly safe. You be the judge, but do be aware that aspartame doesn&apos;t grow on trees. A friend once suggested, &quot;If you can&apos;t pronounce it, don&apos;t eat it.&quot;

3. Cravings - Formaldehyde or not, any sweetener, including benign alternatives such as Stevia, trick the body into craving sugar and/or carbohydrates, which the body then converts to sugar. So if you are drinking low-sugar and low-carb sodas thinking you are staying slim, be forewarned that your body might not get the same message you are trying to tell your brain. Drinking too much soda is an invitation to developing early symptoms of diabetes, because the body gets an overload of sugar and the wrong kind of carbohydrates.

4. You are what you drink - Junk drinks are like junk food ... they fill you up so you don&apos;t recognize the need for quality nourishment. Your body is up to 90% water, and when you get dehydrated, that water needs replacing. If possible, you should drink up to 8-10 8 ounce glasses of water a day rather than filling yourself with soda.

5. Tooth rot - Remember that old elementary school science project where you put a tooth in a glass filled with some carbonated soda, and the tooth rots right before your eyes? The same thing happens in your mouth.

6. Carbonation - Carbonation (think &quot;bicarbonate of soda&quot;) neutralizes natural stomach acid. The reason you have acid in your stomach is to aid with digestion. When there is insufficient acid, your food doesn&apos;t get fully digested. Not only is that a waste of good food, but it can lead to health problems.

7. Acidic pH - Soda encourages an acidic pH in the human body. Ideally, the body should be slightly alkaline, because most disease conditions cannot develop in an alkaline environment. Soda may not directly cause chronic illnesses, but it can certainly make a person more susceptible to conditions such as arthritis.

The next time you pop the top on a can of soda or supersize your fast food drink at lunchtime, be aware that the sweet tasting beverage, in excess, can lead to health problems down the road.
 
Donald Child, Ph.D., is a freelance writer and health coach in addition to being a Senior Technical Writer at Honolulu technology firm DataHouse Consulting. His coaching blog can be read at http://www.healthisyourdestiny.com 
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=Donald_Child,_Ph.D. 
 Did you find this article helpful? 0 0 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Health and Fitness: Nutrition 
 Donald Child, Ph.D. 
 Email Address: Subscribe Nutrition Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Similar Articles

 Soft Drinks: America&apos;s Other Drinking Problem Is Depression a Drug Deficiency? 
 
Recent Articles

 Repair Mineral Deficiencies Better Health With a Better Blender - The Vitamix Three Awesome Health Benefits of Carrots Healing With Nutrition Sports Nutrition - The Day Before Competition Muscle Gain Nutrition With Unique Food Choices Game Day Nutrition - What Should Kids Eat? Vitamins and Minerals for Youth Athletes Abs of Steel - Here&apos;s a Quick Way If You Want to Work! 4 Week Focus on Weight Loss for Health 
 
Submitted On April 13, 2009. Viewed 635 times. Word count: 533.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Child, Donald &quot;Seven Reasons to Stop Drinking Soda.&quot; Seven Reasons to Stop Drinking Soda .
 13 Apr. 2009 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?Seven-­Reasons-­to-­Stop-­Drinking-­Soda&amp;id=2217680 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Child, D. (2009, April 13). Seven Reasons to Stop Drinking Soda .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?Seven-­Reasons-­to-­Stop-­Drinking-­Soda&amp;id=2217680 Chicago Style Citation: 
Child, Donald &quot;Seven Reasons to Stop Drinking Soda.&quot; Seven Reasons to Stop Drinking Soda EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?Seven-­Reasons-­to-­Stop-­Drinking-­Soda&amp;id=2217680 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
