<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009127" url="http://www.retail.wepindia.com/Retail-Micro-Site-Faq.html" time="2012-07-13-02:31" support="3" score="0.0035605860777494554" bingtitle="FAQ - Retail Micor Site Index-Final" webtitle="FAQ">
			<query id="001393" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001408" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="001385" bing-rank="157"/>
	<description>What is Cash Reception Feature? ... In Fast food/Restaurant The Item TYPES will be Plates how will I ... • If You Want to Bill the Table 1 KOT press Dept14 U ...</description>
	<body>
		BP-40 1. How Many Items it can store? 
 It can store 2000 Items.
 2. How Many Bill&apos;s you can print in a Day? 
 You can print up 2000 Bill/day.
 3. Can I Delete ITEM in Database? 
 You can Delete ITEM using Retail UTILITY only (Directly on BP-40 Not Possible).
 4. What are all Reports you can take in this Machine? 
 You can Take Daily sales, Void Bill Report, Item wise sale report for
 2 days (Yesterday&amp;Today), Bill wise    Detailed report for 2 days (Yesterday&amp;Today), Monthly Report&amp;Yearly;Report.
 5. Can I Erase or VOID any bill? 
 Yes, you can erase any bill for the sale happened for today (Y&apos;day bill not possible).
 6. Will the erased/VOID bill appear in the Report? 
 Yes, it shows as Void.
 7. Which is the Latest Version of S/W residing inside BP-40 Machine&amp;How to check this? 
 Latest Ver. Is 2.1.1&amp;to check this Hold LF button&amp;POWER ON the machine It prints Demo page in which Ver no   of the S/W is mentioned.
 8. What is the use of this RETAIL UTILITY? 
 This is used to Load Item database, Header&amp;footer to BP-40 Machine.
 9.Which is the Latest Version of Retail Utility? 
 Latest Version of Retail Utility is 4.1A.
 10. Can I Upgrade my Old BP-40 Machine to new S/W? 
 You can do that by using Retail utility version 4.1A
 11. How to Upgrade new S/W to BP-40 Machine? 
 You can Hold ONLINE&amp;LF BUTTON together&amp;Power ON the Machine.
 12. How to Upgrade new S/W to BP-40 Machine? 
 You can Hold ONLINE&amp;LF BUTTON together&amp;Power ON the Machine, Open Retail Utility in your PC (Ver. will   display as 4.1A). Select upgrade F/W, Browse&amp;Select the S/W file to Download to BP-40.
 13.How will I come to know weather it is programming properly or Not? 
 While Programming Firmware, 1st P.OUT (Red Light) will blink&amp;then ONLINE (green light ) will blink then   machine will rest after 1-2 Minutes time.
 14. How to Print Demo page or Selftest? 
 Hold LF button&amp;Power ON. It will print Demo page in which S/W ver will also get printed as Ver 2.1.1.
 15. What are the Default PC settings required before Downloading to BP-40 Machine? 
 Ensure you have a 9 Pin Dot matrix printer driver loaded in PC&amp;set as Default Driver.
 16. I have observed some times Date&amp;Time is getting reset to 00 why? 
 This happens if the POWER SWITCH is ON&amp;if you insert the POWER to BP_40 Ensure before giving Power to      machine BP-40 Switch is in OFF mode. 
 We have a solution to this problem by changing the BP-40 Logic card(Pls.   Talk to our Local Support Person/RPS in your region)
 17. What is the Life of BP-40 Ribbon cartridge? 
 You can print upto 6 Paper Roll per Ribbon cartridge.
 18.What is the approx cost per Bill in BP-40? 
 Roughly it comes to less than 3 Paise/bill.
 19. Can I give Discount using this BP-40? 
 Yes, There are 3 Types of Discount possible in this Machine, 1) on every Item you can program fixed % discount,   2) You can also give % discount on Total 
 3) You can also give Rupees Discount of Total.
 20. What is this Rupee Billing Feature&amp;Where it can be used? 
 It is mainly used in Petrol Pumps? Ex:- with this feature you can bill Petrol/diesel in Rupees instead of Litre. Just   select the Item Then press &quot;MENU&quot; Button, enter the amount (instead of Qty) it will automatically calculate the Liter   consumed for the entered amount&amp;Print the same in the Bill.
 21. Can I use BP-40 in Garment/Textile to Bill Cloth in METER? 
 Yes, Pls. Select the Item Type as ML. (It prints as M which means METER)
 22. How many Items Can I put in a Bill? 
 You can enter 250 Items in a single Bill.
 23. What is the Max&amp;Min Qty I can enter to any Item? 
 Max is 999&amp;Min is .01
 24. Can I take Data Backup of BP-40&amp;Transfer to PC? 
 No Data Can&apos;t be taken out from BP-40.
 25. Can I use BP-40 W/O PC? 
 You can use w/o PC. (Only for Header/Footer Programming for the 1st Time You need PC)
 26. I want to Take duplicate bill Is it Possible? 
 You can take duplicate Bill of Yesterday&amp;Today&apos;s transaction. (You can print Y&apos;days duplicate bill if you have not   changed the Bill no)
 27. How many types of Taxes it supports? 
 Mainly it supports 2 Types of Taxes, VAT&amp;Service Tax. Vat is for individual Item&amp;you can program from .1% to   99% Service tax will be on Total Value of the Bill.
 28. What are the Warranty Terms for BP-40? 
 We support ON SITE REPLACEMENT warranty for 6 Months from the date of Sale. All parts are covered under      warranty period (Except Ribbon&amp;Paper)
 29. Can I change the Price/Item name stored in the BP-40 when ever I need? 
 Yes, you may do so by going to MENU&amp;EDIT ITEM option.
 30. Can I bill different rates depending on Customers? 
 Yes, by enabling PRICE CHANGE option in the Machine.
 30. Can I bill different rates depending on Customers? 
 Yes, by enabling PRICE CHANGE option in the Machine.
 31. What is Cash Reception Feature? 
 To help cashier /avoid using calculator to check Cash recvd&amp;balance to be paid.
 32. What is round OFF feature? 
 You can enable/Disable this Feature for 0.25Paise/0.50&amp;1 Rupee.
 33. What are the Security features available in this Machine? 
 It has got 2 Passwords One for User (called common password) Default Password is 0000. This can be used     only for Billing&amp;Taking Reports One more for OWNER (called admin password) Default password is 0000. With  this you may Void bill, set date/Time, Edit/Add ITEMS etc.
 34. In Fast food/Restaurant The Item TYPES will be Plates how will I use this? 
 Program all Items as Packets in the Bill it appears as P.
 35. In Case of Power Failure how to Use BP-40? 
 This supports UPS/Inverter.
 36. How Much Power it consumes? 
 It consumes Max of 35Watts during Printing&amp;3 Watts when it is not printing.
 37. How much time I can use BP- 40 with standard 500VA UPS if power fails? 
 You can use 2-4 Hrs. depending on prints.
 38. What is Password for Retail Utility? 
 wepindia (case sensitive)
 39. I forgot my Machine password can I change Password? 
 To change Password you need to know old password. If you don&apos;t have old password then through Retail utility   &quot;CHANGE PASSWORD&quot; option you can set new password.
 BP-1000 
  PLU or Items that can be put in the machine : - 
 It supports 12000 PLU&apos;s / Items
 PLU&apos;s Code can be programmed for Barcode scanner 13 Digit Code No.
 Name of a PLU&apos;s/item can be Max of 20 Alpha Numeric Key&apos;s.
 Option of Setting Default Qty for any PLU as 1 or Zero (if one is selected then by pressing that PLU it Prints       the Bill. It is useful for Token Application.
 PLU&apos;s can be Linked to any Departments ex:- Food Items to Food Dept, Liquor&apos;s to Liquor Dept, papers/Pens to Stationery Dept.
 PLU&apos;s can be programmed for COST/Selling/VIP prices.

  Decimal Point Support. 
 Supports only 2 Decimal Point (1.00) i.e. Rs 100.50 is possible. Rs 100.505 is not possible.
 Quantity entered can be 3 digits after decimal point. I.e. 1.255 Kg or 0 .999 liter is possible.

  Multiple customer Billing at any Time. 
 While billing 1st Customer in between you may have to stop his transaction due to some reason&amp;Bill other customer. This is possible by saving 1st Customer&apos;s data by Pressing Function Key&amp;after 2nd customer&apos;s billing is over , 1st Customer&apos;s data can be Called/Viewed/Modified/Added&amp;Billed..

  Memory Size . 
 56 MB Total.
 Can be configured for PLU/Reports/other features based on requirements.

  Stock Management. 
 Max stock size is 99999 / PLU.
 There is Option for Safe Stock level setting.

  VIP Price or Special Price. 
 Can be set to Particular Customer Code.
 Support&apos;s Max of 3000 Customers.
 First enter the Code of Customer then Press VIP button&amp;then as per normal Billing Procedure.
 Max stock size is 99999 / PLU.


  Departments: 
 Supports 50 Departments.

  Hot Keys: 
 50 /Hot Keys.

  Billing: 
 Press PLU code&amp;Press PLU Button follow this sequence for more Items&amp;at end Press CASH/ENTER Button to Print the Bill.

  Clerk: 
 Supports 50 Clerks.
 Can Program Name.
 You can assign rights to him Ex - RM/Material Return, VOID enable/Disable, X/Z report Access, Open price access.


  Clerk Login security : 
 Login Name&amp;Password (1&amp;0000 for Clerk1) .

  Payment Modes : 
 There are 8 Types of configurable Payment collection Modes (Cash/Credit/Coupon etc) .

  Auto second Receipt : 
 Can Print 2 Bills (One to Customer&amp;one for storage Option to Enable/Disable in Settings/Printing/Profiles/Auto 2nd receipt)
 Double Receipt Detail (Mainly used in Fast food to give To collect food) Settings/Printing/Profiles/Ticket for 2md Receipt


  Settings 
 1) PLU settings 2) Departments settings

  Open price : 
 Can be performed only for hot keys. Enter the Amount Then Press HOT KEY , then press the CASH button.

  Discount : 
 Can be given after selecting the PLU then enter qty of dis.&amp;% then sub tot
 You can Give Discount for Any Item (Only One type of Discount is Possible)VAT
 Option for VAT Inclusive/Exclusive
 VAT Details on Bill Enable/Disable Option (Under setting/Printing/Profiles) Very useful for VAT INCLUSIVE ITEMS Billing.


  Profit Report 
 It is available under PLU Report (Item Qty/Amount/Profit)

  Hourly Report 
 In This report it prints the Hourly Report for No of customer, Value, Qty&amp;% of Business Ex:- 13:00 - 14:00 Amount-9999, Quantity-45, Customer-34, Business %.

  Paper Save Mode 
 Saves Paper by not printing many details which customer doesn&apos;t require (Can be enabled/Disable)

  Barcode&apos;s on Bill 
 Item&apos;s SL#/Batch code can be displayed on a Bill (Option to enable/Disable)

  External Devices Support 
 Supports RS-232&amp;RS-485 Serial Ports.
 External Printer can be Attached to Serial Port- RS 232.
 External Keyboard Can be connected to PS2 connector.
 Barcode Reader can be attached to Serial Port.
 PC can be I/F with Serial port .
 Weighing Scale can be connected to Serial Port - Mettler-Toledo Global brand (Tiger series) of weighing scales .
 Additional Customer Display also can be connected to Serial Port.


  PC UPLOAD/DOWNLOAD 
 You Can UPLOAD Total Daily Report. (VAT Report Can&apos;t be Downloaded)
 You can D/L all Data except for VAT settings.


  KOT Operation 
 Press Table No.&amp;Press DEPT14 Key then Select PLU&apos;s. Again Press DEPT14 to Save these KOT&apos;s
 Now Press Table No.&amp;Press DEPT14 Key then Select PLU&apos;s. again Press DEPT14 to Save these KOT&apos;s
 If You Want to Bill the Table 1 KOT press Dept14 U can View/Cancel the KOT ITEM&apos;s then Press ENTER to PRINT the BILL
 You Can print the KOT by again pressing DEPT14 Key (ensure your Setting/printing/profiles/Rcpt ON in TN MODE is ON


  Additional Tax/ Service Charge/Service Tax. Programming 
 1. Go to P-SETTING.
 2. Go to FUNCTION KEY
 3. Go to Keyboard FF Key
 4. Redefine FF Key.
 5. Select %1
 6. Now Press any of the Department Key to enable this Function (This will work like HOT KEY)
 7. Now come to Function KEY Menu
 8. Select % Key
 9. Select % 1 Key
 10. Enter the Name as per your Requirement
 11. Enter the Rate in %, for 12.00 % enter as 12.500
 12. Select Positive attr
 13. Select Item after enable as NO.
 14. ST after enable as YES
	</body>
</document>
