<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009332" url="http://www.coastnews.com/c0060.htm" time="2012-07-13-02:42" support="1" score="0.00034196348600012256" bingtitle="mcdonald&apos;s - CoastNews.com: Portraits of three sister cities: San ..." webtitle="mcdonald&apos;s">
			<query id="000311" bing-rank="234"/>
	<description>As construction workers go in and out the side door of the kitchen ... The sign is about 4 feet tall--modest by fast-food restaurant proportions. Bill Kilroy, a field ...</description>
	<body>
		NORTH COAST GETS ITS FIRST
MCDONALD&apos;S 

 louis martin
 cns news&amp;features 

 Fort Bragg, California-- 

 For 286 miles along the North Coast
of California--from San Francisco to Eureka--there is not a
single McDonald&apos;s restaurant in operation. Some residents of the
North Coast are proud of that record, while others could care
less. Whatever one&apos;s view--opposed, indifferent, or even in
favor--the record will change on Thursday. After 5 and a half
years of planning, and 2 and a half years of public opposition,
the American fast-food institution will open its doors in Fort
Bragg. 

 Raymond Costa, who owns the
franchise, is a little nervous about it. That&apos;s because the
debate went all the way to the Supreme Court. There the matter
was settled some two months ago in favor of McDonald&apos;s. 

 Construction began about a month
ago, and now it&apos;s finished. The arches are in place, and the
final touches are being put on the landscaping. 

 Costa, who seems a little gun-shy
from all the opposition, insisted, ``McDonald&apos;s Corporation isn&apos;t
here; it&apos;s a locally owned business.&apos;&apos; All he&apos;s done is bought
the name, he said. 

 As construction workers go in and
out the side door of the kitchen, Costa said 50 restaurant
workers have been hired already. He is hoping to hire 20 more.
Inside the pale blue building with a lawn out front, young people
sit at tables with clip boards filling out applications. 

 The restaurant was due to open on
Tuesday, but because of last minute hitches, it will open
Thursday instead. It will be the basic McDonald&apos;s
hamburger-and-french-fry bill of fair plus soup. Said Costa,
``Soup&apos;s kind of a specialty item; not a lot of McDonald&apos;s
restaurants have it.&apos;&apos; 

 Costa said he and McDonald&apos;s tried
to make the building fit the area. It&apos;s located in what city
planners call the ``scenic corridor&apos;&apos; to the town. Said Costa,
pointing to the golden arches on a low street sign on Highway 1,
``That is the biggest arch right there.&apos;&apos; The sign is about 4
feet tall--modest by fast-food restaurant proportions. 

 Bill Kilroy, a field service manager
with McDonald&apos;s, was up in Fort Bragg on Tuesday working on last
minute details in the kitchen. Said Kilroy, a large man in a
maroon sweater,&quot;We&apos;re happy to be here in Fort Bragg.&apos;&apos;
There have been rumors about a possible protest when the
restaurant opens. A group called Friends of Fort Bragg has
opposed it from the beginning. But said Kilroy, ``I wouldn&apos;t have
any idea about anything but good things happening here.&apos;&apos; 

 The restaurant will be open 7 days a
week, from 6 AM to 11PM. 

 (11/28/95) 
 
 Comments?
 editor@coastnews.com 
 
 Return to News Page? 

 Return to Main Page?
	</body>
</document>
