<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009566" url="http://sinr.com/index.php?h=random" time="2012-07-13-02:57" support="5" score="0.0056900909510522535" bingtitle="Sinr.com - your sins in one place" webtitle="Sinr.com - your sins in one place">
			<query id="001216" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="001204" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="001210" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="001215" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="001023" bing-rank="214"/>
	<description>Naturally, I hadn&apos;t let them give me a receipt for my 6.79€ fast food restaurant ... They are all catholic and keep running to ... Waste</description>
	<body>
		Confess Your Sin Register | Login 
 
 

 

 your sins in one place | 
 

 
 
 
NEW 
RANDOM 
NEW ENTRY CHARTS 
TOP100 
Places 
 
 new comments: Leavicci (21:37 CET) 
 I&apos;m sad to say that I started to laugh after reading this. Bastards like that deserve it, though I imagine that the page must have been excrusiating! 
 ( &quot;Toothpricked&quot; ) Goodlove00 (13:42 CET) 
 How are you? I hope you are fine, My name is Miss Esther, my heart is seeking for a true lover that will bring joy and happiness back in my life. I [...] 
 ( &quot;Towel cabinet&quot; ) Goodlove00 (13:42 CET) 
 How are you? I hope you are fine, My name is Miss Esther, my heart is seeking for a true lover that will bring joy and happiness back in my life. I [...] 
 ( &quot;Toy Train&quot; ) Goodlove00 (13:42 CET) 
 How are you? I hope you are fine, My name is Miss Esther, my heart is seeking for a true lover that will bring joy and happiness back in my life. I [...] 
 ( &quot;Fun in the Gondola&quot; ) Goodlove00 (13:42 CET) 
 How are you? I hope you are fine, My name is Miss Esther, my heart is seeking for a true lover that will bring joy and happiness back in my life. I [...] 
 ( &quot;Tax office&quot; ) 
   
 
 
 

 
 
 The Phone Kiss (00000076) 
 1 comments 
 2.88/5 1 2 3 4 5 
 2.9 /5 (26 Votes) 
 
 Two years ago I had what was for those days a modern folding cell phone. I used it for about a year and was totally satisfied. Recently, I was on the phone with a friend and he jokingly mentioned that I ought to leave off with the kiss for him at the conclusion, because it struck him as being a bit homoerotic. Ultimately through other people I discovered that that was no isolated instance. I discovered that my cell phone on being folded shut made a funny sound that sounded like&quot;mmwaahh,&quot;i.e. like a short kiss. Funny to say, that year I didn&apos;t find a job because my potential bosses believed I would kiss them. So, everyone whom I kissed telephonically, it was unintentional!
 Tags: Embarrassment Unfairness Phone 
 
 Tweet 
 Posted on 19.02.2010, 01:00:33 CET
Place: Vienna, Austria 

 
 
 The Weight of Air (00000084) 
 0 comments 
 2.79/5 1 2 3 4 5 
 2.8 /5 (24 Votes) 
 
 I would like to confess that I hate going shopping with my girlfriend. There&apos;s this one thing in particular: she won&apos;t tie up the plastic bags she puts vegetables in, because she thinks the cashier would then weigh the air that&apos;s in the bags, too, and that the supposed extra weight would cost her more. Even my explanation that, if the air was being weighed it would tip the scale all the time, falls on deaf ears. Let it be understood that she is very intelligent and in many ways much sharper than your average Joe, but this life-skill naivetédrives me batty.
 Tags: Stupidity Anger Despair Shopping Relationship 
 
 Tweet 
 Posted on 11.02.2010, 03:35:58 CET
Place: Kiel, Germany 

 
 
 Gifts for the yards (00000110) 
 0 comments 
 1.96/5 1 2 3 4 5 
 2.0 /5 (49 Votes) 
 
 I, when I was about eight or nine, lived in this very Family-oriented apartment complex. However, I lived in the very back of the apartment complex, and my school bus dropped me off at the very front of the complex, and I&apos;d walk home alone. On my way home, being the little douche bag I was, I&apos;d go into people&apos;s yards, take their things, and put it in other people&apos;s yards.
One time, I took someone&apos;s stepping stone that had their kid&apos;s hand prints on them, and put it in front of a house a couple buildings away. Two weeks later, the apartment I put the stone in front of was vacant, and every other house in the complex guarded their things like it was golden.
 Tags: Unfairness Stealing Vandalism Neighbors 
 
 Tweet 
 Posted on 12.07.2011, 10:34:24 CET
Place: Lake Mary, FL 

 
 
 Ski Vacation Affair (00000078) 
 0 comments 
 3.24/5 1 2 3 4 5 
 3.2 /5 (38 Votes) 
 
 My girlfriend was on a ski vacation. Back from it, I soon found out, that gotten it on with a guy. Thanks to Facebook, I had the guy&apos;s name relatively quickly. Confronted with it, everything was confessed, also that the rat was married. My confession: I send him a bouquet of flowers at home through Fleurop, hoping that his wife would get it. On the card was everything that the swine had been up to. Oh, yes, she did actually receive the bouquet!
 Tags: Revenge Unfaithful Holiday 
 
 Tweet 
 Posted on 22.02.2010, 23:45:08 CET
 
 


 
 
 The Embedded Tooth (00000093) 
 1 comments 
 3.05/5 1 2 3 4 5 
 3.1 /5 (39 Votes) 
 
 When I was 5 years old, I got my first loose tooth and naturally wanted to be rid of it as soon as possible. I bit down hard into an apple. Regrettably, I swallowed the small piece of apple with the tooth embedded in it. My father then explained to me that it would emerge when I sat on the toilet. Over the next few days I wanted to have the tooth and tried passing it, but succeeded only while in my kindergarten. So I brought a nice, fat, brown clump to the kindergarten lady, asking her to find the tooth for me, and then I went back to playing. I confess that because of me that poor woman probably had the worst coffee break of her life.
 Tags: Unfairness Disgust Greed Curiosity Kindergarten 
 
 Tweet 
 Posted on 11.05.2011, 01:05:52 CET
Place: Rainer-Langen Weg, 41812 Katzem, Germany 
 
 

 
 116 Sins.
 
 

 Seiten (24) : 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 ... vor» 
 Page 

 Abuse    Addiction    Adultery    Aggression    Alcoholism    Anger    Audacity    Betrayal    Cowardice    Curiosity    Despair    Discord    Disgust    Drugs    Embarrassment    Envy    Evilness    Fetish    Fraud    Gluttony    Greed    Hate    Heartless    Ignorance    Jealousy    Laziness    Lie    Lust    Masturbation    Mistrust    Murder    Obsession    Prejudices    Pride    Prostitution    Revenge    Self-harm    Selfishness    Sex    Shamelessness    Sloth    Stealing    Stupidity    Unbelief    Uncleanliness    Unfairness    Unfaithful    Vandalism    Vanity    Violence    Waste    
 
 
 
 
 

 Sinr.com©2010-2011
Beichthaus.com©2004-2011 Topuser 
 PreCheck 
 Terms 
 Support / FAQ 
 Imprint
	</body>
</document>
