<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009186" url="http://www.openrice.com/english/restaurant/sr2.htm?shopid=18220" time="2012-07-13-02:34" support="45" score="0.0972480314706443" bingtitle="Si Sun Fast Food - Hong Kong Style Hamburger Fast Food in Hung Hom ..." webtitle="Si Sun Fast Food - Hong Kong Style Hamburger Fast Food in Hung Hom - Hong Kong Restaurants Guide HK Restaurant - OpenRice in English">
			<query id="000906" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="001112" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000892" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="001174" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001506" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="001191" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="000345" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="001526" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="001118" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000359" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000910" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000977" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000924" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="001172" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000987" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="001161" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="001218" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000878" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="001363" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="001180" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000046" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000109" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="001510" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000986" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="001381" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001004" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000973" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="001219" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="001395" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="001204" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="001385" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="000662" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="001207" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000972" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="001192" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000349" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000678" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001287" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000992" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="001520" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="001196" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="001206" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="001534" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="000100" bing-rank="209"/>
	<description>... paid $100, got the change (1 x $50, 1 x $10 bill, 1 ... Lowu and decided to pay a visit to Si Sun Fast Food ... I went to the old spot to order my food but did not realize ...</description>
	<body>
		香港(繁體版) 中国 China India Indonesia Malaysia Philippines Singapore Thailand 
 Remember my choice Other Region Login with Facebook Register Login MyOpenRice My Favorite Restaurants 中文版 Select District --All Hong Kong-- Aberdeen Admiralty Ap Lei Chau Causeway Bay Central Chai Wan Cyberport Deep Water Bay Happy Valley Heng Fa Chuen Lan Kwai Fong Mid-Levels North Point Pok Fu Lam Quarry Bay Repulse Bay Sai Wan Ho Shau Kei Wan Shek O Sheung Wan Soho Stanley Tai Hang Tai Koo The Peak Tin Hau Wan Chai Western District --All Kowloon-- Cheung Sha Wan Choi Hung Diamond Hill Ho Man Tin Hung Hom Jordan Knutsford Terrace Kowloon Bay Kowloon City Kowloon Tong Kwun Tong Lai Chi Kok Lam Tin Lei Yue Mun Lok Fu Mei Foo Mong Kok Ngau Tau Kwok Prince Edward San Po Kong Sham Shui Po Shek Kip Mei Tai Kok Tsui To Kwa Wan Tsim Sha Tsui Tsz Wan Shan Wong Tai Sin Yau Ma Tei Yau Tong --All New Territories-- Fanling Fo Tan Kwai Chung Kwai Fong Lau Fau shan Lo Wu Lok Ma Chau Ma On Shan Ma Wan Sai Kung Sha Tin Sham Tseng Sheung Shui Tai Po Tai Wai Tai Wo Tin Shui Wai Tseung Kwan O Tsing Yi Tsuen Wan Tuen Mun Yuen Long --All Outlying Islands-- Chek Lap Kok Cheung Chau Discovery Bay Lamma Island Lantau Island Ping Chau Po Toi Island Tai O Tung Chung Advanced Search Map Search Hot Types: Online Reservation Hong Kong Style Western Japanese    OpenRice iPhone App Home : Dining Guide &gt; Restaurant Search &gt; Hung Hom &gt; Si Sun Fast Food   
 Si Sun Fast Food 時新快餐店 
 
 Overview Review (1235) Photo (1480) Video (0) 
 
 G/F, 1A Whampoa Street, Hung Hom 
紅磡黃埔街1A地下 Hong Kong Style | Fast Food | Hamburger 

 
 2362 1279 Below $40 
 809 vs 257 vs 89 
 
 
 Update Restaurant Info Add to Favorites Send to Friends Print Add Photos (Total of 1480 Photos) 
 
 
 | 
 View Full Map 
 Report Map 
 3.51 Taste
 Environment
 Service
 Hygiene
 
 Value for Money
 
 

 
 

 About this Restaurant :The simplicity of Si Sun&apos;s freshly made burgers draw customers from all over Hong Kong. Being exceptionally affordable, these burgers are best served with a fried egg on top and with some Chicken Drumsticks. 
 Signature Dishes : Fried Chicken Drumsticks, Fish Fillet Burger, Double Cheese Burger 
 
 
 Opening Hours: Mon.-Sun. 06:00-21:00 
 
 Payment Method: Cash 
 
 Alcoholic Drinks: No 
 
 May Bring Your Own Wine: Yes 
 
 10% Service Charge: No 
 
 TV: Yes 
 
 Gourmet Review English only (32) | English&amp;Chinese (1235) First to Review: quayteow Showing 1 to 15 of 32 Reviews 1 2 3 
 Display: Listing View | Full View Search: Filter Options Close 
 
 Member Level All Member Non-member Verteran Level or above Editor&apos;s Choice All Editor&apos;s Choice Review Rating All Smile OK Cry Occasion All Birthday | Anniversary | Christmas | Valentine&apos;s Day | Mother&apos;s Day | Father&apos;s Day | Chinese New Year | New Year&apos;s Eve | Xmas&apos;s Eve | Meal Type All Breakfast | Lunch | Tea | Dinner | Night Snack | Other | 
 
 
 
 
 supersized 15 Review(s) humdinger! Jun 26, 2012 
 
 been dying to try this place out to see what the fuss was about and very nearly didn&apos;t make it as i was ravenous making my way over from hong kong side... but i thought id be a trooper and brave it through...and boy am i glad i did!i ordered the hamburger with egg and an iced lemon tea... ($26)when it came the sauce was dripping out the side so i had a quick lick and it was to die for .. yet another sweet, slightly tangy sauce to compliment the juicy patty (i&apos;m a huge fan - see my wing lok yuen entry)the egg was an ingenious touch (i&apos;d never think to add egg!) and the whole thing really came together nicelyone bite and i was hooked (or should i say lick!?) -that&apos;s all it took!this place without a doubt puts all the major burger names to shame!go get several today! i know i&apos;ll definitely be back!p.s save some room for a quick trip over to mammy pancake and sample one of their egg waffles! another must try! Recommended Dish(es): a burger! you can&apos;t go wrong
 Table Wait Time: 5 minute(s)

 Date of Visit: Jun 26, 2012
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 5 |  Environment 3 |  Service 3 |  Hygiene 3 |  Value for Money 5 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 mya02 2 Review(s) Bad Service, Mediocre burger Apr 12, 2012 
 
 So I wanted to try it out since a few of my friends mentioned this place is famous for their burgers.

We entered, and told the cashier 4 cheeseburgers for take away, paid $100, got the change (1 x $50, 1 x $10 bill, 1 x $5 coin and 1 x $1 coin) and sat down to wait. When they were calling our number, we saw they were giving us 1 burger. So we checked our receipt and saw the cashier only punched 1 burger and that&apos;s when we realized he got our order wrong and also gave us the wrong change. On the receipt, our change should have been $86 but we only got $66. We asked the cashier if he gave us the right change and he said yes. I checked my wallet again and found that even with all the loose change plus the $50 and $10 bill, it doesn&apos;t amount to $86. I brought this to cashier&apos;s attention and he immediately dismisses my complaint growling at me saying&quot;No, I gave you the $86&quot;. At one point he even slipped and said $66 by mistake but when I pointed it out, he of course denied it.

$20 is not that big of a deal but if you&apos;re going to be dishonest with your customers, you&apos;re off my book and I&apos;ll be sure to tell everyone I know. I know it&apos;s my fault not checking if the change was correct but it doesn&apos;t give you the right to be inconsiderate and rude.

ALL IN ALL: Burger is mediocre but the cheap price makes it attractive, SERVICE IS BAD. Takeaway Wait Time: 15 minute(s)

 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 2 Vote(s) View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 C:Y 40 Review(s) Famous for a reason! Aug 26, 2011 
 
 I&apos;m sure if you are a foodie/food lover, you would have definitely heard of the name 時新.
And if you do happened to live in Kowloon or Hung Hom like me, you would definitely paid countless visits to 時新.

Although an extremly lazy person like me rarely goes as far as 時新 from my home. I do happened to go there once I get the chance.
Thanks to C who hadn&apos;t tried 時新 before, I got a reason to persuade myself to taste the heavenly HK styled hamburger once again.

It was clear to us that without doing much thinking, we decided to order two Double Cheese and Egg Hamburger (雙層芝士蛋漢堡) right away. Perhaps the only thing you would comment on your whole experience at 時新 is the waiting period. The waiting period took quite a while, at least 5-10 minutes. The shop was small and crowded, with limited seats and air-conditioning/fans, we had no choice but to stand by the serving bar...it wasn&apos;t a pleasant wait. The busy lady Nevertheless, just by starring at this busy lady trying hard to fry the eggs and beef in a short amount of time was enough to make me forgotten about the waiting for a while. It was quite an amazing scenery to watch. Nice packaging We didn&apos;t dine in due to the unattractive seating conditions. We decided to do takeaways instead. The packaging of the hamburgers were quite special and attractive, at least is something of a special design that I would take a second to look at. 雙層芝士蛋漢堡 雙層芝士蛋漢堡 I can gurantee you that, the following process is as the most heavenly eating experience you could imagine for hamburgers. Just by pulling down the plastic paper was enough to electrify your smelling sense! And the next second your eyes are telling you that a freshly cooked beef, nicely fried double egg, and just-melted double layered of cheese were greatly placed in between two soft pieces of bread. Not only did they smell good but every bite I had, the ingredients of the hamburger were greatly combined in terms of flavour and texture. We chose the sauce as Salad dressing so it provided a lighter flavour along with the freshly cooked beef and the plain flavour of egg and cheese. I guess anything that is freshly cooked would be good - and same for this fantastic hamburger. 

Only one thing to comment would be the size of the hamburger was quite small. I could still remember the first time I had this was around 3 - 4 years ago, the hamburger was slightly bigger and the price was cheaper.. too bad. 
All in all, 時新 is definitely going to be my all time favourite and I dare to say that 時新 is the proud of Hong Kong. The only place that you can find good HK Styled Hamburgers!

 - Y 

 Recommended Dish(es): 雙層芝士蛋漢堡
 Takeaway Wait Time: 8 minute(s)

 Date of Visit: Aug 13, 2011
 Spending per head: Approximately HKD18
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 5 |  Environment 2 |  Service 3 |  Hygiene 3 |  Value for Money 3 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 4 Vote(s) View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 Introverttraveler 6 Review(s) Great sliders Jul 10, 2011 
 
 With 700+ people before me, there&apos;s not much more I can add but to add one more Smile to the rating. The double cheeseburger was nice and juicy - so many places in HK mess up this basic detail. This place did not disappoint! Awesome! Mmmmmm. Table Wait Time: 0 minute(s)

 Date of Visit: Jul 10, 2011
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 5 |  Environment 3 |  Service 3 |  Hygiene 3 |  Value for Money 5 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 1 Vote(s) View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 gonwan 2 Review(s) great burgers May 13, 2011 
 
 This place does not disappoint, for mcd pricing, this is so much better. I ordered the double cheeseburger and although small, it was fantastic.
One was not enough, but at that price just order another one. 

 Table Wait Time: 5 minute(s)

 Date of Visit: May 09, 2011
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 5 |  Environment 4 |  Service 4 |  Hygiene 3 |  Value for Money 5 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 1 Vote(s) View Results Recommend Message (1) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 princesseva 4 Review(s) Delicious! Apr 27, 2011 
 
 Finally a decent burger in HK. This reminds me of the buger vans in the UK, always very tasty and smell great.

Although small, the price is small. Go for the double cheeseburger with egg for $16. Lovely
 Table Wait Time: 7 minute(s)

 Date of Visit: Apr 26, 2011
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 5 |  Environment 3 |  Service 4 |  Hygiene 3 |  Value for Money 5 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 1 Vote(s) View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 YummyNY 15 Review(s) Seriously good burger Nov 22, 2010 
 
 No wonder this restaurant has such great reviews! I love their tasty yet cheap pork w. egg burger. Normally there is a long wait, but if you go around 12 (when it first open) or in the afternoon (2-5pm), then you can probably get a seat. Date of Visit: Nov 18, 2010
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 5 |  Environment 2 |  Service 2 |  Hygiene 3 |  Value for Money 5 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 2 Vote(s) View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 ardin 9 Review(s) Very nice pork sausage burger with egg Oct 27, 2010 
 
 

Asked my colleague to help me get a pork sausage burger with egg to go while they ate there for breakfast. Although the location of our office and the store is 10 minutes away, the burger was still warm while it reached my hands.

 TASTE 
Seriously the taste is better than the one at Mc D. They use the same Garden bread, so no expectation for that, at least it&apos;s soft and warm. The sausage itself is minced, even mixed with some fish aroma. The sauce I &apos;ve chosen was salad one, although I &apos;d say it&apos;s like tartar sauce. With some chopped onions inside, and the egg inside is kind of over medium type.

 OVERALL 
It&apos;s quite filling for me (mid 20&apos;s girl) for breakfast. Be prepared that you might need a mouth rinse after that, thanks to the onions inside.

Will definitely have it again. 豬柳蛋漢堡 Recommended Dish(es): 豬柳蛋漢堡
 Takeaway Wait Time: 10 minute(s)

 Date of Visit: Oct 11, 2010
 Spending per head: Approximately HKD14(Breakfast)
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 4 |  Environment 2 |  Service 2 |  Hygiene 3 |  Value for Money 3 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 cho0020 2 Review(s) Not as good as the reviews! Oct 15, 2010 
 
 I went to this place again of the massive number of excellent reviews.
I visit 時新快餐店 on 7/10/10, before Miriam Yeung Concert.
I want 25min for one double chesse burger with egg $16.
For me, it was nothing special. The patties were small. The sauce was all the bag,
The bun was too soft, so when you bite into the burger everything just falls apart.
I would not go back there again on purpose. Takeaway Wait Time: 25 minute(s)

 Date of Visit: Oct 07, 2010
 Spending per head: Approximately HKD16(Night Snack)
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 3 |  Environment 3 |  Service 3 |  Hygiene 3 |  Value for Money 3 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 1 Vote(s) View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 wildcat 35 Review(s) Not just burger, 炸雞脾 also a must try Sep 14, 2010 
 
 Had breakfast in the morning so not feeling want to eat anything at lunch....so at tea time felt a bit hungry, so immediately thought of going to 時新for their burger...

When arrived, surprisingly not a long queue but 2 person ahead of me only...saw a couple having burger and fried chicken leg, the chicken leg smell so good and look juicy, but is too much for both chicken leg and burger...so I decided to give the chicken leg a try!

For $10, I waited about 7 mins and when I picked it up, it was so hot!!! 

Can&apos;t resist with it&apos;s smell I was eating right outside the store...not to bother finding a seat or bring it home....it&apos;s so juicy where all the juicy were collected in the plastic bag 

Taste is just right, you can tell it&apos;s cooked from raw to well done, not like other fast food store to cook half way then when someone ordered they just fried it for a minute...which make all the juicy gone...

I really appreciate they still stick with the traditional cooking, it&apos;s fast food but still maintain the good way to cook, not like those chained fast food store to have everything prepared to be more efficient....well just a min or two quicker but the taste make a hugh different!!! Recommended Dish(es): 炸雞脾
 Table Wait Time: 7 minute(s)

 Date of Visit: Sep 12, 2010
 Spending per head: Approximately HKD10(Tea)
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 5 |  Environment 2 |  Service 2 |  Hygiene 2 |  Value for Money 4 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 1 Vote(s) View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 Slagathor89 1 Review(s) My new spot in Hung Hom Sep 08, 2010 
 
 Love this place. I have had many good burgers in my life so I think I can say claim that these are good burgers. My burger of choice is the double burger with egg. Delicious, juicy and best of all cheap. The burgers aren&apos;t amazing and they aren&apos;t american style if that&apos;s what your going for but in my opinion it beats mcdonalds any day. And again the price point is just great.

The only down side is that I feel exceptionally unhealthy when I dine here more than once in a day... Oh well I guess I should sample other local fare once in a while Recommended Dish(es): Double burger with egg
 Spending per head: Approximately HKD20(Lunch)
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 4 |  Environment 3 |  Service 3 |  Hygiene 3 |  Value for Money 5 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 1 Vote(s) View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 sansan_mountain 149 Review(s) too hong kong ese Jul 05, 2010 
 
 用餐日期: 2009 年 3月 15日 (成年前- 唔太記得清楚)
 食物: 雙層芝士蛋漢堡, 薯條, 凍奶茶
 味道: 雙層芝士蛋漢堡都幾大份, 雖然係雙層芝士﹐ 但食唔到強烈既芝士味, 芝士 亦未溶.﹐ 係新鮮弄好,好香。自己加入茄汁。味道還可以﹐ 唔覺好好食-個牛扒無咩肉味﹐ 但食到有洋蔥碎係入面。

 Date dined : 15th March 2009 (whole yr ago - Do not remember too clearly)

 Food: Double cheese burger with egg, fries and cold milk tea
 Taste: Double cheese burger with egg: It definately looked good, it doesnt look as big as some photos I have seen, everything is quite flat. Probably smaller than a big mac. But it definately smells real good. Smells of nice fried egg and grilled burger. We put ketchup in a bun, which is most traditional taste as i know. Tbh I didnt like it much although it has been top on Openrice and I have been eagerly wanting to pay a visit. I am too used to REAL burger, these are Hong Kong style burger. The beef patty is small, and it does taste good, but not juicy enough! the egg is pretty tasteless, and it just seem abit dry and I dont like the fact it has no vegetable. The bun is cold and dry, not fluffy and soft enough
Fries: Looked nice, but bit soggy I found it. Not crispy enough. seems like those microwave chips you culd get in 7-11 back in days. I didnt like it

 Environment Very small and stuffy Not enough seats, but it remind me of old old HK style fast food. Which was quite cool.
 Services: Not much service, they all in a rush, as there were lots n lot sof people waiting. You had find seat yourself and I didnot see anyone wiping or cleaning the place

 OVERALL: if you like chinese style burger then you would love it. But I am a big fan of shake em buns, big meaty juicy burger with lots of cheese. But this place is cheap and it does have it own style. But I would recommend you to give this place a visit and a try. Not many places do such authentic OLD Hong kong style burger
 Recommended Dish(es): 雙層芝士蛋漢堡,
 Table Wait Time: 5 minute(s)

 Date of Visit: Mar 15, 2009
 Spending per head: Approximately HKD20(Tea)
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 3 |  Environment 2 |  Service 2 |  Hygiene 2 |  Value for Money 5 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 jason.bonvivant 180 Review(s) Si Sun Fast Food 時新快餐店 Jul 03, 2010 
 
 When it comes to Hong Kong style burger, most people would point you to Si Sun Fast Food for its bargain hearty burger with homemade sauce and meat patty. For around HKD16 you get yourself a double cheese burger with fried egg! Do expect long queues and cramped seating arrangement on a first come first served basis. You can bring you own stool and sit outside if you like, no one is going to stop you.

Was it worth the wait? I guess so for its price but not sure if I will come back for the next several months until the summer is gone. It was a pleasant experience thanks to the great company. Check out Mochachocolata Rita&apos;s version of this visit. They all ordered mat burgers while for some odd reasons I ordered a fish burger because ... I want to be different? And I even forgot to snap a picture of the fish burger as well! Argh! The Double Cheese Burger with the melting cheese was like calling to be eaten! I was told that the bun was rather soft and the meat ... the meat ... well, hard to tell whether it as pork or beef? HAHA ... At least my fish tasted like fish. As long as it was meaty, it was good enough as a burger (Hong Kong style wise of course)! The addition of the fried eggs in my opinion was a very crucial item for a Hong Kong style burger!

They do offer Pork Burger with cheese but as Rita mentioned, the size of the burgers were pretty TINY that I did not dare to ask for a bite as well. One bite from me would be ... 70% of the whole burger!

I finished my tiny fish burgers within 3 tiny bites and I was ready to tackle the fries and deep fried chicken legs! Who do many of us love deep fried food? Are we going to get tired of it? Not me for sure! The fries were unexciting and the deep friend chicken legs were a bit too dry. It was hard to share so I had to dissect it carefully. I really wanted to order a few more but a look at the line up changed my mind. I really miss the Big Deep Fried Chicken Slab from Taipei&apos;s night market which is large enough to serve a small family of ...6!? (alright, maybe small family of ... 4!?)

Likes:
- Price? Bargain? ...
Dislikes:
- Long queue all the time and cramped seating arrangement
- Burger size pretty TINY!
Avg Spending: Below HKD 100 per person
Original Post: http://www.jasonbonvivant.com/2010/06/si-sun-fast-food.html Other Ratings: 
Taste 3 |  Environment 2 |  Service 2 |  Hygiene 3 |  Value for Money 4 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 4 Vote(s) View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 mochachocolatarita 73 Review(s) Yummy HK Style Burgers Jun 28, 2010 
 
 What does it mean by Hong Kong style burger?

It means...
- Generic burger sweet buns you can buy from supermarket, probably from Garden bread?
- You can hardly tell if the patty is beef or pork or anything else?
- Salad sauce = Miracle Whip + Sugar + Water
It also means bloody DELICIOUS!

I order the above tower-of-sin (double cheeseburger + fried egg), it&apos;s yummy to the max! I didn&apos;t care that I could not tell if it was beef or pork. The double pork cheese burger was equally delicious, tasted pretty much the same as mine minus the fried egg...

Some of us ordered fish burgers...quite small, you might want to order something else to fill you up. I&apos;ve also requested to order a serving of Hong Kong style deep fried chicken leg and a pile of Hong Kong style fries, which were yummy!

Remember to go early as the place gets really crowded.

http://mochachocolatarita.blogspot.com/2010/06/hong-kong-style-burger-from-si-sun-fast.html Double cheeseburger with fried egg&amp;salad sauce Double Pork burger with salad sauce Fish burger Fried chicken leg and fries Recommended Dish(es): double cheeseburger with fried egg
 Date of Visit: Jun 06, 2010
 Spending per head: Approximately HKD30(Lunch)
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 5 |  Environment 3 |  Service 3 |  Hygiene 4 |  Value for Money 5 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 2 Vote(s) View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 Food Craver 167 Review(s) Nice Local Hamburger Restaurant Jun 26, 2010 
 
 This day I went back from China through Lowu and decided to pay a visit to Si Sun Fast Food Restaurant. Luckily there wasn&apos;t any queue when I arrived at the restaurant and there were some seats available for dinning in. As squash as usual, I made my way to a seat in between madly in loved couple and energetic students.

I decided to have a light lunch so I could have some egg pancakes around the corner later on. I went to the old spot to order my food but did not realize they have now got a reception for food ordering. Embarrassed as I was, I ordered a Cheese&amp;Egg Hamburger with tomato sauce. I got my tag and the food was served fast.

The Hamburger had such an appetizing look, but I had to hold my drooling as I had to snap a few photos before enjoying it. The Hamburger Bun was slightly toasted to give a light crusty texture but was mostly soft. I love the drizzling sesame on top of the bun. The cheese was warm but had no intention in melting. Disappointing but understandable as the whole burger would not be baked in an oven.

The Patty was not particularly thick, but at least double of what Mc Donald&apos;s offers. The texture was quite tender and very juicy. Upon having a few bites, the patty&apos;s juice would be all over the place, sliding down from your hand to your waist and along your forearm. Be prepared to get messy while having this burger. The patty was freshly made and gave a strong seasoned beef tasted which was nice to munch on.

The Sun Fried Egg on the other hand was just an average, nothing really special about it. It would be better if it could be fried one sided so the egg york was just halfly done when served.

Si Sun is a very nice fast food restaurant that could offer you the environment for local culture experiencing. The squeezy table seating, the fast delivery of food, freshly made hamburgers, TV at the corner, nostalgic menus sticking on the wall with promotional advertisements hanging alongside. Laughter was everywhere, Burger lovers were enjoying their burger messily and workers were craving their lunch sets hastily. Not sure if it would be the right spot for foreigners to experience the HK culture, but definitely a must try for the locally born Chinese.

www.cinnamon4coffee.blogspot.com The Fast Food Store Front Cheese n Egg Hamburger with Tomato Sauce Peeking ithe inside layer of my hamburger! Recommended Dish(es): Cheese&amp;Egg Hamburger
 Date of Visit: Jun 16, 2010
 Spending per head: Approximately HKD15(Lunch)
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 4 |  Environment 3 |  Service 4 |  Hygiene 3 |  Value for Money 5 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 2 Vote(s) View Results Recommend Message (1) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 1 2 3 Home | Restaurant Search | Review | Coupon | Recipe | Forum 
 Mobile OpenRice | OpenRice in Chinese | OpenRice Travel | Online Restaurant Reservations | 开饭喇 
 Member Registration | Submit Restaurant Info | About Us | Editor&apos;s Blog | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | Site Map OpenRice.com is Hong Kong&apos;s most popular dining guide to help people find places to eat based on the restaurant reviews written by real local people. OpenRice also offers restaurant discount coupons , food delivery directory and recipes .Through our Hong Kong restaurant search engine, users can easily find their desired dining places by districts such as Central restaurants , Causeway Bay restaurants , TST restaurants and cuisines such as French restaurants , Italian restaurants , Chinese restaurants , Japanese restaurants , and buffet . 
Copyright©1999-2012 Openrice Group Inc. All Rights Reserved.
 Hong Kong&apos;s Most Popular Dining Guide,
with restaurant search, restaurants reviews, and dining coupons. 
 Other Group Products 


 
 Gourmet Feed 
 Sorry, no information Loading 
 Quick Display of Restaurants 

 Restaurants Around Living Area Restaurants Around Working Area 
 My Favourite Restaurants 
 
 Share this page: Quick Display of Restaurants:
	</body>
</document>
