<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009829" url="http://www.manta.com/mb_35_C432C000_000/eating_places" time="2012-07-13-03:13" support="1" score="0.001286202463273498" bingtitle="Restaurants in the United States | Find a Restaurant" webtitle="Restaurants in the United States | Find a Restaurant">
			<query id="000359" bing-rank="202"/>
	<description>When you eat with us, you are not just eating the best ... everyone else at Milano Inn invites you to have a seat ... Fast-Food Restaurant, Chain · Cafes · Caterers · Mexican ...</description>
	<body>
		%3c%54%41%42%4c%45%20%69%64%3d&quot;%73%62%62%5f%46%69%59&quot;%20%73%74%79%6c%65%3d&quot;%64%69%73%70%6c%61%79%3a%6e%6f%6e%65&quot;%3e%3c%54%52%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%65%47%63%6a%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%49%48%52%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%42%70%48%5a%55%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%78%44%4b%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%49%65%53%4b%6c%53%56%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%64%45%76%61%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%52%4f%41%4d%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%70%56%73%56%5a%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%50%76%51%4c%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%4b%65%78%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%58%4c%49%74%62%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%71%6b%70%57%46%49%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%64%52%55%69%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%6e%4b%6e%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%50%51%64%4a%43%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%4d%4e%7a%58%61%61%73%41%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%75%4d%79%71%50%41%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%45%62%72%71%7a%42%4f%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%72%48%4e%65%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%42%71%5a%7a%68%49%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%2f%54%52%3e%3c%54%52%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%74%65%72%65%7a%58%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%50%4a%43%61%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%78%45%7a%61%56%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%49%50%64%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%73%53%67%61%43%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%45%6e%64%6c%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%76%44%78%77%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%54%51%43%6e%62%41%73%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%43%66%54%6a%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%49%6c%57%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%78%43%6b%42%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%47%46%47%54%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%76%42%49%75%67%4a%58%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%4f%71%4c%68%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%55%47%6e%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%77%63%72%4e%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%45%47%4a%76%67%51%46%43%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%57%74%74%6d%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%74%51%58%6a%41%71%76%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%48%6a%67%74%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%2f%54%52%3e%3c%54%52%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%69%6d%45%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%61%64%68%54%56%68%46%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%4e%68%4b%6b%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%61%48%4b%6b%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%42%70%58%72%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%63%6a%72%71%49%42%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%79%67%62%4b%75%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%5a%79%53%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%77%4b%57%4b%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%4b%45%41%64%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%64%77%64%41%71%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%6c%6b%78%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%47%4c%71%46%4a%55%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%74%49%42%79%58%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%5a%41%6a%52%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%6b%78%57%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%79%51%69%63%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%4c%6c%7a%62%62%41%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%51%70%52%4a%54%4d%67%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%48%53%73%58%79%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%2f%54%52%3e%3c%54%52%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%61%58%77%49%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%4a%6b%47%4d%68%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%42%70%4f%75%46%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%45%79%4e%53%45%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%4e%4c%78%57%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%6f%64%64%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%69%78%42%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%46%62%79%43%41%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%52%55%52%75%69%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%53%75%43%53%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%64%43%6e%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%79%77%56%56%79%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%51%4d%56%6c%66%49%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%73%79%77%77%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%4c%4b%41%62%7a%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%64%64%4d%6c%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%48%57%62%76%46%52%6c%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%42%53%55%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%51%45%43%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%54%44%78%66%76%54%54%63%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%2f%54%52%3e%3c%54%52%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%4c%64%64%63%46%4b%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%70%4d%6d%76%55%57%72%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%4a%45%49%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%61%4e%61%6a%50%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%57%75%67%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%55%63%43%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%74%55%69%74%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%4f%50%56%72%61%76%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%44%66%44%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%72%6e%4e%76%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%6b%4f%74%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%71%43%4f%68%58%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%4e%55%50%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%5a%49%6e%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%7a%61%47%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%42%4b%44%78%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%4c%73%6b%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%62%7a%4a%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%54%44%20%6f%6e%63%6c%69%63%6b%3d&quot;%72%65%74%75%72%6e%20%27%66%71%6d%73%27&quot;%3e%3c%53%50%41%4e%3e%50%58%6f%61%4b%57%3c%2f%53%50%41%4e%3e%3c%2f%54%44%3e%3c%2f%54%52%3e%3c%2f%54%41%42%4c%45%3e Sign In Email Password 
 Forgot your password? 
 New to Manta? Join Free U.S. Companies Worldwide Manta Connect Features Promote Your Business Add Your Company Search U.S. Companies Search only Restaurants Search the World (except U.S.) Companies Chart It 
United States Restaurants

Manta has details on 260835 Restaurants in the United States. Of these Restaurants, 30% make more than $500,000 annually and 19% employ more than 20 people. See other rich data such as location and contact information for Restaurants in the United States.
 
 + Add Your Company for Free Top Featured Companies 
 
 
 Prohost Insurance 
 166 Hill Top Road, Germantown, NY 12526 P. O. Box 537 , Germantown NY 12526 map (518) 697-0336 1 Recommendation hide Eve Mersfelder (client) Top qualities: Personable Expert Good Value “I contacted Richard when I started...  Richard   Scott Hospitality Insurance   Restaurants, bars, taverns, caterers, golf and country clubs, small/medium size motels, anything to do with where folks meet to eat and greet! 
 Golf and Country Clubs Restaurants Bars and Taverns view all 
 
 
 
 Green Chili Indian Cuisine 
 1 Nicholas Rd # 49 , Framingham MA 01701 map (508) 877-4670 0 Recommendations Green Chili, located in the Pinefield Plaza, serves an eclectic mix of all-day breakfast, South and North Indian Cuisine.   All kinds of meats,Veggies,Seafoods many more items available such as:All kinds of Dosa(Crepes) all type of Uttaphoms(Pancakes) all types of Curries,all kinds of appetizers, also hotdogs, Wraps, Indian all kinds of Pizzas Sandwhices,home made drinks plus other soft drinks are here, Kids meals,8 different brand Ice Creams,Specially Meat products Halal, food preparation infront of you from the Counter, All food are custom made food from scratch: order through Menu,we don&apos;t have Buffet if you have patience to wait please visit our website&amp;come down give it a try your best interested you will feel the flavor,texture,quality&amp;quanties not like other restaurants.Fast food dine in&amp;dine out Open Now Monday through Saturday 10 am to 10 pm. Sunday and Holidays 12 pm to 10 pm. Additional Info: EXCELLENT FOOD, Excellent Staff, we have great food, good times, warm friendly smiles and LOW prices waiting for you to experience!
I like to introduce myself that my name is Anthony Gomes. 49 years 
 Green Chili Indian Cuisine Menu Green Chili Indian Food Menu Items view all 
 
 
 
 PHO 21 Noodles and Grills 
 2230 S Collins Street , Arlington TX 76010-6403 map (817) 801-0016 0 Recommendations Vietnamese Food, pho, beef noodle soup, grill meats, BOBA TEA   authentic vietnamese cusine including Pho beef noodle soup, vermicelli noodles , fried rice, HU TIEU clear noodle soup, BOBA tea smothie drinks. 
 noodles RICE PLATES RICE PLATE view all 
 
 
 
 Yacht Events LLC. 
 Chelsea Piers-23rd St&amp;the Hudson River New York, NY 10011 , New York NY 10011 map 646-801-2628 0 Recommendations Flawless Execution is Our Mission
The premier NYC special event location and has been setting the standard for fine dining aboard luxury yachts in NY   As independent representatives, we now have the ability to further provide enhanced services to our clients. When our fleet is fully booked, and/ or a privately owned yacht is a better fit for a clients needs, we provide that extended service. Our yachts for charter are perfect for any event from 20-1200 guests. We offer a diverse style to accommodate our client&apos;s individual taste and preferences.
With Flawless Execution, as the leading one-stop solutions provider for yacht events, we manage it all-from assisting with the initial strategy and developing measurable objectives to logistics -all within budget and on time!
But don&apos;t just take our word for it. Look to the organizations who rely on us to meet their yacht needs. Our clients are principally Fortune 500 companies. 
 Corporate catering and event planning view all 
 
 
 
 Cebiche House 
 117 N Frederick Ave , Gaithersburg MD 20877-2437 map (301) 330-2400 0 Recommendations Fine Peruvian dining, specializing in seafood. Lunch buffets. Live events on weekends.   Cebiche House is owned and operated by Flavors of Peru, LLC. Cebiche House was opened near to Old Towne Gaithersburg on December 26th, 2010. Cebiche House is regarded as the headquarters of Peruvian cuisine in the United States. It is constantly evolving, thanks to the quality of its dishes. It is the only restaurant specializing in seafood and having dishes created in its own kitchen: (1)&quot;Ceviche House&quot;(the most popular), (2) skewered chicken in Pachamanca and Pisco sauce, and (3) the current sensation: Huancaina spaghetti with medallions. In Peru, the&quot;Cebiche Club&quot;brings together 32 exclusive restaurants specializing in seafood. Thirty (30) are in Peru and two (2) are in the United States: Panca in New York and Cebiche House in Washington DC. Additional Info: One of 2 members of Cebiche Club in USA 
 Peruvian Restaurant Entertainment Buffet 
 
 
 
 Rawhide Bar N Grill 
 211 Main St. , Starbuck WA 99359 map 3 Recommendations hide Thanks to the owners of the Rawhide Bar N Grill for the instant hospitality your enthusiasm and...  Brenda  Criss view all BBQ Food and Family Fun is our specialty!   We have a wide variety of Food&amp;Entertainment
-Famous Steak Dinner-Ribeye, Flat Iron, Gourmet cut New Yorks
-Beer to Go
-Sack Lunches
-Free Pool
-Free Darts
-Free Horse pits
-Pool or Horse Shoe tournaments every SUNDAY!
-Kids menu, coloring pages&amp;Balloons... High chairs for the little ones
-Big Screen TV-Sports, Outdoors, Nas Car ect.
-Juke Box (Roll the Bartender for Music $)
-Party Resevations
-Outside dining&amp;music
-Poker Runs
-Bi-annual litter pick *Sign up 2day
-Located on the Tucannon&amp;Snake River
-Just around the corner from DARVER TACKLE&amp;REEL PEOPLE FISHING GUIDE SERVICE
-Up the road from the Pallouse Falls, Lyons Ferry Marina, Little Goose Dam, Texas Rapids camp Ground, Little Goose --Landing Camp Ground
-$1 off your drink for every fish you catch!
-&amp;Mor 
 Beer and Wine Outdoor Dining&amp;Games BBQ Food 
 
 
 
 Nations Cafe Lounge 
 8290 Roswell Road , Sandy Springs GA 30350 map 0 Recommendations Nations Café is a part of our parent company, Destiny Food Services and Banquet Catering Inc., a firm of experienced and multi-talented professionals.   Chef Okon James&apos;s extensive experience in the hospitality industry which includes service at the Ritz-Calton Hotel in Buckhead, Japanese Innovation at the Nikko Hotel in Buckhead, The Buckhead Diner, Graceland Dining, Nations Café, Conyers and the Hilton Hotel&amp;Tower in downtown Atlanta as well as service at PYA Monarch - Food Distribution Coorporation.

At Trader Vic&apos;s, he was trained by Chef John Lui until he became executive sous chef. Shortly after, he moved on to Nikkolia&apos;s Roof for further training by seasoned French master Chef Marc Benoid along with AAT Culinary Arts at Gwinnett Tech for food preparation and management development, earning his diploma for food service management in the hotel and motel industry. At the Atlanta Hilton&amp;Towers, he prepared American food, while at the Terrace Garden restaurant, he prepared Southern cuisine. He also received extensive training at T.H. Hamilton Management School for Piccadilly managers and assumed an Assistant General Manager position at the Travel Center of America after completing his management training program. Additionally, he attended Paine College and Clayton State College. 

He is currently serving cross-functional responsibilities in restaurant management and operations. When you eat with us, you are not just eating the best, but the finest you can imagine. Please come in and visit us! Our clients eat free on their anniversary! For that True unique Taste come see us for all your dinning and catering needs. Additional Info: Prestigious Award - Best African Restaurant in Atlanta 
 African Food - Catering and Full Service view all 
 
 
 
 Little Bucharest Bistro 
 3661 N elston ave , Chicago IL 60618 map 2 Recommendations hide Of course I had a great experience here; Traditional Romanian/Serbian recipes spiced up with a Contemporary American...  Kai  Camillo view all American Contemporary Traditional Romanian Cuisine.

Daily specials, weekly discounts, online catering and delivery!   Out door patio with inlaid rustic brick as if you were back in the rare Bucharest of Romania or France.

Marble and wood refinement dining decor to enclose a colourful but sensual eating experience.

Family oriented for parties, celebrations of every culture and mix of people! Limo service for reservations of six or more through our website!

Great staff, of multi-cultural influences, down to their attire, presentation, and ambiance.

Tailored cocktails with specific herb infusions, our mixologists and wine selections are working hard for your diverse palette.

Fresh ingredients,eggplant spreads, raw and perfected culminations of dishes that will surprise you, charm you,and keep you coming back!

If you&apos;re in the Chicago Area, you must come on down for our flaming saganaki! Opa!!! Additional Info: Romanian and Serbian culture. 

The owner Branko Produmedic visited with The President of Romania for the Chicago Summit of this year 2012 
 Catering 
 
 
 
 Angels Country Kitchen 
 1878 Church Ave. , Harrah OK 73045 map 0 Recommendations ANGEL&apos;S COUNTRY KITCHEN good old down home country cooking at its best, we are talking biscuits and gravy and home fries and much more   ANGEL&apos;S COUNTRY KITCHEN good old down home country cooking at its best, chicken fried steak, biscuits and gravy and home fries and buffets and breakfast any hour open 
 country breaksfast all day long great hamburgers view all 
 
 
 
 Milano Inn 
 231 S College Avenue , Indianapolis IN 46202-4005 map 0 Recommendations The Milano Inn has served delicious food with Italian hospitality to downtown Indianapolis since 1934.   Relying on Italian hospitality and good food, Milano Inn has stood watch as Indianapolis has evolved. It was founded during the Great Depression, flourished as manufacturers prospered during the 1940s and survived as subdivisions lured families to the suburbs starting in the 1950s. It has seen the rise and fall of Market Square Arena and the Hoosier Dome. Skyscrapers, world-class hotels, and a resurgence in urban living has revitalized downtown in recent years and, as always, Milano Inn has welcomed those from the neighborhood and beyond with warmth, and tried and true family recipes.

As custodians of this proud tradition, the LaGrotte family, Chef John White, and everyone else at Milano Inn invites you to have a seat at our table. Additional Info: We are family-owned and are known for being Indianapolis&apos; oldest Italian Restaurant. We are dog-friendly and welcome groups of any number. 
 Restuarant Catering Bar 
 See all featured companies Featured Categories · Restaurants · Pizza · Fast-Food Restaurant, Chain · Cafes · Caterers · Mexican Restaurant · Sandwiches · Chinese Restaurant · Coffee Shops · Delicatessens 
 All 260,835 Companies Too many to display. Narrow by category or location below. Current Category for location United States 
 All Industries ~ Restaurants&amp;Bars ~ Restaurants ~ Restaurants 
 Browse Other Subcategories of Restaurants 
 
 American Restaurant (14,729) 
 
 Appetizers and Snacks (15) 
 
 Arranged Banquets (11) 
 
 Automat (Eating Places) (22) 
 
 Banquet Rooms (2,343) 
 
 Barbecue (15,550) 
 
 Beverage Stores (336) 
 
 Box Lunches (122) 
 
 Buffet (Eating Places) (4,081) 
 
 Cafes (42,206) 
 
 Cafeteria (2,286) 
 
 Cafeterias (2,697) 
 
 Cajun Restaurant (623) 
 
 Carry Out Restaurants (5,490) 
 
 Caterers (39,609) 
 
 Catering-Kosher (30) 
 
 Chicken Dinners (19) 
 
 Chicken Restaurant (6,100) 
 
 Chili Parlors (130) 
 
 Chinese Restaurant (31,836) 
 
 Coffee Shops (29,929) 
 
 Commissary Contractors (118) 
 
 Concessionaire (1,859) 
 
 Contract Food Services (1,631) 
 
 Deli-Bakery (99) 
 
 Delicatessens (23,121) 
 
 Dessert Preparations (35) 
 
 Diner (6,858) 
 
 Drive-In Restaurant (5,998) 
 
 
 
 Eating Places, Nec (4) 
 
 Ethnic Food Restaurants (6,175) 
 
 Family Restaurants (18,071) 
 
 Fast Food Restaurants and Stands (4,914) 
 
 Fast-Food Restaurant, Chain (55,528) 
 
 Fast-Food Restaurant, Independent (3,741) 
 
 Food Bars (497) 
 
 Food Delivery Restaurants (463) 
 
 Food Service-Industrial (18) 
 
 Foods-Institutional (20) 
 
 French Restaurant (1,227) 
 
 Frozen Yogurt Stand (1,239) 
 
 German Restaurant (344) 
 
 Greek Food Products (1,421) 
 
 Grills (Eating Places) (18,532) 
 
 Hamburger and Hot Dog Stands (2,561) 
 
 Health Food Restaurant (613) 
 
 Hot Dog Stands (1,938) 
 
 Ice Cream Parlors (21,857) 
 
 Indian/Pakistan Restaurant (2,322) 
 
 Industrial Cafeteria Operators (4) 
 
 Italian Food Products (50) 
 
 Italian Restaurant (14,693) 
 
 Japanese Restaurant (6,866) 
 
 Jewish Foods (2) 
 
 Korean Restaurant (845) 
 
 Lebanese Restaurant (126) 
 
 Luaus (9) 
 
 Luncheonette Food Supply (1,847) 
 
 
 
 Lunchroom (61) 
 
 Mexican Restaurant (33,136) 
 
 Mobile Concessions (60) 
 
 Oyster Bars (262) 
 
 Pakistani Restaurant (68) 
 
 Pizza (69,378) 
 
 Pizzeria, Chain (22,061) 
 
 Pizzeria, Independent (3,088) 
 
 Refreshment Stands (2,337) 
 
 Restaurant Management (2,909) 
 
 Restaurant, Family: Chain (17,548) 
 
 Restaurant, Family: Independent (6,699) 
 
 Restaurant, Lunch Counter (578) 
 
 Restaurants (260,823) 
 
 Sandwiches (32,271) 
 
 Seafood Restaurants (10,015) 
 
 Seafood Shack (529) 
 
 Snack Bar (1,324) 
 
 Snack Shop (522) 
 
 Snow Cone Stand (353) 
 
 Soda Fountain Shops (216) 
 
 Soft Drink Stand (789) 
 
 Spanish Restaurant (662) 
 
 Steak Restaurant (9,576) 
 
 Steak and Barbecue Restaurants (2,271) 
 
 Sushi Bar (3,611) 
 
 Tea Rooms (232) 
 
 Thai Restaurant (5,276) 
 
 Theatres-Dinner (232) 
 
 Vietnamese Restaurant (1,327) 
 
 
 Get Listed on Manta. It&apos;s Free! 
Thousands of people add their company to Manta everyday.

Add your website links, social media, business information and more.

 Get Listed Now 
 Current Location for category Restaurants 
 United States 
 Browse States 
 
 Alabama (3,545) 
 
 Alaska (716) 
 
 Arizona (4,528) 
 
 Arkansas (2,169) 
 
 California (32,615) 
 
 Colorado (4,629) 
 
 Connecticut (2,788) 
 
 Delaware (736) 
 
 District of Columbia (1,118) 
 
 Florida (18,876) 
 
 Georgia (8,834) 
 
 Hawaii (1,700) 
 
 Idaho (1,148) 
 
 Illinois (10,473) 
 
 Indiana (4,274) 
 
 Iowa (2,247) 
 
 Kansas (1,991) 
 
 Kentucky (3,172) 
 
 
 
 Louisiana (3,537) 
 
 Maine (1,274) 
 
 Maryland (4,247) 
 
 Massachusetts (5,687) 
 
 Michigan (7,070) 
 
 Minnesota (3,593) 
 
 Mississippi (2,106) 
 
 Missouri (4,476) 
 
 Montana (948) 
 
 Nebraska (1,290) 
 
 Nevada (2,841) 
 
 New Hampshire (1,184) 
 
 New Jersey (8,110) 
 
 New Mexico (1,696) 
 
 New York (21,755) 
 
 North Carolina (7,374) 
 
 North Dakota (458) 
 
 
 
 Ohio (7,744) 
 
 Oklahoma (2,857) 
 
 Oregon (4,004) 
 
 Pennsylvania (9,630) 
 
 Puerto Rico (201) 
 
 Rhode Island (1,020) 
 
 South Carolina (4,124) 
 
 South Dakota (577) 
 
 Tennessee (4,734) 
 
 Texas (20,853) 
 
 Utah (1,817) 
 
 Vermont (626) 
 
 Virgin Islands (12) 
 
 Virginia (6,167) 
 
 Washington (6,277) 
 
 West Virginia (1,562) 
 
 Wisconsin (4,890) 
 
 Wyoming (534) 
 
 
Refine Your Results
 
Filter companies by:
 
Newly Formed Businesses
 Date Started: 1 week ago 2 weeks ago 3 weeks ago 4 weeks ago 5 weeks ago 6 weeks ago 7 weeks ago 8 weeks ago 9 weeks ago 10 weeks ago 11 weeks ago 12 weeks ago 13 weeks ago 14 weeks ago 15 weeks ago 16 weeks ago 17 weeks ago 18 weeks ago 19 weeks ago 20 weeks ago 21 weeks ago 22 weeks ago 23 weeks ago 24 weeks ago 25 weeks ago 26 weeks ago 27 weeks ago 28 weeks ago 29 weeks ago 30 weeks ago 31 weeks ago 32 weeks ago 33 weeks ago 34 weeks ago 35 weeks ago 36 weeks ago 37 weeks ago 38 weeks ago 39 weeks ago 40 weeks ago 41 weeks ago 42 weeks ago 43 weeks ago 44 weeks ago 45 weeks ago 46 weeks ago 47 weeks ago 48 weeks ago 49 weeks ago 50 weeks ago 51 weeks ago 52 weeks ago All since selected week Selected week only 
 Enhanced Profiles
 Has been claimed by a co. representative Has Twitter Has Facebook 
Company Revenue
 Less than $500,000 $500K → $1M $1M → $2.5M $2.5M → $5M $5M → $10M $10M → $20M $20M → $50M $50M → $100M $100M → $500M $500M → $1B More than $1Billion 
Number of Employees
 1 → 4 5 → 9 10 → 19 20 → 49 50 → 99 100 → 249 250 → 499 500 → 999 1,000 → 4,999 5,000 → 9,999 More than 10,000 
Ownership
 Public Companies Private Companies 
Location Type
 Headquarters (HQ) Branch Single Location   Recently Updated These Restaurants have updated their profiles. Add your company now. 
 
 
 Blue Moon Cafe&apos; 

Kihei, HI

Updated 7/12/2012
 
 
 
 Atlantis Grill 

Pompano Beach, FL

Updated 7/12/2012
 
 
 
 Tom&apos;s Hotdog Services 

Cleveland, OH

Updated 7/12/2012
 
 
 
 CJ&apos;s Bar-B-Skew 

Tampa, FL

Updated 7/12/2012
 
 
 
 We Cader Picnic Tables 

Mckinleyville, CA

Updated 7/12/2012
 
 
 
 Guelaguetza Plaza Mexico 

Lynwood, CA

Updated 7/12/2012
 
 
 
 Off Route 32 Cafe 

Stewardson, IL

Updated 7/12/2012
 
 
 
 Teresa&apos;s Restaurant 

Brooklyn, NY

Updated 7/12/2012
 
 
 
 SpitfireZ 

Wilmerding, PA

Updated 7/12/2012
 
 
 
 LA Subs 

Daphne, AL

Updated 7/12/2012
 
 
 
 Mac The Knife Steakhouse 

Stamford, CT

Updated 7/12/2012
 
 
 
 Hooligans Sports Food Drink 

Alpharetta, GA

Updated 7/11/2012
 
 
 
 Motherland Kitchen LLC 

Marietta, GA

Updated 7/11/2012
 
 
 
 Gilly&apos;s Restaurant 

Pompton Plains, NJ

Updated 7/11/2012
 
 
 
 Bart&apos;s Bar-B-Que 

Dickson, TN

Updated 7/11/2012
 
 
 
 Father&apos;s Table Catering Inc 

Lynchburg, VA

Updated 7/11/2012
 
 
 
 Little Italy italian restaurant 

Lake Worth, FL

Updated 7/11/2012
 
 
 
 On The ROX 

Richmond, VA

Updated 7/11/2012
 
 
 
 Bucket&apos;s Sports Grill 

Laredo, TX

Updated 7/10/2012
 
 
 
 Frankie C&apos;s Pizzeria 

Wake Forest, NC

Updated 7/10/2012
 
 
 See all claimed profiles Companies in this category may offer: 
 Meal Delivery Services Restaurants by Speciality Drinking Establishments Membership Restaurants Restaurants by Country Cuisines Restaurant Reservation Services Open Air Restaurants 
 People searching this category also searched for: 
 Memberships Restaurants Mohegan Sun Casino Restaurants Snacks Restaurant Bankside Restaurants Brinkleys Restaurants Member Ship Restaurants Breakers Hotel Restaurants Membership Restaurant Club Soda Restaurant Brinkleys Restaurants - Putney Station Union Hotel Restaurant Blue Stone Restaurant Restaurant 
 Companies by Location: United States Business Topics 
 Small Business Sales Expertise Human Resources Marketing Franchise Technology 
 Browse Companies 
 U.S. Australia Canada UK Worldwide 
 Resources 
 Videos Jobs White Papers Site Map 
 Manta Links 
 About Manta Contact Manta Manta Careers Media Resources FAQ Advertise With Us 
 Copyright©Manta Media Inc. All rights reserved 
 Note: Our Privacy Policy and Terms&amp;Conditions have changed 6/1/12 
 Blog Twitter Facebook Manta News
	</body>
</document>
