<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009174" url="http://www.lowcountrytoday.com/npps/story.cfm?nppage=27511" time="2012-07-13-02:34" support="1" score="0.0002912956178581572" bingtitle="Cinebarre Mt. Pleasant Taking Movie Night To Next Level News Article" webtitle="Cinebarre Mt. Pleasant Taking Movie Night To Next Level News Article">
			<query id="001301" bing-rank="123"/>
	<description>Cinebarre doesn’t bill itself as a five star eatery, yet they are light years above any fast food restaurant. ... At $6 it’s no more than you’d pay for ...</description>
	<body>
		Your Charleston SC Low Country Community Guide 
 
 Jul 12, 2012    
 
 Home
 My LCT 
 Networking 
 Contact Us Visitors 
 Restaurants 
 Hotels 
 Nightlife Events 
 Contests 
 Coupons 
 e-Cards Classifieds 
 Shopping 
 e-Shopping Mall 
 Business Directory Employment&amp;Jobs 
 Real Estate 
  - Homes For Sale 
  - Apartments&amp;Rentals News 
 Blogs 
 Forums 
 Letters Announcements 
 Newsletters 
 Photos 
 Features / Videos 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 
   
 News » Entertainment   Charleston SC Newspaper Entertainment Section Article 

 Entertainment   

   

 
Cinebarre Mt. Pleasant Taking Movie Night To Next Level
 
 
 Popular Low Country Theater Celebrates,&apos;Eat, Drink,&amp;Watch Movies&apos; 
 
 By Jeff Walker, Entertainment Writer 

 

 There’s a great little eatery on Houston Northcutt Boulevard in Mt. Pleasant that offers up movies on the side, or is Cinebarre a movie theater that offers up a side of great food and drink. Either way you slice it, it’s a great combination. Cinebarre Mt. Pleasant has taken the concept of‘dinner and a movie’to the next level.

There are plenty of places throughout the low country to catch a movie. You can take in a flick from Oakbrook of Summerville to West Ashley, and from North Charleston to James Island. But there is only one place in all of greater Charleston where you can eat, drink, and watch movies all under one roof.

Now I’m not talking your standard fare of soft drinks, popcorn, and candy. Every theater from here to Timbuktu has the same tired snack choices But then again, Cinebarre is not your average movie theater. They are offering up a memorable night at the movies, whether you’re out with family, friends or just seeking the perfect destination for‘date night’.

As soon as you walk into the lobby of Cinebarre you’ll notice the difference right away. It has more of a laid back bistro meets lounge kind of feel. A couple of pool tables surrounded by comfortable sofas, with various bistro table and chairs scattered about. The walls are bedecked with a plethora of vintage movie posters celebrating some of Hollywood’s greatest and most obscure cinematic masterpieces.

Center stage is a relaxing bar where you can sit and have a cold beer (including local breweries) or a glass of wine while you’re waiting on your movie. Although most patrons enjoy the menu items while watching their movie choice, it is perfectly fine to enjoy your meal out in the atrium. Plenty of personable wait staff ready to cater to your night out.

Following the current trend, Cinebarre provides stadium style seating, where each row of seats is elevated. That way you’re not seeing the back of someone’s head. However Cinebarre has taken that concept to the next level, whereby they have removed every other row, replacing it with a full length counter for patrons to eat at.

After renovating Mt. Pleasant Cinema back in 2008, Cinebarre converted one of the existing 12 theatres into a fully functional kitchen where wait staff buzz in and out of carrying your selections to your seats. Order sheets located at every seat inside the theater along with pre-movie instructions provide patrons all the necessary information should they decide to partake in dinner with the movie.

Keeping in mind that most movie watchers don’t want to get messy during their visit, Cinebarre serves up finger friendly foods that are not only tasty but easy to maneuver. Appetizers, sandwiches, designer pizzas, and desserts that will satisfy even if your movie choice doesn’t. What I find most clever is that every menu item reflects a movie title or a character from a movie. Just another way they spice up your adventure.

Cinebarre doesn’t bill itself as a five star eatery, yet they are light years above any fast food restaurant. No frozen quick fix microwave dinners poured out of a bag. The kitchen staff prepare a variety of items from scratch, and for a theater that is rare. Cinebarre is selling pretentious, rather they are offering up an innovative movie experience.

From the appetizer menu I would strongly suggest the‘Body Snatchers’aka loaded potato skins. Covered in bacon, melted cheddar, and chives, they are as good as any upscale chain restaurant. Great with ranch dressing or sour cream. The fresh cut Idaho potato fries (Blade Runners) is well worth $6. Looking for something more hardy, the plump and juicy chicken tenders are seasoned to perfection and a meal unto themselves.

The specialty pizzas are perhaps the biggest sellers on the menu, and at just $12.50 moderately priced. Simple to eat and easily feeds two diners. The‘Chicken Run’will excite your taste buds. Caramelized red onions, green peppers, cilantro, with grilled chicken, smothered in cheddar and mozzarella. An excellent choice. Meat lovers may opt for the‘Italian Job’layered with pepperoni, or the‘Bull Durham’loaded with pepperoni, Canadian bacon, and sausage. Over a half dozen gourmet pizzas to choose from or build your own.

A typical two hour movie leaves more than enough time to squeeze in a little decadent dessert. Hey you’re out for the evening, so splurge.‘Just Like Heaven’is just that, a heavenly slice of creamy New York style cheese cake drizzled with strawberry syrup. At $6 it’s no more than you’d pay for similar fare in downtown Charleston.

‘Goin’South’celebrates our local heritage with made from scratch pecan pie. Chocolate lovers beware, the‘Chocolat’is a sumptuous double portion of Ghiradelli brownie. Served warm for $5 or with vanilla ice cream for an additional $2. Six sweet treats to tempt to delight your taste buds. Skipping dinner, than split a dessert with a glass of wine. Adding a little romance to date night.

Come in early and eat in the lobby, enjoy your food while taking in your movie selection, or hang out after the flick and munch on late night appetizers with a cold brew. You’ll find Cinebarre very refreshing and very inviting. It’s a nice change of pace. If you’re planning to eat out and catch a movie, then you’ll pay the same at Cinebarre with less hassle and plenty of free parking.

Keep Cinebarre Mt. Pleasant on your radar. They offer $5 movies on Tuesdays, with senior discounts, and family friendly times on specific days of the week. During the warmer months Cinebarre shows movies on the 70 foot inflatable screen in the parking lot. Great way to see your favorite film under the stars.

Bottom line is Cinebarre thinks outside the box. Progressive, innovative, or just‘avant garde’their sole mission is threefold, to provide patrons with good food, a decent movie, and most of all an overall unique experience.
 

 
 
  
 Submit A Comment Most Recent Comments There are no comments posted yet. Share your thoughts! Submit your comment about this story. 
 
 
 
 Send This Story To Someone Your Email: Their Email:  Comments: 
 
 
   

 

 

 
 
 News Archive   |   News Home Page   |   RSS Feeds Announcements   |   Blogs   |   Columns&amp;Newsletters   |   Features Submit A News Story   |   Contact The Editor 
 
 
   
 
 
 
 

   Ads by Low Country Today 

       Sounds Like Fun Mobile DJ   Perfect DJ For Receptions, Reunions
Anniversaries, Holiday Parties,&amp;More. Theme parties, Beach&amp;Shag,
Oldies, Big Band, Country, Disco
Perfect DJ for mixed crowds and all
your Baby Boomer get togehters.
Call Jeff 530-4284
   

   
   

   
 

   
   
 
 
 
   
 
 
 

   
 

   News&amp;Info    News  |  Events  |  Announcements  |  Blogs  |  Newsletters  |  Features / Videos  |  RSS       Guides    Cars  |  Real Estate  |  Restaurants  |  Hotels  |  Golf  |  Attorneys  |  Medical  |  Dental  |  Parks  |  Visitors   Marketplace    Business Directory  |  Jobs  |  Classifieds  |  Coupons  |  Contests  |  Shopping  |  e-Shopping       Community    Photo Gallery  |  Forums  |  Answers/FAQs  |  Schools   |  My LCT  |  Networking  |  Join LCT Email Lists   Local    Bonneau | Charleston | Cottageville | Daniel 
 Island | Folly Beach | Goose Creek  | Hanahan |  Hollywood | Isle 
 of Palms | James 
 Island | Johns Island        Ladson | Moncks Corner  |  Mount Pleasant  |  North 
 Charleston | Ravenel | Saint 
 George | Saint Stephen | Sullivan&apos;s 
 Island | Summerville | Walterboro 

 
   
 
 Home  |  Site Index  |  Privacy Policy  |  Terms of Service  |  Advertise With Us  |  Contact LCT ©2006-2009 Low Country Today, Inc. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
