<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009485" url="http://chicago.menupages.com/restaurants/windy-city-gyros/" time="2012-07-13-02:52" support="1" score="0.002111054024017422" bingtitle="Windy City Gyros - Chicago Restaurant - MenuPages Sandwiches, Hot ..." webtitle="Windy City Gyros - Chicago Restaurant - MenuPages Sandwiches, Hot Dogs, Chicken Restaurant Search">
			<query id="001449" bing-rank="23"/>
	<description>I usually call ahead so I don&apos;t have to wait around for my order. They do have decent ... This place is great for a greasy end of a bar night, or just watching the game ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to MenuPages - Please Select a city:

 New York City San Francisco Los Angeles Philadelphia Boston Chicago Washington, DC South Florida 
 New Menupages Desintations London   Paris 
 hide 
 
 Home Blog My MenuPages Restaurateurs Submit a Menu Change City Food Delivery Login 
 
 MenuPages 

Now Serving: 4288 Menus for Chicago Restaurants
 
 Search Advanced Find-A-Food 
 
 Areas Neighborhood All Areas Downtown North Side Northwest Side South Side Southwest Side West Side All Neighborhoods Albany Park / North Park Archer Hts / Brighton Pk Bridgeport-McKinley Park Bronzeville / Douglas Chicago Lawn / Ashburn Chinatown / Pilsen Edgewater / Andersonville Far NW Chicago Far SE Chicago Far SW Chicago Gold Coast Hermosa Humboldt-Austin-Garfield Hyde Park / Kenwood Irving Park Lawndale Lincoln Park / DePaul Lincoln Sq / Ravenswood Logan Square / Avondale Loop Midway Montclare / Cragin Near West New City / Chatham Old Town / Goose Island Portage Park / Dunning River North Rogers Park / Devon Ave Roscoe Village / North Ctr South Loop / Near South South Shore / Woodlawn Streeterville Ukranian Village Uptown West Loop / Greektown Wicker Park / Bucktown Wrigleyville / Lakeview Cuisines All Cusines Afghan African American (New) American (Traditional) Argentinean Asian (other) Asian Fusion Australian Austrian Bagels Bakeries Bar Food Barbecue Belgian Bistro Brazilian British (Modern) British (Traditional) Burgers Cafes&amp;Coffeehouses Cajun&amp;Creole Californian Caribbean Central American Central Asian Cheesesteaks Chicago Grill Chicken Chinese Cocktails Crepes Cuban Delis Desserts Dim Sum Diners&amp;Coffee Shops Dutch Eastern European Eclectic&amp;International Ethiopian Filipino Fish&amp;Chips French Gastropub German Greek Haitian Hawaiian Health Food Hot Dogs Indian Indonesian Irish Italian Jamaican Japanese Korean Kosher Latin American Local/Organic Mediterranean Mexican Middle Eastern Moroccan Noodle Shops Nuevo Latino Other Pakistani Persian Peruvian Pizza Polish Puerto Rican/Dominican Russian Salads Sandwiches Scandinavian Seafood Small Plates/Tapas Smoothies/Juice Bar Soups South American Southern&amp;Soul Southwestern Spanish Steakhouses Sushi Teahouses Thai Tibetan Turkish Vegan Vegetarian-Friendly Venezuelan Vietnamese Wild Game Wine Bar Wings Street Zip code Cross street Restaurant name 
 
Hold down Control (PC) or Command (Mac) key + mouseclick to select more than one option
 
 
Windy City Gyros
 + SHARE 


 $ 
 Rating Avg. Dinner Entrée $$$$$ Greater than $25 $$$$ $18.01 - $25 $$$ $12.01 - $18 $$ $7.01 - $12 $ Less than $7 
 Sandwiches, Hot Dogs, Chicken 3932 N Broadway St , Chicago   IL 60613 41.95354 -87.64998 (At W Dakin St) Subway Directions 

 
 
 Phone: (773) 975-7335 
 
 Profile&amp;Reviews Menu http://www.menupages.com/restaurants/windy-city-gyros/menu Report Errors Add to
My MenuPages Email 
 Facebook Twitter + MORE 
 
 
User Ratings (Based on 4 reviews) 
 4.38 5 
 Food 4.6 Value 4.4 Service 4.6 Atmosphere 3.9 
 
 Rate and Review this restaurant 
 
Other Restaurant Info
 Phone: work (773) 975-7335 Notes: Major Credit Cards Hours: Sun-Thu: 10am-4am Fri-Sat: 10am-5am Serves: Lunch,
 
 Dinner Features: Cheap Eats,
 
 Open Late,
 
 Wheelchair Friendly,
 
 Accepts Credit Cards,
 
 Take Out 
User Reviews
 
 Windy City Gyros 
 Posted by Anonymous on 09/10/2011 
 
Great Late Night Spot
 
I have bern going there for years, and I always get the ribs tips. I simply love them. They are quick when you want your food.
 Windy City Gyros 
 Posted by Miss KP on 04/05/2011 
 
Great greek chicken!
 
I&apos;ve been visiting Windy city for years and almost always order a whole Greek chicken. This is the best Greek chicken that I&apos;ve had in Chicago. It costs about $12.00, a good value for the amount of food you get. I usually call ahead so I don&apos;t have to wait around for my order. They do have decent seating if you want to eat right there.
 Windy City Gyros 
 Posted by Fooddog on 03/19/2008 
 
Awesome food for what it is!
 
The review according to me: I got the double cheese burg with everything and a chili cheese dog w/fries. The burger was very solid. The dog was T.A.S.T.Y. the fries were average at best. I called ahead to have it picked up at 9:30. I walked in at 9:29 and the man was wrapping up the burger as I entered. Talk about good timing! This place is great for a greasy end of a bar night, or just watching the game style meal. The inside is comfortable but could benefit from some music of any kind. The prices are very reasonable. Overall I would give it 3.75 stars out of 5.
 Windy City Gyros 
 Posted by Pancho on 02/19/2007 
 
Crazy spot
 
This is a Chicago food joint to the max. Where else can cops, bootleggers, hookers and us simple folk come together and enjoy fast food in the city? This place definitly has character. Pita Chicken with a side of Feta cheese. Open late as hell.
 
 
 1 
 
 Rate and Review this restaurant 
 
Advertising
 
Movies near Windy City Gyros
 Regal City North Stadium 14&amp;RPX 
2600 North Western Avenue

Chicago
 TCM Presents Singin&apos;in the Rain 60th Anniversary Event  (PG) Savages  (R) Katy Perry: Part of Me  (PG) Katy Perry: Part of Me 3D  (PG) The Amazing Spider-Man 3D  (PG-13) The Amazing Spider-Man  (PG-13) Show More [+] More Nearby theaters» 
 Ticketing provided by
 
Hot and Fresh Restaurant News Delivered Weekly
 You are signing up to receive: Weekly updates delivered straight to your inbox covering the latest restaurant news, menus, openings, closings, and food events Menupages Chicago Newsletter You may also be interested in: Hear about special offers from MenuPages or its partners about future events, promotions and features. Offers&amp;Promotions Sign Up 
Thanks for subscribing!

You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you selected.

To enjoy more benefits and personalization available on MenuPages.com, register now! 
 Checkbox is required 
Advertising
 
 About Us Careers Contact Us Advertise With Us Restaurateurs Privacy Policy Legal Notices Copyright Notice 

©2002-2012 Slick City Media, Inc. All Rights Reserved. MenuPages®is a trademark of Slick City Media, Inc. Disclaimer
	</body>
</document>
