<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009652" url="http://www.littlerocktours.com/coach_services.html" time="2012-07-13-03:03" support="1" score="0.00039538864224269245" bingtitle="Little Rock Tours and Travel | Coach Services" webtitle="Little Rock Tours and Travel | Coach Services">
			<query id="000798" bing-rank="95"/>
	<description>Take exit 139A - Roosevelt Road; Merge onto Frontage Road; Turn left at stoplight and go ... New I-30 Motorcoach Facility Opens near 5 Major Interstates. Little Rock, AR, January 28 ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Tour Calendar Hogs Football&amp;
Basketball Packages Coach&amp;Cruises Motorcoach Planning 101 Conference Tours, Events&amp;Entertainment Packages Group Tours Destination Management Casino Schedule Hotel Deals School Groups Coach Services Vehicles For Hire Links Staff Contact Us Our Brag Page Local Weather 
 
Little Rock Tours, Inc.
3100 Interstate 30
Little Rock, AR 72206
 
   
 
Coach Services

Little Rock Tours has a new dumping station less than 2 minutes from downtown Little Rock with easy interstate access. Dump fee: $35


 Dump Station and Mechanical Services. Fee during regular office hours: $35. Bus Cleaning (including dump): $75. Emergency Services available 24/7. 
 
 Directions | Press Release 

 Directions:

 
 Dumping Services 
501-868-7287
3100 Interstate 30
Little Rock, Arkansas


 From Interstate 30 West 

 Take exit 139A - Roosevelt Road
 Merge onto Frontage Road
 Continue straight on Frontage Road for 1/4 mile.
 Little Rock Tours is on right. 

 From Interstate 30 East 

 Take exit 139A - Roosevelt Road
 Merge onto Frontage Road
 Turn left at stoplight and go under interstate over pass.
 Turn left at stoplight onto Frontage Road.
 Continue straight on Frontage Road for 1/4 mile.
 Little Rock Tours is on right. 

 View Flyer and Map - PDF 

 
 
 Contact: 
Little Rock Tours
Phone 501-868-7287
800-933-3836

3100 I-30
Little Rock, AR 72206
Fax 501-978-4393

Press Release

New I-30 Motorcoach Facility Opens near 5 Major Interstates

 Little Rock, AR, January 28, 2009 
Just outside the crosshairs where Interstate 30 and Interstate 40 converge, Little Rock Tours and Travel has built a new dumping facility complete with mechanical services. The address is 3100 Interstate 30, and the facility is actually within 3 minutes of five different interstates…including I-30, I-40, I-630, I-440, and I-530.

“Talk about easy on and easy off the interstate…any of them,”says Cary Martin, owner of Little Rock Tours.“We recognized that a number of coaches were not stopping to see the sights in our great city, in part, because there wasn’t easy access to a dumping facility in Little Rock. We want motorcoach operators to visit, and stay awhile.”

Little Rock Tours—the state’s only daily sightseeing, group tour, and charter company—moved to the new Interstate 30 facility in downtown Little Rock in 2006. But it took the company more than two years to open the facility to other operators. The 13,800 square foot facility is located next to Ryder Transportation Services, which is at the Roosevelt exit, off Interstate 30 near downtown Little Rock.

“The move not only improved and made our current operations more efficient, but it will help tourism in Little Rock and Arkansas in general,“said Cary Martin, President and CEO of the company.“We work with out-of-state motorcoach operators every day planning their itineraries. As it is now, they can’t wait to get up the road to Branson or Memphis where they can easily dump or perform maintenance on their buses. We intend to aid operators in this capacity, so that they can plan their stays longer and see everything our state has to offer. The facility will make us a‘motorcoach friendly’city.”

Little Rock Tours’fleet has grown tremendously since the company first started in February 2003. Little Rock Tours now has vans, mid-size buses, as well as eight full size 56-passenger motorcoaches available for charter. In addition to its daily sightseeing tour, the company is also a full-service receptive operator and an outbound tour company. For more information call (501) TOUR-BUS (868-7287) or 1-800-933-3836. Or log onto www.littlerocktours.com.


 



 
 
 
 
 
© 2009 Little Rock Tours. All Rights Reserved Site Map
	</body>
</document>
