<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009373" url="http://www.savings.com/c-Food-and-Beverage-coupons.html" time="2012-07-13-02:44" support="82" score="0.4606596348771682" bingtitle="Food &amp; Beverage coupons - Savings.com | 20% off Your Order" webtitle="Food&amp;Beverage coupons - Savings.com | 50% off Most Gift Certificates - Now $5 for $25 + Free Shipping">
			<query id="000594" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000595" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="000277" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001499" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001530" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000276" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000181" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="001506" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="001497" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="001500" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000438" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000533" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000657" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000444" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000283" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="001348" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000618" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000164" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000158" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000878" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="001373" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000252" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="001443" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000227" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000413" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="001371" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000902" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000270" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000619" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000467" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000187" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000532" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000180" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="001476" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="001411" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="001355" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="000244" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000275" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="000460" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000436" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="001529" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="000176" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000281" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000896" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000963" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="000620" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="001512" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000220" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000907" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000900" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="001475" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000221" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000461" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001504" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000425" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000173" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000556" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="001493" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000430" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000182" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="001524" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000422" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000407" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000617" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000431" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000253" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000884" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000964" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000274" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000942" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000965" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000119" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000601" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000095" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="001528" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000941" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000554" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000185" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="000901" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000462" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000284" bing-rank="84"/>
	<description>At Savings.com, get free Food &amp; Beverage coupons ... Consoles &amp; Gift Cards, Clearance and Great Price items. ... Use the code at checkout to get 15% off any order of $500 ...</description>
	<body>
		Register Sign-in 
 Join our community, win Savings swag! savings.com Save Money. Be Happy. 
 Top Searches: Sears , Shoes.com , JCPenney , Travelocity , Lands&apos; End 
 Home Coupons Local Grocery Community Blog 
 
 
About Our Food&amp;Beverage Coupons

You come to Savings.com for great deals and coupons for electronics, computers, clothes, shoes and more--but did you know that we have food coupons as well? Our Food and Beverage category includes coupons for food, beverages, candy&amp;sweets, gourmet food, grocery coupons, coupons for restaurants and fast food coupons and a whole section dedicated to wine!

You can use our food coupons free of charge--no printers to install, no fee involved, no personal info to fill out. We have food deals for Meijer , Safeway , Genuardis , Vons , Sam&apos;s Club and other online grocery stores. If your taste runs to gourmet food, try our food coupons for Kansas City Steak , LobsterGram , Swiss Colony , Omaha Steaks or Gourmet Gift Baskets .

Satisfying a sweet tooth? We&apos;ve got food deals to fulfill your craving with stores like Mrs. Fields , David&apos;s Cookies , Jelly Belly and Godiva . If you ask me, chocolate is one of the four basic food groups--so in addition to Godiva, thank goodness we have food coupons for Fannie May , Ghirardelli , Nirvana , Gertrude Hawk , Hotel Chocolat and ChocolateSource.com .

But as the saying goes, &quot;Man does not live by bread alone&quot;--you need something to wash it down with! That&apos;s why we even have food coupons for your favorite beverages. Kick start your day with food coupons for coffee vendors like Boca Java , Cafe Britt , Starbucks , Peet&apos;s Coffee and Gevalia . Soft drink lovers will swallow the savings with food deals for Coca-Cola , Jones Soda and Soda Club . And if you&apos;re of legal age, try our food coupons for My Wines Direct , Mr. Beer and Wine.com .

No matter what you&apos;re craving, you&apos;ll find great savings with food coupons from Savings.com!
 
 Categories &gt;

Food Coupons
 
Food&amp;Beverage
 Filter Popular Exclusive Printable Free Shipping Get Code Expires today 
 Go to store 50% Off + Free Shipping 
Enter the code at checkout to save 50% on most restaurant gift certificates. + More 
 
Now, most will cost $5 for $25 worth of food and drink, instead of $10 for $25. Free shipping is included. See site for details.

 Expires: Jul 12, 2012 Submitted: 3 days ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (1) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By pmiller 
 Get Code Expires today 
 Go to store Extra 15% off Keurig K Cups Coffee 
Save an extra 15% on the Keurig K Cups Coffee by using the code at checkout. + More 
 
Ends soon.

 Expires: Jul 12, 2012 Submitted: 2 weeks ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (11) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By cate.g 
 Get Code 
 Go to store $10 Off 
Follow this link and enjoy $10 discount on all orders $30 or more. + More 
 
Just apply this code at checkout to redeem offer. Limited time offer.

 Submitted: 4 months ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (24) Bad Deal (3) 

 Share By johanne 
 Get Code 
 Go to store $20 Off 
Use this code at checkout and get a $20 discount on orders $40 or more. + More 
 
Restrictions may apply. If your order is still $40 after the discount, your order ships free.

 Submitted: a month ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (3) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By paper1 
 Get Code Expires in 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 2 days 
 Go to store $10 Off + Free Shipping 
Enter this code at checkout to get $10 discount on purchase $50 or more. + More 
 
Includes free shipping. Restrictions may apply.

 Expires: Jul 14, 2012 Submitted: yesterday 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (0) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By cheng25 
 Get Code 
 Go to store $25 Off 
New customers can get $25 off orders $99 or more with the code at checkout. + More 
 
 Expires: Aug 31, 2012 Submitted: 4 months ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (232) Bad Deal (8) 

 Share By Dealman 
 Get Code 
 Go to store $15 Off 
Enter this code at checkout to get $15 off first order worth $60 or more. + More 
 
Some restrictions apply. Go through this link to learn more.

 Expires: Dec 31, 2012 Submitted: a month ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (7) Bad Deal (1) 

 Share By PingGuerrero 
 Get Code 
 Go to store $10 Off + Free Shipping 
Enter this code at checkout to save $10 savings on all orders $50 or more. + More 
 
Get free shipping on orders $50 and up plus free Blueberry Bliss/Pineapple Kona Pop Tea Blend. Restrictions may apply. Click through to start.

 Expires: Jul 31, 2012 Submitted: 2 weeks ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (6) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By edelweiss16 
 Get Code 
 Go to store FRS 40% Off 
Enter this code at checkout to get 40% discount all products. + More 
 
No minimum order required. Some restriction may apply. Limited time offer.

 Submitted: a week ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (0) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By digitalee 
 Get Code 
 Go to store $50 Off 
Use the code at checkout to get $50 off your first two orders of $125 or more - for a total of $100 off $250. + More 
 
 Submitted: 2 weeks ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (10) Bad Deal (1) 

 Share By Dealman 
 Activate Coupon Expires in 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 3 days 20% Off 
This week only all Gold Card members will receive 20% off their entire order. + More 
 
Click through the link for more details.

 Expires: Jul 15, 2012 Submitted: 3 days ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (2) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By megan.sorenson 
 Get Code 
 Go to store 30% Off + Free Shipping 
Enter this code at checkout to get $30 off all orders worth $200 or more. + More 
 
Some restrictions apply. Also includes free shipping.

 Expires: Jul 31, 2012 Submitted: 2 weeks ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (1) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By PingGuerrero 
 Get Code 
 Go to store $15 Off 
Use this code at checkout and get a $15 discount on orders $40 or more. + More 
 
Restrictions apply. Limited time offer.

 Submitted: 1 week ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (0) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By paper1 
 Get Code 
 Go to store $15 Off 
Use this code at checkout to get a 15% discount on orders $39 or more. + More 
 
Orders $55 or more. ships free. Some restrictions may apply. For a limited time only.

 Submitted: 4 months ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (39) Bad Deal (1) 

 Share By kweeny 
 Print Coupon $3 Off Whole Foods 
Get a $3 discount on one case of 12 Glaceau Smartwater. + More 
 
 Expires: Sep 30, 2012 Submitted: about 16 hours ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (0) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By nayrb23 
 Get Code 
 Go to store 10% Off 
Use this code at checkout to get 10% savings on your first order. + More 
 
Orders of $75 or more ship free. Limited time only.

 Submitted: 4 months ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (17) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By oichnas 
 Get Code 
 Go to store $25 Off 
Click through this link and enter this code at checkout to get $25 off all orders over $75. + More 
 
Limited time offer.

 Submitted: 4 months ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (9) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By johanne 
 Activate Coupon 60% Off 
Snatch up scrumptious confections at a fraction of the cost with savings up to 60% off the original prices of select items throughout the site. + More 
 
 Submitted: 2 years ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (3) Bad Deal (1) 

 Share By dstearns 
 Print Coupon $1 Off Whole Foods 
Save $1 on a single pomegranite juice. + More 
 
 Expires: Sep 30, 2012 Submitted: about 16 hours ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (0) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By nayrb23 
 Exclusive Activate Coupon FRS $25 Off 
Use this link to get a $25 discount on your purchase of $50 of more The savings appear in your cart. + More 
 
 Submitted: 3 months ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (0) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By rbarnes 
 Get Code 
 Go to store 15% Off 
Enter code at checkout to get 15% savings on your entire order with no minimum spend. + More 
 
Some restrictions may apply. Limited time offer.

 Submitted: 2 months ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (39) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By odyc14 
 Activate Coupon 60% Off 
Browse the Sale section for savings up to 60% on candies, chocolates and gifts. + More 
 
 Submitted: 2 years ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (1) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By dstearns 
 Print Coupon $1 Off Whole Foods 
Save $1 on a single 4 count pack of Bakehouse cupcakes. + More 
 
 Expires: Sep 30, 2012 Submitted: about 16 hours ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (0) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By nayrb23 
 Get Code 
 Go to store 20% Off 
Use this code at checkout and get a 20% discount on all orders. + More 
 
Restrictions apply.

 Expires: Sep 28, 2012 Submitted: 1 week ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (7) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By paper1 
 Get Code Expires in 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 a week 
 Go to store $15 Off 
Get $15 off your first purchase of $75 or more by using the code at checkout. + More 
 
Restrictions apply. See site for details.

 Expires: Jul 18, 2012 Submitted: 2 days ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (0) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By Dealman 
 Get Code 
 Go to store 30% Off 
Enter this code at checkout to get 30% discount on orders $2500 to $4,999.99. + More 
 
Some restriction may apply. Limited time offer.

 Submitted: a week ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (0) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By digitalee 
 Get Code 
 Go to store 20% Off + Free Shipping 
Use this code at checkout to get a 20% discount plus free shipping on orders $85 or more. + More 
 
Restrictions may apply.

 Expires: Jul 31, 2012 Submitted: a week ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (0) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By johanne 
 Get Code 
 Go to store $10 Off 
Save $10 on any order of $50 or more when you enter the code at checkout. + More 
 
Limited time offer. See site for details.

 Submitted: a year ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (79) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By dealtown 
 Exclusive Activate Coupon FRS 40% Off + Free Shipping 
Use this link to get a 40% discount and free shipping on your purchase of any of their brand name bottles. + More 
 
The savings appear in your cart.

 Submitted: 3 months ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (1) Bad Deal (8) 

 Share By rbarnes 
 Get Code 
 Go to store 10% Off 
Use the code at checkout to get 10% off your order. + More 
 
 Submitted: 10 months ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (6) Bad Deal (1) 

 Share By Dealman 
 
 Previous Next 
Top Products in Food&amp;Beverage
 Buy 1 Decaf Espresso Roast Pods, Get 1 Free - $4.95 @ Starbucks 
 $4.95 
 Buy 1 VIA Tribute Blend, Get 1 Free - $11.95 @ Starbucks 
 $11.95 
 
Latest Blog Posts
 
 Unit-Pricing: How to Tell if Bulk Is Better 

By JulianaWeissRoessler Guest Blogger 
at 12:09PM, 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 a month ago
 |
 under Shop Smarter 
 
You&apos;re in the grocery store aisle with the
purpose of buying more sugar since you&apos;ve run out. There&apos;s two
packages of your favorite brand,one large and one small. It&apos;s
likely that you grab the big package without even giving it a
second thought. After all, you need a lot of sugar, and it&apos;s
abetter deal.



But is it a better deal? Originally, marketers
began selling bulk products at a discount because it encouraged
their customers to buy more.But over time, they got wise to the
fact that we weren&apos;t actually crunching the math. If we saw a
bigger package, we&apos;d just assume it was cheaper than buying a
comparable amount of smaller packages.

So what did they do? They upped the price
again! Often,making the bulk packages cost moreânot less. Of course, that&apos;s not always the case, but you can&apos;t
assume just because you&apos;re buying more that you&apos;re getting a better
deal.
 
 Better Leftovers, Better Savings 

By savingtools.com Guest Blogger 
at 5:08PM, 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 a month ago
 |
 under Personal Finance 
 Stretching your food budget is as easy as learning to take
those leftovers that usually get pushed to the back of the fridge
and using them to create a new and exciting dish. The key to doing
this successfully is planning your meals to take full advantage of
everything in your kitchen. Following a few simple rules will
ensure that you don&apos;t end up with a refrigerator full of plastic
leftover containers. 

 Plan Ahead 

 There are literally thousands of ways to take main course
leftovers and turn them into something dramatically different. One
of the easiest ideas is making tacos, which can be done with
shredded beef, chicken or even turkey. Soups are another easy
transformation for a former main course meat. The tried and true
pot pie is also a great choice. 
 Cost-Saving Mother&apos;s Day Gift: Cook a Meal! 

By JulianaWeissRoessler Guest Blogger 
at 9:15AM, 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 2 months ago
 |
 under Holidays 
 
If you&apos;re wracking your brain for last-minute
ideas on something to do for Mother&apos;s Day that doesn&apos;t involve
hundreds of dollars or yet another generic bouquet of flowers,
consider doing something that truly comes from youâcook mom a meal!



Even if you&apos;re not a gourmet chef (and if you
are, why didn&apos;t you think of this sooner?!), mom will appreciate
you serving her for once, and she&apos;ll marvel at the hard work you
put in. Just as importantly,you&apos;ll be able to show her you love her
for a fraction of the cost of going out to a restaurant.

The best way to go about this is to find some
of your mom&apos;s favorite foods or meals and make those, but if you&apos;re
having trouble, here area couple of ideas to get you started.

 Blueberry Bedcakes 

These pancakes with fresh blueberries are a
great way to start of mom&apos;s day.
 
Related Community Posts
 
 FREE Beaulieu Vineyard Wine Guide 
 
 champ76 in All Freebies – 8 months ago 
 
 FREE Activate Vitamin Drink Sample 
 
 champ76 in All Freebies – 8 months ago 
 
 Buy one holiday beverage at Starbucks between 2-5pm and get second one FREE now through November 20th! 
 
 Tom-Kuljis in All Freebies – 8 months ago 
 Featured Stores 
 ► 11 coupons ► 9 coupons ► 3 coupons ► 8 coupons ► 6 coupons ► 11 coupons 

 View All Stores ► View All Brands ► 
 
Categories

 Food&amp;Beverage Beverages Restaurants Specialty Foods 
 All Categories 
Related Categories

 Groceries Diet&amp;Nutrition 
 Top Brands in Food&amp;Beverage 
Typically have the best discounts in this category

 Kmart Omaha Steaks Red Envelope LivingSocial MakeBeer.net 

 Vons Coopers Brewery Dollar General Pro Bike Kit Bon Ton 
 See more brands… 1st in Coffee 3 Blind Moose 7-Eleven A. C. Calderoni&amp;Co. Acacia Acme adagio Adagio Teas Ahmad Alain Voge Alexander Valley Alice White All In Energy Drink Allegrini Almaden Alois Lageder Alpha Estate Alvita Tea Amanzi Tea Amarone Anderson Valley Andre Angove&apos;s Anselmi Antinori Appetizerstogo Archipel Baja Fresh Bake Me A Wish Barefoot Contessa Baxter Tea Company Beer Machine Ben and Jerrys Bentley&apos;s Better Water Store Betty Crocker BevMo! Big Train Bob Evans Bodega Norton Brassfield Breezy Morning Bristot Bulk e Candy Cajun Grocer Cali Earthquake Kits California Tea House Campbell Shop CANDY CRATE Capella Cappojim&apos;s Celebration Herbals Celestial Seasonings Chateau Teyssier Chef du Jour Choice Organic Christmas Tree Shops Cinnabon Clos du val Coffee Bean and Tea Leaf Coffee Wishes CoffeeAM Cold Stone Creamery Colombo Dale&amp;Thomas Popcorn Dannon DaVinci Gourmet Diedrich Direct E-Cig Doka Estate Domaine chandon Domaine Ste. Michelle Domaines Schlumberger Dominus Doritos Douwe Egberts Dream Dinners Dry creek vineyard E. guigal Ecco Domani Echelon Eight O&apos;Clock Emergency Reserve Estancia Felipe Rutini Felsina Ferrari Carano Fetzer Feudi Di San Gregorio Feudo Arancio Fife Finca Luzon Fine Lobster Fleur Du Cap Flora Springs Florio Folgers Folonari Food Lion Food Service Warehouse Forest glen winery Francis Coppola Freixenet Fresh&amp;Easy FreshDirect Gaja Gallo Gekkeikan General Mills Georges Duboeuf Geyser Peak Ghirardelli Girard GJ Cookies Glass Mountain Glenny&apos;s Glennys Gloria Ferrer Gloria Jean&apos;s Gloria Jean&apos;s Coffees Good Earth Teas Graham London Green Mountain Coffee Greg Norman Estates Groth Guayaki Haagen Dazs Hampstead Tea Hartley&amp;Gibson&apos;s Hawaiian Shaved Ice Health King Healthy Choice Henry&apos;s Drive Hess Hobe Labs Homeland Honest Tea HoneyBaked Ham Hugel Hula Girl Coffee iGourmet illy Inglenook Iron horse vineyards J Vineyards&amp;Winery Jacob&apos;s Creek Jason winters Java One Jekel Vineyard Jim&apos;s Organic Coffee JL Hufford Coffee and Tea Company Joseph Drouhin Kashi KegWorks Kelloggs Cereal Kendall-Jackson Kickback Catering Kim Crawford Kraft Kunde Estates La Terre La Vieille Ferme Laci Le Beau Lean Cuisine Leonard Kreusch Lipton Liquorama Fine Wines&amp;Spirits Livingston Cellars Lobsters-Online.Com Long Life Los Vascos Louis Bernard Louis Jadot Louis Latour Louis M. Martini Louis Roederer Luna Di Luna Luzianne MacMurray Ranch Mad Fish Madly Pop&apos;n Maison Leroy Majella Marchesi di barolo Marques De Caceres Marques De Riscal Marquis Philips Martini&amp;Rossi Masi Matanzas Creek Maxwell House McManis Family Vineyards Mer Soleil Mezzacorona Mighty Leaf Millstone Mionetto Mission Grounds Gourmet Coffee Moet&amp;Chandon Monin Montes Montevina morfoods.com Morrell Wine Mount Hagen Mouton-Cadet Natural Grocers Nestle Numi Old Spaghetti Factory Opici Osborne Pampas Argentine Grill Paringa Peets Coffee Penfolds Pepperwood Grove Pepsi Perrier-Jouet Pessagno Pfaelzer Brothers Pillsbury Pine Ridge Pinkberry Pizza Fit&apos;n Free Placido Pommery Popcornopolis Post Cereal Prince of peace Pringles PROBAR Procter and Gamble Progresso Soup Publix Pure Electronic Cigarettes Quinta Do Noval Rancho Zabaco Ravenswood Raymond Redwood Creek Republic Of Tea Rocca Delle Macie Rodney Strong Rombauer Rosemount estate Rosenblum cellars Ruffino Rutherford Hill Saint Francis Saintsbury San Francisco Sandeman Santa Margherita Santa Rita Sara Lee Schmitt Shne Schwan&apos;s Seattle&apos;s Best Segura Viudas Senseo Shari&apos;s Berries Shingleback Silverado Vineyards Simi Skybar Smart Ones Smoking Loon St. Clement St. Dalfour St. Supery Stag&apos;s Leap Starwest Botanicals Stash Tea Sterling Vineyards Stonestreet Stouffers Superfresh SuperWater.com Sutter Home Tablas Creek Taltarni Tazo Tea Fort Tea Spot TeaTech Teavana Teeccino Terrabianca Terrazas De Los Andes Tetley The Jade Teapot The Ready Store Thompson Cigar Timothy&apos;s Torani Torrefazione Italia Torres Traditional Medicinals Trapiche Trefethen Trimbach Trinchero Triple Leaf Tea Trumpeter Tully&apos;s Turning Leaf Twinings Two Leaves and a Bud Twomey Uncle Lee&apos;s Tea VAH Marketing Valentin Bianchi Valley Of The Moon Vendange Veramonte Verdi Veuve Clicquot Villa Maria Village Tea Company Walnut Crest Warre&apos;s Water.com Wente Whitehall Lane Whole Foods Whole Latte Love Wild Horse Wild Vines Willamette Valley Wine Country Chef Wisdom Natural Wisdom of the ancients Wise Foods Wolf Blass Wonka Woodward Canyon Yalumba YamaMotoYama Yarden Yellow Tail Yogi Tea Zenato 
 About Us About Coupons Stores Brands Contact Us Affiliate Program Community Guidelines Privacy Policy Terms of Service Find More Products
	</body>
</document>
