<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009249" url="http://www.whattoexpect.com/pregnancy/eating-well/week-17/eating-out.aspx" time="2012-07-13-02:38" support="9" score="0.026114941710911076" bingtitle="Eating Out During Pregnancy" webtitle="Eating Out During Pregnancy">
			<query id="000995" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="001001" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000984" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000870" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="000987" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000999" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000997" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000996" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000972" bing-rank="44"/>
	<description>Find out how you can eat healthy when eating out ... Log-in with your What To Expect Account: ... lentil, bean, or vegetable soup on the menu, order a ...</description>
	<body>
		3 Things To Do Today » Save on baby accessories » Introduce new foods to your baby » Get prepared for childbirth 
 
Follow Us On
 Sign in Close Register 
Log-in to What To Expect with one click!
 
 OR 
 Log-in with your What To Expect Account: 
E-Mail Address:
 
Password:
 Forgot Your Password? That&apos;s ok, we can send you a new one. Click Here 
 Preconception Pregnancy First Year Toddler 
 
 Community Groups 
 Community Find a Group Start a Group My Preferences 
 Blogs 
 Word of Mom 
 Members&amp;Friends 
 Meet Members 
 Photos 
 Recent Photos Popular Photos 
 Local Resources 
 New York City Los Angeles Houston Chicago Find Groups Near You 
 Contests&amp;Deals 
 Diaper Deals Feeding Deals Wipes Deals More Family Deals Photo Contests Group Giveaways The WTE Bookstore 
 
 
Pregnancy

 Topics 
 Due Date Calculator Eating Well For Dad Labor and Delivery Looking Good Love During Pregnancy Planning for Baby Pregnancy and Work Pregnancy Basics Pregnancy Calendar Pregnancy Fitness Pregnancy Health Pregnancy Questions Pregnancy Toolkit Pregnancy Videos Sex During Pregnancy Symptoms and Solutions Twins&amp;Multiples Word of Mom Your Emotional Life 
 
 
 
What You Can Do While Pregnant
 
Celebrity Baby Bump Love
 
The Perks of Being a Mom
 
 
 
Pregnant on TV — But Hiding It!
 
Heidi on Eating the Placenta
 
 Home » Pregnancy » Eating Well » Eating Well Week by Week »Week 17 of Pregnancy: Eating Out for Two? Eating Well During Pregnancy 
Eating Out For Two During Pregnancy

Good nutrition is almost always on the menu—though in some restaurants, you&apos;ll have to look a little more closely to find it.
 Comments 
Whether it&apos;s a quick lunch on the run or a five-course feast at a four-star restaurant, there will be plenty of times during your pregnancy when you&apos;ll be doing the eating — but not the cooking. While it&apos;ll certainly be a relief to be relieved of the cooking — don&apos;t forget that you&apos;re still on baby-nourishing duty even when you&apos;re not on kitchen detail. Keep your uterine cafécatering to your baby&apos;s nutritional best interests at 17 weeks pregnant by following a few key guidelines when you&apos;re dining out.

 Choose the restaurant. You may not always have this opportunity, but seize it when you can. (Cash in the &quot;I&apos;m pregnant, I&apos;m fussy&quot; chip whenever possible.) Certain restaurants are better suited to the pregnant diner than others (a fish restaurant with a salad bar, good — a sushi bar restaurant with limited cooked options, not so good). If heartburn or other tummy troubles have your meal options limited to the bland, blander, and blandest, you may want to opt out of that spicy new Indian place, or that eatery that prides itself in frying everything (including the ice cream).

 Speak up about special requests. You&apos;re not the only picky eater these days. Wait staff and chefs in most establishments are used to (if still not always particularly happy with) substitutions of all kinds. Go ahead and hold the mayo, ask for your dressing and sauce on the side; skip the bacon and blue cheese on the Cobb, see if the rare duck breast can be served cooked through.

 Watch your portions. Many restaurants serve entrée portions large enough to feed small villages (or at least, small families). Resist the temptation to be queen of the clean plate club (you&apos;ll only pay the price in indigestion — as well as in too many pounds if you&apos;re dining out often). Instead, leave over what you&apos;re too full to eat and doggie bag leftovers for tomorrow&apos;s lunch or dinner. Or ask for half-portions.

 Don&apos;t be misled by the bread. Search out whole-grain options when you dig into the bread basket. Can&apos;t locate any? Ask if the kitchen has some on hand (if they serve sandwiches, they probably have sliced whole-wheat available). No wheat in sight? Have some white — but try not to fill up on those empty calories. Instead, quickly order a healthy appetizer.

 Go for greens. Make a habit of ordering a salad or grilled veggies as your first course, or a sautéed leafy green such as spinach, escarole, or broccoli as a side.

 Soup&apos;s on! If there&apos;s lentil, bean, or vegetable soup on the menu, order a bowlful. Same goes for tomato-based broths and chowders (take Manhattan when it comes to clam). Avoid bisques and other cream soups unless they&apos;re made with milk or yogurt in lieu of heavy cream and butter. The only way to know is to ask. (Don&apos;t be shy — everybody&apos;s doing it these days. Besides, you&apos;re pregnant — it&apos;s kind of obvious why you&apos;re nutrition-conscious.)

 Scope out the sides. Even fast-food restaurants offer healthy side dishes these days (baked potato with that?). Ask and ye shall receive: steamed veggies, that baked potato (instead of the fries or onion rings), yams, and brown or wild rice are all super sides.

 Go global. Indulge in a variety of healthy options at ethnic restaurants — tummy permitting (and it won&apos;t always be). When in Italian restaurants, dine as the Romans do, on grilled or braised fish, chicken, veal, or lean beef entrées accompanied by gorgeous greens; or pasta and pizza with fresh tomato sauce, seafood, or cheese. Enjoy teriyaki fish or chicken, miso soup, edamame, and soba noodle dishes in Japanese restaurants (as well as sushi featuring cooked fish or vegetables). As long as your stomach&apos;s amenable to the spices, Indian restaurants make a particularly nutritious option (order practically anything that isn&apos;t fried, especially tandoori-grilled meats marinated in yogurt, vegetable and lentil dishes, and whole-grain breads). And for a Mexican fiesta, enjoy black bean soup, fajitas (you&apos;ll score plenty of vitamins from those bell peppers) with corn tortillas, fresh salsa, and guacamole.

 Fill up before dessert. Try not to save room for that Mississippi mud pie, but if you&apos;re still hungry (or hankering for something sweet) after the main course, ask for fresh fruit, sorbet, or frozen yogurt. Your name won&apos;t be mud if you do end up giving into the mud pie (as long as you&apos;re not giving in every day), but you&apos;ll feel better in the morning if you stop at a few bites before passing the dessert (and the calories) to the other end of the table.

See more tips for eating well while pregnant .
 Comments 
Related Articles
 
 Out and About 
Is eating out on the menu? Here&apos;s how to make sure a healthy meal&apos;s on order even
 Pregnancy Eating Plans 
Pregnant and eating at work, on the road, or on the run? Here&apos;s how to stick to your
 On Special Occasions 
Never mind being the life of the party — is there even a point in going to the party
 On the Job 
Feeding baby is a 24/7 effort (and you have the late-night cravings to prove it),
 
 
More Pregnancy Topics
 
 Pregnancy Resources Pregnancy and Work Your Emotional Life Symptoms and Solutions For Dad 
 
Track Your Baby&apos;s Growth Today!
 
Register for FREE and get a customized newsletter.
 Estimated due date or baby&apos;s birth date: month Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sept Oct Nov Dec day 1 2 year 2020 2019 2018 2017 2016 2015 2014 2013 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 I do not have a due date Sign Up 
Follow Us
 
 
 
What Members Are Saying
 
 It&apos;s sounds like you&apos;re doing all the right things for long term weight Prayers coming your way. :) My Grandpa is having out patient prostate surgery I am 37 tears old soon to be 38 (JAN 10th) and this is my first baby and i wouldto Do you mean after birth ? Arnt most of the details written in our baby books (purple I will pray. I&apos;m so sorry. I can&apos;t even imagine. Praying for a safe and 
 
What Members Are Reading
 
Browse

 Preconception Pregnancy First Year Toddler Community Family Deals 
 
About

 About What to Expect What to Expect Foundation What to Expect Bookstore Everyday Health Network Contact Us Word of Mom 

 Terms of Use Privacy Policy Advertising/Editorial Policy Advertise With Us Partnerships Press Room 

 Facebook Twitter Pinterest Help Feedback Careers 
 The material on this website is provided for educational purposes only and is not to be used for medical advice, diagnosis, or treatment, or in place of therapy or medical care. See additional information . This site is not intended for users under the age of 18. Use of this site is subject to our terms of use and privacy policy Advertising Notice 
This Site and third parties who place advertisements on this Site may collect and use information about your visits to this Site and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like to obtain more information about these advertising practices and to make choices about online behavioral advertising, please click here
	</body>
</document>
