<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009116" url="http://www.trulia.com/property/3055426120-5-Ashley-Ct-Lynnfield-MA-01940" time="2012-07-13-02:30" support="1" score="0.0007344695313227541" bingtitle="5 Ashley Court, Lynnfield MA | MLS# 71249609 - Trulia" webtitle="5 Ashley Court, Lynnfield MA - Trulia">
			<query id="000770" bing-rank="198"/>
	<description>Unique Scholtz des brick ft home w/his/her sep 2 car ... fl Mster BR/Gst Ste w/Jac br; 10 ceil; gas FP FR;tray ... Communities near 5 Ashley Ct, Lynnfield | MLS# 71249609</description>
	<body>
		Homes ▼
 Homes Rentals Local Info Advice Professionals Mortgages Advanced Search 
 Buy 
 More Search Options FREE List a property 
 Rent 
 More Search Options FREE List a property 
 Advice 
 Q&amp;A Advice Blogs Guides Ask a Question Write a Blog Post 
 Mortgage 
 Home Loans Mortgage Refinance Mortgage Trends Mortgage Advice Mortgage Calculators 
 Local Info 
 Local Home Foreclosure Center Directory 
 Find a Pro 
 Real Estate Agents Brokers Mortgage Brokers or Lenders Builders/Developers Property Managers 
 
 Help Log in Sign up 
 
 Trulia Mobile For Professionals 
It looks like Javascript is disabled in your browser.
 Trulia requires Javascript to be enabled in order to use our site.
 Please follow these instructions to enable Javascript. 
 for sale resale $1,799,000 
5 Ashley Court, Lynnfield MA 01940
 Executive Home with Office, Boardroom, Classroom, and Guest Suite. His and Her separate 2 Car Heated Garages. First floor 38x24 Master Suite with 2 Full Baths and a Wet Bar. Ultra Kitchen and connecting Family Room with Bose Sound and Video. Subsonic Gas Heating with 9 Zones for efficiency. Ultimate Landscaping with 16 zone Sprinkler System and Nightscape Lighting. Great Room (53x21) with Wet Bar,Bose Sound and Video, and a Full Bath with Steam Room. housing 42.54435 -71.04817 Home Facts Photos 25 Map&amp;Nearby Mortgage Comparables Sales Trends Schools 
 Photos of 5 Ashley Court, Lynnfield MA 
 View large photos (25) Watch virtual tour 
 
 
 Price: $1,799,000   •Mortgage payments •Rent vs Buy Est. payment: $8,757 /mo Your Credit Score Bedrooms: 4 72 days on Trulia Bathrooms: 5 full, 2 partial 1,321 people have viewed Property type: Single-Family Home Size: 8,426 sqft Lot: 0.75 acres Price/sqft: $214 /sqft Year built: 2005 MLS/ID: 71249609 Zip: 01940 Provided by: newenglandmoves.com This info was not provided by this listing source. Ask an agent for more details about this home. Listing agent: Nikki Cappadona Broker: Coldwell Banker Residential Brokerage 
 Contact agent Follow home Share 
 Send email Share on Facebook 
 Check your credit Report error Get Prequalified More 
 Print this page Ask a question Write a note Report an error 
 Executive Home with Office, Boardroom, Classroom, and Guest Suite. His and Her separate 2 Car Heated Garages. First floor 38x24 Master Suite with 2 Full Baths and a Wet Bar. Ultra Kitchen and connecting Family Room with Bose Sound and Video. Subsonic Gas Heating with 9 Zones for efficiency. Ultimate Landscaping with 16 zone Sprinkler System and Nightscape Lighting. Great Room (53x21) with Wet Bar,Bose Sound and Video, and a Full Bath with Steam Room. Write a personal note about this listing 
My Notes
 Edit  |  Clear List view Table view 
Listing Info for 5 Ashley Ct 
 Most recent information provided by newenglandmoves.com on 07/12/2012 04:32 AM: 
 Price: $1,799,000 Status: For Sale MLS/Source ID: 71249609 4 Bedrooms 5 full, 2 partial Bathrooms 8,426 sqft Single-Family Home Built In 2005 Lot Size: 0.75 acres Fireplace Style: Colonial Deck Patio Sprinkler System Garage 
 
Public Records for 5 Ashley Ct 
 Official property, sales, and tax information from county (public) records as of 09/2011: 
 Single Family Residential 4 Bedrooms 4 Bathrooms 2 Partial Bathrooms 6,882 sqft Lot Size: 0.75 acres Built In 2004 Stories: 2 story with basement A/C Heating: Hot Water Parking: Attached Garage Exterior Walls: Wood Siding Roof: Asphalt 9 Rooms 1 Building Construction: Frame Basement: Unfinished Basement Style: Colonial Fireplace County: Essex 
 
Property Taxes for 5 Ashley Ct 
 
 Year Value Land   Improvements   Total Tax 2011 Assessed $581,500 + $859,600 = $1,441,100 $19,440   
 Source: Public Records This property may be overassessed. Find Out Now» 
Price History for 5 Ashley Ct 
 Alert 
 Date Event Price Source 03/10/2005 Sold view details $1,800,000 Public records Public records   Recording Date 03/10/2005   Sale Price $1,800,000   Price Type Full amount stated on Document.   Transaction Type Purchase/Resale Arm&apos;s Length Residential Transaction   Document Type Deed 
 
Location Information near 5 Ashley Ct 
 
 Comparables Schools Estimates Crimes Amenities Transit 
 Comparables Estimates Schools Crimes Amenities Transit $1,099,500 4 br / 2 ba Single-Family Home OPEN HOUSE Sun Oct 16, 2pm to 4pm Lynnfield local info 
 Sold Homes near 5 Ashley Ct 
 
 Address Distance Property Type Sold price Sold date Bed Bath Sqft 5 Devonshire Rd, Middleton MA 4.76 mi Single-Family Home $1,290,000 3/30/12 5 5 6,292 
 View all homes similar to 5 Ashley Court, Lynnfield MA» 
 Elementary Schools Middle Schools High Schools Type GreatSchools Rating Distance Nearby Schools No public schools where found for this property and grade level. Summer Street Elementary School View Homes Public 10 0.8 mi West Memorial Elementary School View Homes Public 4 1.8 mi John E Burke Elementary School View Homes Public 8 1.9 mi Dolbeare School View Homes Public 7 2.0 mi J Warren Killam Elementary School View Homes Public 8 2.1 mi Lynnfield Middle School View Homes Public 8 0.5 mi North Reading Middle School View Homes Public 8 3.0 mi Arthur Coolidge Middle School View Homes Public 9 3.2 mi Galvin Middle School View Homes Public 7 3.2 mi Walter Parker Middle School View Homes Public 9 3.7 mi Lynnfield High School View Homes Public 9 0.8 mi North Reading High School View Homes Public 9 2.8 mi Reading Memorial High School View Homes Public 9 3.2 mi Wakefield Memorial High School View Homes Public 7 3.3 mi Northeast Metro Regional Vocational School View Homes Public 3 3.4 mi Private Schools No private schools where found for this property and grade level. Covenant Christian Academy View Homes Private - 2.3 mi Our Lady Assumption School View Homes Catholic - 2.9 mi Odyssey Day School View Homes Private - 3.9 mi Agape Christian Academy View Homes Private - 4.5 mi Meritor Academy View Homes Private - 4.7 mi Covenant Christian Academy View Homes Private - 2.3 mi Our Lady Assumption School View Homes Catholic - 2.9 mi Odyssey Day School View Homes Private - 3.9 mi Austin Preparatory School View Homes Catholic - 4.0 mi Agape Christian Academy View Homes Private - 4.5 mi Nazareth Academy View Homes Private - 2.3 mi Covenant Christian Academy View Homes Private - 2.3 mi Austin Preparatory School View Homes Catholic - 4.0 mi Edgewood Greater Boston Academy View Homes Private - 5.8 mi Malden Catholic High School View Homes Catholic - 8.0 mi 
 indicates schools assigned
 to this home. School data provided by OnBoard Informatics.
 Boundaries provided by Maponics. 
Home Estimates near 5 Ashley Ct 
 Loading data 
Individual Crimes near 5 Ashley Ct 
 Loading data 
Nearby Restaurants, Banks, and Grocery Stores
 Loading data 
Transit Stops near 5 Ashley Ct 
 Loading data 
Price Comparison of 5 Ashley Ct 
 This Home $1.80M VS Sold Price Price/Sqft Zip 01940 $405,000 Lynnfield $405,000 10yr 5yr 1yr 
Real Estate Trends in 01940 
 
 Sale price for 5 Ashley Ct $1,799,000   Average listing price for similar homes $1,253,849 30% below sale price Median sale price for similar homes $1,290,000 28% below sale price Average listing price for all homes in 01940 $638,898 64% below sale price Median sale price for all homes in 01940 $405,000 77% below sale price 
 View more Sales Trends for 01940 » 
What Trulia users think of this area
 Overall area rating: 

 Excellent We need more ratings to calculate an average. Top rated categories: 

 Schools 

 Cleanliness 

 Safety 

 Pet-friendly We need more ratings to calculate top categories. Total ratings: 175 | View all ratings Last updated 17 hours ago Rate this area: Rate it Rate these categories: 
 Safety Rate it Pet-friendly Rate it Walkability Rate it Restaurants&amp;Shopping Rate it 
 Rate and Review Read 1 review » 
Contact Info for 5 Ashley Ct 
 
 Agent: Coldwell Banker Residential Brokerage (781) 334-5700 Broker: Coldwell Banker Residential Brokerage Listing website 
 Inquire about this property Name : Email : Phone : Message : I was searching on Trulia and found this listing. Please send me more information about 5 Ashley Ct, Lynnfield MA 01940. Thank you. Contact the agent 
By sending, you agree to Trulia&apos;s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy .
 «See similar homes Prev Next Request more information Coldwell Banker Residential Brokerage Tel: (781) 334-5700 Real Estate Agent Single-Family Home 01940 5 Ashley Ct Lynnfield,MA Coldwell Banker Residential Brokerage Name : Email : Phone : Message : I was searching on Trulia and found this listing. Please send me more information about 5 Ashley Ct, Lynnfield MA 01940. Thank you. Contact the agent 
By sending, you agree to Trulia&apos;s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy .
 Homes you might like... Alert 
 10 Windsor Rd, Lynnfield MA 19 photos 
 $1,840,000 

7 br / 6 full, 1 partial ba

10,623 sqft

Single-Family Home
 1 Thistle Ln, Lynnfield MA 25 photos 
 $1,595,000 

6 br / 5 full, 1 partial ba

11,000 sqft

Single-Family Home
 2 Bridle Path, Lynnfield MA 28 photos 
 $1,299,888 

5 br / 5 ba

6,414 sqft

Single-Family Home
 524 Lowell St, Lynnfield MA 28 photos 
 $1,249,000 

4 br / 5 full, 1 partial ba

4,300 sqft

Single-Family Home
 420 Chestnut St, Lynnfield MA 25 photos 
 $1,379,000 

4 br / 5 full, 1 partial ba

5,932 sqft

Single-Family Home
 
 View all homes near 5 Ashley Ct» 281fd2663cc480441a489a7ed1f77a35 Sponsored Resource Center Buying a Home? Check your Credit Score today for - $0 This property may be overpaying their property taxes. Check For Free Discussions in Lynnfield, MA 240 followers Ask Question Recent Activity 159 kimball rd...the property picture of beautiful colobial IS NOT the house! VERY VERY MISLEADING! Somebody should be fired! Answer first Is This House Still Avalabile ? 2 answers recent home sale on Salt Island Rd., Gloucester, MA 1 answer multiple listing #71400438 Please send me info on that house: 6 Glen Drive, W. Peabody MA 01960 4 answers HAS ANYONE LOOKEDAT THE COLONIAL AVE HOME? 1 answer HAS ANYONE LOOKEDAT THE COLONIAL AVE HOME? 2 answers anybody seen Lisa Ferrari ? She disappeared....Graduated from SMH in 1985.. Answer first View recent questions More local advice More Advice: 
 Recent Q&amp;A in Lynnfield, MA Recent blog posts in Lynnfield, MA Find a real estate professional Lynnfield, MA 
 
 Send this property to a friend 5 Ashley Ct, Lynnfield MA $1,799,000 4 br , 5 full, 2 partial ba , Single-Family Home Friend&apos;s email: [+] Add another friend&apos;s email Your email: Your name:
 (optional) Message:
 (optional) Cancel Send 
By sending, you agree to Trulia&apos;s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy .
 Done       

 My Notes Done Save a personal note that only you can view. Clear Save my note       

 Report Listing Error 5 Ashley Court, Lynnfield MA Error Type: Please select... Property Sold/Withdrawn Price has changed Incorrect Agent/Broker Link Doesn&apos;t Work Incorrect Photo Incorrect Property Details Incorrect Map Other   Current Revised Price: $1,799,000 $ Property Type: Single-Family Home Select One Single-Family Home Condo Townhouse Coop Apartment Loft TIC Apartment/Condo/Townhouse Mobile/Manufactured Farm/Ranch Lot/Land Multi-Family Income/Investment Houseboat Unknown Listing Type: -- Select One Resale New Home Beds: 4 Baths: 7 Sqft: 8,426 Lot size:
 (acres) 0.75 acres Year Built: 2005     Please remove this listing
until this issue is resolved Details: Your name Your email
 (optional): 
 Cancel Send 
 Done       

 Ask a question about this property Sorry, we couldn’t find contact information for this agent. Try asking your question on Trulia Voices below. 
 Did you know? You can ask the Trulia Voices community about this property to get information and advice from real estate experts and locals .
 150 characters left Question Ask real estate experts,locals, and friends... 1000 characters left More Details (Optional) Optional details about your question This question is about this property: http://www.trulia.com/property/3055426120-5-Ashley-Ct-Lynnfield-MA-01940   Get email alerts as people answer my question ASK!       

 Success! DONE       
 Nearby homes 
 3 Ashley Ct Lynnfield, MA 7 Ashley Ct Lynnfield, MA 1 Ashley Ct Lynnfield, MA 2 Ashley Ct Lynnfield, MA 4 Ashley Ct Lynnfield, MA 11 Cider Mill Rd Lynnfield, MA 1 Saunders Rd Lynnfield, MA 3 Ivanhoe Dr Lynnfield, MA 58 Essex St Lynnfield, MA 375 Main St Lynnfield, MA 
 Show more You might also be interested in... Similar Homes New Listings Price Reductions View all» Previous 
 23 photos 12 Townsend Rd 
 $659,900 

on

 4 br  2 full, 1 partial ba   3,058 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 25 photos 465 Main St 
 $489,900 

on

 4 br  2 full, 1 partial ba   2,074 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 25 photos 3 Russell Rd 
 $969,000 

$80,000 on 06/27/12

 4 br  5 full, 1 partial ba   4,740 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 20 photos 72 Canterbury Rd 
 $379,900 

on

 3 br  2 ba   1,400 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 19 photos 19 Edgemere Rd 
 $799,900 

$70,000 on 05/27/12

 4 br  3 full, 1 partial ba   4,510 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: Sun Jul 15

12pm to 1:30pm
 11 photos 10 Ramsdell Way 
 $1,100,000 

on

 4 br  3 full, 1 partial ba   4,000 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 photos 2 Essex St 
 $689,900 

on

 4 br  2 full, 1 partial ba   2,469 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 15 photos 47 Brook Dr 
 $369,900 

$10,000 on 06/17/12

 4 br  2 ba   2,684 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 22 photos 6 Timberhill Ln 
 $589,000 

on

 4 br  2 full, 1 partial ba   3,453 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 15 photos 794 Lowell St 
 $454,900 

$15,000 on 06/10/12

 3 br  2 ba   2,168 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 25 photos 419 Chestnut St 
 $799,000 

on

 5 br  2 full, 1 partial ba   3,631 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 25 photos 2 Willis Ln 
 $799,900 

$25,000 on 05/22/12

 6 br  3 full, 1 partial ba   4,787 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 25 photos 5 Ashley Ct 
 $1,799,000 

on

 4 br  5 full, 2 partial ba   8,426 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 22 photos 319 Lowell St 
 $749,000 

$10,900 on 05/25/12

 4 br  4 full, 2 partial ba   3,641 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 25 photos 7 Liberty Ln 
 $969,900 

on

 4 br  3 full, 2 partial ba   3,640 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 
 Next 281fd2663cc480441a489a7ed1f77a35 281fd2663cc480441a489a7ed1f77a35 
 What do you think of this area? 
Thanks! Your review has been submitted

Thanks! Both your review and ratings have been submitted
 
Thanks! Your changes have been saved
 Done We are collecting ratings for the surrounding area, not for this or any other specific property or listing.       
 
 Communities near 5 Ashley Ct, Lynnfield | MLS# 71249609 
 Lynnfield Real Estate Lynnfield Real Estate Lynnfield Foreclosures Lynnfield Single-Family Homes 01940 Real Estate 01940 Single-Family Homes 01940 Apartments for Rent Lynnfield Apartments for Rent 
 
 Nearby Cities Homes for Sale South Lynnfield Homes for Sale Wakefield Homes for Sale Peabody Homes for Sale Reading Homes for Sale North Reading Homes for Sale Saugus Homes for Sale See All Nearby Cities 
 
 Real Estate and Mortgage Guides Lynnfield Real Estate Guide Lynnfield Schools Essex County Home Prices Heat Map Massachusetts Home Prices Heat Map Lynnfield Mortgage Lynnfield Refinance Lynnfield Home Loan 
 
 Compare 5 Ashley Ct With... Similar homes to 5 Ashley Ct Recently sold Lynnfield homes Recently sold 01940 homes Compare to 5 Ashley Ct 
 

 Nearby Cities Homes for Sale South Lynnfield Homes for Sale Wakefield Homes for Sale Peabody Homes for Sale Reading Homes for Sale North Reading Homes for Sale Saugus Homes for Sale East Lynn Homes for Sale Middleton Homes for Sale Hathorne Homes for Sale Lynn Homes for Sale       

Residential Real Estate

 San Francisco real estate  |  New York real estate  |  Los Angeles real estate  |  Orlando real estate  |  Miami real estate  |  Philadelphia real estate  |  Phoenix real estate  |  San Diego real estate  |  San Jose real estate  |  Chicago real estate  |  Arizona real estate  |  California real estate  |  Florida real estate  |  Illinois real estate  |  Massachusetts real estate  |  New Jersey real estate  |  Pennsylvania real estate  |  Texas real estate  |  Other local real estate  |  California apartments  |  New York apartments  |  Texas apartments  |  Apartments for rent  |  Home price maps  |  Real estate community  |  U.S. Property records 
 
Explore Trulia

 Homes for Sale  |  Homes for Rent  |  Stats&amp;Trends  |  Real Estate Advice  |  Real Estate Apps  |  Trulia Labs  |  Trulia API  |  Trulia Estimates 
 
For Professionals

 Agents  |  Brokers  |  MLS  |  Advertisers&amp;Partners  |  Tools&amp;Widgets  |  Submit Your Listings  |  Real Estate Leads 
 
Corporate

 About Trulia  |  News Room  |  Trulia Blog  |  Careers  |  Privacy  |  Terms of Use  |  Subscription Terms of Use  |  Community Guidelines 
 This Single-Family Home located at 5 Ashley Ct, Lynnfield MA, 01940 is currently for sale and has been listed on Trulia for 72 days. This property is listed by newenglandmoves.com for $1,799,000. 5 Ashley Ct has 4 beds, 7 baths, and approximately 8,426 square feet. The property has a lot size of 0.75 acres and was built in 2005. 5 Ashley Ct is in Lynnfield and in ZIP Code 01940 . The list price of $1,799,000 is 182% higher than the average list price of $638,898 for 01940 real estate and 182% higher than the average list price of $638,898 for Lynnfield, MA real estate . The price for this property is 331% higher than the average sales price of $417,700 for 01940 and 331% higher than the average sales price of $417,700 for Lynnfield. The price per square foot for this property is $214, which is 0.23% lower than the average of $214 for 01940, and 0.23% lower than the average of $214 for Lynnfield. Copyright©2012
 Trulia, Inc. All rights reserved. |  Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity Have a question? Visit our Help Center to find the answer 
 
 $1,799,000 5 Ashley Court, Lynnfield MA
 Follow Share Contact agent
	</body>
</document>
