<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009763" url="http://www.menuism.com/restaurants/marios-la-fiesta-mexican-restaurant-berkeley-406154" time="2012-07-13-03:09" support="2" score="0.001288340752896943" bingtitle="Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant - Reviews &amp; Menu - Elmwood ..." webtitle="Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant - Reviews&amp;Menu - Elmwood - Berkeley 94704">
			<query id="000950" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="001139" bing-rank="220"/>
	<description>... Mexican Restaurant is a Mexican, Lunch, and Fast Food restaurant ... One tip, you can order it “wet” if you prefer. ... large burrito, and so filled that I tried to pick ...</description>
	<body>
		Menuism - Restaurant and dish reviews 
 Explore Restaurant Reviews&amp;Menus 
 Restaurants Near Me Make Online Reservations Order Delivery&amp;Takeout Restaurant Week Directory Popular Cities Popular Chains What&apos;s Menu ism ? Monthly Review Contest 
 Remember Personal Dining Journal 
 My Favorites My Try List My Photos Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 
 Learn Foodie Education Blog 
 Food Primers Exclusive Interviews 
 
 FIND AROUND GO 
 Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 

 Not a member? To save, rate, and share reviews, sign up! Already a member? Log in (OpenID) Connect with Facebook 
 
 larger map / directions 
 
 - Actions - Write a Review Add to Try List Add to Favorites Suggest Corrections Upload Pics 

 - Pages - The Restaurant Map/Directions Dishes/Menu 
 Berkeley Restaurants » Elmwood » Mexican » Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant Share | 
Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant
 
 4.27273 star rating           
  4.3 rating over 3 reviews 
 (510) 540-9123 

 2444 Telegraph Ave ( ) 

 Berkeley , CA 94704-2321 

 View Nearby Businesses» 
 Send to Phone Email Listing Print Listing   
 View Menu Read Reviews (3) View Map/Directions 
 
 Information From the Restaurant Offers 
 
 Description:  Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant is a Mexican , Lunch , and Fast Food restaurant where most Menuism users came for fun with friends , paid less than $10 , and tipped more than 18% . Tags: Mexican, Burrito, Cal, Delivery, Dinner, Lunch, Crowded, Cheap, Small, and Carry-out Stats: 
 66 dishes entered by diners at Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant 2 users want to eat at Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant 5 users love Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant 
 
 
Nothing yet.
 
 Do you own Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant? Contact us to connect with your diners. 
 
 Suggest Corrections/Menu 
 
Reviews for Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant
 Write a review 
 3 reviews First reviewed by spam_i_am 
 
&quot;food good&quot;

 251 helpful votes over 29 reviews 
 spam_i_am 
 29 Restaurant Reviews +249 Loves this restaurant 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant spam_i_am 
 January 25, 2007 
 5.0 
 5.0 star rating           
 +12 5 +12 12 Votes   
Best Burrito in Berkeley
 
A Berkeley institution, on Telegraph Ave. Delicious, cheap eats.

Decor/Ambiance: Casual, typical Mexican mom and pop. Seating is usually no problem, except maybe during football game days.

Service: Good, attentive.

I think it’s way better than La Burrita, another Berkeley favorite. Stick to the Super Burrito and you can’t go wrong!
 
Dishes I tried:
 
Super Burrito - Carne Asada (Steak)
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
This is the burrito to get. Rice, beans, cheese, salsa, guacamole, sour cream. Get it with black beans. Grab some salsa and slather it on. Welcome to burrito heaven.
 
Chicken flautas
 
 4.0 star rating           
 
Rolled-up fried tacos filled with chicken and topped with guacamole and tomato sauce. Not too oily, crispy, good.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add/Show Comments (5) 
 
Comments
 
 fattiusthebear 
 01/25/2007 
&quot;because a bear&apos;s gotta eat well&quot;

 623 helpful votes over 156 reviews 
 156 +623 This number is the number of useful votes fattiusthebear has. The more useful votes, the more you can trust the quality of reviews. 
i never got around to eating here. now i know i should.
 
 john 
 01/25/2007 
&quot;consumption with gumption.&quot;

 735 helpful votes over 154 reviews 
 154 +735 This number is the number of useful votes john has. The more useful votes, the more you can trust the quality of reviews. 
Wow, interesting choice. I was always a big La Burrita fan when I was there–guess I never gave this place its fair chance. I’ll keep this in mind the next time I’m back.
 
 justin 
 01/26/2007 
&quot;Co-Founder of Menuism - always ready to eat!&quot;

 900 helpful votes over 317 reviews 
 317 +900 This number is the number of useful votes justin has. The more useful votes, the more you can trust the quality of reviews. 
You gotta try Frausto’s Mexican on Shattuck. They have huge burritos that you can get drenched with sauce (they serve it in a plastic box for takeout). I used to eat them all the time when I worked over there.
 
 knat28 
 02/01/2007 
 101 helpful votes over 28 reviews 
 28 +101 This number is the number of useful votes knat28 has. The more useful votes, the more you can trust the quality of reviews. 
This is THE best burrito place in Berkeley! Sorry guys. La Burrita might have been on the walk home, but Marios is waay better.
 
 justin 
 02/01/2007 
&quot;Co-Founder of Menuism - always ready to eat!&quot;

 900 helpful votes over 317 reviews 
 317 +900 This number is the number of useful votes justin has. The more useful votes, the more you can trust the quality of reviews. 
No…it’s Frausto’s! I agree La Burrita does suck (but we were able to buy beer to go in a soda cup…kudos points for that). I stand strongly by frausto’s–i think it fed me my entire senior year.
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply 
 9 helpful votes over 2 reviews 
 shopnut 
 2 Restaurant Reviews +9 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant shopnut 
 January 29, 2007 
 5.0 
 5.0 star rating           
 +6 1 +6 6 Votes   
Best burritos in Berkeley
 
Every time I go back to Berkeley, I have to eat at Mario’s. It’s family owned, and you always see the same wait staff.

The food is always top notch, and the salsa really is spicy. They don’t hold back the heat for the gringos at all.

I agree with Spam_i_am, the menu item to hit up is definitely the Super Burrito Carne Asada.
 
Dishes I tried:
 
Super Burrito - Carne Asada (Steak)
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
This is a really delicious and filling burrito. Part of it is because Marios’s makes really top notch, chunky guacamole (none of that overly smooth stuff you pick up in the deli section of the neighborhood supermarket). They use a lot of cheese, and even the rice in the burrito is flavorful. (I usually find it to be a bit bland at other places.) Did I mention that the burrito is pretty darn big? It’s big enough to fill almost any appetite. It’s been a long time since I’ve last been able to finish a burrito, and I’m not a wimpy eater.

One tip, you can order it“wet”if you prefer. They’ll throw some of the red enchilada sauce on top of it. No matter which way you order it, it’s fantastic!
 
Cheese flautas
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
Also an excellent pick. My husband loves this because they fill a corn tortilla with cheese, fry it up fresh, and top of it with a generous topping of the best guacamole in Berkeley. He usually orders this a la carte and adds a grilled bean, cheese and rice burrito for a meal.
 
Grilled Burrito - Bean, Rice&amp;Cheese
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
One of the cheapest items of the menu (it’s about $3), the grilled bean, rice&amp;cheese burrito is absolute amazing. They grill the burrito until it’s triangular, which really brings out the rich bean and cheese flavor. Try it, it’s even better than it sounds.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add/Show Comments (1) 
 
Comments
 
 justin 
 02/01/2007 
&quot;Co-Founder of Menuism - always ready to eat!&quot;

 900 helpful votes over 317 reviews 
 317 +900 This number is the number of useful votes justin has. The more useful votes, the more you can trust the quality of reviews. 
Hmm, I don’t remember the guacamole at Marios. I guess I’ll have to head back there next time in town. I’ll also have to get those cheese flautas!
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply 
&quot;because a bear&apos;s gotta eat well&quot;

 623 helpful votes over 156 reviews 
 fattiusthebear 
 156 Restaurant Reviews +621 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant fattiusthebear 
 February 28, 2007 
 5.0 
 5.0 star rating           
 +5 1 +5 5 Votes   
truly great burritos
 
I am going to have to agree with the other reviewers. This place probably does have the best burritos in Berkeley, of what I have tried. The carne asada burrito seemed to be the item to get, and it definitely did not disappoint. Thinking about it makes me happy. It is quite a large burrito, and so filled that I tried to pick it up, it would tremble. It was obviously too big to pick up without exploding its goodies. After I used knife and fork, it was stable enough to eat by picking it up. The filling they use inside blend well together. It also comes with lettuce next to the burrito. I guess if you want a bite to refresh your palette. I ate it with the fallen entrails of the burrito. Definitely worth trying, if you like Mexican food at all.

As for the prices, they were quite cheap for the burrito. It was $5.80 including tax. I think that is quite a good deal, especially for the quality and size. Some of the other dishes are more expensive, but they are the more specialty dishes such as tamales and combo plates. The decor seemed pretty authentic. It was very festive, full of paintings, pictures, and Mexican novelties. The staff was always busy, but they were friendly and still quite attentive. I fully plan on coming back to try the other stuff.
 
Dishes I tried:
 
Super Burrito - Carne Asada (Steak)
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
An outstanding burrito. Better than the other carne asada burritos in Berkeley, in my opinion. Big enough that only big eaters can finish it (like me!).
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add/Show Comments (1) 
 
Comments
 
 fattiusthebear (Author)
 03/15/2007 
&quot;because a bear&apos;s gotta eat well&quot;

 623 helpful votes over 156 reviews 
 156 +623 This number is the number of useful votes fattiusthebear has. The more useful votes, the more you can trust the quality of reviews. 
i’d like to add that the restaurant is kinda dirty. just so you know.
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply 
Best Dishes at Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant

These dishes from the Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant menu are contributed by Menuism users directly, 
 as part of a restaurant review, or as part of an image upload.
 
Super Burrito - Carne Asada (Steak) ( $5.35 ) 
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
Cheese flautas
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
Grilled Burrito - Bean, Rice&amp;Cheese ( $3.00 ) 
 
 5.0 star rating           
 View all dishes 
 Zebra Tattoo&amp;Body Piercing 
 92 reviews 5.0 stars Moe&apos;s Books 
 17 reviews 4.5 stars Reprint Mint 
 3 reviews 5.0 stars PostalAnnex+ Framer&apos;s Workshop The 
 2 reviews 5.0 stars Berkeley Hat Company Postal Annex Campus Flowers 
 5 reviews 4.5 stars Walgreens U C Hair Salon&amp;Waxing 
 29 reviews 5.0 stars 
 Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant is located near the cities of Columbus, Regina, Albany, Rockridge, and Kensington. People found this by searching for: La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant Berkeley, Mario&apos;s Elmwood Mexican Restaurant, Happy Burrito Berkeley, Frausto&apos;s Berkeley Menu, Berkeley Mexican Restaurant Expensive, La Fiuesta Berkeley Flauta, Flautas Berkeley, and Fraustos Berkeley Menu. 
Featured in Berkeley
 
 3.875 star rating           
 Kirala 
 3.75 star rating           
 Downtown Restaurant 
 3.5 star rating           
 La Mediterranee 
 3.0 star rating           
 Thai Delight Cuisine 
 4.5 star rating           
 Musical Offering 
 4.25 star rating           
 Picante 
 3.75 star rating           
 King Dong Restaurant 
 5.0 star rating           
 Virginia Bakery 
 4.0 star rating           
 West Coast Pizza 
 3.5 star rating           
 Drunken Boat Restaurant 
 Upload Pics Photos
 
Loves Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant (5)
 mandeelish 
 Santa Clara, CA 
 +336 useful
 spam_i_am 
 New York, NY 
 +249 useful
 mmm_good 
 New York, NY 
 +157 useful
 mirabell_19 
 Los Angeles, CA 
 +121 useful
 arhammer 
 Berkeley, CA 
 0 useful
 

 
Wants to Try Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant (2)
 justin 
 Chicago, IL 
 +898 useful
 john 
 Seattle, WA 
 +735 useful
 

 
Nearby Restaurants
 Bear House Berkel Berkel Restaurant Slurp Noodle House Cafe Intermezzo Raleigh&apos;s 
Link to Mario&apos;s La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant
 
Copy the link below and paste onto your website or blog to display badge.

 Copy 
 
Related Links
 Yelp Reviews Reviews on TripAdvisor 
 Follow Menuism around the web Find us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter Find us on Google+ 
 
 Learn More
 Advertise About
Advertise
FAQ
Privacy
Terms of Use 
 Take Action
 Link to Menuism / Badges and Widgets 
 Browse
 Restaurant Week Restaurant Locations Popular Cities Sitemap 
 
 ©2006 - 2012 Delta Beans, LLC
 Contact Menuism
	</body>
</document>
