<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009369" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Pompano-Beach/Take-Sushi_5" time="2012-07-13-02:44" support="3" score="0.005437643616650119" bingtitle="Take Sushi - Fast Food Restaurant Pompano Beach, FL 33062" webtitle="Take Sushi - Fast Food Restaurant  Pompano Beach, FL 33062">
			<query id="000046" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000047" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000059" bing-rank="157"/>
	<description>Take Sushi a Fast Food restaurant with a location at 2661 E Atlantic Blvd in Pompano Beach, FL. Enjoy Fast Food menu in Pompano Beach and coupons of Take Sushi and ...</description>
	<body>
		0 Friend Requests Friend Requests 0 Messages Send a New Message Messages 0 Notifications Notifications 
 
 Find Friends Login 
 or login with: User Pages Photos Events Videos Polls Forum Threads Restaurant Search Results For User Search Results For Pages Search Results For Photos Search Results For Events Search Results For Videos Search Results For Polls Search Results For Forum Threads Search Results For Restaurant 
 Places Deals Recipes Photos Members Blog 
 
 Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Take Sushi
 
Average User Rating
 
5
 
Average
 
Sponsored Link


 
(954) 785-2442

 
 FL &gt; Pompano Beach &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Take Sushi listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Take Sushi to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Take Sushi
 Take Sushi is a Fast Food restaurant located at 2661 E Atlantic Blvd in Pompano Beach, FL 33062. Take Sushi has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 5 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Take Sushi
 
 
 
All Reviews for Take Sushi


 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Take Sushi:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   0

 
Comments
 
 
Take Sushi News
 Sushi Chain Takes $600,000 Loss on Japanese Tuna for Patriotism A Japanese sushi chain will take a more than $600,000 loss on the most expensive ... with more of the coveted awards than Paris and New York combined. At Sushiyabashi Jiro, which has three stars, a course can cost more 35,000 yen ($460). Reason for Not Eating Out #49: Getting Over Your Food Fears This was a huge step for me, because I love the taste of eel in sushi or with rice, but am terrified by the appearance of a fresh, uncooked eel. This probably happened sometime in my childhood. My family would take week-long summer vacations on the ... Pele&apos;s Wood Fire brings modern Italian-American cuisine to Riverside It was at the San Marco restaurant, where Tierney met and worked with Micah Windham, Pele’s executive chef. But it took investor Mark Frisch’s affections for New York’s famous ... Windham as the “Italian sushi effect,” where all ... Food Network Premieres New Series &quot;Fat Chef&quot; and Returns With a New Season of &quot;Heat Seekers&quot; in January Fat Chef Premieres Thursday, January 26th at 10:00pm ET/PT Heat Seekers Premieres Monday, January 16th at 8:00pm ET/PT NEW YORK, NY - January 4 ... to experience the spiciest dishes take them to restaurants in Atlanta, Dallas, Kansas City ... Meet Your New Favorite Beach Town: Montauk, N.Y. It&apos;s the eastern-most point of New York State, a wild bit of nature ... a split-level dockside restaurant that Foley opened in 2006 with five other commercial fisherman (sushi from $6). There, the catch of the day is grilled, fried, sautéed, or carved ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing New York Restaurants New York Restaurants Let&apos;s face it, the Big Apple is the mother of all cities. There simply is no contest. Take your pick, choose a restaurant, food style of your ... New York City Restaurants, New York City Menus, Ratings, Reviews ... What&apos;s a hot menu?Every night we calculate the most-clicked restaurants of the preceding 24 hours and display them here. If a restaurant makes the Hot Menus list for ... New York City Restaurants - New York, New York - Yahoo! Travel Hey take a look at this. I went into the draw to win an iPad2 and won! All I did was choose a colour submit my email and two days later I found out I ... Lotus Restaurant - The Ultimate In Chinese, Japanese, and Sushi ... Home Join our mailing list for special coupons, announcements, and more! What&apos;s better than unwrapping a brand new iPad 2 this year? Winning it from Lotus!!! NYC.com | New York Hotels - Broadway Tickets - New York ... Save more with NYC.com, the trusted New York City experts. Book New York hotels and lodging, buy New York Broadway tickets and event tickets, reserve New York ... 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 82° 
Fri
 
 77° - 90° 
Sat
 
 77° - 90° 
Sun
 
 79° - 90° 
 
Address
 
Take Sushi

2661 E Atlantic Blvd

Pompano Beach, FL 
 
33062
 
Telephone
 (954) 785-2442 
Take Sushi
 
 Rating :  5 out of 10 based on 5 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Take Sushi Photos
 
 Fast Food 
 
 Local Places
 
 Kentucky Fried Chicken 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Wendy&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Pasquale Pizza 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Burger King 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Quiznos 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Taco Bell 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food American Legion Post 142 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Top Choice 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Wingsn Things 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Jacks Old Fashion Hamburger House 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Angie&apos;s Coffee Experience 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food KFC 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Razzleberry&apos;s Icecream 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Fine Art Wholesales Incorporated 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries A1 Beverage Corporation Liquor 
Cuisine: Liquor Store Mgt Intelligence Group Incorporated 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Bispos Cellar 
Cuisine: Grocery Stores Ramada Inn NRT 
Cuisine: Hotels Motels 
 

See all Pompano Beach Art Museums Galleries 
See all Pompano Beach Liquor Store 
See all Pompano Beach Grocery Stores 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Take Sushi Coupons 

 Take Sushi Pompano Beach 

 Take Sushi Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Pompano Beach Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | Y Z 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
