<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009107" url="http://www.liveleak.com/view?i=e51_1190898887" time="2012-07-13-02:29" support="2" score="0.0006222921840541721" bingtitle="LiveLeak.com - McDonalds Staff Sprayed With Mace In Drive Thru." webtitle="LiveLeak.com - McDonalds Staff Sprayed With Mace In Drive Thru.">
			<query id="000609" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000704" bing-rank="104"/>
	<description>... Broward Sheriff&apos;s Office is investigating a fast-food restaurant ... up to the take-out window, and the left back seat ... You need to be registered in order to add comments!</description>
	<body>
		Create Account  |  Log in  |    
 
 Home Recent Items Channels Forums 
 
 News&amp;Politics  | Yoursay  | Must See  | Iraq  | Afghanistan  | Entertainment  | Chat  | Staff Blog  | More Blogs  | Top Leakers 
 McDonalds Staff Sprayed With Mace In Drive Thru. 
OAKLAND PARK, Fla. -- The Broward Sheriff&apos;s Office is investigating a fast-food restaurant drive-through pepper spray attack that left several employees irritated.

BSO deputies said a blue Toyota Solara with five females inside pulled up to the McDonald&apos;s drive-through window at 3073 W. Oakland Park Blvd. at about 4:30 p.m. Wednesday.

The driver ordered a 69-cent soda, but when the employee told the customer through the intercom that it wasn&apos;t available, she became verbally abusive, according to the BSO. The driver then pulled up to the take-out window, and the left back seat passenger pulled out a can of pepper spray and sprayed the inside.


Three employees went to the hospital for treatment, while eight other employees complained of residual pepper spray effects but required no treatment.

The driver of the car is described as a thin black female with large earrings. The front seat passenger was dressed as a woman, but BSO deputies said the passenger might have been a cross-dressing man with red, white and blue hair accessories. Three other females were in the back seat of the car.
 Loading the player ... Get Embed Code 
 
 Item Info Links 
 Added: Sep-27-2007  
 By: barnesy 
 In: News 
 Tags: staff , maced , at , mcdonalds 
 Marked as: approved
 Views: 20680 | Comments: 33 | Votes: 0 | Favorites: 1 | Shared: 1 | Updates: 1 | Times used in channels: 2 | Reports: 0 (Reposts: 0) 
 Direct link: 
 

 Direct link without comments: 
 
 You need to be registered in order to add comments! 
 View comments (33) 
 Tweet 
 Items 
 Updates Related 
 
 
 Drive Thru Pepper Sprayers Caught. 
 
 Advertisement below 
 

 Advertisers 
 Advertise on Liveleak 
 Liveleak Forums 
 ProChan - Anonymous Interaction 
 Videos of Guns and Explosives! 
 China Wholesale 
 Create your own video channels 

 
 F.A.Q. |   Site Support |   Contact Us |   Privacy Policy |   Terms&amp;Conditions |   Copyright |   Advertise 
 BACK TO TOP
	</body>
</document>
