<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009608" url="http://www.firstcoastnews.com/news/strange/default.aspx" time="2012-07-13-03:00" support="14" score="0.017506834589391625" bingtitle="Strange &amp; Unusual News | Jacksonville, FL - St. Augustine, FL ..." webtitle="Strange&amp;Unusual News | Jacksonville, FL - St. Augustine, FL - Brunswick, GA | Firstcoastnews.com">
			<query id="000699" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="001031" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000702" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000922" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="001026" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="001021" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000712" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000670" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000713" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="001430" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000851" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000694" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="001227" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000717" bing-rank="27"/>
	<description>-- A 25-year-old woman from Lincoln Park, Mich., who continued to collect food stamps ... drinks while leaving her 5-year-old daughter unattended for an hour inside her car.</description>
	<body>
		Continue Reading » Advertisement 
You will be redirected to the page you want to view in   seconds.
 
 Events DealChicken ABC25 NBC12 2012 Olympics 
 
 Home News 
 
 
 Data Center Education First For You Florida News Georgia News Local News Money Health News Political Florida Special Reports Strange News US and World 
 
Latest Headlines
 
 Sheriff: Reduction in revenue means a reduction in services 

JACKSONVILLE, Fla. -- At a sitdown with the media today, Sheriff John ...
 
 Lake City woman faces lien for home damaged by police 

Natalie Custer lived on NW Irma Avenue in September 2011 when Lake City police ...
 
 JSO charges a former Assistant State Attorney with two misdemeanors 


 
 
 Weather 
 
 
 Live Doppler: Your 2 Minute Advantage 7 Day Forecast E-Hurricane Guide Beach Forecast Fire Weather Forecast Local Temperatures Satellite Tropics Stormtrack iMap Tracking the Tropics Weather App Android Weather App iPad Weather App iPhone 
 
 
 Traffic 
 
 
 Jacksonville Traffic Cams Car News Gas Prices Text Alerts Travel 
 
 
 Video 
 
 
 Good Morning Jacksonville 12 p.m. 5 p.m. 5:30 p.m. 6 p.m. 7 p.m. 11 p.m. ABC News Player ABC Shows Player Previews Player Viewer Videos 
 
 
 Life 
 
 
 Community Daily Crossword Entertainment Events Calendar Jobs Lottery Military Moms Publix Kitchen Recipes Stuff the Bus Think Pink 
 
 
 Sports 
 
 
 2012 Olympics College Basketball College Football Gators Golf News High School Sports Jaguars NBA NFL Seminoles Sharks Buy Tickets 
 
Latest Headlines
 
 City selling sponsorship packages for Florida-Georgetown 

JACKSONVILLE, Fla. -- If you want to attend the Nov. 9 Georgetown-Florida ...
 
 Kingfish Tournament is next week 

JACKSONVILLE, Fla. -- The 32nd Annual AT&amp;T Greater Jacksonville Kingfish ...
 
 FSU star Greg Reid arrested for marijuana possession 

TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) - Star Florida State punt returner Greg Reid has been ...
 
 
 Features 
 
 
 Buddy Check 12 Contests Coupons / Weekly Deals First Coast Living Great Hang Up Hero Central Kick It Up First Coast My First Coast Health Watch Student of the Week Teacher of the Week 
 
 
 
 
 FEATURED: Slideshows High School Sports ABC Player I&apos;m Telling Ken 
 Search 
Strange and Unusual News

 
 
 Top News Most Viewed 
 Presented by 
 Starbucks to open inside a South Carolina funeral home 
 1:59 PM, Jul 12, 2012 
If you&apos;re dying for one more for double latte in Easley, S.C., we have
just the thing: Starbucks is opening a &quot;coffee corner&quot; inside the
Robinson Funeral home next month.
 
 Girl starts summer lobster stand 
 12:07 PM, Jul 12, 2012 
 Man suspected in Fla. cattle theft caught in Mexico 
 11:34 AM, Jul 12, 2012 
 VIDEO: Shark steals fish off hook Home invasion suspects fist-bump at Walmart Man finds beloved car stolen more than 40 years ago - on eBay Michigan woman: I tended corpse, watched NASCAR Neighbors try to shut up laughing yoga group 
 Strange&amp;Unusual Video SEE MORE VIDEO | SUBMIT VIDEO Strange&amp;Unusual News 
 Unborn baby may have saved mom&apos;s life in crash 
 2:06 PM, Jul 11, 2012 
LONGMONT, Colo. -- The grandfather of the woman who lost her yet-to-be
born son in a suspected DUI crash says his granddaughter was so far
along in her pregnancy, that when he got a call to get to the hospital,
he originally thought the baby was coming.
 
 Bank director vanishes, $17 million missing 
 11:22 AM, Jul 11, 2012 
ATLANTA -- After penning a rambling letter to financial regulators and
writing notes to his family, a south Georgia bank director boarded a
ferry in Key West, Fla., and disappeared.
 
 Wolverines need &apos;refrigeration zone&apos; to reproduce 
 9:01 AM, Jul 11, 2012 
Famously formidable, wolverines require a springtime &quot;refrigeration zone&quot; home to feed their cubs, biologists report.
 
 Afraid of lightning strike, New Jersey teen jumps from chairlift 
 8:52 AM, Jul 11, 2012 
NEW JERSEY -- A New Jersey teenager said Monday she &quot;freaked out&quot; when
her chairlift ride high above a beach stopped as a thunderstorm
approached - and that&apos;s why she jumped.
 
 Sheriff Arpaio: Phoenix arsonist likely took cyanide after guilty verdict 
 8:44 AM, Jul 11, 2012 
PHOENIX -- Maricopa County Sheriff&apos;s investigators on Monday found a
canister of cyanide in the car of Michael Marin, likely confirming the
theory that Marin committed suicide in court on June 28.
 
 Hotels put UV scanners to work on germs 
 8:13 AM, Jul 11, 2012 
DETROIT -- Yes, hotel guests want chic rooms and free Wi-Fi. But most of all, we want the room to be clean.
 
 Police: Naked man arrested after biting man&apos;s stomach 
 4:06 PM, Jul 10, 2012 
ST. AUGUSTINE, Fla. -- Officers with the St. Augustine Police Department
were called to a home on Palmetto Avenue a little before 4:30 Saturday
morning after residents of the home found a naked man on their roof.
 
 Police: Woman swallowed diamond, pawned it later 
 2:39 PM, Jul 10, 2012 
SALT LAKE CITY -- A Utah woman is accused of theft after police say she
swallowed a $4,000 diamond ring at a department store before pawning it
off after it passed through her system.
 
 Va. judge tosses lawsuit from White House crasher 
 1:33 PM, Jul 10, 2012 
FRONT ROYAL, Va. -- A Virginia judge has dismissed White House party
crasher Tareq Salahi&apos;s $50 million lawsuit against the rock musician who
ran off with Salahi&apos;s wife.
 
 Parents charged in UAE after hidden baby found in carry-on 
 11:21 AM, Jul 10, 2012 
An Egyptian couple has been charged with putting their child at risk and
attempted smuggling after security officers at an airport in the United
Arab Emirates found their 5-month-old boy hidden in a small handbag.
 
 Detroit cops probe how officer&apos;s holstered gun killed woman 
 9:06 AM, Jul 10, 2012 
Detroit police still don&apos;t know how an off-duty officer&apos;s holstered gun
discharged and killed a woman who reportedly embraced him from behind
during a backyard party, according to news reports.
 
 Code enforcement officer walks into home 
 7:43 AM, Jul 10, 2012 
Monday morning, Erica Masters was sleeping in her bed when
Columbia County Code Compliance Officer Jimmy Vowell came to serve a
violation notice for her grass being too long. Erica caught the whole
incident on tape.
 
 Police destroy grenades found under L.A.-area highway bridge 
 7:24 AM, Jul 10, 2012 

 
 Kayaker tells of being trailed by great white shark 
 6:55 AM, Jul 10, 2012 
A newbie kayaker tells the Boston Globe he had &quot;my own little
moment with God&quot; while being trailed closely by a great white shark as
he paddled off a crowded Cape Cod beach over the weekend.
 
 Minnesota trooper pulls over driver of unsafe Ford Pinto 
 4:46 PM, Jul 9, 2012 
MINNEAPOLIS -- On Sunday, a Minnesota State Trooper pulled over an
unsafe vehicle on Highway 53 in Koochiching County. In the process,
he found a heck of a story to tell.
 
 CAUGHT ON CAMERA: Tightrope walker survives fall 
 1:48 PM, Jul 9, 2012 
PINGJIANG, China -- An acrobat in central China was walking a 2,200-foot
tightrope backwards and blindfolded when he fell 132 feet.
 
 Fireworks used to attack unsuspecting homeowners 
 1:46 PM, Jul 9, 2012 
LAND O&apos; LAKES, Fla.- William Bagley spent his Fourth of July house
sitting for friends on vacation when Wednesday night he suddenly smelled
smoke filling the home.
 
 Police: Woman allegedly killed by naked man in California 
 12:14 PM, Jul 9, 2012 
TRACY, Calif. -- Tracy police are investigating a murder that took place in the Hacienda Motel Saturday night.
 
 N.Y. man nears 3 millionth mile in beloved &apos;66 Volvo 
 9:29 AM, Jul 9, 2012 
BAY SHORE, New York -- It just keeps going, and going, and going. No, it&apos;s not a battery. It&apos;s Irvin Gordon&apos;s 1966 Volvo P1800S.
 
 More public schools splitting up boys, girls 
 8:12 AM, Jul 9, 2012 
MIDDLETON, Idaho -- Robin Gilbert didn&apos;t set out to confront gender
stereotypes when she split up the boys and girls at her elementary
school in rural southwestern Idaho.
 
 U.S. Airways plane gets stuck in tarmac because of the heat 
 8:04 AM, Jul 9, 2012 
WASHINGTON -- A U.S. Airways flight at Reagan National Airport was
delayed Friday after the jet&apos;s wheels sunk into the tarmac because of
the excessive heat, the The Washington Post reports.
 
 Has James Dean Lost His &apos;Cool&apos;? 
 1:18 PM, Jul 7, 2012 
Ilan Dar-Nimrod listens to the classics-the Beatles, the Doors, Genesis. He is a voracious reader, with some of his favorite authors being Kafka, Murakami and Vonnegut. He used to own a motorcycle. In his free time, he goes backpacking through Europe, Asia or Latin America. He&apos;s friendly and laughs easily, but, as a scientist and academic, he has chops in the brain department.
 
 St. Augustine police: Naked man arrested after biting man&apos;s stomach 

ST. AUGUSTINE, Fla. -- Officers with the St. Augustine Police Department
were called to a home on Palmetto Avenue a little before 4:30 Saturday
morning after residents of the home found a naked man on their roof.
 3:06 PM, Jul 10, 2012 
 Rutherford asking for property tax rate increase 

JACKSONVILLE, Fla. --Thursday afternoon Sheriff Rutherford, flanked by senior staff, broke down his budget.
 1:56 PM, Jul 12, 2012 
 235 pounds of cocaine seized at Port of Jacksonville 

JACKSONVILLE, Fla. -- Customs and Border Protection officers seized 235 pounds of cocaine at the Port of Jacksonville Tuesday. The cocaine has an estimated street value of $3.47 million.
 8:55 AM, Jul 12, 2012 
 1,500 prescription pills seized in Operation &apos;Pain Management&apos; 

More than 1,500 prescription pills were taken off the streets and 103
individuals now face drug-related charges in Operation &quot;Pain
Management,&quot; an eight-month investigation by the North Florida High
Intensity Drug Trafficking Area Tri-County Narcotics Task Force, which
is sponsored by the Florida Department of Law Enforcement.
 3:34 PM, Jul 11, 2012 
 Women Welders Wanted 

JACKSONVILLE- Many across the country and here in Jacksonville are struggling to find a job. But there&apos;s one sector of the economy that has huge demand for workers 
 4:40 AM, Jul 12, 2012 
 Jacksonville police: Thief tries to cash in stolen lottery tickets 

JACKSONVILLE, Fla. -- The Jacksonville Sheriff&apos;s Office is looking for a
suspect wanted for the armed robbery of a Hess gas station located at
8346 Normandy Boulevard.
 12:54 PM, Jul 12, 2012 
 FL Dept. of Health responds to tuberculosis outbreak allegations 

JACKSONVILLE, Fla. -- The Florida Department of Health responded Wednesday to allegations in a Florida news story regarding a Jacksonville tuberculosis outbreak.
 10:23 PM, Jul 11, 2012 
 Bath salts still emerging on the First Coast 

It may be banned, but the First Coast is still seeing the emergence of the drug known as bath salts.
 5:27 AM, Jul 12, 2012 
 Man arrested for burglary after ramming a cart into Family Dollar 

JACKSONVILLE, Fla. --A man was arrested for burglary after he rammed a
shopping cart through the glass front door of a Family Dollar early
Tuesday morning.
 11:12 AM, Jul 12, 2012 
 Jacksonville ranked 6th for top 10 real estate buyers&apos; markets 

Chicago, Milwaukee and Cleveland lead the list of Zillow&apos;s top real
estate buyers&apos; markets, with homes in those metropolitan areas taking
longer to sell and buyers receiving an average discount of 5 percent off
asking prices. Jacksonville ranked 6th.
 9:06 AM, Jul 12, 2012 
News Links
 Links mentioned on-air during First Coast News 
Check It Out
 
 
 
Don&apos;t Miss
 MORE 
 
 Olympic events schedule for participating UF athletes 
 
 Florida releases elementary, middle school grades 
 
 Restaurant Inspections&amp;Violations 
 
 Get the FCN Weather app with Live Doppler Radar 
 
 Cold and Flu 
 
 Where the Jobs Are 
 
 Political Coverage 
 
 News Links 
 
 ABC Video Player 
 
         MORE 
Follow us anywhere
 
 MOBILE TWITTER FACEBOOK RSS EMAIL SMS 
 FIRST COAST NEWS ON MOBILE Check the latest news, sports, weather, video and more on the go. 
 All mobile devices:
 fcn2go.com News App:
 iPhone | Android Weather App:
 iPad | iPhone | Android Political Florida:
 iPad | iPhone | Android 
 FOLLOW US ON TWITTER Follow our latest activity on all topics from Firstcoastnews.com 
 @FCN2go @FCNgmj 
 JOIN US ON FACEBOOK Connect with First Coast News on Facebook 
 First Coast News First Coast Living 
 SUBSCRIBE TO RSS FEEDS Find RSS feeds for the latest news, weather, sports, business, entertainment and more. 
 Select from all of our RSS offerings 
 SIGN UP FOR OUR EMAIL NEWSLETTER Get news and information via email. 
 Select a newsletter 
 SIGN UP FOR TEXT ALERTS 
 Sign up for Mobile Text Alerts from First Coast News 
 
 Photo Galleries 
 
 
 Jacksonville police looking for gas station robber 
 
 New sculpture installed in UNF building 
 
 103 individuals charged in &apos;Operation Pain Management&apos; 
 
 $6,000 reward offered for robber of liquor store 
 
 Peter Bragan Sr. memorial service 
 
 Female lion cub born at the Jacksonville Zoo and Gardens 
 
 Peter Bragan, Sr.: 1923-2012 
 
 Natalie Wood death certificate changed to &apos;undetermined&apos; 
 
 Minnesota trooper pulls over driver of unsafe Ford Pinto 
 
 Celebrities who have died in 2012 
 
 The running of the bulls in Pamplona 
 
 2012 Summer Jazz Series at The Seawalk Pavilion 
 
 Firestock 2012 benefits local fallen firefighter&apos;s family 
 
 Patriotic pet adoptions 
 
 First Coast Gears: Hellfighters Motorcycle Ministry Car&amp;Bike Show 
 
 Man wins $1,000 Sourpuss contest to donate to charity 
 
 Nathan&apos;s Famous International Hot Dog Eating Contest 
 
 Independence Burger Eating Contest in Washington 
 
 First Coast Gears: DiCaprio invests in Fisker 
 
 Independence Day celebrations around the First Coast 
 
 4th of July fireworks at the Jacksonville Landing 
 
 City: Landing fireworks will go on as scheduled 
 
 Florida bald eagle population seeing resurgence 
 
 Jacksonville police investigate credit union robbery 
 
 A look back: Andy Griffith 
 
 Ashley Madison releases list of famous athletes married women want to cheat with 
 
 Bark N&apos;Brew 
 
 Aerial photographs show flooded Clay County 
 
 Boston plays at St. Augustine Amphitheatre 
 
 Surf camp for local foster children 
 
 First Coast Gears: Chevrolet Corvette turns 60 
 
 Ringo Starr and His All Starr Band plays in St. Augustine 
 
 Debby: The aftermath 
 
 Rock Pythons born at the Jacksonville Zoo and Gardens 
 
 First Coast News says thank you and goodbye to outgoing GM 
 
 TomKat through the years 
 
 On the red carpet: &apos;The Amazing Spider-Man&apos; premiere 
 
 Parts of First Coast still feeling Debby&apos;s impact 
 
 U.S. Supreme Court upholds health care reform law 
 
 Kilt Girl 2013 Calendar Shoot 
 
 
More Photo Galleries | Submit Photos 
 
More Strange&amp;Unusual News
 
 Utah Boy, 4, Dies After Being Crushed by Tombstone Elvis impersonator falls into hoarding Restaurant owner dies hours after meeting Obama Couple seeks permit for pet wallaby Bear spray attack backfires on suspects TomKat split puts spotlight on Scientology Candidates with same name run for different roles Mass. man pays off mortgage with pennies Phoenix mother accused of putting beer in son&apos;s sippy cup Emaciated Fla. teen found in burning mobile home Tropicana Field doubling as a gun target? &apos;Black Widow&apos; wins hot dog eating contest with 45 Do speed eaters pay later for 15 minutes of frankfurter fame? Male African elephant euthanized at Zoo Miami 4 charged with robbing Florida woman 3 times Woman survives jump from Sunshine Skyway bridge San Diego fireworks go kaboom then fizzle - prematurely Brown widow spider creeps into SD Tall people convention held in Jacksonville Police: Pa. inmate tried to hail cab from hospital 
 
 
 
MOST POPULAR
 
 St. Augustine police: Naked man arrested after biting man&apos;s stomach Rutherford asking for property tax rate increase 235 pounds of cocaine seized at Port of Jacksonville SEE MORE 
 
Interactive Radar
 Interact with the latest radar images and weather conditions 
My Community
 Local news, events and featured businesses where you live 
FOLLOW US ON TWITTER&amp;FACEBOOK

Add First Coast News on your favorite social networking site and stay connected and up to the minute on the latest news.
 

 Top football recruits compete at &quot;The Opening&quot; in Oregon Leader of the pack: Wolfson coach battles cancer Summer basketball report Big Man on Campus: Laremy Tunsil 

 
 
 
MOST POPULAR VIDEO

 JSO will cut 319 positions, Rutherford writes in internal letter Fl. Dept. of Health responds to tuberculosis allegations Tim: Tropical trades SEE MORE 
 
MOBILE

 Check the latest news, sports, weather and more on your mobile device.

 All mobile devices:
 fcn2go.com News App:
 iPhone | Android Weather App:
 iPad | iPhone | Android Text Alerts 
 
 
         Site Map   |   Back to
 Top 
 Home News 
 Data Center Education First For You Florida News Georgia News Local News Money Health News Political Florida Special Reports 
 

 Weather 
 Live Doppler: Your 2 Minute Advantage 7 Day Forecast E-Hurricane Guide Beach Forecast Fire Weather Forecast Local Temperatures Satellite Tropics Stormtrack iMap Tracking the Tropics Weather App Android Weather App iPad 
 Traffic 
 Jacksonville Traffic Cams Car News Gas Prices Text Alerts Travel 
 

 Video 
 Good Morning Jacksonville 12 p.m. 5 p.m. 5:30 p.m. 6 p.m. 7 p.m. 11 p.m. ABC News Player ABC Shows Player Previews Player Viewer Videos 
 Life 
 Community Daily Crossword Entertainment Events Calendar Jobs Lottery Military Moms Publix Kitchen Recipes Stuff the Bus 
 

 Sports 
 2012 Olympics College Basketball College Football Gators Golf News High School Sports Jaguars NBA NFL Seminoles Sharks 
 Features 
 Buddy Check 12 Contests Coupons / Weekly Deals First Coast Living Great Hang Up Hero Central Kick It Up First Coast My First Coast Health Watch Student of the Week Teacher of the Week 
 
 
 
HELPFUL LINKS
 About First Coast News Advertise With Us Closed Captioning Contact Us The Country Network EEO Public File Internship Program Jobs at First Coast News Press Releases Reporter-Anchor Bios Talent Request Terms of Service WJXX ABC25 TV Schedule WTLV NBC12 TV Schedule 
 
 
FOLLOW US
 Twitter Facebook Mobile RSS E-mail Alerts Text Alerts 
 Search 
 
 Copyright©2012
 Multimedia Holdings Corporation. All rights reserved.
Users of this site agree to the Terms of Service and Private Policy/California Privacy Rights
	</body>
</document>
