<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009231" url="http://www.smartcouponing.com/index.php/2010/08/02/do-you-tip-at-pei-wei/" time="2012-07-13-02:37" support="6" score="0.009307894874731203" bingtitle="Do You Tip at Pei Wei? |" webtitle="Do You Tip at Pei Wei? |">
			<query id="001134" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000131" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="000156" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000977" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="000139" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="000155" bing-rank="209"/>
	<description>... the better the attitude and the fuller my cup ... it when you go to a restaurant and the CASHIER has a ... If it’s a fast food restaurant and they only give me food at a ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Amazon Freebies CVS Walgreens Target walmart Publix Printable Coupons 
 
Do You Tip at Pei Wei?
 Written on August 2, 2010 Leave a comment! - 21 Comments 
 

 Update: Thanks for all the insightful comments, we did get to talk to the Manager at Pei Wei that night and he emphasized that Pei Wei is established as a more casual diner/take out place where tips are not necessary, and he went on about how they trained their staffs to serve from the heart ..bah bah bah..nevertheless my hubby still insisted that we should at least leave a couple  dollars because there were servers bringing us food and cleaning up our table afterward.  So in case you wonder, they really do not expect tips from customers.

Now…as promised….here’s the lucky reader who will receive a special $5 Amazon Gift Code:

 Rainey (rainranda5@…) 

Rainey’s comment–”I rarely tip at a fast food place since most of them don’t offer anything for one here.  At Starbucks I do if they are quick and really nice.  But always at a sit down restaurant, the better the attitude and the fuller my cup, they bigger the tip. If I am with my family (who are cheap) and they don’t leave a tip, I always go back and leave one that would be enough to cover all of us (lucky we are a small family) then I tell my family in the parking lot before we get in our cars that they are a bunch of cheapskates LOL”

Thanks guys for the great discussion !!

*******************************************************************************************************

My original post:

Hubby and I had dinner at Pei Wei on Monday night cause we had the 2 entrees for $10.00 coupon, we ordered the Mongolian Beef and Sesame Shrimp with 2 waters, tax was $0.65, so our final cost is only $10.65, without coupon that would easily be over $20….anyways that’s not the point of this post…ok…while we always try to go for great deals and bargains, we are in fact very generous when it comes to tipping (especially my hubby…he even tips at starbucks… )  well…I, on the other hand, sometimes feel not as sure about some of the situations, like Starbucks, Pei Wei, Dunkin Donuts, then what about McDonalds and all the other fast food chains.  We did get to talk to the Manager over at Pei Wei about this issue, but before I tell you guys what he told us, I’d like to hear what you think and how you tip, go ahead and share your thoughts with me!!





 

 « Previous Post Next Post » 21 Responses to Do You Tip at Pei Wei? 
 Nat August 2, 2010 | 1:07 PM 
I tip when it’s a sit down restaurant with servers. If I have a coupon I tip based on what the total price would’ve been without the coupon. I don’t feel that the server should take a hit, they still served the meal and took care of us through our meal so they deserve to based on the meal total before discount/coupon! 
 Tammy July 30, 2010 | 7:32 AM 
I don’t like to tip at fast food restaurants. I also do not appreciate it when you go to a restaurant and the CASHIER has a tip jar by the register.
 Rainey July 30, 2010 | 4:36 AM 
I rarely tip at a fast food place since most of them don’t offer anything for one here. At Starbucks I do if they are quick and really nice. But always at a sit down restaurant, the better the attitude and the fuller my cup, they bigger the tip. If I am with my family (who are cheap) and they don’t leave a tip, I always go back and leave one that would be enough to cover all of us (lucky we are a small family) then I tell my family in the parking lot before we get in our cars that they are a bunch of cheapskates LOL
 Chelsie July 29, 2010 | 5:58 PM 
My husband actually was a Restaurant Mgr at Pei Wei and myself as a former restaurant server. Establishments such as Pei Wei, Dunkin Donuts or your nearest Mom&amp;Pop joint tipping is an option. These places aren’t your normal sit down restaurant where you are waited upon as soon as you hit the entrance. My husband said that any tip is a good tip but not required. The servers are definitely grateful, for sure but not expectant to find bills waiting for them at the table. I agree as a server.

So be free with your tips, conservative or when ever you feel like it. I say if you were impressed with the service at any place whether Pei Wei, Wolfgang Puck’s or Starbucks, by all means knock yourself out.
 Cin July 29, 2010 | 11:27 AM 
Pei Wei is a tricky situation. they dont wait on you but they do bus the tables and clean up the floors. In the past I’ve just put a couple dollars on the table—not percentage of meal like I would at a typical sit-down restaurant where you have a hostess, waiter, kitchen staff and buser. I look forward to hearing what the manager had to say!
 Robin July 29, 2010 | 11:13 AM 
If there is a server, I tip. If not, I do not tip.
 Anne July 29, 2010 | 11:11 AM 
This is were I am also iffy on.
 Rachel S July 29, 2010 | 10:58 AM 
Anytime I sit down to eat, I tip. And I’m usually a good tipper because waiters don’t get minimum wage. They get an amount below that and tips are supposed to make up for that. I have some friends that worked in the food industry and it’s pretty stressful. If they pick up after me, I tip. If it’s a fast food restaurant and they only give me food at a counter then if I pay cash I’ll leave leftover change (they usually don’t have tips but jars for a cause–like McDonalds).
 Kelly July 29, 2010 | 10:02 AM 
I usually never have cash so at places like Pei Wei I usually don’t tip unless I have cash. But I usually only tip whatever change I have been given back. As you can tell I have never worked in the restaurant/food business. I have made a point when service has been outstanding to tell the manager what a great employee they have.
 Mary July 29, 2010 | 1:27 AM 
I do know from working fast food that they are not supposed to accept tips. I only tip at sit down restaurants, or if I know that they are making the server wage.

I don’t feel the need to tip Starbucks or any other coffee place they already make above min wage.

As far as fast casual places like chippotle or pie wei they don’t bring me anything so I feel no need to tip.
 Amy July 28, 2010 | 10:56 PM 
As a former waitress (for many years) my rule is I tip (20+%) at places where the help only receives server minimum wage which is $2.37 per hour and not regular pay. Therefore, I do not tip at fast food restaurants, etc.
 Mandy July 28, 2010 | 10:55 PM 
I usually only tip at sit-down restaurants, but if someone did an amazing job while we were there (the person who took our order, someone walking thorough the restaurant to clean up), we will stick some moolah in the tip jar for sure. I sometimes hesitate because I think they have to divide the tips in the jar so the person who I intended the tip to be for most likely won’t get it…
 Carrie July 28, 2010 | 9:28 PM 
I’m interested in your response. We are also generous with our tips but in Pei Wei, since we order the food at the counter we do not tip because we also have to get our drinks. If they were to bring the food to the table and fill/refill our drinks I would leave a few dollars.
 Linda July 28, 2010 | 8:18 PM 
At Dunkin Donuts I will only tip if the server hands me back the bills BEFORE they hand me the change. If they hand me the change first, I am inclined to keep my hand out while I wait for the bills. If they had me the bills first, I always give the“no, keep it”wave. Sometimes, if I’m feeling especially nice, I may give the cashier a“verbal tip”to“always hand back the bills first…you will likely get more tips”.

For sit-down restaurants I will always tip generously (providing I at least get decent service) based on the amount of the bill BEFORE any coupons/discounts. The waiter/waitress works just as hard–even if you meal is reduced–so they deserve the full tip. The way I look at is that even if I leave a generous tip, I’m still paying less than full price because I had a coupon.
 Melissa July 28, 2010 | 7:52 PM 
I don’t usually tip at fast food or coffee establishments unless the service is just incredible. At sit-down restaurants, we often order one meal and split it. We then tip based on what it would have cost if we had both ordered a meal since we feel like the server is doing the same amount of work.
 Loni July 28, 2010 | 6:22 PM 
I only tip at some establishments, if I gave a tip every where I went to dine or get coffee, I would be broke.
Here is my list of places I DO TIP: Starbucks (not drive-thru), Sweet Tomatoes, Pei Wei, any sit down restaurant where they bring your food, clear your table and ask if you need anything and always delivery. Even if your server sucks, you should always tip atleast the minimum.
Places I DO NOT TIP: fast food, drive thru or take-out.
 Brooke Jones July 28, 2010 | 6:01 PM 
If it’s just my husband and I, we don’t usually tip at Pei Wei’s since you don’t have a waiter there . . . but when we bring the kids with us we always tip since the kids (all 5) make a big mess and I feel sorry for whoever has to bus the table when we leave.
 Deanna July 28, 2010 | 5:29 PM 
I tip whenever I eat at a sit-down restaurant. If the service was great, 20-25% tip is completely understandable. With a coupon deal at a restaurant, I would definitely feel inclined to tip, no matter the setting. Except drive-thru fast food places. I don’t see tipping as part of the culture in those establishments. However, great service should be rewarded anywhere! I think to myself If I worked there, would I expect a tip? 
 A.Marie July 28, 2010 | 5:11 PM 
I am a very generous tipper. If we are eating at a place like, say, Pizza Hut, and we have a waiter bringing us our food, drinks, etc., I always leave them a tip. If I am eating at a fasty-food place, where no one is bringing me my drink, food, etc., like McDonald’s, I don’t see the purpose of tipping. The tip is for the benefit of the server; they usually are paid very little and the tips are really a necessary part of their wage.

My twin sister used to be a waitress back when she was in her early 20s, newly married to a military guy, and she worked at a fish joint. You placed your order at the counter, but she’d have to bring it to you along with whatever else you needed. She was paid below minimum wage with the idea that tips would bring it up to a decent wage. One night, she waited on a party of about 10 people and the total bill was around $200 dollars. They demanded her attention for 2 hours with refills, more silverware, napkins, etc., and after they left, she had a huge mess to clean up and NO TIP!!! I have never forgotten how exhausted and tired she was and how much she cried. So, I guess what I am saying is: if you are seated at a table and someone else is doing the running for you, please consider tipping them generously for their efforts and time.

Since we have no Starbucks near my small town, I’m not sure of how you should tip, but I guess if there is a tip jar near the cashier, it probably isn’t a bad idea to tip your barista if you are happy with your coffee drink. 
 Rachel July 28, 2010 | 5:04 PM 
We don’t have a Pei Wei here, but typically we only tip if it’s a sit down restaurant. Now there are exceptions, like sometimes at coffee shops if I get great service, but I never tip at fast food places.
 Fawn July 28, 2010 | 4:59 PM 
We always tip at most restaurants, but not fast food. I would say we’re generous tippers, we tip 20%, sometimes a bit more, as we have a toddlers who is messy and we feel bad for leaving a mess behind (although we try and clean up as best we can!).
 
 
 PRINTABLE COUPONS 
 
 
 Amazon.com Widgets Free Sweepstakes and Contest ***Grab My Button*** 
 Networked Blogs Follow this blog 
 Go To Top 
Copyright @ Smart Couponing 2010
	</body>
</document>
