<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009235" url="http://fastfood.einnews.com/country/singapore" time="2012-07-13-02:37" support="7" score="0.01173394712267793" bingtitle="Singapore Fast Food News - Fast Food News Today" webtitle="Singapore Fast Food News - Fast Food News Today">
			<query id="000365" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="000458" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="001526" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000427" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000898" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="001118" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000178" bing-rank="122"/>
	<description>Why did F&amp;B receipts crash last month? … % yoy ... precaution, police have instructed a fast food ... &quot;After seasonal adjustment, fast food outlets and other eating places … .</description>
	<body>
		Friday Jul 13, 2012 Fast Food News Today A service for Global Professionals 
 Change your billing and/or user information Extend your subscription period Re-activate an expired account Manage your Email Alerts Add additional users to your account Manage your additional user account(s) Retrieve a lost password Get an invoice for your subscription Cancel your account by sending us an email through the feedback form 
 
 News by Topic News by Country 
 Tools 
 Publications Submit News Members About Contact 
 
Singapore Fast Food News

Latest Singapore News
 from
 Fast Food News Today.
 South-East Asia &gt;Singapore
 | Singapore
 Topics 
 Get by: Email or RSS 
 
 
 Sip costs star $1.5M 
 12 Jul 20:36 GMT 
 …)facial hair  (1)fail  (1) fast food (1)FBI  (1)FDA  (1…Florida  (4) Food (50) Food Integrity Campaign  (1) Food Network  (1) Food Safety News…Stewart  (2)JPL  (1)junk food (1)jury duty  (1)kabbfox29…1)shopping  (3)shortages  (1) Singapore (1)Siri  (1)skip jury… 
 
 Western-style Fast Food Increasing Heart Disease Risk In Southeast Asians 
 12 Jul 14:01 GMT 
 …Asians who frequent American-style fast food joints are increasing their…,584 Chinese living in Singapore aged between 45 and…, hot dogs, and other fast food sandwiches. The results revealed…that people who ate fast food frequently consumed less vegetables… 
 
 Retail sales to boost Singapore visitor arrivals by 9.9% end-2012 
 12 Jul 10:31 GMT 
 …holidays, Singapore should be on track to meet the Singapore Tourism Board… food and beverage services index, which tracks sales at restaurants, fast food outlets and food caterers, rose 2.9… 
 
 Study: American fast food increasing heart disease risk in Southeast Asians 
 11 Jul 13:42 GMT 
 …in Singapore who reported eating American-style fast food twice…found. Furthermore, Chinese-Singaporeans eating fast food four times or…intake of American-style fast food ate less vegetables…them restaurant-based, western-style fast food . The study… 
 
 Fast Food Joints Export Poor Health to Singapore 
 11 Jul 04:42 GMT 
 …to Singaporeans with their portions of burgers and fries, western-style fast food joints…Asia: American Fast Food Is Fare for the Rich Are Fast Food Companies Deliberately Making North Americans Sick? Food Systems Creating… 
 
 Singaporeans moved by elderly woman’s plight 
 11 Jul 01:47 GMT 
 MANY people gave food and money to a partially…newspapers by the roadside in Singapore with her seven-year-old grandson, reported…) to buy food . One of them even bought KFC for my grandson… 
 
 Western style fast food increasing health risks in Asia 
 9 Jul 20:04 GMT 
 …in Singapore who reported eating American-style fast food twice…found. Furthermore, Chinese-Singaporeans eating fast food four times or…intake of American-style fast food ate less vegetables…them restaurant-based, western-style fast food . The study… 
 
 Fast Food Consumption Around the World Linked to Health Risks 
 8 Jul 21:40 GMT 
 …disease since fast food restaurant chains like McDonald’s, Burger King and KFC started setting…. Prior to that time, American-style fast food was practically unknown there and…with the National University of Singapore , the UM team analyzed medical… 
 
 Eating Fast Food Increases Heart Disease, Diabetes Risk 
 6 Jul 22:05 GMT 
 …examine the association of Western-style fast food with cardio-metabolic risk in a…52,000 Chinese residents of Singapore who have experienced a recent…study participants who reported eating fast food most frequently were younger, better… 
 
 Fast food ups heart disease 
 3 Jul 09:50 GMT 
 …in Singapore and found new evidence that a diet heavy in fast food …to people who avoid fast food . For people eating fast food two-three times each…consume fast food items four or more times each week. Eating fast food two… 
 
 Fast food can bring on diabetes, heart disease 
 3 Jul 05:40 GMT 
 …avoid fast food , according to the latest research. For people eating fast food two-three…counterparts from National University of Singapore reviewed a 16-year-old study, based…study participants who reported eating fast food most frequently were younger, better… 
 
 Heart Disease and Type 2 Diabetes - Increased risk seen with Fast Food Eaters in Singapore 
 3 Jul 05:32 GMT 
 …found that people in Singapore who ate fast food on a regular basis…researchers found that even eating fast food once weekly showed a 20…from Singapore . Odegaard said that most of the people eating fast food were… 
 
 Fast food intake increases risk of diabetes and heart disease in Singapore 
 3 Jul 00:05 GMT 
 …in Singapore and found new evidence that a diet heavy in fast food …to people who avoid fast food . For people eating fast food two-three times each…consume fast food items four or more times each week. Eating fast food two… 
 
 Britain uses Olympics to shed stodgy food ... 
 28 Jun 16:01 GMT 
 …million meals — much of it fast food — to those coming for…quot;simple but memorable&quot; food .&quot;Just simple ingredients:…fare such as pizza, Singapore noodles and jerk chicken…British cuisine.&quot;British food showcases our heritage, openness,… 
 
 Britain uses Olympics to shed stodgy food image 
 28 Jun 14:17 GMT 
 …meals — much of it fast food — to those coming for…fare such as pizza, Singapore noodles and jerk chicken…British cuisine.&quot;British food showcases our heritage, openness,…/Heston-Blumenthal Ivan Day Historic Food : http://www.historicfood.com/… 
 
 UHV professor&amp;#39;s Singapore trip promotes importance of childhood creativity 
 16 Jun 23:37 GMT 
 …as sports and music. In Singapore , the out-of-school activities are academic…parts of Singapore . They enjoyed learning about local culture and food . A…is westernized with plenty of fast food chains.&quot;I&apos;m… 
 
 Russia - Burger King have big plans 
 11 Jun 02:29 GMT 
 … BURGER KING WORLDWIDE HOLDINGS, INC.   Founded in 1954, BURGER KING ® is the second largest fast food …Capital operates in Moscow, London, Singapore , Dubai, Hong Kong, Sofia, New…All-Russia Investor Survey.       Contacts   For Burger King Worldwide Holdings, Inc. Miguel Piedra… 
 
 Burger King Worldwide Holdings, Inc. Announces Aggressive Expansion Plans for BURGER KING(R) Brand in Russia 
 6 Jun 08:14 GMT 
 …in 1954, BURGER KING (R) is the second largest fast food hamburger chain in…Capital operates in Moscow, London, Singapore , Dubai, Hong Kong, Sofia, New…=50301279&amp;lang=en SOURCE: Burger King For Burger King Worldwide Holdings, Inc. Miguel… 
 
 The Fast Food Risk In BRIC&amp;Emerging Market Nations 
 5 Jun 16:05 GMT 
 …in its analyst downgrade.  Its KFC unit is huge in China…new restaurant development announcements in Singapore , the Middle East and North…? We do not see these fast food outfits contracting their international and… 
 
 A whopping outdoor treat Fast food chain rolls out garden concept dining 
 1 Jun 03:13 GMT 
 FAST FOOD chain Burger King invites Malaysians to dine ‘outdoors’…Grill concept outlet opened in Singapore in August last year. Today…bring Burger King Malaysia’s growth plans to fruition. Currently, Burger King has two… 
 
 Olympics McDonald&apos;s to serve British-only chicken 
 30 May 20:40 GMT 
 A Locog spokesman told Telegraph Sport on Wednesday:&apos;&apos;All of our chicken is British and Red Tractor assured. McDonald&apos;s will also only serve British chicken in their four restaurants at the Olympic Games.&quot;The volte-face followed an… 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 Next Follow @EIN_News NEW French Alps Avalanche Kills 9---Latest News Updates from EIN News Press Releases 
 Latest See All Submit a Release 

Reach our readers and post your press release.

 Country Style Cooking Restaurant Chain to Hold 2012 Annual General ... [12 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Pretzelmaker® Kicks Off Summer With the Exclusive Pretzel Dog and ... [12 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Dunkin&apos; Brands Group, Inc. to Announce Second Quarter Fiscal Year 2012 ... [12 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Domino&apos;s Pizza® Brings Mobile Ordering App to Amazon&apos;s Kindle Fire [11 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Don&apos;t Call Him Junior: Son of Baconator Joins Wendy&apos;s Hamburger Lineup [10 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Pizza and Garlic Bread Together At Last: Pizza Hut Introduces Garlic ... [10 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Lombardi Family Concepts Chooses GiftCardLab.com To Provide Company-... [10 Jul 2012] PR Newswire The Dunkin&apos; Donuts&amp;Baskin-Robbins Community Foundation Awards $127,... [10 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Caribou Coffee Names Leigh Anne Snider Senior Vice President of Retail ... [10 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Central Coast McDonald&apos;s® Will Send One Lucky Customer to See Local ... [09 Jul 2012] PR Newswire 
 Learn more about advertising opportunities Today&apos;s Photos 
 huffingtonpost.com
 Farm Bill Lasting Five Years Approved By House Committee motherjones.com
 5 Surprising Ingredients Allowed in Organic Food 
 OP/ED 
 Latest See All Submit 

 The Great LIBOR Robbery And The Corruption of Major Markets Sorkin&apos;s Fictional&quot;Newsroom&quot;Gets It Right, As CNN, Fox And Others Get It Wrong Romney&apos;s 1 Per Cent Class Parties in Utah; What will The Uninvited Do? 
 Conferences 
 Latest See All Submit 
 GCSE-Food&amp;Health Protection Conference - Toronto Canada 
 Featuring:
 - Consumer Protection - Championing Effective Solutions
 - ... 
 3rd Juice, Nectar&amp;Soft Drinks Summit 2012 
 Magenta Global in cooperation with the Turkish Fruit Juice Industry Association (MEYED) is ... 
 
 International Conference on QA , QC&amp;Validation 
 OMICS Group cordially invites all the participants across the globe to attend the ... 
 Marketplace 
 Latest See All Post a Listing 

 Press Release Distribution 
Get your press release seen by business and industry professionals and at all corners of the web for $79 or less
 Global Technology Forum 
Business strategies for the digital age. Free website from the Economist Intelligence Unit.
 Accounting Services 
Accounting, Tax&amp;Payroll Services. Enjoy your business, leave the paperwork to us. We are certified accountants.
 
 
 FAST FOOD NEWS TODAY BACK TO TOP 

 Account Info: 
 My Account Subscriber Billing Info Member Center 
 Change your billing and/or user information Extend your subscription period Re-activate an expired account Manage your Email Alerts Add additional users to your account Manage your additional user account(s) Retrieve a lost password Get an invoice for your subscription Cancel your account by sending us an email through the feedback form 
 
 Create an Account: 
 Sign up for a Free Trial Register for an Account 
 Help&amp;Information Center: 
 Help Contact Us 
 Submit 
 Submit Press Releases Submit Marketplace Listing Submit a Conference Reserve Ad Space 
 About 
 About Fast Food News Today Members List User Agreement Privacy Policy Copyright Policy 
 Navigate: 
 Site Map Home Fast Food News by Topic Fast Food News by Country Fast Food News by US State Fast Food Press Releases Fast Food Press Releases by 24-7 
 Tools and Formats: 
 Email Alerts RSS Feeds 
 
 EIN News Home About EIN News 
Founded in 1995, EIN News is an international leader in real-time news tracking and digital information services. Our systems continuously scan the web, indexing news from thousands of worldwide sources. The data is then filtered and organized into news streams. The process is supervised by a team of professional news editors.

We are news professionals and technologists dedicated to producing the fastest and most comprehensive news streams on the planet. We are committed to providing our members with the highest quality software tools and resources available.

 EIN News is a division of Internet Product Development Group Inc. 
To reach us send an email or call +1 202 657 5158.
 EIN Presswire EIN Marketplace EIN Events and Conferences Newsfeed Maker Inbox Robot IPD Group EIN Twitter EIN Facebook 
 
 ©1995-2012 IPD Group, Inc. All Right Reserved. +
 Fast Food News Today
 = Unlimited access to real-time news Create your EIN News account now. EDITOR&apos;S PICKS 
Founded in 1995, EIN News is an international leader in real-time news tracking and digital information services. Our systems continuously scan the web, indexing news from thousands of worldwide sources. The data is then filtered and organized into news streams. The process is supervised by a team of professional news editors.

We are news professionals and technologists dedicated to producing the fastest and most comprehensive news streams on the planet. We are committed to providing our members with the highest quality software tools and resources available.

 EIN News is a division of Internet Product Development Group Inc. 

Main office: 1025 Connecticut Ave. NW, Suite 1000, Washington, DC 20036
To reach us send an email or call +1 202 657 5158.
 About 
 About Fast Food News Today Aimed at business leaders and global professionals worldwide, Fast Food News Today is a media monitoring service provided by EIN News.

 About EIN News Established in 1995, EIN News began by supplying business professionals and individuals with relevant and interesting news products. It has grown to become the largest digital news provider in Europe.

 Member List See the partial member list and join a community of professionals from private industry, institutions, and governments that rely on EIN as a critical source for research, breaking news and media services.
 
 EIN Presswire A platform to publish your press or news releases online and be read by thousands of decision-makers, leading journalists and industry professionals who rely on EIN News as an indispensable source of breaking news. Your release will also immediately appear in the Google database and stream out to our content partners, Facebook and Twitter.
 
ALL NEWS PUBLICATIONS

 EIN News provides breaking news coverage on the following topics:
	</body>
</document>
