<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009405" url="http://www.roadfood.com/Restaurant/Overview/150/jks" time="2012-07-13-02:46" support="4" score="0.015303598197931045" bingtitle="JK&apos;s - Danbury, CT - Roadfood.com - The most memorable local ..." webtitle="JK&apos;s - Danbury, CT">
			<query id="000016" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="001351" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000007" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="000223" bing-rank="201"/>
	<description>Restaurant review for JK&apos;s, Danbury, CT ... bacon in addition to the usual condiments; it’s also possible to get a ... &quot; JK’s looks like any modern fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Your Guide to Authentic Regional Eats Sign In | Register for Free! Restaurants Recipes Forums Eating Tours Merchandise FAQ Maps Insider 
 JK&apos;s 
 126 South St. , Danbury , CT - (203) 743-4004 Overview Reviews( 1 ) Rate Restaurant Upload Photos Bookmark Email JK&apos;s Texas hot wieners are plump little sausages, split lengthwise and cooked until slightly crusty on the surface, loaded into a big spongy roll, then topped with mustard, onions, and hot sauce with a chili-pepper kick. Some connoisseurs order them with cheese, chili, and/or bacon in addition to the usual condiments; it’s also possible to get a heap of excellent house-made slaw on top or to get the bun toasted. 91% Approval Rating ( 24 votes) 
Scorecard
 Overall: One of the Best - Worth a Trip 
 Bowl of Chili Grape-Nuts Pudding Texas Hot Wiener French Fries with Gravy Milk Shake 
 Rate this place See more ratings... 
Highlighted Reviews
 Michael Stern - Photos (7) &quot; JK’s looks like any modern fast-food restaurant, but photographs on the wall tell another story: decades of weenie history. The nostalgic black-and white pictures show JK’s with its hot-dog sign hanging over Main Street many years ago; interior pictures show a ...&quot;   [Read More] 
 Submit photos Submit a review See more reviews... 
Map&amp;Web Site
 126 South St., Danbury, CT
(203) 743-4004

 
Hours&amp;Policies

 Seasons: Open Year Round Meals Served: Breakfast, Lunch Operational Hours: Always Call Ahead! Credit Cards Accepted: No Alcohol Served: No Outdoor Seating: No Reservations Accepted: No Delivery Available: No Takeout Counters: Yes 
 
&quot;Two classic JK&apos;s Texas hots, topped with mustard, onions, and hot sauce.&quot;
 Michael Stern 





 
&quot;Our milk shake was so thick that a straw stood up easily (but was of little use sucking up the drink, which must be gulped). The silver serving beaker held another glass-and-a-half. The blurry pictures on the wall behind the milk shake show JK&apos;s many incarnations through the decades since it began in the 1930s.&quot;
 Michael Stern 


 
&quot;French fries are availabe on a plate or in a basket, topped with cheese and/or gravy. Another option is seasoned curly fries with cheese and bacon bits.&quot;
 Michael Stern 


 
&quot;JK&apos;s always has rice pudding and Grape-Nuts pudding for dessert. The latter is pictured here. Note the copious veins of softened cereal spread throughout the custard.&quot;
 Michael Stern 


 
&quot;In the foreground: a bare Texas Hot Wiener. In the background: a Texas Hot topped with chili and cole slaw. We paid 10 cents extra to have the bun toasted, but next time would save our money. The normal soft bun is a better mitt for holding one of these short but meaty franks, especially if it&apos;s loaded.&quot;
 Michael Stern 


 
&quot;Jane, me, Seafarer John, and Gail (Mrs. Seafarer) polish off a bunch of Texas hots and milk shakes. I must say, the waitress was patient indeed when my camera didn&apos;t work right. And when the first picture proved too dark, she was happy to take another. Good service!&quot;
 Michael Stern 


 
&quot;Here is JK&apos;s wall of accolades from local celebrities, including beloved WTNH newsman Dr. Mel.&quot;
 Michael Stern 


 
 What is Roadfood?    |    Submit Content    |    Privacy Policy    |    Contact Roadfood.com    Copyright 2011 - Roadfood.com
	</body>
</document>
