<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009572" url="http://basicchef.wordpress.com/" time="2012-07-13-02:57" support="1" score="0.0005096171802373679" bingtitle="The Basic Chef | A Cooking Blog from a beginner chef. If I can do ..." webtitle="The Basic Chef | A Cooking Blog from a beginner chef. If I can do these recipes, you can too.">
			<query id="001277" bing-rank="184"/>
	<description>And for a “fast food” restaurant, I had to admit the ... I’m not sure if it’s because the selection ... chocolate- you can still successfully make the cups ...</description>
	<body>
		The Basic Chef 
 A Cooking Blog from a beginner chef. If I can do these recipes, you can too. Skip to content 
 Home About 
 ← Older posts 
 Pop Tart 
 Posted on October 11, 2010 | Leave a comment 
I don’t have kids yet, but I do participate in a mentoring program. My little “sis” is almost 10 years old and her favorite thing to do is cook. Therefore I’ve been on the hunt for great recipes that are easy and child friendly. Even though I’ve got tons of easy recipes, I didn’t really think she was ready for sweet potato and brie as ingredients.

Thanks to other websites including Family Fun, I’ve found tons of great recipes that my little “sis” can fully participate in and enjoy the final product.

This is her favorite. Homemade Pop-Tarts. I think she agreed to make them because she thought they would be like the store bought ones, loaded with sugar and topped with frosting. I like the recipe because it was the complete opposite. It’s the healthiest and freshest version of a pop tart I’ve ever seen. And what I really like is (this seems to be a common theme for me) the versatility. You’re options on filling are endless.

The first time I tested the recipes (pre little sis) I used preserves as the recipe suggested. But by the time I brought my little sis into the kitchen I got way more creative. I used a small amount of store bought preserves and mixed with fresh fruit. By our third and fourth time we were experimenting with mixing fruit flavors and adding non-fruit flavors like honey and chocolate. Next time we attempt this fun food we’re going to try to make the “preserves” from scratch.

The moral of the story, if you want to put a little or a lot of time into this recipe it always turns out great. It’s tons of fun for kiddos and even kiddos at heart (like me).

Pop Tarts

 

Pie or Tart Dough
I like this one from The Barefoot Contessa, but you can use any recipe you’re comfortable with.
2 cups all-purpose flour
1 Tablespoon Sugar
1/2 teaspoon kosher salt
12 Tablespoons col unsalted butter
½ cup ice water

Combine flour, sugar and salt using a mixer, add in butter pieces and continue to mix (chop) until butter is a small pea size. Add water until mixture begins to bind (will be in flaky pieces, not smooth batter).
Quickly remove from bowl and knead into a ball of dough.
Wrap dough in saran wrap (or air-tight plastic baggy) and set in refrigerator for 1 hour.

Pop Tarts Fruit Jam/ Preserves
1 egg
Raw or regular sugar
Parchment Paper

 

Create small square shaped portions of the dough. Roll out on a well floured surface to create a long rectangle.

 

Move from floured surface to parchment paper and dust off excess flour.
 Add jam/preserves filling, leaving a one inch edge around three sides.

 Fold dough over creating a pocket.

 Using a fork bind the edges

Cut off excess edges with a knife to create a smooth edge.
Brush the top and sides with an egg wash (the more egg wash you use the pretty the outcome).
Vent the top of the pop tart to avoid the filling from bursting out during baking (you can use a v shape, and x, or any design you’d like)
Sprinkle a small amount of raw or regular sugar on top.
 Bake at 400 degrees for 18-20 minutes. Bake time depends on thickness of dough, amount of filing, size, etc. I usually check mine around 15 minutes and go from there. Let cool and then serve to hungry mouths. These can keep for a decent amount of time in the refrigerator and a quick warm up in a toaster oven or microwave.
 
 →Leave a comment 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 Ode to the Falafel 
 Posted on August 19, 2010 | Leave a comment 
I spent one high school summer in Israel. It was an eye opening experience about my religious heritage and different societies around the world. It was also the start of my adventurous spirit. I found myself doing things I never even imagined, like hanging out in a cave filled (more than filled) with bats or joining the Israeli Army (that’s a whole different story!)

Not only did I learn so much about myself, I learned quickly to acquire new taste buds. Tomatoes, Cucumbers and cheese for breakfast, lots and lots of chicken, and one of the greatest discoveries of my life, the falafel. This uniquely Middle Eastern treat is popular world-wide, but I had never tasted a true falafel until I purchased one on the streets of Tel-Aviv (and then again on the streets of Jerusalem, Elat, Sfad….).

Luckily my summer trip included a lot of walking and hiking (Mt. Sinai at 3 am-wow!). Because if my feet hadn’t hit the pavement as much as they did, I certainly would have returned home twice the size as when I left, from eating so many falafel balls.

For years after my trip I would scour out any opportunity to eat falafel, mostly satisfying my need with Gyros. There was one particular spot in Boulder that served up incredible falafel and Gyro. It could have been the authentic Middle Eastern proprietor or it could have been my drunken-state hunger that lead me to his storefront on “the hill” every night at 2 am. Whatever it was, it made me happy.

After college I moved to areas that weren’t quite as diverse and falafel soon fell off my radar as a tasty treat. Then this past month my sister introduced me to heaven. She took me to Garbanzo Mediterranean Grill, a “Chipotle” type restaurant that served- you guessed it- garbanzo beans. Which means they served falafel. And for a “fast food” restaurant, I had to admit the falafel was pretty tasty. It got me in a Middle Eastern mood and I quickly ran to the grocery store to buy every can of chickpeas they had.

I’m not going to sugar coat it, there is an art to making great falafel, and I by no means mastered this art. It’s still difficult for me to find the correct way to make the falafel balls stay together without scorching them. But I was able to make a tasty, somewhat looks like a real falafel, ball. I devoured my first batch by dipping them in hummus (those extra cans of chick peas sure do come in handy). But by the second batch I found a trick. I put my raw falafel balls into the oven to bake for just a few minutes (at a low temperature) and that helped them bind a little bit more, so when I put them in the oil they stayed as balls (the previous time I had to pancake them down to make them bind). It’s still a work of progress. But now I have tricks up my sleeve, and enough restraint to wait to put the falafel balls into a sandwich. By stuffing the small balls into a half of a pita, along with hummus, cucumbers, tomatoes, a little bit of lettuce and a squeeze of lemon, I created the best lunch ever. (pics coming soon)

 
Falafel
1 1/2 cups chickpeas, soaked overnight
1/2 onion chopped
1 garlic cloves
1 teaspoon ground coriander
1 cup fresh cilantro
1 teaspoon baking powder
1 teaspoon salt
½ teaspoon cumin

Soak the chickpeas over night in water (change the water a few times)
In a food processor combine all ingredients. Blend until mixture is grainy.
Form small loose balls (do not compact them tight), approximately the size of a ping pong ball.
Fry in vegetable oil until golden. Let cool a little bit.
 
 →Leave a comment 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 Living on the Edge (of a budget) 
 Posted on July 12, 2010 | 2 Comments 
There are a few things that those closest to me know are facts:
1. I never get tan. Want to feel better about your not yet there summer tan (even in the winter), stand next to me.
2. I laugh. A lot. More than a lot.
3. I’m constantly on a budget.

The last one dictates a big part of my life. Even when I take every measure to save every penny, it seems like I am always struggling for money. I’m sure I’m not to different from most people out there, especially in this “economic environment” (probably my least favorite phrase of all time, but yet I get a kick out of using it). I’m always looking for a way to save a buck or two. And one of the best ways I’ve discovered is by cooking large meals and eating them for a week. This is easy for me to do since I’m a single girl and most recipes call for 4-6 servings. Sure every now and then I’ll get the generous bug and want to share my recipes with friends, but mostly I love knowing how far my dollar stretched.

I work at a company that mandates unpaid vacation time, in order to save money company wide. I’m ok with that (especially if that savings helps us reach our financial goals and I get a bonus at the end of the year- it all evens out), but it does mean that once a year I get a piddly little paycheck that barely covers my expenses. Since I’m too cheap to dip into my savings I really try to stretch my dollar even further during this period. During this year’s forced vacation I found a recipe for Black Bean Enchiladas. Jackpot! Not only was I craving fresh Mexican food, but the recipe called for 8 enchiladas. I added in a few extra ingredients (what recipe doesn’t need corn added?) and was able to stretch it out to 12 enchiladas. That fed me for week.

You’re probably thinking one of two things. Gross, who wants to hang out with a girl after eating a weeks worth of beans; or didn’t you get tired of eating the same meal every day? Both good points/questions. As to the first, I used black beans, they aren’t as much of a “magical” fruit. To the second question, yes a normal person would get tired of the same food. But I was able to intertwine other products that were already in my house (pasta, cereal, bisquick- we’ll get to that magical box of goodness later), and disperse the enchiladas between dinners and lunches. But really they tasted so good that I found myself wanting them for lunch and dinner, even in the same day.

The best part of this recipe is how well the enchiladas kept. I froze 6 of them in plastic bags right off the bat and when I defrosted them, they tasted as good as new. So for those of you who are budget conscious, planning a big meal or just want to eat a lot of black beans, here’s the long awaited recipe.

Black Bean Enchiladas 

1 green pepper thinly sliced
1 can black beans
1can corn
1 red pepper thinly sliced
1 medium onion thinly sliced
 1 clove garlic
1 cup of rice
½ cup of Salsa
1 Tbsp Chili powder
1 tsp Cumin
Tortillas
Cheddar or Mexican style cheese

Sauté peppers and onions until soft
Add black beans, corn and salsa
Add in garlic, chili powder cumin, and salt and pepper to taste.
Add rice and cook for 5 more minutes.
Soften tortillas in microwave (approx 20 seconds).
Fill tortillas with the cooked mixture, roll (or turn in sides) and place in a glass baking dish.
Top with Salsa.
Bake at 375 degrees for 40 minutes.
Uncover, add cheese on top of salsa and bake additional 5 minutes.
 
 →2 Comments 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 Who’s listening? 
 Posted on July 2, 2010 | 2 Comments 
Hello, is there anybody out there? Just nod if you can hear me…..

Pink Floyd never had it so right. As I sit here typing away feverishly at my computer I wonder if anyone is listening. In reality it’s ok if no one is. I started all this as my own little version of an online cookbook/diary/sense of self wittiness. Really, I did. I wanted an easy place to look for all of my recipes, especially the ones I turn to all the time.

You’d understand if you ever saw my cookbook cupboard- yep, it’s a whole cupboard. I love, no I LOVE, cookbooks. I don’t know if it’s the beautiful pictures or the promise of something wonderful hitting my taste buds, but I love to have a new cookbook in my hot little hand. I also love to scour the internet for recipes that use the ingredient de jour, aka whatever I’m craving at that moment. So this cupboard, it’s stuffed with random papers, pretty cookbooks, gifted cookbooks, scraps of recipes and magazine clippings. I needed some organization.

Most people at this point in time would recommend one recipe book, or a recipe box. But the only thing worse than my budgeting skills is my penmanship. I really don’t know what happened. Ms. Robins thought I had beautiful handwriting and even gave me two gold stars in the second grade. But by the time third grade came around I was a mess. So messy I was destined to become a doctor. Sometimes I can’t even read my own handwriting.

I think it’s because most of the time my mind works faster than my hands, which today they would probably call ADHD but I call it creativity. I think I wanted my hand to keep up and therefore neat handwriting went completely out the window. I don’t mind unless I’m trying to write a card or thank you note to someone. I’ve actually had to ask my co-worker to write the notes for me before. Sigh.

On the other hand, Katie- what? You don’t know Katie by now? She’s my cooking, fashion, music and penmanship guru- Katie has the most beautiful handwriting. She once was even tapped for a Microsoft office font. So in my dreaming glory I have always imagined a beautiful recipe book with Katie’s flawless inscriptions of the most delicious recipes. But it all goes back to being cheap- I don’t want to pay her to do that for me. And I know she loves me, but she certainly doesn’t have time to do that for free.

That’s what brought us here, to this long winded story. I needed a place that I could gather my recipes and read my own handwriting. I never really expected other people to care what I had to say, but the “wants to be a popular 8th grader” in me still exists and I guess it would be kind of nice to know that someone, somewhere out there (Feivel?), is listening.

So are you?
 
 →2 Comments 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 Start Your Day Right 
 Posted on June 21, 2010 | Leave a comment 
 There is no better meal than breakfast, to me. Correction, there is no better meal cooked by someone else, than breakfast, to me.  If give the option I would choose to go out to breakfast over dinner any day. I’m not sure if it’s because the selection of breakfast menu items supersedes anything I make at home, or if it’s the idea of starting the day off with friends and good food. Whatever it is, I’m a sucker for breakfast.

Ironically I’ve never been a good breakfast eater during the week. I’ve heard the facts that say breakfast is the most important meal of the day, and I know that eating early in the day speeds up your metabolism. But for me eating breakfast seems to just make me hungrier. If I eat a bowl of cereal at 8 am, I’m hungry by 9 am. Therefore, when I eat breakfast I find myself eating 10 meals throughout the day, just to quench my new hunger.

My lack of breakfast is also due to my poor meal planning first thing in the morning. When I go grocery shopping I’m great at planning out my lunches and dinners for the next two weeks, but for some reason I always seem to forget breakfast items. They then become an after thought as I’m heading towards the checkout stand at the store. Sometimes I’ll grab some bagels, but forget cream cheese, or I’ll buy cereal and no milk. Once I even bought a massive 32 pack of yogurt from Costco so that I wouldn’t have to remember to buy breakfast for a month. Let me tell you, the convenience was not worth it. By the 10 th day I never wanted to see another peach yogurt again. A little variety would have been helpful.

All that being said, I finally caved to the importance of breakfast. This month is Bike to Work Month in my town. I look at this challenge as a benefit for me in multiple ways. First I save gas (extra money is always good!), next I’m getting exercise, and finally I’m helping the environment. All good reasons to drag my slow butt up the mountain that stands between my house and my office. At first the challenge completely kicked my @#%^&amp;*.  But then I started to realize if I drank more water first thing in the morning I had more energy. Then I realized if I actually ate breakfast, and ate something with substance, I could really make it up that hill.  Slowly but surely I have gotten into the routine of waking up a little bit early and making breakfast before heading into work.

So now my dilemma is keeping breakfast at home different and exciting. The good news is I finally have an excuse to use the lifetime supply of Bisquick I once bought. The bad news is pancakes just taste gross after three days in a row. So I looked in my fridge, grabbed the most random ingredients I could find and wound up discovering my new favorite breakfast treat.

The variety of possibilities are endless, that’s what makes this pancake recipe great. So go for it, find a fruit, or two or three, and mix it in and make your kind of pancakes.

 Ricotta Pancakes 

 1 cup of Bisquick mix
½ cup of milk
1 egg
¼- ½ cup of Ricotta Cheese (depending on your taste)
Fruit (I started with dried cranberries the first time and fresh strawberries the second. Both were amazing).

 Mix the egg, milk and cheese in a large mixing bowl. Add in Bisquick. Add additional mix as necessary. (the mixture will be thicker the more cheese you use).

Add in fruit and mix well.

Scoop out pancakes in whatever size or style you like (I’m a small, Mickey Mouse pancake kind of girl).

When ready you can top pancakes with butter, syrup, powdered sugar or whip cream. I like whip cream best!
 
 →Leave a comment 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 My Dish 
 Posted on June 15, 2010 | 1 Comment 
 This is the one, the one that defines me. That my kids one day will say “this was my mother’s recipes, her signature recipe.” The one recipe I can mess around with, add a dash of this, a pinch of that. The recipe I can play with to no end and still love. It always evolves and I love that it’s so versatile yet so easy. And did I mention yummy?

I’m a stuffed person. Yes, I’m usually stuffing my stomach with something, but that’s not what I mean in this case. I mean, I’m a fan of items that are stuffed. Stuffed Cabbage, Stuffing, stuffed tomatoes, turkducken. The more things packed in there, the better. Therefore, it should come as no surprise one of my all-time favorite recipes is for stuffed peppers.

The obsession began long ago in my youth. The same youth I mentioned in my first blog. The youth filled with TV Dinners, which proved more integral in my upbringing than one can imagine. Once a week my mother would invite me (drag me? What’s the difference?) to the supermarket to help her shop. And by help her, I mean walk quietly next to the cart and wait for the moment she asked if I wanted seltzer or lemon flavored seltzer…. Until we got to the frozen food isle. This was my heaven. My mother would let me pick out a few options that would be served as dinner for the week.

After trying frozen chicken tenders and soggy burritos I found the glory that is Stouffer’s Stuffed Peppers. Oh happy day! After this earth-shattering discovery the hardest decisions I had to make was one pepper or two, and do you eat directly from the plastic provided or move the meal to a real dish (risking the loss of precious tomato sauce).

I loved those stuffed peppers. I ate them all through college and into adulthood. Up until finding this recipe for stuffed peppers I could still be found reheating the red-box delight at work. And even today when I’m tight on time and need to grab a quick lunch from the supermarket, I go straight to Stouffer’s Stuffed Peppers.

The beauty of this recipe is its versatility. Personally, I’m a meat girl. But I’ve made a vegetarian version with extra veggies and lentils. I’ve also done ground turkey instead of beef and never been the wiser. It all tastes good. The peppers can be basic or dressed up for a dinner party. It’s that easy.

Okay, I gotta go make stuffed peppers, my mouth is literally watering.

 Stuffed Peppers 

 4 peppers (green, red, yellow or orange) with flat bottoms
1 package brown rice (boil in the bag)
2 additional peppers: red, yellow or orange diced
1 medium yellow onion diced
1 clove of garlic minced
salt and pepper
1 pound ground beef
2 8oz can of tomato sauce
Cheese

Preheat Oven to 375 degrees

 Cut the tops off the 4 peppers to be filled. (I dice up the cut off tops to add to the filling mixture). Remove the insides and place peppers in a medium pot filled with water. Boil until peppers are soft, but still durable. When peppers are done cooking set them in a small cooking dish. Use the same water to cook rice.

At the same time, brown ground beef in a large skillet. Drain grease.

Add peppers and onion and sauté until onions are soft.

Add garlic, salt and pepper to taste.

Add cooked rice and 8 oz of tomato sauce.

Cook on medium heat for approx. 5 minutes.

Spoon mixture into peppers. Add remaining mixture to the bottom of the cooking dish. Top with additional tomato sauce.

Bake for 30-35 minutes.

Add cheese topping to peppers if you wish and cook for an additional 4 minutes. 
 
 →1 Comment 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 The First Date Dish 
 Posted on June 9, 2010 | 1 Comment 
I spent the bulk of my early twenties in a relationship with a great guy who most certainly knew his way around the kitchen. When the relationship ended, I realized I didn’t have much culinary pizzazz to bring to the dating world. I was ok with this as I went off in search of a new boyfriend who could cook up a storm. When I met the next boyfriend-to-be it was all peachy-keen until he suggested for dinner one night, “I’ll bring the wine, if you cook.”

“Sure,” I said, having no clue what I just committed to. I needed a recipe that was easy and quick (I didn’t have a world of time) and something that would make him think I knew anything about cooking.

I called my older sister in desperation. Keep in mind my sister grew up in the same household I did. We consider family recipes to be the “hot dog dish” (don’t ask, you don’t want to know) and spaghetti. But I thought being the older, wiser sister she might know a good trick. And boy did she ever.

I whipped up her quick recipe for feta stuffed chicken and it looked like I slaved all day. The boyfriend-to-be was so impressed he stuck around for a while. Luckily he was adventurous both in our relationship and in the cooking that I served him during the relationship. Which gave me the confidence to continue to try new recipes.

They say you learn something new in each relationship, and I say you learn new recipes in each new relationship. But here’s the one that started them all.

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 
Mallary’s Stuffed Chicken 
4 chicken breasts
1 package of feta cheese*
1 egg
Seasoned bread crumbs
1 package fresh Spinach
Strawberries (thinly sliced) or blueberries

Pre heat oven to 325 degrees

Crack the egg in a bowl with a wide bottom (Tupperware works great) and whip egg

Pour bread crumbs in a bowl with a wide bottom

Pound the chicken breasts with a meat tenderizer until flat, usually doubling the size of the original breast.

Dip the chicken in the egg then dip the chicken in the bread crumbs. Lay on a baking sheet.

Layer feta on one side of the chicken breast and fold over the other side to cover the feta. Repeat with additional chicken breasts.

Bake for 25 minutes.

 Combine spinach and fruit with a light drizzle of vinaigrette. Put combination on a plate or wide-bottom bowl. Top with Chicken and serve.

 

*Often times I’ll buy Feta with additional spices and flavors mixed in, or I’ll add my own like basil, sage, roasted red peppers, etc
 
 →1 Comment 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 ← Older posts 
 
Search It!
 Search for: 
Recent Entries

 Pop Tart Ode to the Falafel Living on the Edge (of a budget) Who’s listening? Start Your Day Right My Dish The First Date Dish The Cherries Epiphany A Sweet Tooth Paying Homage 
 
Links

 Cake=Happiness Dine and Dish 
 
 The Basic Chef Blog at WordPress.com .
 Theme: Coraline . Theme: Coraline by Automattic . Blog at WordPress.com . Follow 
 Follow“The Basic Chef” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com Add your thoughts here... (optional) Post to or Cancel
	</body>
</document>
