<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009060" url="http://www.dailyfinance.com/2008/11/18/santas-bringing-a-gas-gift-card-this-year-oh-joy-of-the-seaso/" time="2012-07-13-02:27" support="2" score="0.0025261966526068024" bingtitle="Santa&apos;s bringing a gas gift card this year - oh joy of the season ..." webtitle="Santa&apos;s bringing a gas gift card this year - oh joy of the season! - DailyFinance">
			<query id="000576" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="001299" bing-rank="244"/>
	<description>... your Christmas stocking to see what Santa put ... Nothing like getting a fast-food restaurant gift card under the ... However, some credit-card branded gift cards, such as ...</description>
	<body>
		AOL MAIL 
 You might also like:  AOL Jobs ,  AOL Real Estate  and  More 
 


 DailyFinance 
 Home Saving 
 Savings Experiment Consumer Ally Economizer Family Money College Finance Fantastic Freebies 
 Spending 
 Credit Cards Credit Reports Debt Retail Technology 
 Investing Planning 
 Power of Planning Retirement IRA Center Calculators Insurance Banking 
 Taxes 
 Tax Center Tax Tools&amp;Resources 
 Jobs 
 Search Jobs Get Career Advice 
 Real Estate 
 Homes for Sale Mortgages 
 Questions or Feedback ? 
 
Santa&apos;s bringing a gas gift card this year - oh joy of the season!
 By Aaron Crowe Posted 9:00AM 11/18/08 Posted under: Relationships , Economy , Credit , Economizer , Personal Finance Share 
 Imagine it&apos;s Christmas morning. You rush downstairs and first check your Christmas stocking to see what Santa put inside -- a gasoline gift card. Surprise! Merry Christmas!

In what is now an ongoing joke in my household, I buy my wife a $10 Christmas gift card at one of the finer stores in town: Longs, Safeway, McDonald&apos;s or Burger King. I see practicality, she sees a cheapskate. Now, with the economy in a recession, it looks like more people are coming around to the practical view, despite the lack of Christmas morning excitement they produce.

This holiday season, more gift card recipients plan to use them for necessities and not on luxuries, according to a new study released by Bankrate, Inc.








However, fewer people plan on buying gift cards this year, the study found. According to an Archstone Consulting survey, Americans will spend $25 billion on gift cards, down 25% from 2007.

Gift card sales are expected to dip with the economy, said Lauren Coady, manager of consumer research at National Research Network, which conducted a 2008 gift card trends survey with The Harman Group. &quot;Overall, 60% are still planning to purchase at least one gift card this holiday season,&quot; Coady said in the press release. &quot;But roughly one-third of consumers are planning to buy fewer gift cards and/or spend less on gift cards this holiday season due to the current economic situation.&quot;

The study also found that nearly a third of gift card recipients tend to redeem them on necessities. Nothing like getting a fast-food restaurant gift card under the tree, right? Instead of Neiman Marcus and Bloomingdale&apos;s, discount stores like Costco and Wal-Mart are likely to see increases in gift card sales.

Everyone enjoys unwrapping that special Christmas present under the tree, but for the perfect gift that you can&apos;t find, a gift card can&apos;t be beat. While maybe a little impersonal -- OK, a lot impersonal -- gift cards take the anxiety out of choosing a gift and let the receiver pick what they really want. They are popular. Fifty-five percent of consumers told the National Retail Federation they want to receive gift cards this holiday season -- more than any other type of gift.

Gift cards used to commonly have expiration dates, but many retailers have gotten rid of that hassle. However, some credit-card branded gift cards, such as for Visa and American Express, charge a monthly service fee if they haven&apos;t been used in 12 months. The credit card gift cards also charge fees from $3.95 to $4.95 to use them.

 Aaron Crowe is an unemployed journalist in the San Francisco Bay Area. Read about his job hunt at www.talesofanunemployeddad.blogspot.com 

 
From Our Partners:
 Last-Minute Holiday Festivity! - AOL Real Estate Xmas is for Tree Lovers, not Tree Killers - AOL Real Estate Three Perfect Holiday Hostess Gifts - AOL Real Estate U.S. Incomes Surge 0.5% In December, Though Consumer Spending Was Flat - AOL Jobs 7 Job Search Lessons Learned From Santa Claus - AOL Jobs 8 Last-Minute Holiday Gifts for Job Seekers - AOL Jobs 
More On DailyFinance:
 Target and Neiman Marcus, an Odd Fashion Pairing? Not At All Christmas in June: A Sneak Peek at 2012&apos;s Hot Holiday Houseware Gifts 
 Tagged: christmas , christmas gifts , christmas shopping , ChristmasGifts , ChristmasShopping , gift , gift card , gift cards , GiftCard , GiftCards , gifts 
 Share Getty Images 
 CLOSER TO A BAILOUT? FHA&apos;s Mortgage Delinquencies Soar - CNNMoney Dimon Faces Round Two Before Congress - FOXBusiness HEALTH CARE REFORM: 5 Investing Scenarios of Obamacare Ruling - InvestorPlace The Biggest Sign of a China Bubble - The Motley Fool THE FED&apos;S SUMMER SEQUEL: Operation Twist 2 - IBTimes How to Stomp Out Pesky Travel Fees - CBS MoneyWatch FedEx Earnings Don&apos;t Deliver - 24/7 Wall St. 
 
Add a Comment
 Sign in» Add a Comment Type your comment here *0 / 3000 Character Maximum Submit 
 manage My Portfolios


 Track Your Investments Here! 
See why so many people use the DailyFinance portfolio tool as the cornerstone of their investing strategy.
 Sign In or Register Now advertisement 
Most Popular Stories

 1 
 New McDonald&apos;s CEO&apos;s Grand Plan Involves a Lot of Chicken 
 2 
 Brides Say &apos;Yes&apos; to Selling Their Dress ... Before the Wedding! 
 3 
 Get the Best Bargain on Perfect Pillows -- Savings Experiment 
 4 
 The LIBOR Scandal Explained in One Simple Infographic 
 5 
 Ousted Duke Energy CEO Earns Up to $44.4 Million for a Few Hours Work 
 
 
DailyFinance Wire

 Merchants May Win the Right to Charge Credit Card Users More A Farewell to Marvin Traub: The Retail Genius Who Changed How You Shop Olympic Chief Bites Tongue on McDonalds, Coke Sponsorships 8 Things to Never Keep in Your Wallet 8 Signs Your Identity Has Been Compromised Listen Up, Ladies: Tips for Closing the Financial Gender Gap New Jobless Claims Fall Sharply to Four-Year Low 
 More DailyFinance Stories 
Newswire
 AP CNN 24/7 WallSt 
 China&apos;s economic slowdown painful despite... Appeals court tosses antitrust claim over ATM... Possible pilot shortage raises safety concerns Summary Box: Yahoo shareholders grill interim... All eyes on JPMorgan as banks report earnings Ex-investigators for HP sentenced in fraud case Stocks slide on Wall Street for sixth straight... 
 
 Young dad, $15,000 in credit card debt 30-year mortgage rate falls to record 3.56% Why health care costs keep rising 700,000 homeowners no longer underwater New foreclosures jump 9% in second quarter $400,000 portfolio, too many holdings Homes lost for as little as $400 in back taxes 3 tuition bills, only $35,000 saved 
 More from CNNMoney 
 24/7 Wall St. Closing Bell — July 12, 2012: Markets Continue Slide on No Signs of Easing Cheniere Lands $3.4 Billion Credit Facility to Build Natural Gas Export Facility US Drought Worsens Despite Some Rain Gambling Revenues Continue to Fall in Nevada Can Activist Investors Fix Procter&amp;Gamble? Take A Poll!!! Groupon Shareholders Stuck Where They Are, CEO&amp;All Boeing Gets Order for 150 Planes from United Groupon, Zynga at Post-IPO Lows 
 More from 24/7 Wall St. 
Follow Us

 Facebook Twitter RSS To Go 
 
Compare Mortgage Rates
 Mortgage Rates by Zillow 
Headlines From DailyFinance Partners
 
 BEWARE JPMORGAN&apos;S PROFIT Stocks falter on global growth fears,... Wells Fargo in $175M unfair lending... 
 More CNNMoney.com 
 Sale considered of ING Japanese unit Yahoo acknowledges attack by hackers Peregrine probe eyes accounts in Iowa 
 More Financial Times 
 Markets Await JPMorgan &apos;Whale&apos; Report,... More Americans Think Rich Deserve Their... No Sign of a China Hard-Landing: Rattner 
 More from CNBC.com 
 5 Reasons China&apos;s Problems Signal... Why It Pays to Delay Social Security The Case for European Blue Chips 
 More at SmartMoney 
 Five Steps to Effective Investing as a... Estimate Cost of Utilities on Your Next... Blah Job Stats Deliver Lovely Mortgage... 
 More Fox Business 
 How to stop unwanted robocalls Consumer Reports Index: Americans... Who serves the best pancakes? 
 More from Consumer Reports 
 
 WATCH: Bay Area Startup Culture Spoofed... Company PAYS You To Go On Vacation...A... Mitt Romney&apos;s Own 2002 Testimony... 
 More from Huffington Post 
 Big Oil Sees Big Growth for Renewable... 2012 Maryland Clean Energy Summit Don&apos;t Ban Coal for Electricity... 
 More from AOL Energy 
 Peyton Manning&apos;s $5 Million Denver... Wells Fargo to Pay $125 Million to... David Hoffman of Marin County, Calif.,... 
 More from AOL Real Estate 
 Ex-Wet Seal Managers Claim The Company... Yoga Teacher Gets Fired After Glaring... Customer Service Rep Allegedly Tells... 
 More from AOL Jobs 
 DailyFinance 
Business News

 Main Autos Books Charity Columns Crime Food Green Media People Travel Jobs Real Estate 
 
Personal Finance

 Debt Insurance Credit College Finance Retirement Recalls Taxes 
 
Investing

 Portfolios Media Credit Stocks in the News ETF&apos;s Earnings 
 
Our Partners

 Tech News Small Business Real Estate 24/7 Wall St Autoblog 
 
 DailyFinance Sitemap | Terms of Service | Privacy Policy | Trademarks | HELP | Advertise With Us 

©Copyright 2012 AOL Inc. All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
