<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009082" url="http://www.smh.com.au/news/sport/cricket/kfc-cricket-sponsorship-must-end/2008/10/05/1223145162618.html" time="2012-07-13-02:28" support="1" score="0.000897605200220731" bingtitle="KFC sponsorship of cricket must end: obesity experts - Cricket - Sport" webtitle="KFC sponsorship of cricket must end: obesity experts - Cricket - Sport">
			<query id="001462" bing-rank="75"/>
	<description>The chain has been the official fast food restaurant for the sport ... Caterson say the sponsorship relationship must end. ... our cars are made; Find us on Facebook; Sell your car ...</description>
	<body>
		The Sydney Morning Herald: national, world, business, entertainment, sport and technology news from Australia&apos;s leading newspaper. 
Skip directly to: Search Box , Section Navigation , Content . Text Version .
 NEWS | JOBS | REAL ESTATE | CARS | FINANCE | MOBILE | DATING | TRAVEL | WEATHER 
   network map | member centre   
 
 The Sydney Morning Herald: national, world, business, entertainment, sport and technology news from Australia&apos;s leading newspaper. 

 The Sydney Morning Herald: national, world, business, entertainment, sport and technology news from Australia&apos;s leading newspaper. 
 
 NRL 
 League HQ NRL News Ladder Fixtures Experts Clubs Tipping Sin Bin Origin 
 Union 
 Rugby Heaven News Super 14 Tri Nations Six Nations Clubs&amp;Provincial International Calendar Experts Rugby Blog 
 Beijing Olympics Cricket AFL 
 Real Footy AFL News Ladder Fixtures Experts Clubs Tipping Footy Talk 
 Football Horse Racing Golf Motorsport Swimming Tennis Basketball 
 
 You are here: Home » Sport » Cricket Show site sections 
 
Search smh:
 
 KFC sponsorship of cricket must end: obesity experts 
 
 Email Printer friendly version Normal font Large font 
 October 5, 2008 - 6:24PM 
 
Obesity experts have called on Cricket Australia to end its
sponsorship deal with the fried chicken chain KFC, saying the
relationship is &quot;unhelpful and irresponsible&quot; during a childhood
obesity epidemic.

Specialists at the University of Sydney&apos;s Institute of Nutrition
Obesity and Exercise say they were alarmed during the last
Australian cricket season to see Australian cricket players
prominently badged with the logo of KFC and heavy advertising of
KFC products.

The chain has been the official fast food restaurant for the
sport since 2003.

But Professor Stephen Colagiuri and Professor Ian Caterson say
the sponsorship relationship must end.

&quot;We are increasingly concerned and disappointed that Cricket
Australia has a sponsorship agreement with, and consequently
promotes, KFC,&quot; the specialists wrote in the latest Medical Journal
of Australia.

&quot;This advertising uses the standing of cricket and its players
to endorse and promote unhealthy eating habits, one of the major
root causes of obesity in Australia.&quot;

The nation&apos;s most comprehensive childhood obesity survey, now
more than a decade old, estimated 21 per cent of children and
adolescents were either overweight or obese, but it is believed the
figures have climbed steeply since then.

Prof Caterson said this had led to an &quot;explosion&quot; of obesity
related illness, like diabetes, and left no place for what he
called the &quot;enthusiastic encouragement of unhealthy and undesirable
eating habits&quot;.

&quot;It is ironic that Cricket Australia, while having done so much
for the sport, regrettably encourages the promotion of unhealthy,
high fat, high calorie KFC products which more than negate any
benefit of the increased physical activity associated with playing
cricket,&quot; he said.

&quot;Cricket Australia should consider its responsibilities to
Australia&apos;s children and youth and review its sponsorship by KFC
... to benefit the health of the community and demonstrate
leadership and social responsibility by Cricket Australia and
Australia&apos;s elite cricketers.&quot;

But Cricket Australia corporate spokesman Peter Young said
telling children they could not have KFC was not going to help in
encouraging them to have a balanced, healthy lifestyle.

&quot;As far as convenience food or fast food is concerned, our view
is everything in moderation,&quot; he told AAP.

&quot;As long as consumers take that approach and have an active
lifestyle with a balanced approach to life and a balanced approach
to nutrition, then we should be on track to having better national
health rather than worse national health.&quot;

Mr Young said KFC helped the organisation deliver its programs,
including In2Cricket, a major new initiative to get children
involved in the sport and get active.

&quot;Australia has got the least physically active kids in the world
and that&apos;s an issue for sport as well as for national health,&quot; he
said.

&quot;We&apos;re grateful to KFC for the financial support they provide to
cricket.

&quot;It helps keep cricket in the playgrounds, on the ovals and at
an elite level in the field internationally.&quot;

 AAP 
 
 
 
 Email Print this story Normal font Large font 
 
 Add to Facebook Add to del.icio.us Digg this story RSS Feed 
 When news happens: 
send photos, videos&amp;tip-offs to 0424 SMS SMH (+61 424 767 764), or us.
 
 Did you know you could pay less than $1 a day for a subscription to the Herald? Subscribe today. 
 1223145162618-smh.com.au http://www.smh.com.au/news/sport/cricket/kfc-sponsorship-of-cricket-must-end-obesity-experts/2008/10/05/1223145162618.html smh.com.au AAP 2008-10-05 KFC sponsorship of cricket must end: obesity experts Sport Cricket 
TODAY&apos;S TOP 10 ARTICLES

 Ponting warns Afridi - and Strauss The Geale deal adds power to his smart glovework Elena bursts Venus vanquisher&apos;s bubble Cassidy plans operations to end the pain Death by a single cut: Williams sent packing 

 More most viewed articles 
 
 Motoring 
 
 10 things to look for in a new car 
 
 Drive.com.au World&apos;s Fastest Wagon Find us on Facebook Sell your car easily 
 
 Jobs 
 
 Personalise your job search with MyCareer 
 
 Mycareer.com.au Sign up to the new MyCareer Don&apos;t miss the latest jobs. 1000&apos;s of jobs in Australia 
 
 Real Estate 
 
 Renovating bit by bit 
 
 Domain.com.au Buy real estate Plan your property inspections Nice house - can you afford it? 
 
 Managed Funds 
 
 Most Popular Investment Funds 
 
 Managed funds, shares... Find a managed fund FREE investment newsletter 
 
 TheVine 
 
 Adriana Lima looks hot in Vogue 
 
 thevine.com.au TheVine Radio Player Review: Prince of Persia SJP hearts Bassike 
 
 SMH Home National World Opinion Business Technology Sport Entertainment Life&amp;Style Travel Weather 
 Copyright©2008 Fairfax Digital 
 National Breaking News Obituaries Special Reports News Video 

 World Breaking News Environment Snapshots Strange but true News Video 

 Opinion Blogs Column 8 Letters Stay in touch 

 Business Breaking News Executive Style Personal Finance Portfolio Quotes Share Market Data Small Business 

 Technology @ Home Breaking News Biz Tech Connectivity Gadgets Games Security Tech Tips 

 Sport AFL (Realfooty) Breaking News Cricket Football Golf Horse Racing Motorsport NRL (League HQ) Swimming Tennis Union (Rugby Heaven) 

 Entertainment Arts Books Film Good Living Cuisine Music TV&amp;Radio What&apos;s On City Guide 

 Life&amp;Style Beauty Bridal Diet Fashion Health House&amp;Home Parenting People Pets Relationships Drive Life Design 

 Travel Australia Activities&amp;Interests Deals&amp;Bookings Short Breaks World 

 Weather Local (Sydney) State (NSW/ACT) Australia World Marine Snow (Perisher) 
 
 OTHER SECTIONS: Adonline Crosswords Education Notices Photo Galleries Sun Herald Video CLASSIFIEDS: Announcements Accommodation (Stayz) Cars&amp;Bikes (Drive) Dating (RSVP) Jobs (MyCareer) Real Estate (Domain) Other Classifieds Place an Ad 

 SERVICES: About SMH Advertise with Us Contact Us Events&amp;Charity Law Notices Member Centre News Archive Network Map Overseas Sales Photo Sales Sitemap SMH Shop Subscriptions Property Data (APM)
	</body>
</document>
