<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009362" url="http://www.chefbecky.com/testimonials.htm" time="2012-07-13-02:43" support="1" score="0.0013199307418128676" bingtitle="Chef Becky - Testimonials" webtitle="Chef Becky - Testimonials">
			<query id="001444" bing-rank="241"/>
	<description>... just exactly what you want at the end of a ... dieter to go into a convenience store or fast food restaurant and find ... you could probably tell from the info on my food ...</description>
	<body>
		Client Testimonials for: Catering Service | Personal Chef Service 
 I no longer cater events. I decided to discontinue the catering side of my business to focus on my daughter and family. 
Chef Beckys Mission: Create full-fledged meals within our budget for a film crew of over 50 hardworking&amp;hungry people, six-days-a-week for an entire month. The crew had diverse tastes consisting of; meat eaters, vegetarians, vegans, special dietary needs, food allergy specific individualsthen have it all arrive at a precise time, piping hot&amp;tasting great, at locations such as Thompsons Mill in Shedd @ 1am on one day and the Covered Bridge in Fall Creek @ 4pm the next.
Mission Completed! Chef Becky came through for us and then some. I would highly recommend her services for any occasion and the next time I shoot a film in Eugene I know who Im calling for catering. Chef Becky is the BEST!
 Brian Cooper 
Line Producer
Symbolic Entertainment 
Out of all the catered meals Ive ever ordered, I always get the MOST compliments from Beckys potato salad!! It is out of this world!
 Mary Stringfield 
Molecular Probes 
Chef Becky has catered several occasions for me and I could not be more pleased with the food and service. First she did a bridal shower which was a wonderful buffet. Next she supplied me with 3 days of meals for 15 house guests. All the meals were delicious and each one a little unique. She had also cooked on location, doing a BBQ for 60 guests. It was great not to have to worry about the food!
 Renee&apos; Pokvitis 
 
I want to take a moment to thank and commend you for the fine catering job you did for me at my listing at 677 Spyglass Drive. I cant tell you how many positive responses I received from the more than 50 persons who toured the house that day. They were especially pleased with the menu offered and the quality of the food available. I will strongly recommend your services to others who are in need of a quality and affordable caterer. Oh, and by the way, we had an offer to purchase that home, which was priced at over $620,000 within 3 days after our event. Coincidence? I dont think so. Thank you so much.
 Don Mogenson 
Curtis Irving Realty 
Chef Becky was contracted to provide a morning brunch buffet for 90 people for a wedding at our home. Becky came to our home to survey the layout weeks before the event, and advised us of what space she needed. The morning of the wedding, Chef Becky and her helper were prompt, calm, quiet, and efficient. We hardly knew she was there. Everyone remarked on how wonderful everything looked and tasted. Chef Beckys cleanup was amazing. She left absolutely no trace that she had ever been here. We found her to be excellent and reasonable, and would hire her again in a heartbeat.
 Elle Meierotto and Candace Luis 
Chef Becky is the best chef in town!!
 Kellie Chambers 
Thank you for the wonderful job you did in catering Megans wedding brunch. Clearly, I would not have made it without you. The food was deliciouseveryone raved. Your quiet and calm organization set the tone. We are grateful for your help.
 Judy&amp;Gil James 
We would like to give you heartfelt thanks for your efforts on our behalf. We have had numerous compliments from our guests regarding your work. We were able to enjoy our wedding brunch as if we were guests. We cant imagine anyone doing a better job. Keep up the good work!
 Joseph&amp;Lydia McKinney 
Oregon Roads 
Our guests praised the food repeatedly. And Becky was a pleasure to work with: easy going, professional, flexible, and unobtrusive. I didn&apos;t worry about the catering at all; Becky took care of it, and helped out above and beyond. Our Middle-Eastern style vegetarian wedding buffet was a great success. Thank you!
 John&amp;Julia Christensen 
You did a great job catering our event last Friday. I really appreciate your expertise. The food was very good and I heard lots of positive remarks from the guests. Thank you so much!
 Vicki Simrell 
Alterations by Vicki 
 Client Testimonials for: Personal Chef Service | Catering Service 
Just to let you know... the Caribbean Mango Tilapia was outstanding! In fact, we were all fighting for the last piece.
The Meatloaf and the Low Carb Pork Chops with Mustard Cream Sauce were spectacular, again... fighting for the last bite!
YUMMY! Keep it coming!
 Charlene Engelmann 
For nearly a year now, Becky has been cooking for us. It started with some help at Thanksgiving and grew from there. She runs a very professional business, really gets to know her customers, learns their likes and dislikes and boy oh boy, can she cook! If you love to eat, but don&apos;t necessarily love to cook, Chef Becky is a godsend. I highly recommend her services.
 Duane&amp;David Funk 
Funk&amp;Associates 
Our children gave us a gift certificate for Chef Becky last Christmas. We have been enjoying the meals ever since! Chef Becky&apos;s entrees are tasty, unique, and easy to prepare - just exactly what you want at the end of a busy day. We look forward to each new dinner - always a treat!
 Chuck and Sue Kesey 
Springfield Creamery 
Chef Becky has been a God send for our family. It&apos;s great that she makes kid friendly dishes for our children. She meets everyone&apos;s special diet needs despite what diet restrictions they may have. We had Chef Becky come to our home on Mother&apos;s day and she prepared the most amazing meal, my family is still talking about it. With all the chaotic schedules at our home we can always pull something out of the freezer for breakfast, lunch or dinner. Chef Becky is the best!
 Kathy&amp;Dr. Scott Kitchel 
Oregon Spine Associates 
We are very pleased with our service from Chef Becky. She has been especially accommodating with my special dietary needs. Not only did she research my condition, but she also shopped and experimented with recipes that would suit my needs. All of the food has been delicious and easy to prepare. I love our &quot;Chef Becky&quot; nights because it gives me a free evening while still providing the family with a great meal!
 Diza and Dave Hilles 
Chambers Construction 
My schedule was filled with too many demands and too little time when I met Chef Becky. A friend who had been to a luncheon she prepared referred me to her service. Now I am a regular client. Becky prepares delicious gourmet meals. It&apos;s a pleasure to know there is always have something easy to prepare and good to eat waiting for me when I get home.
 Ann Maxwell 
Thank you for all of the wonderful food over the last two months. I was pleasantly surprised by my husband when he told me that he found you and that you would be preparing great meals and delivering them to us while I was recovering from childbirth.
I love your detailed food questionnaire because it takes into account food dislikes and allergies for everyone in the family. Your meals are so nicely packaged and labeled. Dinnertime has been a joy! Victors favorite was the shrimp risotto; mine were the sesame crusted ahi tuna with wasabi mayonnaise, ginger beef stir-fry, southwest turkey chili, and the pork chops with mustard cream sauce.
We would gladly recommend your services to anyone. Its evident that you take a lot of care in your planning and preparation. We definitely appreciate it.
 Pamela Quan and Dr. Victor Lin 
For the last six months, I have been following the Atkins diet with help from Chef Becky. Before using her service, I had attempted the diet, but found it too difficult to continue. It is impossible for the Atkins dieter to go into a convenience store or fast food restaurant and find safe low carb foods. Everything is loaded with starch and sugar. I have been using Chef Beckys low-carb meals with great success. I keep a supply of meals in my freezer at work, so I know that I wont have to go out and cheat on my diet by ordering fast food. The great variety of tasty meals makes it very easy to stay on my diet. Thank you Becky!!
 Craig Matthew 
Action Automotive 
The idea that the only thing I have to do for dinner is turn on the oven has brought me such peace I can&apos;t even tell you!
As you could probably tell from the info on my food questionnaire, I am super picky. I think your enchiladas are perfect! Crunchy where they should be, just the right amount of flavor...wonderful! I&apos;m hardly ever satisfied with other people&apos;s cooking, so this is huge! I had the Coq au Vin last night...wonderful!!! I gave my daughter her plate and she looked at it like it was moving (she&apos;s 6...) and said she didn&apos;t want it. She made a huge stink about it! I told her to try it first, a couple of minutes later it was gone and she was going crazy about how delicious it was! She is even pickier than I am so this is huge!
We just adore your food and service! You have two devotees! Thank you! Keep up the awesome work!
 Chris&amp;Andrea Bones 
The service from Chef Becky has been a welcome relief in our household. We found that having a nutritious gourmet meal ready to put in the microwave or oven immediately when we arrived home, not only saved time and energy, but also was more affordable than eating out.
 Jeanne and Doug Harcleroad 
Lane County District Attorney 
I just have to let you know what I think of your crab lasagna, which is what we had for dinner last night, with the green salad. The crab lasagna was to die for. I don&apos;t know when I&apos;ve eaten something I liked as well. It was WONDERFUL! Thanks for your hard work on the food. If it&apos;s all as good as the lasagna, we are in for a real treat.
I longed for another dish of the lasagna, so had a dish of it at 10:30 this morning and just now had another for lunch. I guess that confirms that I really, really liked it.
 Lois Dillon 
McClure Associates 
 
 
 

 

 Web Design by Feynman Group 
 Site Developer : PRISE design GROUP : prisedesign.com
	</body>
</document>
