<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009707" url="http://bedandbreakfastantwerp.com/" time="2012-07-13-03:05" support="1" score="0.00040418809502017325" bingtitle="bedandbreakfastantwerp" webtitle="Bed and Breakfast Antwerp">
			<query id="000869" bing-rank="225"/>
	<description>A deluxe breakfast from your local fast food restaurant can ... Having considered the fact that eating healthy breakfast meals is a ... 1 cup rolled oats 1 1/2 cups water 1/2 cup ...</description>
	<body>
		Bed and Breakfast Antwerp 
 Skip to content 
 Home Breakfast and Amenities 
 
 How To Discover A Bed And Breakfast Beechworth 
 Posted on March 18, 2011 by admin 
There are many perks to staying in a bed and breakfast Beechworth. These places are warm and cozy and will feature some of the element of home. Situated in quiet neighborhoods, there is a lot to gain out of a vacation in a place like this. There are different prices and packages that can make these places affordable and attractive. Many tourists do not realize just how appealing these residences are, staying in a hotel can have someone miss out on many of Australia’s fantastic features.

 

A neighborhood feeling is what a tourist will have when staying in a bed and breakfast. Most homes are situated in a neighborhood with other homes and a sense of community. A hotel may give someone a fast moving feeling, where the only option for food is a high priced restaurant or fast food. There are things that vacationers can experience when they begin their journey right in the hear of a city.The business operators can give their guests the inside information about where to visit and fun things to do. They will know what places to avoid and which ones are worth the money and time. When tourist spots can be visited that have a reputation for being great, then a traveler will feel more confidant about doing it.
 Posted in Bed and Breakfast | Comments Off 
 Cheap Healthy Breakfast 
 Posted on February 7, 2011 by admin 
Breakfast may be the most important meal of the day because it follows a period of eight or more hours of no food. For maximum nutrition at breakfast, you should eat a variety of foods representing several food groups. Breakfast meats and many sugar-laden cereals can be expensive as well as unhealthy, and you should avoid them.

 There are many delicious breakfast foods that are both healthy and inexpensive.EggsEggs are an inexpensive source of protein and nutrients. One egg contains most essential vitamins and minerals, except vitamin C, as well as six and 1/3 g of protein, over half of which is in the white part of the egg. Vitamins A, D, E and K are only in the yolk, as are omega-3 fatty acids and two carotenoids—lutein and zeaxanthin—which are known antioxidants. The University of Michigan says the yolk contains 210 mg of cholesterol. Adults should consume less than 300 mg of cholesterol daily. If you eat a whole egg, reduce meat and dairy in other meals. Or substitute two egg whites for a whole egg in omelets or scrambled eggs. Add chopped vegetables and serve with fruit and a glass of skim or soy milk for a balanced breakfast.

 
 Posted in Healthy Breakfast | Tagged Breakfast , healthy , vitamins | Comments Off 
 Breakfast in Bed 
 Posted on January 10, 2011 by admin 
Always wanted to have breakfast made for you and brought to your room? Fresh coffee, warm croissants and fresh squeezed orange juice, delivered to your room. This is just one of the perks of staying at our Fort William B&amp;B.Other amenities include a complimentary nightcap in your room, all rooms with TV and DVD players, a wide choice of the latest films or some golden oldies. Toiletries for the ladies and a hairdryer in every room.

 
 Posted in Morning Breakfast | Tagged Bed , Breakfast , room | Comments Off 
 Healthy Breakfast Tips 
 Posted on December 12, 2010 by admin 
Breakfast eaters have all the fun, according to recent research.  People who eat breakfast are less likely to be overweight and are more successful at losing and maintaining weight loss.  They have fewer cravings and choose healthier foods throughout the day.  In fact, at the end of the day, breakfast eaters get more fiber, vitamins and minerals.  Not only that, they are late for work less often and perform better at work and school, especially on those memory tasks!

 

Breakfast is a great opportunity to start out the day right and get some of those food groups that we typically lack:  fruits, whole grains, and low fat dairy or milk.  However, breakfast can also start your day out wrong!  A deluxe breakfast from your local fast food restaurant can cost you more than half the calories you need for the day as well as your entire limit of fat and saturated fat!   Even a quick latte and muffin from the coffee shop will give you 650 calories, 25 grams of fat, and 8 teaspoons of sugar!
 Posted in Healthy Breakfast | Tagged Breakfast , Fun , healthy breakfast | Comments Off 
 Exploring Health Management Avenues for Healthy Breakfast Meals 
 Posted on November 17, 2010 by admin 
In today’s world where everything seems to be in a rush it is quite hard to remain healthy and for most people, especially the busy working class and teenagers, to maintain a healthy weight. People do not even have time for healthy breakfast meals. Health management is nowadays more about charting out health goals and planning healthy meals.

 

It therefore goes without saying that health foods and weight loss products are the main items in nutritional care nowadays.Having considered the fact that eating healthy breakfast meals is a path to healthy living, we then need a health management source that will always be available to take care of our questions about nutrition and also supply our food orders. This source will have much bearing in the eventual success of the health goals and needs that we are anticipating. Of course, this source must be one supplying high quality foods that are palatable remembering that good taste in diet foods helps dissuade relapses to the spicy and fat-filled foods we are trying to stay away from.The foods that help us create healthy breakfast meals in today’s busy schedules include health shakes, bars and drinks. These are fast, convenient and easy foods that can help provide and maintain a healthy nutrition and are the foods advised by many health management centers besides taking healthy meals at home diet meals at home and the restaurant.
 Posted in Healthy Breakfast | Tagged eating , espacially , healthy breakfast | Comments Off 
 Bite Of Minnesota: A Hearty, Healthy Breakfast 
 Posted on October 22, 2010 by admin 
 By Crystal Grobe, Cafe Cyan 
 
Do you eat breakfast every day? Studies show that you should eat breakfast to jump start your day. It helps you perform better and regulates your mood among other things.

Breakfast is one of my favorite meals (my other two favorite meals are lunch and dinner, just in case you are wondering). Growing up, my parents made sure we ate a bowl of non-sugared cereal or peanut butter toast before school and we indulged in eggs and bacon only on the weekends. It was one of the rare times my dad would enter the kitchen to cook as he could whip together fried eggs with runny yolks like nobody’s business.
  
 
One thing we never ate much of growing up was oatmeal; we refused to eat it at the time. Funny how things change, as now I really like oatmeal and try to find new ways to incorporate it into my diet. I’ve even made oatmeal packets to stash at work in case of a meal emergency.

Over the weekend, I made a fantastic oatmeal dish using crunchy walnuts, plump raisins and rich molasses, and packaged it up for breakfast this week. It is so simple to throw together that you could easily make this on a work night and have a special meal in the morning. I use thick cut oats, so I had to add 1/2 cup water halfway through cooking.
  
 
 Baked Aporridgy 
from La Dolce Vegan by Sarah Kramer
(serves 2-4 depending on serving size)

1 cup rolled oats
1 1/2 cups water
1/2 cup milk
2 tbsp maple syrup
2 tbsp ground flax seeds
2 tsp molasses
1/4 tsp salt
1/4 tsp ground nutmeg
1/4 tsp ground cinnamon
1/4 tsp ground ginger
1/4 cup raisins
1/4 cup walnuts

Preheat oven to 350°. In a lightly oiled 8×8 baking pan, stir all ingredients together and bake for 40-45 minutes, stirring once while cooking, adding more water if needed to reach desired consistency.

 
 Posted in Breakfast Recipe | Tagged Breakfast , crunchy , egg | Comments Off 
 Healthy Breakfast 
 Posted on September 5, 2010 by admin 
My lovely breakfast prepared by Da Phui. He is the one who is very particular about having a good and hearty breakfast. No matter what happened, he will have to eat a nice breakfast with his kopi‘peng’only then will he be satisfied.

 

On the other hand, I’m totally the opposite. I don’t mind skipping my breakfast. I loved my sleep more than my breakfast. Which resulted in my bad habit of sleeping until the last min in the morning then only will I wake up in a rush and go to office. A habit that I learn during uni time when my parents are not living with me. =P
But now that my stomach has accustomed back with breakfast every morning except Sunday, I will start to feel dizzy by 9 or 10 am if I didn’t eat anything. But then I’m still not willing to change my habit of waking up at the very (VERY) last minute. Nothing can be sacrifice when it comes to my beauty sleep.
 Posted in Uncategorized | Comments Off 
 Europeon Breakfast 
 Posted on August 8, 2010 by admin 
Sunday morning Chilihead and I had a bittersweet good-bye breakfast with Jeana and Faith  Before heading back to Oklahoma, Chilihead and I stopped at Ikea and spent entirely too much time and money on kitchen gadgets.  We had a stranger take our picture during checkout wearing our Ikea bags, looking all sophisticated and European.  (“Yes,”Chilihead said,“nothing says sophisticated and European like a couple of middle-aged Oklahoma housewives wearing Ikea bags.”)

 
Despite a bit of getting lost on the way home, Chili and I had a ball, talking until I nearly lost my voice.  Is there anything better than time in the car with a girlfriend…and no kids?
I’m home now, a bit road-weary, still hoarse, and buried up to my eyeballs in the laundry and kitchen explosion that occurred in my absence.  But I’m richer, too–I’ve now mirled with some of the very best the blogosphere has to offer, and I happily count these women among my real-life friends.  I’m already looking forward to the next real-life blog gathering, whenever and wherever that may be!
 Posted in Special Breakfast | Tagged Breakfast , europeon | Comments Off 
 This morning breakfast 
 Posted on July 19, 2010 by admin 
Hello everyone,
Welcome to a new week of Saint FM Breakfast with me, Ben Kearns-hope you can join me for the show, as always from half 7 till 10 today, tomorrow and Friday.
As always on Wednesday we’ll have Dead Or Alive after half 8, Gordon From Maldon during the first half hour of the show, some local events to look out for, your news, weather and travel updates and of course (as always on Wednesday and Thursday mornings), this morning’s topical tune.

 I’ve got the story I’m asking you to mull over this morning:

Have a read and when you come up with any song suggestions, let me have them and as always, one of them will be played at around 10 minutes before the end of the show.
As always you can call, email or text me after 7 30, if you’ve got an idea for a song that connects to this story, alternatively leave your suggestions here from… now really.
 Posted in Morning Breakfast | Tagged Breakfast , morning | Comments Off 
 Search for: 
Categories

 Bed and Breakfast Breakfast Recipe Healthy Breakfast Morning Breakfast Special Breakfast Uncategorized 
 
Recent Posts

 How To Discover A Bed And Breakfast Beechworth Cheap Healthy Breakfast Breakfast in Bed Healthy Breakfast Tips Exploring Health Management Avenues for Healthy Breakfast Meals Bite Of Minnesota: A Hearty, Healthy Breakfast Healthy Breakfast Europeon Breakfast This morning breakfast 
 
Archives

 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 
 
Non Stick Cookware
 non stick pans 
 wine merchants uk 
Are you looking for wedding caterers? Check this deWintons wedding caterers 
Tags
 Bed Breakfast crunchy eating egg espacially europeon Fun healthy healthy breakfast morning room vitamins 
 Bed and Breakfast Antwerp Proudly powered by WordPress.
	</body>
</document>
