<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009429" url="http://www.house.missouri.gov/content.aspx?info=/bills061/biltxt/perf/HB1559P.HTM" time="2012-07-13-02:47" support="1" score="0.00032267983077455167" bingtitle="HOUSE COMMITTEE SUBSTITUTE FOR - Missouri House of Representatives" webtitle="Missouri House of Representatives">
			<query id="000623" bing-rank="249"/>
	<description>HOUSE BILL NO. 1559. 93RD GENERAL ASSEMBLY ... 2) &quot;Donor&quot;, any restaurant, cafeteria, fast food restaurant ... the community in which the donor operates in order ...</description>
	<body>
		Home House Members Bill Information Committees Media Center General Information Past Session Archives Quick Links 
 
 
 
 Directory of Representatives House Leadership Legislator Lookup General Info 
 
 
 
 Bill Tracking Bill Activity Reports Floor Activity Copyright Information Dates of Interest Subject Index 
 
 
 
 House Calendar House Floor Schedule Current House Actions Past House Actions Announced Legislation 
 
 
 
 Committee Assignments House Committees Committee Descriptions Hearing Schedules 2011 Interim Committees 
 
 
 
 House Hearing Schedule Senate Hearing Schedule 
 
 
 
 Latest News This Week in the Missouri House Audio Video Photos Media Staff Live Debates 
 
 
 
 House Debate Senate Debate Problems with Audio 
 
 
 
 Chief Clerk of the House Journal of the House Dates of Interest Rules of the House (PDF) Missouri Constitution Missouri Statutes The Legislative Process House Information Showing You, a student handbook (PDF) 
 
 
 
 Making The Law How a Bill Becomes Law (PDF) Glossary of Terms 
 
 
 
 House Staff Directory Employment Opportunities Intern Activities Current Bid Items Third Floor Rotunda Schedule Capitol Floor Maps Visiting The House 
 
 
 
 2011 Regular Session 2011 Extraordinary Session 2010 Extraordinary Session 2010 Regular Session 2009 Regular Session 2008 Regular Session 2007 Extraordinary Session 2007 Regular Session 2006 Regular Session 2005 Extraordinary Session 2005 Regular Session 2004 Regular Session 2003 2nd Extraordinary Session 2003 1st Extraordinary Session 2003 Regular Session 2002 Regular Session 2001 Extraordinary Session 2001 Regular Session 2000 Session 1999 Session 1998 Session 1997 Session 1997 Extraordinary Session 1996 Session 1995 Session 
 
 
 
 House Bill List Hearing Schedules Calendar Journals Floor Schedules 
 
 
 
 House Hearing Schedule Senate Hearing Schedule 
 
 
 
 House Calendar Senate Calendar 
 
 
 
 House Journals Senate Journals 
 
 
 
 House Floor Schedule Senate Floor Schedule 
 
 Bill Search 
Related Links

Related Links
 Missouri State Government Missouri General Assembly Missouri Senate Missouri Revised Statutes Missouri Constitution Visiting the House House Job Opportunities Frequently Asked for Resources Help Finding Amendments Printer Friendly 
 
SECOND REGULAR SESSION

[PERFECTED]

HOUSE COMMITTEE SUBSTITUTE FOR

 HOUSE BILL NO. 1559 

 93RD GENERAL ASSEMBLY 
 
 

 

                    Reported from the Special Committee on General Laws March 2, 2006 with recommendation that House Committee Substitute for
House Bill No. 1559 Do Pass by Consent. Referred to the Committee on Rules pursuant to Rule 25(26)(f). 

                    Reported from the Committee on Rules March 9, 2006 with recommendation that House Committee Substitute for House Bill
No. 1559 Do Pass by Consent. 

                    Perfected by Consent March 16, 2006. 

 STEPHEN S. DAVIS, Chief Clerk 

 4662L.02P 
 
 

 AN ACT 

To repeal section 192.081, RSMo, and to enact in lieu thereof one new section relating to
donation of food.
 


 Be it enacted by the General Assembly of the state of Missouri, as follows: 


              Section A. Section 192.081, RSMo, is repealed and one new section enacted in lieu
thereof, to be known as section 192.081, to read as follows:

              192.081. 1. As used in this section, the following terms mean:

              (1) &quot;Canned food&quot;, food that is commercially processed in hermetically sealed
containers;

              (2) &quot;Donor&quot;, any restaurant, cafeteria, fast food restaurant, delicatessen, or other facility
principally engaged in selling food for consumption on the premises , or any grocery store or
convenience store ;

              (3) &quot;Food&quot;, any raw, cooked, canned, perishable, or prepared edible substance, ice,
beverage, or ingredient used or intended for use in whole or in part for human consumption;

              (4) &quot;Hermetically sealed container&quot;, a container that is designed and intended to be
secure against the entry of microorganisms and thereby to maintain the commercial sterility of
its content after processing;

              (5) &quot;Perishable food&quot;, any food having a significant risk of spoilage, loss of value, or loss
of palatability within ninety days of the date of packaging;

              (6) &quot;Prepared food&quot;, any food prepared, designed, or intended for human consumption
including, without limitation, those foods prepared principally from agricultural, dairy, or
horticultural produce or with meat, fish, or poultry.

              2. Each potential donor, to the greatest extent possible and practicable, may make surplus or excess canned or perishable food available to any bona fide charitable or nonprofit
organization, to any representative or volunteer acting on behalf of such organization, to an
uncompensated person acting in a philanthropic manner providing services similar to those of
such an organization, or to a transporter of any surplus or excess canned or perishable food for
use by such organization or person to feed homeless persons or other persons who are in need
of food and are otherwise unable to provide food for themselves. In achieving this intent, the
following provisions shall apply:

              (1) Each donor may contact charitable or nonprofit organizations in the community in
which the donor operates in order to provide for the collection by such organizations of any
surplus or excess canned food or perishable food from the donor;

              (2) Each charitable or nonprofit organization in this state which provides to the
community in which it operates food for persons who are in need of food or are otherwise unable
to provide food for themselves, or which collects and transports such food to such organizations,
shall make every reasonable effort to contact any donors within the organization&apos;s area of
operations for purposes of collecting any surplus or excess canned food or perishable food for
use in providing such services.

              3. A good faith donor of any canned or perishable food, apparently fit for human
consumption, to a bona fide charitable or nonprofit organization for free distribution shall not
be subject to criminal penalty or civil damages arising from the condition of the food, unless an
injury is caused by the gross negligence, recklessness, or intentional misconduct of the donor.              4. A bona fide charitable or nonprofit organization, or any representative or volunteer
acting on behalf of such organization or an uncompensated person acting in a philanthropic
manner providing services similar to those of such an organization or transporter of any surplus
or excess canned or perishable food for use by such organization which in good faith accepts,
collects, transports, or distributes any canned or perishable food for free distribution and which
reasonably inspects the food at the time of the donation and finds the food apparently fit for
human consumption shall not be subject to criminal penalty or civil damages arising from the
condition of the food, unless an injury is caused by the gross negligence, recklessness, or
intentional misconduct of an agent of the charitable or nonprofit organization.

              5. The department of health and senior services shall make available information
detailing the need of food-recovery programs, the benefit of food-recovery programs, the manner
in which such organizations may become involved in food-recovery programs and the
food-recovery entities or food banks that exist in the state. This information must be updated
annually.

•
	</body>
</document>
