<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009672" url="http://forums.quickbooksusers.com/showthread.php?t=22062" time="2012-07-13-03:04" support="7" score="0.006625055366756275" bingtitle="Enter Credit Card charges in QB - QuickBooks Forums" webtitle="Enter Credit Card charges in QB - QuickBooks Forums">
			<query id="001398" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000303" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000311" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="000049" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="000300" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="001461" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="001408" bing-rank="123"/>
	<description>I’m right now recording a credit card bill. It seems ... be easier to collect the CC sales receipts, and ... to record each individual gas station or fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Advertise here    
     
 

 
   QuickBooks Forums &gt; QuickBooks Software Support &gt; QuickBooks Pro Forum Enter Credit Card charges in QB 
 
 User Name Remember Me? Password 
 
 
 Register FAQ Community Calendar 
 
 
 Community Links Social Groups Pictures&amp;Albums Members List 
 
 Go to Page... 
 
 

   Thread Tools Rate Thread Display Modes 
 
  # 1   02-16-2007, 04:20 PM 
 romualdfavre Registered User   Join Date: Jan 2007 Posts: 12 
 Enter Credit Card charges in QB Im right now recording a credit card bill.
It seems that it can be done in 2 ways: either by means of the function Enter Credit Card Charges, then reconciling the CC bill. Or in recording it as a normal bill. Is that right?
The first way would allow entering regularly into QB the expenses of the CC and reconcile at the end. Also, for each transaction, a specific vendor can be entered. Finally, its a good way of controlling no limit exceeding. This seems hence to be some good advantages for going for this option. But doesnt it take more time proceeding this way? Wouldnt be easier to collect the CC sales receipts, and only check them when recording the CC bill? Also , for some recurrent expenses (like fuel or restaurant), I guess it doesnt make sense to record each individual gas station or fast food restaurant, can we go for a generic vendor name?
Thanks in advance for sharing with me your experience in this matter.
R. Favre 
 
 romualdfavre View Public Profile Find all posts by romualdfavre 
 
  # 2   02-17-2007, 07:28 PM 
 LauraD Moderator   Join Date: Jun 2006 Location: Rhode Island Posts: 1,160 
 I totally vote for setting the credit card up as a credit card type account in QuickBooks. Enter purchases through the &apos;enter credit card&apos; screen.

You can create generic vendors (Meals&amp;ent, Gas&amp;auto, etc) for recurrent purchases where you don&apos;t need to track the vendor name.

You need to expense the purchases anyhow, and using the cc platform gives you the most detail when you do need a report, etc. If you have your preferences set to &apos;auto-recall last transaction for this name&apos;, it will flow rather quickly. . .

It also posts the purchases correctly for tax purposes.

Laura D __________________
Laura Dion
Advanced Certified QuickBooks ProAdvisor
Cents-able Bookkeeping, LLC

www.centsablebookkeeping.com
_______________________________ 
 
 LauraD View Public Profile Visit LauraD&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by LauraD 
 
 


 Bookmarks 
 Digg del.icio.us StumbleUpon Google 
 
 
 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
 
 Thread Tools Show Printable Version Email this Page 
 
 Display Modes Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 Rate This Thread Excellent Good Average Bad Terrible 
 
 
 Posting Rules You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is Off HTML code is On Forum Rules 
 
 Forum Jump 
 User Control Panel Private Messages Subscriptions Who&apos;s Online Search Forums Forums Home Welcome and Info   New users and visitors start here!   Getting Acquainted - Introductions   News, articles, announcements, offers QuickBooks Software Support   QuickBooks FAQ   QuickBooks Forum   QuickBooks Pro Forum   QuickBooks Enterprise Edition Forum   Premier Manufacturing and Wholesale Edition Forum   Premier Nonprofit Edition Forum   QuickBooks UK Forum   QuickBooks Australia Forum   QuickBooks Canada Forum   QuickBooks Mac Forum QuickBooks Services and Jobs   QuickBooks Services Forum   QuickBooks Jobs Other QuickBooks Forums   QuickBooks Seminars, Classes, Workshops   Suggestion Box   QuickBooks 3rd Party Software Forum   Comparison Forum 
 


 All times are GMT -5. The time now is 08:04 PM . 
 
 Contact Us - QuickbooksUsers.com HOME - Archive - Privacy Statement - Top 


 

 

 
 Powered by vBulletin®Version 3.8.4
Copyright©2000 - 2012, Jelsoft Enterprises Ltd. All contents copyright (c) by AccountingUsers Inc.
	</body>
</document>
