<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009260" url="http://sbming.com/healthyrecipes/tag/teach/" time="2012-07-13-02:39" support="1" score="0.0005719763944792303" bingtitle="Teach | Healthy Recipes" webtitle="Teach | Healthy Recipes">
			<query id="001434" bing-rank="192"/>
	<description>Applesauce only has 90 calories per half cup ... Although you often do not change the calorie count by changing ... Maybe a visit to their favourite fast food restaurant after ...</description>
	<body>
		Healthy Recipes It Needn&apos;t Be a Problem Finding Great Tasting Healthy Recipes Subscribe in a reader 
Teach
 W 
 Healthy Habits to Teach Your Kids 
 On April 10, 2012, 
 in healthy recipes , 
 by healthy 
The lifestyle and dietary habits a person learns in childhood tends to follow them into adulthood and throughout their lifetime. Childhood experiences are like a blueprint of the personality. The indelible impressions and habits that are formed in our school age years are often very difficult to change later on in life.

It is essential for every parent to recognize this and consciously play a positive role in the development of their child’s lifestyle and dietary habits. Here are some fundamental starting points, healthy habits to teach your kids:

 Eat fruits and vegetables every day. 5–9 servings is the optimal amount. Fruits are a great and easy snack. They’re naturally sweet and provide good energy without a sugar crash or weight gain. Find out which vegetables your children like and serve those often. Get them in the habit of seeing vegetables on their plate.

 Wear sunscreen when outside, even on cloudy days. Keep small tubes of sunscreen in your child’s backpack, in a cool color or flavor that they enjoy. Put sunscreen on them when they leave home in the morning and when they go outside to play.

 Don’t smoke cigarettes. If you are a smoker, refrain from smoking in the presence of your child. Educate them about second hand smoke and be an example by keeping smokers at a distance. Teach your child that cigarettes are very, very dangerous and very difficult to quit once a habit is formed.

 Get regular exercise. Children are naturally quite active, unless they have a computer or Nintendo or TV to distract them. Our kids have grown less and less active in the last 20 years, due largely to their growing addiction to sitting and gazing at a screen. Limit computer time and tv time. Reward your children for playing outdoors and engaging in sports at school. If your child is not particularly athletic, encourage long walks and hikes in nature. Let them experience for themselves how good physical fitness feels.

 Don’t eat junk food. We all know that junk food is bad and should be severely limited if eaten at all. Don’t buy candy and junk food to keep in the house. They are very tempting and they should not be presented as an everyday food choice. If your child learns at a young age that junk food and nutritious food are very different, they will be better equipped to make wise food decisions on their own. Present healthy alternatives. Learn about healthy sweeteners and healthy snacks.

 Healthy Sweeteners 
 Healthy Snacks 

Lynn Baer is a nutritional researcher/writer, specializing in body detoxification, weight loss and nutrition. Her website Detox Safely is a complete reference guide for safe, natural cleansing and body detoxification. It provides information about how to plan every aspect of your detox program, including a detailed preparation guide for a safe, doctor-recommended detox program. Detoxing can be harmful if not approached wisely!

 Tagged with: Habits • Healthy • Teach   0 Comments Leave a respond W 
 Low Calorie Pancake Recipe That Will Teach You How to Make Healthy Pancakes 
 On February 26, 2012, 
 in healthy recipes , 
 by healthy 
There are many things that can be done to lower the calories of a favorite recipe without sacrificing flavor. For example, you may find it very easy to convert a family favorite pancake recipe to a low calorie pancake recipe. One of the first things to cut out in any recipe to lower its calories is fat. In many recipes, especially for baking, some or all or the fat can be substituted equally for applesauce. The applesauce keeps the product moist but adds no fat. Applesauce only has 90 calories per half cup, but butter or margarine has 810. That means a savings of over 700 calories per half cup. Even if you switch to low fat margarine, you can cut the calories in half.

With some recipes, such as for pancakes, you may be able to leave out any added sugar. This is especially true if you are substituting applesauce for the fat. While sugar only has 15 calories per teaspoon, most of us do not stop with just one teaspoon. Choose egg whites instead of whole eggs. The whites are much lower in fat and cholesterol than are egg yolks.

Although you often do not change the calorie count by changing from white flour to whole wheat, buckwheat or oatmeal, you do increase the fiber in the food. Since the fiber is not digestible, it passes through your system quickly and effectively lowers the calorie count. In addition, the fiber has been shown to lower cholesterol count and the likelihood of cancer. Once you have made some great pancakes, you can also save calories by choosing wisely what you put on those pancakes. If you add lightly sweetened fruit or no sugar fruit spread, you may not need any butter or margarine. If you must have whipped cream or topping, choose the light variety to save calories. The fruit may be sweetened using an artificial sweetener to lower sugar calories.

If you must use syrup on your pancakes, go light. Two tablespoons of regular pancake syrup has 110 calories. In contrast, the same amount of lite pancake syrup has only fifty calories. In addition, consider the low fat margarine again or choose a butter replacement spray. Although these changes may make some significant taste changes in your favorite recipes, they will allow you to enjoy many of your favorite foods.

In addition to the low calorie pancake recipe, you will find that many other recipes that have been family favorites through the years can be converted to lower the calorie and fat content while increasing fiber for a healthier dish to set on your table.

Pancakes are for sure tasty but how to make them healthy? In Ben’s collection of simple and delicious pancake recipe you will also find this low calorie pancake recipe which is basically a diet pancake recipe that you can use if you are on a diet. Ben’s site has also many other pancake, flapjack&amp;crepe recipes.

 Tagged with: Calorie • Healthy • Pancake • Pancakes • Recipe • Teach   0 Comments Leave a respond W 
 Teach Your Kids Healthy Eating Habits–5 Proven Ways to Make it Work 
 On January 22, 2012, 
 in healthy recipes , 
 by healthy 
Almost half of today’s overweight children are obese, the number is rising constantly and something has to be done. Teaching our children how to eat healthy is a parents duty. If done properly, the habit will become second nature to the child and they will take their healthy eating lifestyle into adulthood and the probability of a longer happier life will be greatly increased.

Here are 5 ways you can ensure that will happen.

 1. More Fruit– Getting kids to eat fruit is sometimes like trying to pull teeth, well there are ways to make it more fun and appealing and, if required, some sneaky tricks to get your child eating healthy they will never know about. Make them fruit smoothies and shakes. You can even freeze them and create lollipops and ice pops. Smoothies are great ways to get certain green vegetables into the mix that a lot of children refuse to eat.

 2. Make It Fun –Your children will be more willing to eat a healthier diet if you incorporate play and games into mealtimes. Get them to create a picture on the plate, maybe a garden with green vegetables, or a green smoothie called Hulk Juice. Let them invent their own recipes so long as they include certain ingredients. Fun is always a great way to get your child to enjoy healthier eating habits.

 3. Make it Relevant to Their Interests –Kids view mealtimes as just a distraction from their play times, so seeing a plate of vegetables will make them even more disinterested. If you convince them that, unless they eat a certain food, they won’t be able to run fast or play sports. Or that Spiderman eats broccoli so he can fight bad guys then they will take more interest. There are many various ways to create healthy eating children.

 4. Don’t Take Away Candy –We all know that’s kids love candy and fizzy drinks and anything else that is bad for them. If you take away all these things completely then they will just resent you and the healthier options you have replaced them with. Instead make them rewards for eating something regularly. Maybe a visit to their favourite fast food restaurant after each month of eating healthily.

 5. Join In –Sitting down at the dining table and eating as a family is the No.1 proven way of teaching children how to eat a healthy diet . By all doing the same thing at the same time becomes a routine, and by seeing you do the same as them your kids will be more willing to join in. Also it enables you to make sure they are eating the healthy food instead of sneaking it to the dog.

It is our responsibility to make sure our children grow up to be as healthy as possible. Child obesity is rising constantly and it needs to be stopped. Teaching our kids how to eat healthy is the best way possible for them to become healthy, successful adults. For more ideas and tips visit http://therightplace.weebly.com/simple-healthy-recipes-for-children.html and ensure your children become the best adult they can be.

 Tagged with: Eating • Habits • Healthy • Proven • Teach   0 Comments Leave a respond 
Recent Posts
 
 Delicious Squid With Chinese Noodles Recipe The Joy Of Juice–Fresh Juicing Recipes Mouth-Watering Atkins Diet Recipes–Just Try This Great Weight Loss Temptation 3 Healthy Food Recipes For Dinner Boneless Skinless Chicken Breast Recipes–Two Quick, Easy, and Healthy Recipes Fresh Shrimp Makes Any Recipe Come Alive Save Your Health and Time With Baked Chicken Recipes 
 
Categories
 
 healthy recipes 
 
Tags
 Benefits Breakfast Calorie Chicken Colon Cooking Delicious Dessert Diabetic Dinner Eating Enjoy Family Finding Foods Fresh Fruit Great Health Healthy Heart Homemade Ideas Ingredients Juice Juicing Living Making Meals Natural Quick Recipe Recipes Salad Salmon Should Simple Smoothie Smoothies Snack Tasty Using Vegan Vegetarian Weight 
Archives
 
 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 
 powered by wordpress.org and Paper3 theme
	</body>
</document>
