<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009449" url="http://www.startupbizhub.com/Starting-a-Chinese-Fast-Food-Restaurant.htm" time="2012-07-13-02:48" support="115" score="0.32143552104391526" bingtitle="Starting a Chinese Fast Food Restaurant - Startup Business ..." webtitle="Starting a Chinese Fast Food Restaurant">
			<query id="001378" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="001296" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="001468" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001462" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="001535" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000657" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000996" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000124" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="001304" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="001272" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="001169" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000743" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="001503" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="001533" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="001374" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="001185" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="001311" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000667" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000906" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001521" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="001293" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000727" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000112" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="001450" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="001261" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000560" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="001115" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000556" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001064" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="001052" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="000587" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="001515" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000664" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="001189" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000392" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="001282" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000055" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="001279" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000586" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000748" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000590" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000573" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000119" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000737" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000685" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="001504" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000362" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000047" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000686" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001184" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000591" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000541" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000604" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000120" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000675" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="001472" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000592" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="001361" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000555" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000735" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000747" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000059" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001284" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000744" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="001283" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000681" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001315" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="001500" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000682" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000549" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000720" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001183" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000588" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="001523" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="001367" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001264" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="001499" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000113" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001529" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000579" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000864" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000687" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000624" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000749" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="001188" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="001278" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000570" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000576" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000895" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="001177" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000876" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="001314" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="001473" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="001063" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001467" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="001310" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="001373" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="001461" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000041" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000557" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="001286" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000563" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="001377" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="001453" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000061" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000561" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000618" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="001126" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000612" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="001498" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000123" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="001492" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000550" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="001178" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000623" bing-rank="37"/>
	<description>... when one decides to open his/her own Chinese fast food restaurant. In order for it to profit remember these factors. Chinese fast food restaurants and take out counters ...</description>
	<body>
		News   Franchise 
 117   
Starting a Chinese Fast Food Restaurant


 There are a lot of things to consider when one decides to open his/her own Chinese fast food restaurant. In order for it to profit remember these factors. 

Chinese fast food restaurants and take out counters seem to be sprouting like mushrooms all over the country.

 

Obviously, this kind of business serves as a welcome alternative to burger and hotdog joints. Unlike other specialty cuisine restaurants, Chinese fast food is both filling and inexpensive. Some Chinese food restaurants even specialize in serving quick cooking meals; giving the term fast food a whole new meaning.

If you are thinking of opening this kind of restaurant for yourself, here are a few pointers just to boost you off.

Choosing Location for Chinese Fast food Restaurant

First of all, you have to decide what kind of restaurant set-up you would like. Will your restaurant have a take out counter? Will your restaurant accept home delivery? Will your restaurant be available for advance bookings and party hosting?

These things should come into consideration when choosing a location for your restaurant. If you have a place that is filled with people going to and home from work, you may want to add a take out counter for easier pedestrian access. If you have a place near mostly residential structures, you may want to consider home deliver services and bookings for parties and such.

Of course, choosing a location and setting up shop is intertwined tightly with your budget or overhead expenses. If your pocket can afford it then add what you can to your restaurant. If not though, you should be prudent with what your restaurant may offer to your customers. It simply wont do to overextend your business before you even open shop formally.

Standardization

Unfortunately, one of the greatest hindrances to launching and maintaining a Chinese fast food restaurant is its lack of standardization in all aspects of the business. Cooking, customer service, food portions, sales, etc. do not fall into any form of standardization.

If you would like to maintain your business for a long time, perhaps this area could use more research. You would probably need expert advice in the field of food preparation, customer handling and finance.

Authenticity

What can be worse than indecipherable food passing off as Chinese food? When people go to Chinese fast food restaurants, they are usually looking for that authentic oriental taste. Authentic Chinese cooks are usually trained according to what province they originated from: Northern Chinese or Mongolian cuisine is usually mutton and lamb based matched with bread; Western Chinese or Szechwan / Hunan cuisine is mostly spicy dishes matched with rice and noodles; Eastern Chinese or East China Sea province cuisine (also known as Shanghai cuisine named after the port of Shanghai) have the most eclectic blend of ingredients and style of cooking among all the other provinces which peaks with bread, noodles and dumplings; and lastly Southern Chinese or Canton cuisine that are often punctuated with steaming food and mild flavors.

If you do not have an authentic Chinese cook or at least someone who was trained in the art of Chinese cooking, you may as well choose a different flavor for your restaurant. It will take a skilled cook to create dishes at the top of a hat, and still maintain that oriental taste.

Pricing Food in Chinese Restaurant

Many people go to Chinese fast food restaurants because the food is relatively inexpensive. If your location holds competitors in your same field, you may want to check out their prices and match them (with profit in mind, of course.)



 &lt;&lt; How to Start a Mediterranean Restaurant     Start an Italian Restaurant  &gt;&gt; 

117 Responses to &quot;Starting a Chinese Fast Food Restaurant&quot;.
 1. Sihaam on 5/2/2009 12:26:52 PM I have been to this restaurant before in USA. well, I&apos;m Sihaam from Saudi Arabia, I&apos;m 27 female. I just want to say Restaurant Biz is very successful here in my country and we have too many American Fast Food Restaurants. such as Hardees, Kentucky Fried Chicken, Burger King.. etc. But never have Chinese Fast Food. Which is great idea to have one here in my country . I hope to have one someday. So if you are interested of my idea, u can reach me on ya_dala3@hotmail.com

Regards, 2. md.zahed alam on 7/24/2009 3:41:38 PM Hi! my name is Zahed and I worked for an Italian restaurant for seven years. I am very interested about opening a chinese restaurant here in Toronto. Can you give an idea how much budget will I need to open a 30 to 35 people sitting capacity restaurant? Thank you and appreciate your response.
Zahed, alamzahed@rocketmail.com 3. Stephen Okon on 8/12/2009 10:34:30 AM Dear sir, my nane is Stephen Okon in Nigeria. please i want you to guide with ideas for me to startup my own chinese/nigerian fast foods / restaurant here in nigeria. Thanks 4. Anton Kudishin on 8/18/2009 5:45:20 AM Greetings to all! My name is Anton Kudishin I work at present as the chief of department IT. I have an offer to organize a world network of your restaurants. To begin with it is possible to organise in my city of Penza, near to Moscow. I think your experience and my communications will help us. Write! akudishin@mail.ru 5. leon lin on 8/20/2009 10:05:58 AM Hello everyone, my name is leon lin and I&apos;m a student. After my university life is over, I want to startup my own chinese fast food restaurant in my country, Myanmar. But I afraid to start because I don&apos;t know which ideas, methods, management and business plans are needed to establish the food center. Could you favour me with your ideas and advices? Please write to me &quot;leonlin24@gmail.com &quot;. Thanks. 6. Tom Tao on 9/23/2009 3:01:49 PM Hello everyone. I am in Ottawa and I plan to open a fast chinese food restaurant in Ottawa, Canada. Could you please guide with ideas for me to startup? thanks 7. Becky Faasu on 10/20/2009 12:21:51 AM I want to start a chinese fast food BAR IN MY COUNTRY SOLOMON ISLAND. 8. Khader on 11/3/2009 2:06:16 AM I would like to start an Fast Food Business in Trichy(TN)India. I need to know all the details regarding setting up a kitchen, hiring cooks, waiters, concepts, etc.., i am planning to target medium and upper medium customers. so please send me the details on my mail id, my email id is mkhadershariff@gmail.com. Please give me the Clear Ideas so else it will be helpful for our Company. 9. bobby reddy on 11/8/2009 11:47:49 AM hi everyone. I would like to start a Fast Food Business in guntur{India} Can you give the information regarding hiring cooks and where we can get them and how much we have to pay them for a month and my id is boby.reddy@gmail.com 10. MUSHTAQ ALI KHAN on 11/10/2009 9:37:14 AM Sir, I would like to start my own Chinese Restaurant but very small type of restaurant in india. off course there are lot of chinese restaurants, high class as well as cheap restaurants. I will appreciate if you give me an idea something totally different concept which attracts to middle class people. Thanks in advance 11. Mark A. Velazquez on 12/2/2009 2:54:41 PM Hello, I have a great restaurant business model that will fit in anywhere. I am interested in partnering with anyone in any place. If you are interested please email me at Markaudio545@yahoo.com
Thanks, Mark A. Velazquez 12. Kamal on 1/4/2010 9:25:22 AM HI Folk. wish you a Happy new year 2010. I am planning to start a fastfood center at Tenali (guntur, AP, India). Can some body pls help me out. how much it costs for a medium size stall? what are the things i have take care while opening it. pls reach me at kamal.chopra@ymail.com 13. Jolly nemi on 1/7/2010 3:45:32 PM Hi folks, i really appreciate this forum, its really helpful. Please, I want to start a Fast food Restaurant in my city, where we normally have the Argungu International Fish festival, Argungu, Kebbi state, Nigeria west africa. It is a Tourist center and we have no fast food restaurant there. Pls any body with fast food restaurant model should pls email me through jollynem@yahoo.co.uk. For partnership. Thanks. 14. steve-o on 2/23/2010 9:06:46 AM i want to start a fast food restaurant in grimsby but i was thinking of an indian because chinese sucks, any ideas? 15. sagar on 3/28/2010 10:04:06 AM hey i&apos;m sagar from hospet. i&apos;m planning to start a chinese restaurant in my locality in an up market area. i want some details regarding the capital required and also details regarding the staff. 16. eve on 4/20/2010 10:20:43 AM pls i wld like to have a concrete info on what it takes to open a Chinese restaurant here in nigeria. thx eve. 17. Donald on 4/21/2010 11:33:04 AM Dear Sir, I have a small shop 240 sq ft in Mumbai on the Main busy road in Mira Road and I want to start a Chinese Fast Food Take Away Counter&amp;Home Delivery also. Please advice me on all the pro&apos;s&amp;con&apos;s how I could go about to start this business. All help by way of advice / contact etc are welcome. My email contact donald0220@gmail.com. Regards, Donald 18. Philip on 5/3/2010 7:11:00 AM Hi, my name is Philip and I&apos;m interested in starting a chinese takeaway in my home town. I live in south africa. There&apos;s currently one such take away but their standards aren&apos;t very high and so the people don&apos;t like to go there. Any information will be helpful. My email contact buysphilip@gmail.com. Kind regards, Philip. 19. Rohit Bohra on 5/5/2010 10:55:06 AM I am interested to open a chinese restaurant in Mira Road Plz tell me how much is the minimum budget required to start I have decided to to take on rental basis, 20. Dana on 5/10/2010 10:26:10 PM I&apos;m thinking about starting a fast food restaurant in Winston Salem north Carolina could you give me advice or any contact information. Also the start up and running cost. Thanks a lot. I have never ran a business before. 21. Jan on 5/15/2010 5:30:56 AM Hi, people. I would like to start a Chinese fast casual food restaurant in Almaty, Kazakhstan and appreciate any information on this subject. 22. mahi on 5/16/2010 5:49:12 AM hi i am from Hyderabad, looking to buy chinies furniture to start a restaurant, including lamps and all other interiors. Need some help. Does any one know where can i Buy them. Mail me cutesmile_in@yahoo.com 23. Manmeet on 5/17/2010 2:48:33 AM I am planning to Open a Chinese Takeaway Joint in Chandigarh. Can you Please tell the Budget Required to do the same. 24. Tapan Kumar Das on 5/23/2010 1:27:51 AM I would like to start fast food business in Canada (Toronot), how much capital i should have. 25. sharan on 5/24/2010 5:20:18 AM I am planning to start new business in trichy. AS U said Fast food. what are all needed and how much it cost to start chinese fast food? explain me clearly so it would help to start soon as possible 26. Artur on 5/25/2010 6:46:11 PM Hi everyone. I want to open a chinese fast food canteen/restaurant in London. Can I have more information on the equipment needed to set up a kitchen. Minimum space for a kitchen. And a marketing strategy to attract more customers. We want to open on a busy high street in residential area, zone 2,3,4. And would like to ad a takeaway and delivery services. Can I have more info on that
youngsky@mail.ru 27. Zoya on 6/1/2010 7:13:48 AM Hi, I am planning to start fast food joint in Delhi NCR. Can u give me some knowledge regarding what kind of employees to hire and how are their shifts managed. and also how much capital is required initially to start? 28. kike on 6/8/2010 3:56:47 AM Hello, i would love to start a chinese/indian take away in my country Nigeria and need some expert advice on set up, operation and management.Pls advice. Best regards ladipok@yahoo.com 29. Andrew on 6/10/2010 1:31:53 PM Hello, I&apos;m a first generation chinese immigrant in Wisconsin, United States. I am interested in opening a chinese restaurant and I would like to find a partner so we can have a joint venture. I am open to locations anywhere in Wisconsin but primarily in Madison, Milwaukee, Beloit, or anything in between like Lake Mills, Watertown, or even Janesville. If you are interested, just send me an email at phantomoftherisingstar@yahoo.com. 30. mahenda on 6/11/2010 5:07:13 AM hello i am from delhi hotelier by profession wants to start a fast food restaurant but with only 1 lac capital in hand pls help me in this regard 31. Nithish on 6/19/2010 2:58:11 AM i like to stat a restaurant in thiruvalla, kerala. i like to start a Chinese food restaurant pls help me how to open 32. ahmed on 6/19/2010 9:40:03 AM I would like to start an Fast Food Business in telegana region (AP)India. i am new to restaurant line. I need to know all the details regarding setting up a kitchen, hiring cooks, material, recipes waiters, concepts, etc.., i am planning to target medium and upper medium customers. so please send me the details on my mail id, my email id is smaa_nirl@yahoo.com. Please give me the Clear Ideas so else it will be helpful for me. 33. jatinder singh on 6/21/2010 2:41:36 AM I want to start a chinese restaurant in mukherjee nagar, delhi. I want to make new dishes like tandoori momos and others items which will be having different taste and some uniqueness in them. please suggest me to start this type of innovative restaurant in this area. 34. Owais Malik on 6/23/2010 2:55:23 AM I am interested in running a chinese fast food franchise business in Pakistan. Our main locations would be Karachi, Lahore, Islamabad and Multan step by step accordingly. 35. frieda on 7/14/2010 11:05:07 PM hello , everyone this is frieda . since you are planning to set up a chinese restaurant . may i know are you in need of a chinese chef or waiter if you do , please do not hesitate to contact me thank u. my email agent@chinesestaff.com 36. Sam on 7/16/2010 1:25:46 AM Dear, I am planning to operate one Chinese fast food store, would u pls have some tips and good advice to me, thanks a lot...samtuok@gmail.com 37. Salman Razzaq on 8/1/2010 3:00:55 AM Dear Concerned, I am planning to open up a Chinese restaurant in Kuwait, Any suggestions on the chinese delicacy&amp;Menu would be appreciated. Thanks Salman. 38. patrick fernando on 8/9/2010 2:40:00 PM Sir,i would like to start my own chinese buffet restaurant in birmingham uk, but very small type of restaurant for anybody can come&amp;eat. Please give me the clear ideas. Thanks 39. kiran varma on 8/17/2010 8:45:31 AM Dear Sir, I would like to open a Chinese fast food restaurant specially dealing with momos and rolls. Can you suggest some names and concepts. Planning it in hyderabad. Thanks. kiranvama1977@gmail.com 40. betty on 8/19/2010 8:15:11 PM need help in starting a chinese restaurant in los angeles, CA 41. Redhawi Saleh on 8/22/2010 11:10:54 AM Dear Sir, My name is Redhawi Saleh from Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia. Interested in starting chinese fast food in Kuala Lumpur. My plan is to start with a small shop which more focus on delivery services. In Malaysia we need to produce halal product as it&apos;s the majority are muslims and the selection of the ingredient are essential. Need your opinion in this matter. Thank you 42. aravind on 8/29/2010 11:10:56 AM hi, i am a chef and consultant, i would like to open a typical chinese hygienic fast food with investment of only 3 lakhs at tirupati. india. plz suggest me ... 43. Rishita Banerjee on 8/30/2010 4:27:56 AM hi this is rishita banerjee i want to open one chinese restaurant in the location of kolkata, saltlake city center and my competition will be with the restaurant like hakka thats why i need some idea what can be exceptional i can do than the other restaurants 44. Jitender K on 8/31/2010 8:22:10 AM Brand name for chinese food restaurant and online chinese food service &quot;11CHINESE.com&quot; is available to interested persons. Please send inquiries on jkcp_9@yahoo.co.in Thanks. 45. Gustavo on 9/6/2010 7:49:40 PM I opened a chinese fast food in my location 2 weeks ago and I cannot see profit yet, only lots of expenses in buying groceries. Hope you have some good advice. 46. Sachin Suryavanshi on 9/13/2010 12:08:09 AM Hi this Sachin Suryavanshi from India, Maharashtra, I wanted to start a chinese restaurant in Navi Mumbai. Can any one guide me in this project like what is capital requirement? Kitchen Equipment? and Furniture? 47. C.Kanagaraj on 9/13/2010 2:22:17 AM Im in Trichy, Profeessional in this industry for 17 Years, iam alrady working in Chinese Restaurant. Im looking forward to Start Restaurant in Trichy city, Tamilnadu.

Thanks,

Regards,
C.Kanagaraj 48. Manoj Biswas on 9/14/2010 8:15:15 AM Dear Sir i wanna start Chinese restaurant in new panvel please let me know the budget for starting medium size 20 seater Chinese restaurant. thx manoj 49. G. Ngubane on 9/21/2010 10:14:31 AM Hallow everyone, my name is Gugu from South Africa, Johannesburg, I&apos;m very much interested in opening a chinese restaurant here in Joburg and Durban. I&apos;ve lived in London for years and I know how much people love this food. Please can anyone advise me on how to open this business and where to get financial need? and how much it will cost me? 50. michael on 9/21/2010 1:35:22 PM Chinese cook and partner wanted to open restaurant south of ottawa canada 51. manishchavan on 9/25/2010 10:38:16 AM i am into a project. I am doing hotel management where i have to make such a project which is based on fast food, which needs to be start from a scratch. need help. 52. Jorge Caneda on 9/28/2010 4:05:37 PM Hello From Miami I am interested in starting a small quick and fast paced take out Chinese Food. would like to know the cost approx capital needs to start? License, Food, Packages, Containers, Delivery, Lease, Sq footage its take out no dine in
Credit card accounts, Insurance, Advertising. can any one provide me with some starter points etc... please!!! 53. Sam Kim on 9/30/2010 5:25:59 PM Hello. I&apos;m thinking about opening a gourmet, open kitchen chinese diner in Winchester or Roanoke, Virginia. Please help with start-up cost estimates. Delivery/take out/small dine in. 54. Bill McDanny on 10/12/2010 12:34:25 PM Hi i&apos;m Bill from the US. I plan on setting up a fast food restaurant near Concord. I am 35 yrs. old and have never worked before. I live in my parents basement. Any advice will help greatly. Thanks! 55. Tate on 10/12/2010 12:36:41 PM Hello people, I am a 25 year old college student in Ottawa Canada looking to open up a Chinese restaurant. But I am not sure how to open one up and so if you guys have any ideas feel free to contact me. Thank you. 56. satwinder on 10/19/2010 4:53:34 AM i m thinking to start fast food in bathinda with trained person to know all kind of Chinese fast food pl tell me how to contact that person 57. nikhila mopury on 10/20/2010 8:31:47 AM hi every one.I am nikhila,i want to start a Chinese fast food centre in bangalore.can you please help me out with the investment required,where i can get qualified cooks how much i have to pay them for month 58. Sunny Singh on 10/24/2010 2:44:08 PM I live in usa and i am planning to open up a chuckee cheese kind of set up in CHANDIGARH ,. What kind of investment do i need to open up the same therewith about 30 staff members . please advice. 
thanks 59. Amarnath Reddy Mettu on 10/28/2010 10:29:59 AM Hi Guys, I am from secunderabad, India. I am in to Restaurant Business. I can help people to setup Chinese Restaurant in India&amp;Overseas also, If Interested Contact me on My Email @ amarmettu@hotmail.com. With Regards 60. joane on 10/29/2010 3:19:06 AM dear sir,
i would like to start a singapore style chicken rice and bejing dumpling food stall in manila. previously do own a chicken rice stall in singapore,and as for bejing food, we do have someone with experiences to teaches us the trade.
my problems is to know roughly how much would it cost to investment in such shop with capacity of 30paxes and what kind of location should i look for.
thanks 61. Aruna on 11/7/2010 11:29:44 PM hi every one.I am Aruna,i want to start a Chinese fast food centre in Delhi.can you please help me out with the investment required,where i can get qualified cooks how much i have to pay them for month. 62. Alireza on 11/22/2010 2:38:00 PM hi everyone, i am from Iran, i want to start a chinese fast food restaurant in Tehran. but i don&apos;t know how to start it. i wanted to take some chinese cook to iran, but i am not sure that it is the good way, it is very nice of you if you can help me. my email address is: alireza.bagheri@gmail.com 63. Nasir Baig on 12/1/2010 3:53:14 AM My name is Nasir and I would like to open a Chinese and Moghali outlet here in Hyderabad, India. Kindly suggest to whom I have to contact for getting the best cooks who can prepare all Chinese and Moghali dishes. Appreciate your help. Regards, Nasir.... 64. pruthviraj on 12/2/2010 2:15:47 AM hi, I would like to open a Chinese outlet here in Hyderabad, India. Kindly suggest to whom I have to contact for complete details regarding Chinese dishes. Appreciate your help. Regards, pruthviraj .... 65. srinivas on 12/2/2010 7:09:51 AM Hi all let me introduce myself.My name is Shankar Srinivas and i am an ex chef of taj with Chinese being my specialty.am into restaurant consultancy and mostly deal with chinese. So in any case any one of you want some advice or help from my end with respect to equipments,staff menu planning and other related points then please feel free to call me or mail me. srinivasshankar@hotmail.com. My phone number is 09836433770. i am based out of kolkata but i don&apos;t think it should be an issue. 66. Ruben on 12/3/2010 10:23:47 AM I am in urgent need of a chinese fast food cook with experience, I am opening a chinese fast food in the south bay in california, if you or you know someone, please contact me, my email is rpo12000@yahoo.com 67. nitin on 12/29/2010 7:29:07 PM I am interested to open a chinese restaurant in Powai mumbai-72 Plz tell more information about this business with including gov. lice, capital etc 68. syed raffic on 1/20/2011 5:18:41 AM I would like to open a chinese restaurant so please give me the details including what type of cutlery&amp;Crockery and holloware etc.., it&apos;s should me fine dining experience budget is not a constraint 69. mahesh on 1/25/2011 12:50:50 PM hi everyone ! am mahesh,just like you even am interested to open a chinese fast food center near SASTRA UNIVERSITY ( TANJORE),so please can u help me in this regard, i&apos;l be thankful to you if you reply me as soon as possible. can u please furnish me with all details like how much will be budget and how to get cooks 70. Nikita on 2/10/2011 4:28:55 PM Hey !! I want to open chinese restaurant in Russia. Nizhniy Novgorod. There are no places like this in that city. Can anyone help somehow any consultancy will be a great! How to start it. everything that can help . Thank you in advance!!!! 71. Ahmad Khan on 2/19/2011 12:50:57 PM Gents, I plan to start a regular chinese restaurant business in Lahore Pakistan. It should serve regular dinner and fast chinese food for lunch. Will appreciate any advice or sharing 72. Cornell on 3/4/2011 5:12:46 AM Hi, everyone my name is Cornell, I am an American stationed in the middle east, I have approval to open a chinese restaurant on a central military base, my challenge right know is acquiring supplies and getting setup, please can anyone help or point me in the right direction to get set up. thanks I can be reached at JermaineShotta@yahoo.com 73. Babatunde Adewunmi on 3/9/2011 3:32:01 AM I live in Lagos, Nigeria where the fast food/restaurant business is in the first percentile of least time ROI. I am in the process of opening one in the heart of Lagos and I would appreciate good start up information to guide me. My email address is tundeadewunmi@yahoo.co.uk. I eagerly await your response. Thank you. 74. Parvinder Walia on 3/10/2011 6:01:57 AM Hi, I AM INTERESTED TO START a RESTAURANT IN AUSTRALIA I HAVE TOTAL 10 YEAR EXP IN THIS LINE AND LOOKING FOR FINANCE PARTNER. AS I WILL BE WORKING PARTNER. THANKS PARVINDER.WALIA@GMAIL.COM 75. James on 3/10/2011 6:18:42 AM @Babatunde Adewunmi, it is good to know that you are planning to start a food business. There are so many things that a biz owner will have to go through in starting a business but where exactly you need the help? Let me know. 
Jestin James
Startup Biz Hub - Senior Advisor (Staff)
 76. Babatunde Adewunmi on 3/10/2011 11:37:22 AM @James, Mainly control issues (How to minimize cash losses or how to prevent loss due to collusion by staff), management issues and how to motivate your manager and staff. How to drive sales through the roof! I wouldn&apos;t be there always so i want to know how to bring out the best in my manager. I was also hoping you had some basic info template which one can read up for all restaurant owners. I am actually going through the learning curve right now and i believe advice from someone experienced will save me resources. Thank you. 77. James on 3/11/2011 9:48:58 PM @Babatunde Adewunmi, i am really sorry we have not prepared a restaurant owner&apos;s guide yet but i liked your idea and hopefully jump into it soon. Anyway, if you not gonna manage then the only way that i can see can put you on top of everything is by introducing commission stream to your manager/s. Buy a good insurance for accidents and offer about 10% commission to the manager. To motivate your staff have some friday activity, offer free food, let them take the tips, celebrate their special day, etc. 
Jestin James
Startup Biz Hub - Senior Advisor (Staff)
 78. jovan on 3/15/2011 12:18:17 PM hello my name is Jovany, i&apos;m planing to open chinese fast food in Serbia. can u help me with some details please? jovanpodrascic@yahoo.com 79. Nazia on 3/21/2011 5:41:26 AM I&apos;m interested in starting up a restaurant in hyderabad india, ready to invest, but need good ideas and good people to start up. is anyone who can help me out with the location in hyderabad and great ideas and help could email me. Wanted to have some unique and great ideas and some help with location. 80. Noel Peters on 4/15/2011 5:19:33 AM I am interested to open a chinese restaurant in Ambernath Please tell me how much is the minimum budget required to start a twenty seater medium size restaurant I have decided to start it on a rental shop and grow from there, I am new to restaurant line. I need to know all the details regarding setting up a kitchen, hiring cooks, material, recipes waiters, concepts, etc.., i am planning to target medium and upper medium customers, and also concentrate more on home deliveries. so please could you help me with the details on how to start and maintain it, my email id is noelmartin2000@yahoo.com. Location
Maharashtra-Thane-Ambernath (India) 81. Onna on 5/4/2011 8:14:29 AM I was thinking about opening a chinese fast food restaurant in Anaheim Hills Ca. I was wondering how much money do i need to get my business started? 82. J J on 5/11/2011 12:42:08 AM hi , is there a Chinese chef willing to come down here and work in our take out/delivery Chinese rest? thanks J J - Colombia +57 317 436 0304 jcatano@une.net.co 83. MC on 6/1/2011 3:51:29 PM Hi! I wanted to start a take-out only restaurant in Queensland, Australia. I would like to serve popular &quot;take-out&quot; type dishes (curry, chinese, filipino, finger foods, etc.) and not specialize in one style or origin of food. How do I go about starting the restaurant? Thanks! 84. Parvinder on 6/2/2011 7:09:35 AM hi MC just saw ur add im parvinder walia. ur concept of take out is good and will work in housing location let me know if any other info required. Look for chef if indian is required let me know i will arrange for u. contact me on parvinder.walia@gmail.com 85. domingo on 6/2/2011 4:33:11 PM i am a chinese cook, i know also japanese sushi cousine, help me to find job or employer around europe country. i am now in cyprus but i am willing and interested to go another country. thank you. 86. samreen mallick on 6/13/2011 7:25:09 AM i want to take franchise of yo china in gaya(bihar).i hav my own space in main town.jst need the guidence n plz tell wat will be the investment? 87. Ranjan kumar on 7/5/2011 4:38:39 AM I am interested to open a chinese restaurant in Delhi Please tell me how much is the minimum budget required to start a ten seater medium size restaurant I have decided to start it on a counter trolly on main market on and grow from there, I am new to this line. I need to know all the details regarding setting up a kitchen, hiring cooks, material, recipes waiters, concepts, etc.., i am planning to target medium and upper medium customers, and also concentrate more on home deliveries. so please could you help me with the details on how to start and maintain it, my email id is rimparanjan@gmail.com Location Delhi Mayur vihar phase 1 88. ANIRBAN BANERJEE on 7/22/2011 3:19:50 AM I want to open my own restaurant like fish&amp;chicken basis, i do not have any place, pls, suggest me how to start my own business to make new path of FOOD BUSINESS? 89. abdul aziz on 8/7/2011 3:15:40 AM hey !i want to buy any cafe in any university or college urgently please help me out ... any fast food ..!! thanks looking forward for the reply ..:) 90. Mrs.Tam on 8/17/2011 7:43:57 AM hi, my husband and I want to open a chinese restaurant in Sydney, Australia. We want to find partner because we are Chinese(partner can know communication in chinese will be better), we want to find a partner who has experience for open a restaurant in sydney. anyone want to join? thanks 91. arvin on 8/28/2011 6:09:31 AM Hi,to every body ,by the way. I am a chinese cook expert in wok cooking style 18 yrs exp, from phil. and from now on, I am here in kazakhstan and looking for a new employer .if somebody can help me just contact my email add.arcan_1973@yahoo.com thanks.... 92. Joanne hung on 9/6/2011 12:41:42 AM How can I contact those people who are interested to look for partners to open their restaurant from your site? I am a retiree interested in cooking Chinese home cook food and have proven delicious .will be interested to set up a small Chinese take away which I have done in England before. I am a Malaysian chinese now in china. Please advice. Thanks, I have no problem moving to other countries except India,or war zone countries. 93. KhaHung on 10/4/2011 2:37:54 AM Hi, I&apos;m opening a Chinese fast food restaurant. If you are interested in being hire for this wonderful opportunity. Feel free to contract me at khannahnguyen@yahoo.com thx ;) 94. shyle on 11/11/2011 8:16:15 AM i have this great idea for a chinese/african buffet restaurant. anyone interested in partnering with me here in biringham uk, please send a mail to lucien4luv@yahoo.com 95. shyle on 11/11/2011 8:20:11 AM please can i get the email of patrick fernando, he left a message up here. we sure can do business together. 96. Siddhy on 11/13/2011 4:32:57 AM hii!! i and my boyfriend want to open an chinese restaurant in sydney, AUSTRALIA i want to know how to go about it and what all is required to start regards to finance and other setup. I am basically in India and planning to go to sydney as soon as possible. my boyfriend is resident of Australia. Please advice. waiting for your reply. thanks. 97. Geeta Upadhyay on 11/23/2011 1:18:42 AM i am working in pvt company.Now i want to start new business like chinise restaurant or consultancy, i a BMA with HR 98. Imants Andersons on 12/4/2011 2:37:01 PM I&apos;m from capital of Latvia , Riga. And there is no Chinese fast food restaurant. Anyone interested can contact me andersons.imants@gmail.com 99. Alina on 12/5/2011 1:51:09 AM Hello, I have a dream to create Chinese fast food restaurant in my city Novorossiysk (Russia). There are 300 000 people live in Novorossiysk. We have no Chinese food at all. Pls give me some instructions. 100. Andrea on 12/9/2011 8:01:39 PM Hello, can you give me some advices and an idea how to open a Chinese restaurant in USA? thank you 101. Marzook Kamal Arabi on 12/26/2011 1:59:53 PM Good day. Thank you for giving this opportunity to make inquiries. I intend to start up a comprehensive chinese restaurant in Kaduna State, Nigeria. I have just one well trained cook. What is the requirement for the other supporting staff? Also, could you please provide me with some tips on how to organize and design the interior with suggested fittings. Thank you in anticipation of your response. 102. DEEPALI on 1/5/2012 3:10:10 AM Hello! Since long back I am planning to open a chinese restaurant but I don&apos;t have concerned experience and knowledge. Could you please give me the idea how much capital it needs to do the same on an initial level and what else is required, if I try to open it in Indore City. Thankyou.. 103. sunny on 1/12/2012 6:11:57 AM I WANT TO START A FAST FOOD REST IN DELHI. ANY ONE INTERESTED TO BE THE PARTNER: MAIL MGS68IN@YAHOO.COM 104. Lalita Sharma on 1/27/2012 4:10:55 AM Hello, I want to open a chinese restaurant in India,(Delhi-NCR location). Could you plz provide some tips how to start the rest and how to organize the restaurant. Thank You 105. Anand Choudhary on 2/16/2012 2:03:42 PM hello everyone.! I am currently running a Chinese restaurant here in bangalore. i have a good knowledge of the running the restaurant as i have been doing it past 2 years. now i&apos;m looking for partners who can work along with me. Interested persons can mail me or directly contact me on +91-9916676326. Thanks. 106. ANIL MORIYA on 3/7/2012 9:19:52 AM hi everyone .i would like to start a fast food business in karimnagar AP (INDIA) can you give the information regarding hiring cooks and where we can get them and how much we have to pay them for month and how much it cost to start business and where find cook and much more details want pls help me my id is ......anilmoriya89@yahoo.in 107. daffi on 3/26/2012 7:04:09 AM hi,i would like to know the idea of how to start my own restaurant,we currently have a small restaurant in town and we supply food also its a family business,so i want to make it big,i am also a student from hospitality management background and i am going to complete this year, kindly give me some idea regarding this matter. with your kindness I will remain thankful to you. 108. James on 3/26/2012 10:30:03 PM 
@daffi, you want to make it big so is it you want to increase the offerings or you want to go other places and open the same restaurant. As far as the business goes, you know everything as you already own one.
 
Jestin James
Startup Biz Hub - Senior Advisor (Staff)
 109. agbeleye ajayi cephas on 4/7/2012 3:42:46 PM hi, i am a young entrepreneur and am interested in setting up a Chinese restaurant in my town in Lagos, i will like to meet a consultant who specialize on this particular area and some other practical things that is involve in the set up, contact line 07035327160 110. Alexandra on 4/13/2012 6:42:06 AM Hello! We are planning to start up a chain of the Chinese fast food restaurants on the territory of the Russian Federation. We are looking for a Chinese partner. If you are interested, contact me: business-center-office@yandex.ru, +79160851335 111. Govind on 5/8/2012 12:37:28 AM Hi, I am Govind I want to start restaurant business in Chennai(India). I don&apos;t have any idea. Please explain how to start restaurant. First i want improve step by step so I think if I start Chinese fast food restaurant it will easy for me. Please help me. Thank you. Govind 112. Pratik on 5/12/2012 4:31:21 PM Hi, i am Pratik. I live in Mumbai , India and am looking forward for a partner in Chinese fast food restaurant outside India. I have worked in a chinese restaurant and gathered experience of many dishes first hand. I have chefs and other workers ,just need a partner who is interested in this joint venture. I have the work force&amp;knowledge of functioning of a chinese fast food restaurant. If interested we can open a restaurant on profit share basis. So plz revert back to me at pratik_bhoite666@yahoo.com Regards, Pratik 113. Ren Dev on 5/30/2012 8:49:52 AM I would like to open a Chinese food court in Hyderabad, only thing i am concerened is how to get cooks and waiters. i need Nepali waiters as they are good in customer care. Please help. 114. Daniel on 5/31/2012 11:07:20 AM Hi, my mane is Daniel, I&apos;m planning to open a chinese restaurant in UAE, Abu Dhabi, and it is located in the Mall so i&apos;m gonna need someone very professional at restaurant in-shop designing, pls you can contact me at: danielyang2010@gmail.com 115. Emmanuel on 5/31/2012 6:39:04 PM Hi, my name is Emmanuel Anyanwu, I&apos;m planning to open a Chinese restaurant in Owerri Imo State Nigeria, and it is located in the government area so i&apos;m gonna need someone very professional at restaurant in-shop designing, pls you can contact me at: epamchain@yahoo.com 116. Pramod Batham on 6/7/2012 3:23:54 AM Hi, my name is Pramod Batham. I&apos;m an Government Employee working as Office Assistant Grade- 2. I want to open a Small Chinese restaurant in MHOW, District Indore. MP, India. The location of Shop is infront of Veterinary College and other Colleges. (Full of Student area) Please give suggestion on opening a Small Chinese restaurant: Budget. Workers. percentages of profit. How can I get experience in this line. How can I able to open this. 117. Jo on 6/7/2012 11:45:00 AM I have open up a chinese restaurant recently in Hyderabad, India. I would like to have some idea on how to improve my restaurant business. It would be great if you could provide me some information on chinese restaurant business. 
 Name: 
 Email: 
 Comment: 
 Write your business location to help you better. Exp: City, State, Country 
 ( All the above fields are required. ) 
 

 Sign up for Newsletter 
Restaurant Business

 How to Start an Indian Restaurant Business Juice and Smoothie Bar Starting a Chinese Fast Food Restaurant Starting a Hostel Business Startup Sushi Restaurant 

Mobile Business Ideas

 How to Start Mobile Catering How to Start Your Own Charter Fishing Business How to Start a Mobile Spa Business Mobile Detailing Business Startup Kit How to Start Mobile Notary Business 

Farming Business Ideas

 How to Start a Poultry Farm Starting Chicken Farm Business Starting a Dairy Farm Business How to Start a Fish Farming Business Start a Rabbit Farm 

Service Business Ideas

 Starting a Recruitment Agency How to Start a Courier Business Starting Your Own Money Lending Business Starting Your Own Guest House Business Starting Your Own Computer Training Center 
 
 Advice for Small Business Business Insurance Information Business Marketing and Advertising Entrepreneur Business Idea Farming Business Ideas Financing a Small Business Free Business Ideas Home Based Business Opportunity Ideas for Small Business Instructor Guides Internet Business Ideas Professional Career Opportunities Repair Business Opportunity Restaurant Business Opportunities Retail Store Ideas Rural Business Opportunities Service Business Ideas Shop Business Ideas Small Business Articles Small Business Opportunities Small Manufacturing Business Starting Rental Business Startup Company Ideas Store Business Opportunities Tips for Buying and Selling Unique Business Opportunities Wholesale Business Opportunities 

Small Business Ideas

 How to Start a Towing Business How to Start a Trucking Business Starting a Taxi Business How to Start a Movie Theater How to Start a Shoe Business 

Small Business Articles

 How to Start a Gas Station How Much Does it Cost to Charter a Private Jet Starting a Night Club How Do You Calculate The Mark Up Price 

Home Based Business

 Starting a Home Health Agency How to Start a Home Baking Business Starting a Funeral Home Business Ideas for Home Based Business Starting a Woodworking Business 

Shop Business Ideas

 Starting a Pawn Shop Business How to Start a Meat Shop How to Start a Donut Shop How to Open a Sandwich Shop How to Start Auto Body Shop 

Store Business Opportunities

 Starting a Grocery Store Business Starting a Fashion Clothing Store How to Open a Liquor Store How to Start a Beauty Supply Store How to Start a Drug Store Business 

Startup Company Ideas

 How to Start a Tour Company How to Start a Security Company Start a Cosmetics Company How to Start a Skateboard Company Starting Your Own Repossession Company 
 Copyright©2007 - 2012 StartupBizHub.com. All Rights Reserved.
 About Us | Privacy | Contact Us 
 Site Map
	</body>
</document>
