<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009792" url="http://www.yelp.com/biz/fiesta-fast-food-los-angeles" time="2012-07-13-03:11" support="1" score="0.001978464908300301" bingtitle="Fiesta Fast Food - Highland Park - Los Angeles, CA" webtitle="Fiesta Fast Food - Highland Park - Los Angeles, CA">
			<query id="000446" bing-rank="15"/>
	<description>I just ordered 4 Medium size trays for a small party at work tomorrow and it&apos;s no problem for them to have the food ready for pick up at 12 noon the next day.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Real people. Real reviews. ® 
 
 Search for (e.g. taco, cheap dinner, Max&apos;s) 

 Near (Address, Neighborhood , City, State or Zip) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk 

 Member Search 
   
Fiesta Fast Food
 3 reviews 
 Categories: Restaurants Chinese Restaurants Filipino Chinese , Filipino   [Edit] 
 5532 York Blvd 
 Los Angeles , CA 90042 
Neighborhood: Highland Park
 (323) 255-5195 Add Photos Price Range: $ 
 Accepts Credit Cards: Yes
 Attire: Casual
 Good for Groups: Yes
 Good for Kids: Yes
 Take-out: Yes
 Waiter Service: No
 Outdoor Seating: No
 Wheelchair Accessible: Yes
 First to Review Jamie P. 
 Edit Business Info Work Here? Unlock This Business Page 
 Send to Friend Bookmark Send to Phone Write a Review 
3 reviews for Fiesta Fast Food
 Reviews Matching: Search Reviews Sort by: Yelp Sort | Date | Rating | Elites&apos; | Facebook Friends&apos; 
Facebook Friends


 
From Reviewers You&apos;re Following 


 
Reviews from Your Friends


 
3 reviews in English

 
Review from Jamie P. 
 
 1 friend 16 reviews 

 Jamie P. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 7/2/2008 
Small Filipino Fast Food Eatery with a small choice of already made items.  They only serve lunch on Tuesday through Friday.

The majority of their business is catering.  Their Shanghai lumpia is a good party dish which are small all meat egg rolls.  I&apos;ve ordered this and brought it to all different types of parties and the people are all over it.

Good pancit, crispy chicken and their Turon for dessert is not over sweetened with syrup and is real tasty.

This is the only Filipino restaurant/catering in Highland Park so all you Highland Park folks come on and support your local Flips.

Nice family who will work hard and prepare a good dish for you.  I just ordered 4 Medium size trays for a small party at work tomorrow and it&apos;s no problem for them to have the food ready for pick up at 12 noon the next day.

So give it a try and say hello to Minda.

Their located in a small plaza next to a dentist and coin operated laundry.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Joe W. 
 
 3 friends 47 reviews 

 Joe W. 
 
Temple City, CA
 11/30/2011 
Why only one star?  Because a group of co-workers ordered Lumpia&apos;s from Fiesta and when we drove all the way from the City of Commerce, the place was closed. The owner had totally forgotten about us coming when we called.  While he was cordial and all, it left a bad taste in my mouth.  I will give them another try and if they actually are there when they say they will be, I will adjust the review.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Cheryl L. 
 
 44 friends 152 reviews 

 Cheryl L. 
 
Inland Empire
 7/8/2010 1 Check-in Here 
I&apos;m writing about the Lumpia Shanghai-- that&apos;s it... That&apos;s because their lumpia at Fiesta is out of this world! You bring it to a party, and seriously, it&apos;s gone before you can even get to them!  Each tray is about 100 pieces for $20.00 and comes w/ the sweet chili dipping sauce.  Call ahead to order them- and they will be ready for pickup.  My mom goes here all the time and this was my first to do the pickup-- the service is really friendly and you can tell that they are family run and hard working.  Although not in the best of neighborhoods, at least there is a parking lot so you don&apos;t have to park far!
 
 Listed in:
	</body>
</document>
