<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009069" url="http://biggsthreeriversinn.com/" time="2012-07-13-02:28" support="2" score="0.0022189371097621866" bingtitle="Biggs Three Rivers Inn | The Dalles Motel, Biggs Hotel, Lodging" webtitle="Biggs Three Rivers Inn | The Dalles Motel, Biggs Hotel, Lodging">
			<query id="000811" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="000807" bing-rank="184"/>
	<description>... of The Dalles) at the intersection of I-84 and Hwy 97 (exit #104). It is the perfect place to ... There is a 24-hour family restaurant and 24-hour fast food restaurant within ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Our Amenities Our Rooms Rates and Reservations Local Attractions Contact Us Map 
 
 Se Habla Espanol 

 Biggs Three Rivers Inn (formerly Travelodge) is conveniently located 104 miles east of Portland (20 miles east of The Dalles) at the intersection of I-84 and Hwy 97 (exit #104).

It is the perfect place to stop whether you&apos;re on your way to Canada, Washington, Idaho, Montana, Nevada or points in between. With easy freeway access as well as fun-filled activities to keep everyone in the family happy, Biggs Three Rivers Inn is a great place to plan a stopover.

 Have a pet? No worries - Biggs Three Rivers Inn is pet friendly (for a small fee, with a three night maximum). They also have designated smoking and non-smoking rooms, free Internet service, complimentary continental breakfast as well as many other amenities . We cater to the business traveler and tourist alike. We also have plenty of parking to accommodate truck drivers as well.

The Columbia , Deschutes and John Day rivers are all nearby and provide ample opportunity for fishing, exploring and a plethora of water sports. The Mary Hill Museum Amphitheater and Winery are within five miles. There is a 24-hour family restaurant and 24-hour fast food restaurant within walking distance. Click here to see all of the other nearby attractions that you won&apos;t want to miss.
 Menu 
 Home Our Amenities Our Rooms Rates and Reservations Local Attractions Contact Us Map
	</body>
</document>
