<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009658" url="http://www.qsrweb.com/article/95574/Hardee-s-loads-up-its-breakfast-menu" time="2012-07-13-03:03" support="1" score="0.0021586881313069347" bingtitle="Hardee&apos;s loads up its breakfast menu | QSRweb.com" webtitle="Hardee&apos;s loads up its breakfast menu | QSRweb.com">
			<query id="001062" bing-rank="94"/>
	<description>&quot;After making buttermilk biscuits from scratch for over a quarter of a century, no other fast-food restaurant chain knows ... on its dollar menu and ... Mobile Payments; Other ...</description>
	<body>
		Get Free Membership | Sign In | Advertise 
 
 Home Features News Blogs Videos Photos Webinars White Papers Products&amp;Suppliers▼ 
 Companies by Name Companies by Category Products&amp;Services Submit RFI to Suppliers 
 Research Centers▼ 
 Customer Service / Experience Digital Signage Display Technology Equipment&amp;Supplies Food&amp;Beverage Food Safety Franchising&amp;Growth Health&amp;Nutrition Insurance / Risk Management Marketing / Branding / Promotion Menu Boards Online / Mobile / Social Operations Management Restaurant Design / Layout Staffing&amp;Training Sustainability Systems / Technology Trends / Statistics 
 Events ▼ 
 Retail Customer Experience Executive Summit August 6-8, 2012 | Chicago Foodservice Social Media Universe September 16-18, 2012 | Chicago Fast Casual Executive Summit October 21-23 | San Diego View Full Events Calendar 
 Project Help 
 Research Centers Customer Service / Experience Digital Signage Display Technology Equipment&amp;Supplies Food&amp;Beverage Food Safety Franchising&amp;Growth Health&amp;Nutrition Insurance / Risk Management Marketing / Branding / Promotion Menu Boards Online / Mobile / Social Operations Management Restaurant Design / Layout Staffing&amp;Training Sustainability Systems / Technology Trends / Statistics 
 
 Get help from all our vendors with one click. 
 
 
 
Hardee&apos;s loads up its breakfast menu
 Tags: Burger/Steak/BBQ , Food&amp;Beverage , Sandwich , Trends / Statistics April 18, 2010 - Christa Hoyland 
 Hardee&apos;s is fighting to keep its market share in the breakfast daypart as competition heats up in the morning. The brand has launched the new Loaded Biscuit &apos;N&apos; Gravy, a biscuit sandwich smothered with Hardee&apos;s sausage gravy.   &quot;After making buttermilk biscuits from scratch for over a quarter of a century, no other fast-food restaurant chain knows biscuits—or sausage gravy—like Hardee&apos;s does,&quot; Brad Haley, executive vice president of marketing for Hardee&apos;s Food Systems Inc., said in a news release. &quot;In fact, our Biscuit &apos;N&apos; Gravy has been one of our best-selling breakfast items for such a long time that we wanted to see if we could give people even more of a good thing by loading it up with eggs and sausage to make it more of a full breakfast. Breakfast lovers looking to fill up on flavor won&apos;t be disappointed.&quot;   The Loaded Biscuit &apos;N&apos; Gravy consists of two folded eggs and two sausage patties served open-faced on a freshly baked Made From Scratch buttermilk biscuit and covered with a generous serving of hot sausage gravy. It is available at participating Hardee&apos;s restaurants for $2.99 or in a small combo for $4.69, including crispy Hash Rounds and a beverage. Prices may vary by location.   Breakfast has been a hot topic over the last month as Burger King rolled out a McDonald&apos;s Sausage McMuffin clone on its dollar menu and Subway made its breakfast menu a national program, while Jack in the Box added a breakfast version of its new grilled sandwich line. Taco Bell is testing a breakfast menu that features branded products, and Wendy&apos;s continues to retool its morning menu. 
Related Content

 
 Commentary: &apos;Worst&apos; kids&apos; meal study full of holes 
 Will Instagram become a more effective marketing… 
 Recipe development efforts increase in childhood… 
 Get help from all our vendors with one click. 
 
 Reader Comments 
Add a Comment

We welcome your thoughtful comments. All comments will display your real name.
 
Want to participate in the discussion?

 Register for Free 

Or log in for complete access.
 Email me when comments are added. 
 Clear Post 
 Be the first to post a comment for this story. 
Features

 Commentary: &apos;Worst&apos; kids&apos; meal study full of holes Will Instagram become a more effective marketing tool than Facebook? Recipe development efforts increase in childhood obesity fight »View More Features 
 Sponsored by: 
News

 LevelUp eliminates merchant fees Aspiring food truck operators to battle during Food Network show Ohio State signs Tim Hortons as official coffee sponsor »View More News 
 
Blogs

 McDonald&apos;s, Coca-Cola in the middle of Olympic tug-o-war The service sucked, but that new logo looks great Some chains getting head start on menu transparency »View More Blogs 
 
User Comments

 There is a Denver restaurant chain that has done in my opinion the… Thank you SO MUCH for this article! I&apos;ve developed an ultra simple web… Thanks for your feedback, Josh. The numbers were pulled from recently… 
 Photo Gallery 
462

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show462_thumb6813.jpg

Hobart&apos;s Baxter Mini Rotating Rack Oven

Hobart&apos;s Baxter Mini Rotating Rack Oven

459

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show459_thumb6763.gif

McDonald&apos;s flagship Olympic restaurant

McDonald&apos;s flagship Olympic restaurant

456

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show456_thumb6715.gif

Burger King Summer 2012 menu

Burger King Summer 2012 menu

455

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show455_thumb6701.gif

Taco Bell&apos;s Cantina Bell menu

Taco Bell&apos;s Cantina Bell menu

452

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show452_thumb6515.gif

2012 NRA Show Kitchen Innovation winners

2012 NRA Show Kitchen Innovation winners

448

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show448_thumb6467.gif

Cheba Hut expanding footprint

Cheba Hut expanding footprint

446

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show446_thumb6424.gif

Burger King rolls out new menu, marketing initiatives

Burger King rolls out new menu, marketing initiatives

442

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show442_thumb6374.gif

Cousins Subs 40th anniversary makeover

Cousins Subs 40th anniversary makeover

433

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show433_thumb6178.gif

McDonald&apos;s nutritional kiosk

McDonald&apos;s nutritional kiosk

432

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show432_thumb6168.gif

Cold Stone Frozen Yogurt Creations

Cold Stone Frozen Yogurt Creations
 
 
Hobart&apos;s Baxter Mini Rotating Rack Oven
 
McDonald&apos;s flagship Olympic restaurant
 
Burger King Summer 2012 menu
 
Taco Bell&apos;s Cantina Bell menu
 
 »View More Photos Products&amp;Services 
Manitowoc Ice Machines

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/4871.png

4871/Manitowoc-Ice-Machines

DriverAdvisor Fleet Monitoring

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/DriverAdvisor_iix.gif

1425/DriverAdvisor-Fleet-Monitoring

MVR Reports

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/MVR_Report_iix.gif

1252/MVR-Reports

Business Intelligence

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/4241.png

4241/Business-Intelligence

Executive Briefing and Exchange

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/4237.png

4237/Executive-Briefing-and-Exchange

Kronos Scheduling

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/1853.png

1853/Kronos-Scheduling

Digital Signage PC Solution with Maximum Flexibility

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/philipsicon.jpg

4011/Digital-Signage-PC-Solution-with-Maximum-Flexibility

Philips Video Walls

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/4174.png

4174/Philips-Video-Walls

Social Security Number (SSN) Verification

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/SSN_employmentsearch.gif

1426/Social-Security-Number-SSN-Verification

LG M4225CCBA - 42&quot; class (42.0&quot; measured diagonally)

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/4312.png

4312/LG-M4225CCBA-42-class-42-0-measured-diagonally
 
 
Manitowoc Ice Machines
 
DriverAdvisor Fleet Monitoring
 
MVR Reports
 
Business Intelligence
 
 »View More Products Most Popular 
 Read Emailed Discussed 
 
 Will Instagram become a more effective marketing tool than Facebook? Digital menu boards showing up on food trucks National Restaurant Association reports continued restaurant job growth Remodeled Wendy&apos;s units exceeding 25 percent sales growth Taco Bell promotes Cantina line with BOGO Facebook deal 
 
 No data available. 
 
 Commentary: McDonald&apos;s Skinner retiring with strong legacy in place Customer feedback provides key for location-specific improvements Burger King hosts Design the Crown contest for trip to Legoland Top trends listed from National Restaurant Association Show Franchise lending up 6 percent year over year 
 Sponsored by: White Papers 
 Newest Popular 
 
 Three Strategies for Developing In-House Service and Support Teams Labor Economics: An Assessment of Labor Management Standards for the Restaurant Industry Everything You Need to Know About Bar Refrigeration Refrigeration for Pizza Restaurants Four Strategies to Negotiating a Rent Reduction 
 
 Infographic: 12 Benefits of Digital Menu Boards Three Strategies for Developing In-House Service and Support Teams Improving Restaurant Scheduling Executive Summary: Restaurant State of the Industry Report 2011, Part I: Food and Beverage Digital Display Technology: Learning the Basics of Digital Signage 
 Video Gallery NRA 2012: Georgia Pacific Professional NRA 2012: PeopleMatter HR solutions NRA 2012: Online ordering »View More Videos Request Information From Suppliers Save time looking for suppliers. Complete this form to submit a Request for Information to our entire network of partners. Tell us what you&apos;re looking for... 
 Inside Networld Media Group Network 

 Pizza Marketplace 
 LevelUp eliminates merchant fees Aspiring food truck operators to battle during Food Network show Master franchisee for Papa John&apos;s India names new CEO 

 Popular on Networld Media Group 
 Pizza Industry Report Fast Casual: State of the Industry Report Fast Casual Top 100 Social Media ROI for Restaurants Maximizing ROI for Restaurants with Self-Service Mobile Payments 
 Other Networld Media Group Sites 
 ATM Marketplace Church Central Digital Signage Today Fast Casual Fast Casual Executive Summit Kiosk Marketplace Pizza Marketplace QSR Web Retail Customer Experience Retail Customer Experience Executive Summit Self-Service World 
 Global Partners 
 Digital Screenmedia Association LG Electronics USA, Inc. NEC Display Solutions 
 


 QSRweb.com Home | Showcases | Privacy Policy | Submit RFI | Editorial Policy | About Us | Contact Us 

 Bloggers | Advertise | Mobile Version | Site Map | RSS | News Panel 

 ©2012 Networld Media Group All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
