<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009571" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/248/1151462/restaurant/Northwest-Omaha/Blue-Sushi-Sake-Grill-Omaha" time="2012-07-13-02:57" support="1" score="0.0005564710367593068" bingtitle="Blue Sushi Sake Grill - Northwest Omaha - Omaha | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Blue Sushi Sake Grill - Northwest Omaha - Omaha | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="001264" bing-rank="216"/>
	<description>You get better consistency of food and service at a fast food restaurant. ... go their Happy Hour on Fri, Sat, and Sun. They also have good selection ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Omaha » Omaha » Northwest Omaha » Blue Sushi Sake Grill 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Des Moines Kansas City Los Angeles New York Oklahoma City Tulsa Twin Cities More... 
 
Blue Sushi Sake Grill

 View all 3 Blue Sushi Sake Grill locations 
 
(402) 445-2583
 Northwest Omaha 14450 Eagle Run Dr 
 Omaha , NE 68116 
 bluesushisakegrill.com 
 on facebook.com 
 See all 66 reviews Cuisine Sushi , Japanese , Asian Features Free Wi-Fi , Gluten-Free Friendly , Happy Hour , Late Night , Outdoor Dining , Romantic , Takes Reservations , Vegan Friendly Menu $$ $10-15 per entree Crispy Crawfish, South Pacific, Cali rolls, Rolls and Nigiri, Hawaiian Roll View menu | Add menu photo 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Dinner ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Late ✓ ✓ 
   963 people have voted 83 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 Thai Spice 89% $$ Northwest Omaha - Thai 2933 N 108th St 
 
 7M Grill 88% $$$ Northwest Omaha - International, Bistro 15805 W Maple Rd 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews

 February 1, 2012 Likes it Down Home Foodie The crawfish was crunchy and spicy, the pickle was tangy and crunchy, and the sauce was the icing on the cake that brought it all together. More from Down Home Foodie January 9, 2012 Likes it Adventures and Scars Even their happy hour roll selection is great (which again, is more than I can say for others). If you are going, try the&quot;blue balls,&quot;but get your mind out of the gutter first. More from Adventures and Scars July 28, 2008 Jack Jackson&apos;s Go Take a Nap! Much had been heard and said about Blue, so I tried Baby Blue. I got a strong sense of Baby Blue not quite being grown up yet. There was a general sense of not being ready for walking... More from Jack Jackson&apos;s Go Take a Nap! July 19, 2007 Likes it Gastronomic Fight Club What better way to celebrate the 4th of July than to celebrate our nation&apos;s diversity? After all, what is America if not a melting pot of different cultures and flavors. And since we have... More from Gastronomic Fight Club 
 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 April 23, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it Horrible! Really, really HORRIBLE! by JamesForJesus ( 124 reviews ) What&apos;s the deal with these restaurants owned by the same people - Blue, Roja, the former Bianco...their food is ALWAYS mediocre, always overpriced, and the staff is always rude, obnoxious, and snobby. Blue is no exception. Went there for dinner recently, and the hostess was rude, the waitress was rude, and the food was overpriced for what you get. Seriously - STAY AWAY! 4 out of 4 found this review helpful 
 May 27, 2011 A reply from Megan Longo at Blue Sushi Sake Grill I&apos;m sorry to hear you had a bad experience. We&apos;d love to correct any issues you experienced and also make it up to you. If you can provide an approx date, time and description of your server, we will look further into it. Sincerely, Megan  -mlongo@flagshiprestaurantgroup.com 
 February 1, 2012 Likes it Crispy Crawfish by Katie Robbins ( 16 reviews ) Crispy Crawfish -
Great fried pickles. Super tasty dipping saucy. Crunchy and spicy crawfish. +2 more review from Katie Robbins February 1, 2012 Hawaiian Roll Hawaiian Roll -
tempura fried, salmon, crab, mango, and mirin mango puree Good crunch and flavor balance. A little sweet, but I think the other components offset it well. February 1, 2012 South Pacific South Pacific -
eel tempura, cream cheese, pineapple, scallion, and eel sauce Awesome: spicy, crunchy, sweet, and creamy July 3, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it Meh. by CM ( 17 reviews ) Just OK sushi, definitely not worth what they&apos;re charging for it. You&apos;ll wait forever for a table and the servers will probably be rude. The last time I was there (and I mean the last time ever), we were outright lied to by the hostess about table availability. Once we were seated, our waitress was curt and rude and our food and drinks took an overly long time to arrive. There are much better places for sushi in Omaha, I strongly suggest you skip this one. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful 
 July 27, 2011 A reply from Megan Longo at Blue Sushi Sake Grill I&apos;m so sorry for your experience. If you&apos;re able to provide more info. about the date/time of your visit, I&apos;d love to opportunity to address service issues with our staff. Best, Megan 
 July 2, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it highly overrated by webninja ( 29 reviews ) Bad service, bad chefs, bad service, bad management, annoying customers and bad service. I went with a party of 10 and they forgot my daughter&apos;s order. It took an hour and half to serve 1 salmon roll looooooooong after everyone&apos;s food was already served. The rice is always cold and smashed beyond recognition. When we complained the waitress actually started crying. Sometimes the fish is fresh, sometimes it isn&apos;t. You get better consistency of food and service at a fast food restaurant. I get the feeling people don&apos;t go to Blue for the food. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful April 30, 2009 Doesn&apos;t like it Meh by ace3 ( 16 reviews ) Food isn&apos;t terrible, and the cucumber water is a nice touch. However, the servers, clientele and general&quot;better than you&quot;attitude of the place is a little ridiculous. It&apos;s Omaha, people. Speeding up your service (at least at the 144th/Maple location) sure would be a nice touch. I&apos;m not in any hurry to return. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful October 5, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it painful service. by Nomzilla ( 49 reviews ) The food is good the service can use work. The menu is fairly diverse and the rolls are made well and consistant. I eat at Blue often - and often at the requests of others but the service annoys me everytime. The wait staff is slow, I am always waiting to order. I am waiting for everything - my drink order, my regular order, a drink refill, to getting my check. With the number of wait staff there I am confused on why the staff seems to constantly be running but always late? Also taken back a couple times by the greet staff&apos;s assessment of their customers. I have waited to be seated and watched the hostess (more then one on more then one occasion) look guests up and down as they are entering or standing around waiting. Hey - I might not wear that either but I wouldn&apos;t openly stare or give sideway glances. It&apos;s unnerving and not very professional. Overall this is not my first choice sushi restaurant but due to the popularity amongst friends I will probably be back - thank goodness their food is decent otherwise I wouldnt even bother. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful May 7, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it typical omaha sushi by Food Lover ( 33 reviews ) why true...it is one of the better sushi places in omaha....it&apos;s still not up to par with TRUE sushi places outside of this city. it&apos;s traditional american sushi, where the fish you&apos;re paying for in the sushi is overpowered by untraditional ingredients that don&apos;t exactly compliment the fish, but is rather added as an after thought to appeal to the american masses as in&quot;oh that sounds good, i love avocados lets add that to the roll&quot; if you&apos;re looking fro more traditional sushi that is reasonably priced, go to bellevue to beijiing/tokyo 
 May 27, 2011 A reply from Megan Longo at Blue Sushi Sake Grill Thank you for your feedback. While we offer maki that appeals to a broader audience, we also cater to sushi&quot;purists&quot;. Check out our nigiri, sashimi or new world sashimi next time you&apos;re in. 
 September 9, 2010 Likes it Sunday Happy Hr by Omaha Lady ( 23 reviews ) We enjoy going to Blue on Sundays for their all day happy hour. After trying sushi at a few other places in Omaha, I&apos;d recommend Blue for having some of the better sushi in town. We also like the lettuce wraps, crab cakes, edamame&amp;chicken satay. The downfall of their happy hour is that it&apos;s always packed&amp;they have a limited area for happy hour. Fortunately, you can get Blue&apos;s same happy hour next door at Red!!! 1 out of 1 found this review helpful August 30, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by MW 007 ( 21 reviews ) Ate here on my birthday. Do to the dinning area being full, we ate upstairs in the lounge which was actually quieter. Sushi was excellent as well as their cooked meals. Like most trendy places you don&apos;t get a whole bunch of food for the price but the quality and taste of the food was wonderful! February 17, 2012 Mobile review by AZK ( 1 review ) Tom and his crew are artists! I&apos;m in Omaha for business for a short stay and have made this cuisine my meal of choice for a few weeks now. After a rough week at work this is the perfect place to unwind, enjoy hood company, and be taken care of--top notch. Tom takes time to get to know his customers and really does an admirable job leading his team! So excited to hear about the new Denver location! If only Tom got a raise so he could open a location in Scottsdale! Come south Blue!! March 27, 2009 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Redlion ( 9 reviews ) Service is rude and the fish is rotten - I have eaten sushi all over the world&amp;I don&apos;t the blue sushi is good for consumption - Sushi should be prepared by anartisan master chef or at least under his supervision - sushi blue is simply pulling fish out of can&amp;letting it sit at room temp for a few hours before serving. Not for me. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful December 4, 2009 Really likes it Sushi is always Great... by Schadenfreude ( 29 reviews ) I&apos;ll give the ambiance 4stars. Sushi is always GREAT! Service is&quot;ALWAYS&quot;mediocre at best! November 14, 2009 Likes it Mobile review by Michael ( 32 reviews ) I love Blue except sometimes the service can be poor. Happy hour is great. December 28, 2011 Likes it by John ( 9 reviews ) Fresh food great service. Prices are fair April 14, 2009 Likes it Mobile review by Adam O ( 28 reviews ) My favorite sushi spot in town. Sushi is not the tastiest in town, but its very good and at a good price during happy hour. Late night weekend happy hour is about the best in town for food, sushi, beer and $5 martinis. January 5, 2009 Likes it I like it! by Nat ( 62 reviews ) I like their atomosphere. All blue in the store and has water fall and fish tank. I like bonsai decoration on the shelf. Sushi is decent both price and taste ( I am from Japan so it&apos;s hard to find good sushi in Omaha). I always go their Happy Hour on Fri, Sat, and Sun. They also have good selection for martini. November 26, 2011 Likes it Funky&amp;Fresh! by DiningOutInOmaha ( 14 reviews ) Blue Sushi Sake Grill is Omaha&apos;s #1 sushi restaurant. Starting with a wide selection of unique drinks complete with their very own infused vodka. The hot and cold plates are all to die for! Each has just the right amount of food and the perfect taste for your palate. There is a large variety of sushi and sashimi to choose from. Each roll is fully loading with delicious fillings, complete with just thr right touch. Blue Sushi Sake Grill catering is a perfect choice for that funky fresh feel you want to give to any event! June 14, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it Good Sushi / Good Atomosphere by gabrieljoo ( 22 reviews ) Good Sushi - Good Atomosphere. Fuzzy on the prices&amp;services. The reason I say that, is the people who are making the rolls out in the back lacks skills to make the best rolls in the house. Most high-end sushi places have an experienced chef, to make the specialty rolls - such as dragon rolls / or with cavair: rolls that costs over $30. Missing the art behind making these famous rolls, I ordered them. Some of their rolls are absolutely lame. Don&apos;t go for dragon roll / or with cavair. They are all caterpillar (simple, rould, flat, straight) rolls. I would go back, only because Omaha lacks choices when it comes to sushi. This place is barely in my rotation - and I wouldn&apos;t hesitate to drop it. March 9, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it Great&quot;Meet&quot;market, Bad Sushi by Andrew Gilbert ( 27 reviews ) At least the wait staff is cute. This isn&apos;t sushi. It may be for a lot of Omaha and the midwest. 75 different kinds of rolls and 10 different Nigiri choices do not a sushi restaurant make. The&quot;Blue&quot;family (I think there are 3) are trendy. They are a great people watching place. If you are single it might be a great place to hook up on the weekend. (or, for all I know during the week) Entertaining people from out of town who like sushi? There are other good Japanese restaurant choices in Omaha. Looking to let loose and have fun - Blue might be your place. February 21, 2011 Likes it good if you can afford it by Jesse T ( 10 reviews ) Too pricy. Its my only complaint. Sushi was spot on and perfect temperature. Rolls were extra long (8-12pc). Atmosphere is fresh and modern, if slightly loud. Wait staff was no trouble for us unlike some other reviewers. Overall it was great, i just got the feeling i was paying 30% or more on top of most other sushi places, just to eat it at Blue. 
 Show 40 more 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by Katie Robbins Crispy Crawfish by Katie Robbins South Pacific 
 All 12 photos View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Red Lounge 76% $ Northwest Omaha - Sushi, Tapas The Cove Lounge&amp;Grille 36% $ Northwest Omaha - Pub Food China Buffet 81% $$ Northwest Omaha - Buffet, Chinese, Asian Chipotle Mexican Grill 82% $ Northwest Omaha - Mexican, Fast Food Donut Professor 86% $ Northwest Omaha - Donuts 
 More nearby restaurants 
Nearby Places

 Marcus 20 Grand -
14304 W. Maple Rd 
 People reached this page by searching for: 
 blue sushi omaha blue sushi blue sushi sake grill reviews baby blue sushi omaha baby blue sushi 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
