<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009738" url="http://www.complaintsboard.com/bysubcategory/fast-food-restaurants/?page=8" time="2012-07-13-03:08" support="3" score="0.007874899487129817" bingtitle="Complaints Board - Consumer Complaints, Reviews, Information ..." webtitle="Complaints Board - Consumer Complaints, Reviews, Information | Fast Food Restaurants, Page 8">
			<query id="000231" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000600" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="000888" bing-rank="64"/>
	<description>Contact Allied Irish Bank (Your Order Number PFCDC726091 ... coffee, and I want to keep comming back to drink ... wendy&apos;s fast food restaurant</description>
	<body>
		The most trusted and popular consumer complaints website 
 
 Everything 
 Everything Complaints Articles News&amp;Stories Recalls Videos Groups Questions 
 Home News&amp;Stories Tips&amp;Tricks Questions Videos Photos Recalls Groups Submit Complaint Connect With: Login Register 
 
 
 
Recently Discussed Complaints
 1. (0 mins ago) 
 Club Pogo 
cannot log into my acct. 2. (0 mins ago) 
 KIMBERLY GLASNAPP 
ANIMAL RESCUE FRAUD 3. (3 mins ago) 
 PCS Stamps and Coins 
Sending unsolicited items and then demanding payment for items we didn&apos;t order 4. (3 mins ago) 
 Beatrice Marot PSYCHIC FRAUD AND INTERNET STALKER 
SHE IS A FRAUD AND A STALKER! DO NOT USE HER SERVICES!! 5. (10 mins ago) 
 Beatrice Marot, so called Psychic Reader 
She Has Stalked&amp;Bullied Me For Two Years! 


Consumer Tips&amp;Tricks
 
 
 
    10 Incentives for Renters to Become Homeowners 
 
 
 
    Is Spring Break in Cancun Still Safe? 
 
 
 
    How to Speed Through Airport Security 
 

 
Latest News&amp;Stories
 
    French Total wins gas drilling tender 
 
    Deceptive Marketing For Prepaid Calling Cards Targeting Immigrants 
 
    Who&apos;s Paying For What? Washington Takes Aim at Secret Political Money 
 


Latest Questions
 transcript sueing cr england not getting my welfare check from govement Neotel SA NO RESPONSE MY MISSING MOBILE PHONE E-MAIL 

 
 
 
Fast Food Restaurants Complaints
 Sort by: Date | Popularity 
 
 tim hortons 
 
 Posted: 2012-01-03 by    captain0terror 
 
 
 customer service 
 Complaint Rating: Hello,
I am sorry to complain, but i have had a horrible experience at one of stores at:

2760 Niagara Falls Blvd, Tonawanda NY, 14150
(716) 690-9935

I went to this tim&apos;s(which is right by my house) around midnight, like i do EVERY NIGHT before... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 KFC 
 
 Posted: 2012-01-02 by    a voicu 
 
 
 rude staff 
 Complaint Rating: hi i got my lunch last week in kfc dublin ireland swords pavilions 29-12-2012 round 15 pm . the staff there they are the most rude people i have ever seen i ask them to give me one of there burgers and they said they dont have that one only if i get one of there meals wich is not right and the... Comments Ireland Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 subway westbrook mall calgary 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-29 by    canadapeek 
 
 
 unhygenic and dirty 
 Complaint Rating: I frequent the Westbrook mall in Calgary South West. The worst subway is located in this mall. The staff are very dirty and unhygenic - and they jabber a lot being from the phillipines in their language. Recently i have seen a new caucasian lady (perhaps manager) very rude and equally unhygenic.... Comments Canada , Alberta , Calgary Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Cici&apos;s Pizza 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-23 by    anothermashfan 
 
 
 Health code 
 Complaint Rating: My husband and I went to the Watertown N.Y. location, we had never been to a CiCi&apos;s before. The food was so-so. It was the health and sanitation practices that were sadly lacking! First we saw a employee sweep off a messy table with a broom used on the floor, we know this because we saw... Comments United States , New York , Watertown NY Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Burger King 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-23 by    Malcolm J. 
 
 
 Worst Service at Burger King Restaurant 
 Complaint Rating: I just went to Burger King and waited at the drive thru speaker for about 15 minutes behind two cars, who were also waiting. There was one car sitting at the actual window waiting on food. I was looking for a way to exit when the cars started to move forward. I reached the ordering speaker,... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Taco Bell 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-22 by    T_frank_w 
 
 
 Onions 
 Complaint Rating: I&apos;m tired of going to taco bell and getting a supreme taco with onions all over it. Ive NEVER have gotten onions on it and why is it changed? I almost choked to death after first biting into the supreme taco and while not expecting onions I got them. I will not be going to a taco bell for... Comments United States , Illinois , Joliet Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Subway 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-21 by    allias324 
 
 
 Horrible manager 
 Complaint Rating: I went to your SUBWAY location on *** at about 4 or 5pm. The location is 5628-1 Pelican Strand Blvd Naples, FL 34110...I went to this location to use a coupon I received from another new subway.. It was a bogo 6 inch coupon. The employee rudely said&quot;this is a photocopy of a coupon.. this... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 MCDONALDS UCF 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-21 by    melissa009 
 
 
 rude stupid mean employees, serve bad tea with specks of white floating around in it disgusting 
 Complaint Rating: I have no clue if mcdonalds served me poisonous tea or specs of crap floating around in it but this is truly DISGUSTING. Do NOT go to this mcdonalds if you want to be served any kind of decent food or beverage I just left there after being served tea with at least 50 specks of WHITE floating... Comments United States , Florida , Orlando Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Taco Bell 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-18 by    Geri Goeb 
 
 
 foreign obect in food 
 Complaint Rating: My son and I ordered taco bell from the drive thru this location on 12/16/2011 at 9:35PM. He was eating his burrito and bit into a thick piece of jagged plastic the size of a coin! Thank goodness he didn&apos;t swallow it or we would have been at the emergency room.
We went back to the... Comments United States , Wisconsin , Oak Creek Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 McDonalds 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-15 by    Doifule 
 
 
 Wrongful treatment at the work place 
 Complaint Rating: Barb employed me back in aug of 2009 she has been hell on wheels she is the owner she did not have me a uniform for three months yet i start paying the day i started i complained she said it was the uniform people who insist that they were not getting paid i never been compensated for that not... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 McDonalds 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-13 by    brownie 
 
 
 Very bad food experience 
 Complaint Rating: I went into a McDonalds the other day with a coupon I received a while back for a free iced drink with the purchase of one. I ordered a buger and some fries as well. When I received the food, the fries were old, brown and crusty. Clearly several hours old. I asked them if I could have a new... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Mc Donalds 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-13 by    Siltue 
 
 
 Pubic hair on fry order 
 Complaint Rating: Ordered through drive-thru, got home, daughter noticed a hair at bottom of fry bag, I checked only to see it wasnt only a hair, but it happened to be a pubic hair.I called immedietly, spoke with manager and complaint about it .what I should have done is gone in person and embarrass everyone... Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Sonic 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-13 by    Kruebbes 
 
 
 menu change and poor service 
 Complaint Rating: I was in love with the sonic croissants until recently. They still show the picture of what they used to sell but when you get it, instead of the egg patty, you get this mutilated liquid egg thing thats paper thin and full of pepper and pieces of burger off the grill. I tried to make a complaint... Comments United States , Louisiana , Patterson Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 KFC Walvis Bay 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-13 by    mwelgemoed 
 
 
 No Cheese 
 Complaint Rating: 13 December 2011

This afternoon at 15:00 we went to KFC Walvis Bay to buy burgers. At the counter I ordered a Hawaiian Burger, the lady behind the counter told me they have no cheese. This not the first time we had problems with this KFC. I don&apos;t understand how you can run... Comments Namibia Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Taco Bell 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-13 by    provoriver 
 
 
 Toe Nail found in Bean/Cheese Burrito 
 Complaint Rating: Do Not eat at Taco Bell particuarly in Hemet Ca. We purchased a few Bean/Cheese burritos and found a large human toe nail clipping inside our Burrito! Talk about disgusting we were totally without words when we nearly swallowed this while taking a bite out of the burrito. Taco Bell&apos;s attitude... Comments United States , California , Hemet Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Taco Bell 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-11 by    bad sandwich 
 
 
 triple steak stack 
 Complaint Rating: I want to complain about how the triple steak stack look. It didn&apos;t look nothing like the food on the commercial. The sandwich was running over out of the rapper. Worst sandwich I ever had. The Graham store I believe needs some new management ASAP! Can&apos;t eat there ever again!... Comments United States , North Carolina , Graham Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Wendys /Large Vanilla Frosty 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-08 by    Brown-Beauty 
 
 
 the amount for the price!!!!! 
 Complaint Rating: About a month or so ago I purchased a large frosty. ($2.19) It was filled to the rim of the cup and then there was the domed lid. I stopped again and when I was given it, I said something to the girl that it was not full!!! She said we can only fill it to the line! Which is almost 1 inch below... Comments United States , Ohio , Willard Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Great Kitchens Pte Ltd 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-07 by    aviopack 
 
 
 Fraud from Singapore 
 Complaint Rating: They order two shipments from us and we paid all freight in advance. Finally they pick up air shipment themself and ask us to get back second shipments without any reason.They treat the busienss like the game. When we try to reach them for freight and balance payments, they decline to answer... Comments Singapore Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 IHOP 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-04 by    N3420Q 
 
 
 SLOW UNCARING MANAGER 
 Complaint Rating: The manager was asked to change a $100.00 bill and took fifteen (15) minutes to get the money to the server. When asking the manager why it took 15 minutes SHE said she was busy with other matters. She acted uncaring and as though she was making a statement that a customer should not pay their... Comments United States , Louisiana , Harvey Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 Pizza Hut 
 
 Posted: 2011-12-04 by    Richard1897 
 
 
 Employee Mistreatment 
 Complaint Rating: I have worked for Pizza Hut for 6yrs and feel that the employees which I&apos;m still one of are mistreated. We are the modern day equivalent of SLAVE LABOR. I have yet to receive a raise in my pay. I&apos;m constantly doing everyone&apos;s jobs. One of my mangers that is supposed to work as... Comments United States , Florida , Gainesville Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 Previous 1 ... 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 ... 120 Next 
 
    Submit complaint 
Videos
 Credit Report Ripoff? 
 More Videos 

   
 

 
Latest Groups
 Stop underarm sweating MAKING AND SAVING MONEY Diamonds International Fraud seogo Paul J. Hooten&amp;Associates, Debt Co... 

 
Today&apos;s Mess-Up Photo
 Out Of Drama 
 
 More Mess-ups 

 
 
 
   
 Submit Complaint | Consumer Tips&amp;Tricks | News&amp;Stories | Recalls | Groups | View full list of Companies | Updated Complaints | Complaints | Suspicious Companies | Complaints by Countries | Latest Complaints | Terms of Use | Privacy Policy | DMCA Procedures | Investors / Business Offers | Legal Information | Thank you Emails 

©2012 Consumer Complaints Board 
If you have any constructive thoughts, creative ideas, or reasonable offers, please, contact us immediately via E-mail 
 
 
         
 
Login
 
 Email: Password: 
 
 
 Forgot your password?
	</body>
</document>
