<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009546" url="http://www.yumyucky.com/2009/07/i-heart-wendys-boneless-chicken-not.html" time="2012-07-13-02:56" support="1" score="0.001855520168738443" bingtitle="I *heart* Wendy&apos;s Boneless Chicken…NOT! | Yum Yucky" webtitle="I *heart* Wendys Boneless ChickenNOT!
 | Yum Yucky">
			<query id="000260" bing-rank="140"/>
	<description>The only fast food restaurant we ever eat at anymore is Chick-fil-a ... person preparing them put the nuggets in the tray ... Order now. Shakeology Breakfast Cookie. Shakeology 3 ...</description>
	<body>
		About Contact Press The Greedy Family 
 
 Yum Yucky 

Find Balance Between Fitness and Your Greedy Side
 
 Home Before/After Pics Home Workout Central Food Trap Alerts! Greedy Recipes Shakeology 
 
I *heart* Wendy&apos;s Boneless Chicken…NOT!
 July 13, 2009 By yumyucky 19 Comments 
 

While suffering through brain block in an attempt to sum up the catastrophe that is Wendy’s Boneless Chicken, the commercial for their Sweet&amp;Spicy Asian variety splathered onto my TV screen.

Bingo! Thanks to TiVo, I rewound the commercial about five times to get a clear take on Wendy’s description of the Sweet&amp;Spicy Asian Boneless Wings I had earlier in the day. (The other supposed“chicken temptation”varieties are Honey BBQ and Bold Buffalo )

 Sweet&amp;Spicy Asian: Wendy’s vs. Josie 

 Wendy’s says: “The chicken is tender, juicy, and lightly breaded.” Josie says: The breading is soggy. Some pieces are slightly tender while others look and taste dry. It’s nothing like the good taste of Wendy’s nuggets. 

 Wendy’s says: “The sauce is a mouth watering blend of sweet&amp;spicy.” Josie says: NOT! The sauce is nasty. Health-hater husband equates it drowning cheap chicken in packets of McDonald’s sweet&amp;sour nugget sauce. 

 Wendy’s says: “Every bite delivers a kick of Asian chiles, real red pepper flakes, and a hint of garlic” Josie says: The worse Chinese I ever tasted (at an American buffet) had better Asian flavor…and I tasted zero garlic. 

 Wendy’s says: “It’s about as far as it gets from fast food.” Josie says: It’s about as close as it gets to“Oh hell no! I’m driving back to Wendy’s to demand a refund!” 

To add to the insanity, I’m not certain if I got seven pieces or nine. A few pieces were either giving birth or had a mutant Siamese twin. I don’t have the scoop on Honey BBQ, but judging from some Grub Grade readers who say that Bold Buffalo is a bust , I’m not stepping foot near any of these again.

 Boneless Wings Notes 

 Price Paid: $3.99 520 calories–Bold Buffalo 550 calories–Sweet&amp;Spicy Asian 580 calories–Honey BBQ 

 Reactions from the Taste Test Crew 

 Health-hater Husband: It’s terrible. I can’t eat anymore. Cook me up some of those Dinosaur Chicken Nuggets from the freezer. 
 
 Greedy Kid #2: My entire basketball team ate these while we were on the road.
I kinda like it, but I’d only eat if it somebody else is paying. 
 
 Yum UP! to: TiVo.

 Y uck Down to: Wasting my money on nastiness. I could’ve bought some Go Wraps instead.

View the complete Taste Test Directory and Fast Food Cheat Sheets .

 

 “Cook me up some Dino nuggets, woman!” 


 “Yes, baby, anything for you” 
 Filed Under: Taste Test Reviews 
Share this Post with Your Friends
 Twitter Share on Facebook Email“I *heart* Wendy&apos;s Boneless Chicken…NOT!”to a Friend Reddit Stumble Upon Digg 
Comments

 Erica says: July 13, 2009 at 7:23 am 
I’m not going to lie- when I saw the commercial…I was a little scared by these haha.
 Reply Erin Brooks says: July 13, 2009 at 7:28 am 
Ya I wasn’t impressed by these either. I don’t trust a non Asian food place to try and make some of their non Asian food Asian lol. Sorry for your mutated chicken. 
 Reply Ren says: July 13, 2009 at 11:33 am 
I’ve never thought these looked appealing in the first place, but one of my daughters likes the Buffalo version.
Those dinosaur nuggets, on the other hand, are better than I expected!
 Reply Michael JB says: July 13, 2009 at 1:14 pm 
the dino nuggets are cute! 
 Reply Jody - Fit at 51 says: July 13, 2009 at 4:01 pm 
UGH!!!! I just watched a FoodNetwork Challenge on food stylists&amp;how they make that food look so good in pics&amp;on commercials&amp;they are using some nasty stuff to make it look good.. even healthy food! Makes ya really wonder. I always knew the look in ads vs. what you get is way different but to see what they do. CRAP!
Well, neither me nor my not so healthy lover hubby will be going near these!
 Reply Diane Fit to the Finish says: July 13, 2009 at 6:17 pm 
This was hilarious! And so true. The only fast food restaurant we ever eat at anymore is Chick-fil-a, and that’s only every great once in a while. I have to say that those dino nuggets look much better than the Wendy’s ones!
 Reply Josie Maurer says: July 13, 2009 at 4:47 pm 
I think I saw something about using white glue to make it look like milk on top of cereal. Yummy! (choke)
And who knows how they’re styling those lovely cookies of yours! LOL
 Reply Josie Maurer says: July 13, 2009 at 4:48 pm 
I really do want my money back. That part wasn’t a joke……
 Reply MizFit says: July 14, 2009 at 6:14 am 
OKAY I TRIED THIS 
the ad was too tempting and I too curious.
and it was nasty as you say—THANK GOODNESS 
never want that again.
 Reply Teresa says: July 15, 2009 at 12:07 am 
Hi Josie! Long time lurker, er, reader, first time commenter–I had the misfortune of trying the honey barbeque ones based on the suggestion of a Wendy’s employee. They were gross! The sauce tasted weird and it looked like it had been painted on moments before serving it to me. Not all the pieces were covered either. I didn’t finish it and chalked it up to lesson learned.
 Reply FatFighter says: July 15, 2009 at 2:58 pm 
OMG, you are the sweetest wife EVER.
 Reply Josie Maurer says: July 15, 2009 at 11:02 am 
Well, hello! I had a feeling you were lurking, er, reading. LOL. Thanks for another confirmation of the nastiness. Our taste buds are too sophisticated for this crap! (would you care for a Dino nugget?)
 Reply Kals says: July 22, 2009 at 8:46 pm 
I decided to try the honey bbq and was horrified when i literally saw the person preparing them put the nuggets in the tray thingie, cover it, poured the“sauce”over it, and shake it up. So to Teresa, they really did paint the sauce on moments before serving it. From the commercial, I had the impression that they were cooked with the sauce the way normal people cook, but they’re really nothing more than their regular nuggets shaken up in the same sauce they serve with their chicken nuggets anyway. Might as well just buy the nuggets, they taste better and are cheaper. I was very disappointed.
 Reply Jessica says: July 25, 2009 at 10:00 am 
Calm down. Its not that serious. I work at Wendys.&amp;Its the same chicken in the nuggets as it is in the wings, It just has different breading, I know how they came up with the idea and how its made, So why do people insist on acting like jerks? and If you wanted your money back then get it back, The company makes so much money they arent going to care about a lousy 4.46.&amp;Wendys Chicken is real. Thank you!
 Reply Josie Maurer says: July 25, 2009 at 10:58 am 
Jessica represents the Wendy’s Corporation extremely well. She just earned a 0.15 cent raise and was promoted to Crew Chief for posting her comment. Yay for Jessica! Everyone give her a round of applause.
 Reply Jessica says: July 25, 2009 at 3:24 pm 
15? lol we get more than that! and Wendys isnt my life, Its a job thats gets me through while Im in college. I felt as though I was mean, but then again people say things and dont know the truth about it first. Its irritating.
 Reply Josie Maurer says: July 25, 2009 at 6:41 pm 
That’s great, really (not being a smart ass), but this customer says the Asian Chicken is nastiness. But ask about the Go Wraps. I love them lots. Here’s the review http://www.yumyucky.com/2009/05/taste-test-wendys-go-wrap.html 
 Reply Jessica says: July 26, 2009 at 11:13 am 
I just wanted to say though, This site is really good and nice, I been wanting to work a site with calories or something on health but not good with any ideas, and idk how to get the set up like where you commented me back being the owner of this site. lol Keep up the awesome job!
 Reply BB says: August 27, 2009 at 3:25 am 
Haven’t tried these yet, but that was an excellent and hilarious review which brought a smile to my face.
 Reply 
 
Speak Your Mind Cancel reply 
 
 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
Hey Everybody!
 I&apos;m Josie -- a wife, lover of extra large cake slices, and mom to four greedy kids, ages 3 to 19 years old. These are the tools I use to feel great, stay fit and transform my body:


* Shakeology 

* Interval Timer 

* Organic protein powder 

* Rodney Yee Yoga 

*Invisible Speed Rope
 
 
Organic Protein Powder
 NOW Foods 100% Organic Whey Protein Isolate Click here for a snapshot of Josie&apos;s personal fitness and eating plan. 
Yum Yucky Uses Gymboss
 
Sponsored Links
 
* Vaser in London 

* Lasik London 

* GroceryCouponUpdate.com 

 Full Disclosure regarding paid advertisements, affiliate links and product reviews.
 
PUMP it ya’ll, PUMP it!
 
 I am LOVING this program. My full review on Les Mills PUMP is coming next week.
 
Shakeology Sampler Bonanza
 
 
Snag yourself a 4-pack trial and give Shakeology a spin. You&apos;ll be dizzy with delight. Order now 


* Shakeology Breakfast Cookie 

* Shakeology 3-Day Cleanse 

* BeachbodyCoach.com/YumYucky 
 
Like me on Facebook!
 
Videos
 
 


 

 


 

 
Follow me on the Twittahhh!
 
Search the site
 
Great Fitness Tools
 
 Rodney Yee Yoga Organic Protein Powder Shakeology Interval Timer Leslie Sansone&apos;s Walk At Home
	</body>
</document>
