<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009200" url="http://www.rtbot.net/List_of_fast_food_restaurant_chains" time="2012-07-13-02:35" support="6" score="0.005021225072159999" bingtitle="List Of Fast Food Restaurant Chains Information, Videos, Pictures ..." webtitle="List Of Fast Food Restaurant Chains Information, Videos, Pictures and News">
			<query id="000466" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000450" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000311" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000748" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="001296" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="001299" bing-rank="207"/>
	<description>Gino&apos;s Hamburgers was a fast-food restaurant chain founded ... Another part of the national health care bill includes ... Pick Up Stix (Chinese) Sarku Japan (Japanese) Thaï Express ...</description>
	<body>
		RTBot 
List Of Fast Food Restaurant Chains
 
Information, Videos , News and Images about List Of Fast Food Restaurant Chains
 
 
 
 
 
 Home Videos Wikipedia Images Twitter News Documents WebLinks 
 
 
Top Images

 
 
Top Videos
   Gino&apos;s Hamburgers TV Commercial (70&apos;s) 
 Gino&apos;s Hamburgers was a fast-food restaurant chain founded in Baltimore, Maryland, by Baltimore Colts defensive end Gino Marchetti and running back Alan Ameche, along with their close friend Louis Fischer, in 1957. In Dundalk, Maryland, just outside Baltimore, it got its official name in 1959 when the owners brought on Colts&apos; captain Gino Marchetti. It was an East Coast regional fast food restaurant and had 359 company-owned locations when they were acquired by Marriott Corporation in 1982. Marriott discontinued the brand and converted locations to their Roy Rogers Restaurants chain. The restaurant was known for high quality hamburgers such as the Sirloiner, which was made from sirloin steak, and the Gino Giant, which competed with the Big Mac. The company held the franchise for Kentucky Fried Chicken in the middle-Atlantic states. Their slogan was &quot;Everybody Goes to Gino&apos;s&quot;. Gino&apos;s Bugers and chicken. Marchetti, Romano, and Fischer plan to open new Gino&apos;s restaurants in 2010, with franchise information available in March. Marchetti and Fischer will be serving as consultants. The new restaurant plans to serve burgers, chicken sandwiches, hand-cut french fries and hand-spun milkshakes. Initially, the chain plans to open locations in Pennsylvania and New Jersey. 
 ginos burgers hamburgers gino md maryland baltimore tv television commercial ad advertising fast food opening soon freedom of choice sirloiner giant hero fries french shakes coke root beer musical jingle pop culture dining carry out carry out kfc kentucky fried chicken colonel col. 11 Worst Fast Food Restaurants (w/ Marquis Alexander) - 11 Points Countdown 
 Sam Greenspan from 11 Points is joined by writer and comedian Marquis Alexander to count down the results of a poll on people&apos;s least favorite fast food restaurants. See the full results of the list at 11points.com 
 Food Fast Food Sbarro Burger King Long John Silvers KFC Carls Jr. White Castle Taco Bell Krystal Hot Dog on a Stick Arbys mcdonalds Hardees 11points Fast food restaurants TV ads target kids 
 A look at how fast food TV ads affect children&apos;s eating habits today and later in their lives. 
 diabetes dialog cuny fast food tv ad tv marketing kids 10 Best Fast Food Restaurants 
 the 10 Best Fast Food Restaurants by QSR 2009 Systemwide Sales ($Million). Which Fast Food Chain Restaurant tops Number #1 in Sales? Song Title: from YouTube&apos;s AudioSwap Information from: www.qsrmagazine.com 
 10 Best Fast Food Chain Restaurants by Sales in Millions Dollars number one the song mcdonalds Mc Donalds Fries Burger King Sonic Wendys KFC Dunkin Donuts Starbucks Coffee Taco Bell Dog Pizza Hut Subway Fast food lunch box restaurant in Japan 
 See what I bought at this place: www.youtube.com description: Bento is the Japanese style boxed lunch. The videos in this play list show the different kinds of bento you can get here in Japan. You can also see other bento related videos in this series. Wikipedia: Bento (弁当bentō) is a single-portion takeout or home-packed meal common in Japanese cuisine. A traditional bento consists of rice, fish or meat, and one or more pickled or cooked vegetables, usually in a box-shaped container. Containers range from disposable mass produced to hand crafted lacquerware. Although bento are readily available in many places throughout Japan, including convenience stores, bento shops (弁当屋bentō-ya), train stations, and department stores, it is still common for Japanese homemakers to spend time and energy for their spouse, child, or themselves producing a carefully prepared lunch box. Bento can be very elaborately arranged in a style called kyaraben or &quot;character bento&quot;. Kyaraben is typically decorated to look like popular Japanese cartoon (anime) characters, characters from comic books (manga), or video game characters. Another popular bento style is &quot;oekakiben&quot; or &quot;picture bento&quot;, which is decorated to look like people, animals, buildings and monuments, or items such as flowers and plants. Contests are often held where bento arrangers compete for the most aesthetically pleasing arrangements. keywords: healthy bento recipes, bento for dummies, healthy bento, bento diet, bento blog ... 
 Hokahoka tei ほっかほっか亭 Japanese fast food cheap Japanese restaurant fast food chain store in Japan living in Japan restaurants in Kobe Japan healthy bento recipes bento for dummies healthy bento bento diet bento blog bento ideas bento meals what is bento a healthy lunch meal easy bento lunches lunch box ideas for kids lunch box menu box lunch ideas kids bento recipes obento box Mission 1: Get 40 waters from fast-food restaurants 
 First thing we did on our list of 50 things to do before summer ends. 
 50 things to do before summer ends 40 waters Restaurants required to list calories 
 Another part of the national health care bill includes putting calories on the menu at more than 200000 restaurants. At Bigbby Coffee on Superior Street across from the Lucas County Arena customers can already check calories online, but soon the amount of calories in each item will be available for all customers to see inside. That&apos;s because according to the new law, any restaurant or fast food chain with more than 20 locations will have to include nutrition facts on menus, menu boards and even drive thrus. The new law will apply at Bigbby&apos;s coffee shop. Store employees believe it won&apos;t turn customers away, though. This law will help them keep track of what they eat or drink, and it could also help prevent future health problems. 
 biggby coffee calories at restaurants health care bill law Japanese Style Fast Food -- An Awesome Bento 
 This is the Japanese boxed lunch I picked up at HokaHoka Tei, a chain fast food restaurant in Japan. description: Bento is the Japanese style boxed lunch. The videos in this play list show the different kinds of bento you can get here in Japan. You can also see other bento related videos in this series. Wikipedia: Bento (弁当bentō) is a single-portion takeout or home-packed meal common in Japanese cuisine. A traditional bento consists of rice, fish or meat, and one or more pickled or cooked vegetables, usually in a box-shaped container. Containers range from disposable mass produced to hand crafted lacquerware. Although bento are readily available in many places throughout Japan, including convenience stores, bento shops (弁当屋bentō-ya), train stations, and department stores, it is still common for Japanese homemakers to spend time and energy for their spouse, child, or themselves producing a carefully prepared lunch box. Bento can be very elaborately arranged in a style called kyaraben or &quot;character bento&quot;. Kyaraben is typically decorated to look like popular Japanese cartoon (anime) characters, characters from comic books (manga), or video game characters. Another popular bento style is &quot;oekakiben&quot; or &quot;picture bento&quot;, which is decorated to look like people, animals, buildings and monuments, or items such as flowers and plants. Contests are often held where bento arrangers compete for the most aesthetically pleasing arrangements. keywords: healthy bento recipes, bento ... 
 tonkatsu breaded pork fried chicken ponsu sauce vinegar sauce umeboshi giant shrimp breaded shrimp giant bento healthy bento recipes bento for dummies healthy bento bento diet bento blog bento ideas bento meals what is bento a healthy lunch meal easy bento lunches lunch box ideas for kids lunch box menu box lunch ideas kids bento recipes obento box Don&apos;t be Fooled by Fast Food Diets | Fast Food Diets Unhealthy 
 Fast food restaurants are touting that you can shed the pounds by eating their food. Fast food restaurants are know for their unhealthy,fat loaded,chemical&amp;preservative rich and nondestructive food. healthychefdude on twitter www.healhtychefdude.com Distributed by Tubemogul. My Central Channel: www.MarcusG.tv My facebook http Twitter for my restaurant: twitter.com My personal Twitter: twitter.com My Restaurant website: www.aromathymebistro.com My restaurant YouTube channel: www.youtube.com My wine&amp;beer YouTube channel: www.youtube.comMarcus Guiliano, Chef and Owner of Aroma Thyme Bistro located in Ellenville, NY in the scenic Hudson Valley. Aroma Thyme is know for their &quot;stealth health&quot;(Zagat). The Bistro has an award-winning wine list from Wine Spectator Magazine and over 200 beers. Aroma Thyme is certified green by The Green Restaurant Association. Support Hudson Valley Restaurants. 
 fast food diet taco bell subwayfastfooddiet fat nondestructivefood unhealthy unhealthydieting I Want My Chicken! FAT MAN Screams For Chicken Sandwich 
 At a fast food restaurant, a 300-400 pound fat man screams for his chicken sandwich. Is it a Walmart Mcdonalds? I want my chicken! ORIGINAL VIDEO Subscribe to ManOnTheStreet.TV www.youtube.com for more videos. 
 fast food funny mcdonalds chicken scream fight popeyes walmart want my big mac quarter pounder with cheese fat man shout combat sports fiesta carnival Big Mac mcdonalds Hungry Burger Eating Man On The Street Mots TV Healthiest Fast Food Chains 
 Frances Largeman-Roth from Health magazine lists her top recommendations for eating at national fast food chains to Harry Smith, now that some places are offering more nutritional choices. 
 health magazine frances largeman roth harry smith Jamie Oliver&apos;s Food Revolution: Pink Slime - 70% of America&apos;s Beef is Treated with Ammonia 
 On the Season Premiere of Jamie Oliver&apos;s Food Revolution filmed in Los Angeles and aired on April 12, 2011, Jamie demonstrates how 70% of America&apos;s ground beef contains leftover cow parts (aka &quot;pink slime&quot;) containing e.coli and salmonella that has been treated with ammonia. Ammonia treated meat can be found in virtually all conventional grocery stores, fast food restaurants, many national restaurant chains, and school cafeterias. The saddest part is that the USDA allows this ammonia treated meat to enter the marketplace and with no labeling requirement on the packaging to inform the consumer that the meat their about to buy contains ammonia, thus hiding the truth and pulling a wool over the consumer&apos;s eye. This is certainly a rude awakening to the majority of Americans that don&apos;t know where the meat in their fridge, the meat in their conventional local grocery store, the meat in their fast food hamburger, and the meat in their restaurant made hamburger comes from. How do you avoid this poison? Buy beef that has come from grass fed cows, which can be found at natural and organic grocery stores and your local farmers market. No matter the size of your town or city, grass fed beef (real beef) is not out of reach. Unlike ammonia treated beef, grass fed beef is clearly labeled and contains no ammonia. 
 Jamie Olivers Oliver Food Revolution meat ground beef demonstration demonstrates ammonia washing machine e.coli salmonella Los Angeles April 12th 2011 season premiere USDA label labels requirement package packaged packaging school kids cafeteria cafeterias parents unhealthy lunch lunches episode grass fed fat cow pink slime Keith Warren - Managing Director of Yum! Restaurants International 
 (www.abndigital.com) We focus now on trends in the African fast food industry. Yum is one of the worlds largest restaurant company&apos;s in terms of system restaurants, with more than 36000 locations around the world. The company is ranked #239 on the fortune 500 list with revenues in excess of $11 billion in 2008. The good news is that Yum opened the first KFC restaurant in Nigeria recently. For the details, we are joined from Lagos by Keith Warren, Managing Director of Yum! Restaurants International, in South Africa 
 Keith Warren The 2011 QSR 50 is here! 
 The biggest brands from this year&apos;s top 50 quick-serve and fast-casual list, according to QSR magazine. 
 QSR 50 top fast food chains fast food restaurant chains top restaurant chains restaurant news Vegan Kid Recipes : Vegan Fast Food Scavanger Hunt w/ My Mom - Genghisgirl - Bex Life 
 Please rate, comment, and subscribe! xoxo Visit me on my channel: youtube.com Visit my mom&apos;s channel: youtube.com I asked my mom to drive me to different fast food restaurants to find vegan food that you can order when you hang out with your friends. We ordered Frosties at Wendy&apos;s, but those aren&apos;t vegan... we just like them a lot. The list of food we ate: Burger King French Fries, McDonald&apos;s Apple Pie, Wendy&apos;s Plain Baked Potato, Taco Bell 7 Layer Burrito (no cheese, no sour cream), and a Cold Stone Creamery Citrus Fruit Smoothie 
 vegan vegetarian recipe recipes kid raw diet winona bexlife.com genghisgirl veggie veggiewinona health nutrition health diet how to cooking vlog instruction howto fast food bex life wendys mcdonalds cold stone creamery burger king taco bell Nutrition information on restaurant menus: It&apos;s a good thing. 
 In the Friday, May 29 viditorial, Sun Journal Editorial Page Editor Tony Ronzio talks about a bill before the Maine legislature that would require restaurant chains to list nutrition information on their menus. 
 viditorial sun journal tony ronzio ronzio editorial maine fast food nutrition information nutrition restaurants pingree maine legislature government Top 5 Fast Food Restaurants. 
 Watch diz third vid of mine. 
 restaurants PINK SLIME: Jamie Oliver&apos;s Food Revolution 70% of America&apos;s Beef is Treated with Ammonia 
 Jamie Oliver&apos;s Food Revolution filmed in Los Angeles and aired on April 12, 2011, Jamie demonstrates how 70% of America&apos;s ground beef contains leftover cow parts (aka &quot;pink slime&quot;) containing e.coli and salmonella that has been treated with ammonia. Ammonia treated meat can be found in virtually all conventional grocery stores, fast food restaurants, many national restaurant chains, and school cafeterias. The saddest part is that the USDA allows this ammonia treated meat to enter the marketplace and with no labeling requirement on the packaging to inform the consumer that the meat their about to buy contains ammonia, thus hiding the truth and pulling a wool over the consumer&apos;s eye. This is certainly a rude awakening to the majority of Americans that don&apos;t know where the meat in their fridge, the meat in their conventional local grocery store, the meat in their fast food hamburger, and the meat in their restaurant made hamburger comes from. How do you avoid this poison? Buy beef that has come from grass fed cows, which can be found at natural and organic grocery stores and your local farmers market. No matter the size of your town or city, grass fed beef (real beef) is not out of reach. Unlike ammonia treated beef, grass fed beef is clearly labeled and contains no ammonia. MSNBC reports that the chemical, used in fertilizers, household cleaners and even homemade explosives, was also used to prepare McDonalds&apos; hamburger meat. And while the announcement is making headlines ... 
 Pink Slime Jamie Oliver Ground Beef Ammonia washing Healthy Fast Food Cooking Demo 10 Minutes or Less - Fast Food Nation 
 Michelle Tennant Nicholson is participating in the 2011 &quot;Make the Change - Be the Change&quot; Jillian Michaels Challenge. This past week, Jillian challenged her participants to watch &quot;Fast Food Nation&quot; a movie, not a documentary, about assembly line made industry meat that feeds the fast food restaurants in America, and unfortunately the majority of our familes. There is a sub-story about Mexicans crossing the border and how these undocumented, untrained workers are forced to process the meat in a quick, cheap manner. As a result of the challenge and watching this movie and &quot;FOOD INC&quot; last week, Michelle has chosen to post 10 minute cooking demos to share with families how she&apos;s finding solutions to preparing healthy fast food. In this video, she demonstrates how to prepare beans, rice&amp;tomatoes quickly and buy organic less expensively so it&apos;s a perfect solution for families needing to feed many, healthy, but on a budget. 
 organic food on a budget healthy fast food Fast Food Nation Food Inc Jillian Michaels Michelle Tennant Nicholson beans and rice organic corn bread Shockingly Short List of Ethical Restaurants 
 --Workers&apos; group releases a shockingly short list of ethical restaurants. --On the Bonus Show: South Korean creationists force removal of evolution from textbooks, Adidas cancels &quot;shackle shoes,&quot; more. How do you get the Bonus Show? Become a member: www.davidpakman.com If you liked this clip of The David Pakman Show, please do us a big favor and share it with your friends... and hit that &quot;like&quot; button! www.davidpakman.com http www.facebook.com www.twitter.com feeds.feedburner.com 24/7 Voicemail Line: (219)-2DAVIDP Subscribe to The David Pakman Show for more: www.youtube.com Broadcast on June 19, 2012 
 restaurants fair pay wages minimum wage david pakman show david pakman dave pacman david packman pakman news talk radio television pacifica davidpakman.com entertainment government liberal conservative politics political democrat republican progressive tdps united states america cnn nbc cbs msnbc fox 
The following is a list of fast food restaurants , as distinct from fast casual restaurants , (see List of casual dining restaurant chains ), coffeehouses (see List of coffeehouse chains ), ice cream parlors (see List of ice cream parlor chains ), and pizzerias (see List of pizza chains ).

 
 
Contents
 
 1 International chains 2 Companies by country of origin 
 2.1 Africa 
 2.1.1 Egypt 2.1.2 Nigeria 2.1.3 South Africa 
 2.2 Asia 
 2.2.1 China 2.2.2 India 2.2.3 Indonesia 2.2.4 Israel 2.2.5 Japan 2.2.6 Malaysia 2.2.7 Philippines 2.2.8 Saudi Arabia 2.2.9 Singapore 2.2.10 South Korea 2.2.11 Taiwan 
 2.3 Europe 
 2.3.1 Belgium 2.3.2 Finland 2.3.3 France 2.3.4 Germany 2.3.5 Greece 2.3.6 Ireland 2.3.7 Italy 2.3.8 The Netherlands 2.3.9 Norway 2.3.10 Portugal 2.3.11 Spain 2.3.12 Sweden 2.3.13 United Kingdom 
 2.4 North America 
 2.4.1 Barbados 2.4.2 Canada 2.4.3 Guatemala 2.4.4 Mexico 2.4.5 United States 
 2.4.5.1 Puerto Rico 
 
 2.5 Oceania 
 2.5.1 Australia 2.5.2 New Zealand 
 2.6 South America 
 2.6.1 Argentina 2.6.2 Brazil 2.6.3 Colombia 2.6.4 Peru 
 
 3 Parent companies 4 See also 5 References 
 
 

 [ edit ] International chains 
 
 A&amp;W Restaurants Arby&apos;s Burger King Carl&apos;s Jr. Charley&apos;s Grilled Subs Checkers  / Rally&apos;s Chester&apos;s International Chicken Cottage Chicken Delight Chicken Express Chicken Licken Chipotle Mexican Grill Chowking Church&apos;s Chicken  / Texas Chicken Culver&apos;s Dairy Queen Del Taco Dunkin&apos; Donuts El Pollo Loco Fatburger Five Guys Guthrie&apos;s Hardee&apos;s  / Red Burrito Hesburger In-N-Out Burger Jack in the Box Jamba Juice Jollibee Kenny Rogers Roasters KFC Long John Silver&apos;s Maoz Vegetarian McDonald&apos;s MOS Burger Moe&apos;s Southwest Grill Nando&apos;s Nathan&apos;s Famous New York Fries Noble Roman&apos;s Panda Express Panera Bread Pizza Hut Pollo Tropical Popeyes Chicken&amp;Biscuits Quiznos Raising Cane&apos;s Chicken Fingers Red Rooster Roy Rogers Restaurants Smoothie King Subway Taco Bell Taco Bueno Taco Cabana Taco del Mar Taco Mayo Taco Tico Taco Time Tim Hortons Togo&apos;s Vapiano Wendy&apos;s Wendy&apos;s Supa Sundaes Whataburger White Castle White Spot Wimpy Wingstop Zaxby&apos;s 
 
 [ edit ] Companies by country of origin 

 [ edit ] Africa 

 [ edit ] Egypt 

 Cook Door Mo&apos;men 

 [ edit ] Nigeria 

 Mr Bigg&apos;s Tantalizers Tastee Fried Chicken 

 [ edit ] South Africa 

 Chicken Licken Nando&apos;s Something Fishy Spur Steak Ranches Steers 

 [ edit ] Asia 

 [ edit ] China 

 Mr. Lee 

 [ edit ] India 
 
 Amul Restaurants Barbeque Nation Goli Vada Pav Haldiram&apos;s Jumbo King KaatiZone Monginis Nirula&apos;s Saravana Bhavan Sri Krishna Sweets Vadilal Yazdani Bakery 
 
 [ edit ] Indonesia 

 California Fried Chicken Es Teler 77 Hoka Hoka Bento 

 [ edit ] Israel 

 Burger Ranch 

 [ edit ] Japan 

 First Kitchen Freshness Burger Ichibanya Jef Lotteria MOS Burger Pepper Lunch Sukiya , &quot;Beef bowl&quot; Yoshinoya , &quot;Beef bowl&quot; 

 [ edit ] Malaysia 

 The Chicken Rice Shop KLG Marrybrown Secret Recipe 

 [ edit ] Philippines 
 For a more comprehensive list, see List of Philippine restaurant chains . 
 Chowking Gerry&apos;s Grill Goldilocks Bakeshop Greenwich Pizza Jollibee Mang Inasal Max&apos;s of Manila Red Ribbon Tokyo Tokyo 
 
 [ edit ] Saudi Arabia 

 Al Baik Al Tazaj Herfy 

 [ edit ] Singapore 

 Crystal Jade Old Chang Kee Sakae Sushi 

 [ edit ] South Korea 

 Lotteria 

 [ edit ] Taiwan 

 85C Bakery Cafe Quickly 

 [ edit ] Europe 

 [ edit ] Belgium 

 Quick 

 [ edit ] Finland 

 Carrols Hesburger Kotipizza Picnic 

 [ edit ] France 

 Délifrance Flunch Quick 

 [ edit ] Germany 

 Nordsee Vapiano Wienerwald 

 [ edit ] Greece 

 Goody&apos;s 

 [ edit ] Ireland 

 Abrakebabra Eddie Rocket&apos;s O&apos;Briens Irish Sandwich Bars Supermac&apos;s 

 [ edit ] Italy 

 Spizzico 

 [ edit ] The Netherlands 

 FEBO Maoz Vegetarian 

 [ edit ] Norway 

 Big Bite Submarines 

 [ edit ] Portugal 

 Burger Ranch 

 [ edit ] Spain 

 Telepizza 

 [ edit ] Sweden 

 Max Hamburgers Sibylla 

 [ edit ] United Kingdom 
 
 Bagel Nash Benjys Ben&apos;s Cookies Brewers Fayre Chicken Cottage Chiquito Dixy Chicken EasyPizza EAT. Favorite Chicken Fine Burger Giraffe Greggs Harvester Little Chef Millie&apos;s Cookies Pret a Manger Prezzo Shakeaway Spud U Like Square Pie Table Table Upper Crust The West Cornwall Pasty Company Wimpy 
 
 [ edit ] North America 

 [ edit ] Barbados 

 Chefette 

 [ edit ] Canada 
 
 A&amp;W Amir Burger Baron Captain Submarine Chez Ashton Chicken Delight Dic Ann&apos;s Hamburgers Dixie Lee Fried Chicken Extreme Pita Fast Eddies Harvey&apos;s La Belle Province Lafleur Restaurants Lick&apos;s Homeburgers Mary Brown&apos;s McDonald&apos;s Canada Mr. Sub New York Fries Robin&apos;s Donuts Swiss Chalet The Pita Pit Tim Hortons 
 
 [ edit ] Guatemala 

 Pollo Campero 

 [ edit ] Mexico 

 Doña Tota 

 [ edit ] United States 
 See also: List of restaurant chains in the United States 
 A&amp;W Restaurants Amigos/Kings Classic Andy&apos;s Frozen Custard Arby&apos;s Arctic Circle Restaurants Arthur Treacher&apos;s Baker&apos;s Drive-Thru Baskin-Robbins Bess Eaton Big Apple Bagels Big Boy Restaurants Biscuitville Blake&apos;s Lotaburger Blimpie Bojangles&apos; Famous Chicken &apos;n Biscuits Brooklyn Ice Cream Factory Burger King Braum&apos;s Brown&apos;s Chicken&amp;Pasta Burger Street Burgerville Cafe Rio California Tortilla Captain D&apos;s Carl&apos;s Jr. / Green Burrito Checkers / Rally&apos;s Cheeburger Cheeburger Chick-fil-A Chicken Express Chinese Gourmet Express Church&apos;s Chicken / Texas Chicken CiCi&apos;s Pizza Cluck-U Chicken Cook Out Cousins Subs Crown Burgers Dairy Queen Del Taco Denny&apos;s Dick&apos;s Drive-In Dickey&apos;s Barbecue Pit Dog n Suds Duchess Dunkin&apos; Donuts Einstein Bros. Bagels El Pollo Loco Erbert&amp;Gerbert&apos;s Fatburger Firehouse Subs Five Guys Fosters Freeze Freddy&apos;s Frozen Custard Gold Star Chili Golden Chick Golden Spoon Good Times Burgers&amp;Frozen Custard Grandy&apos;s Gray&apos;s Papaya Great Steak Griff&apos;s Hamburgers Halo Burger Happi House Happy Joe&apos;s Hardee&apos;s / Red Burrito Harold&apos;s Chicken Shack Hogi Yogi Honey Dew Donuts Hot Dog on a Stick Hot &apos;n Now Huddle House IHOP In-N-Out Burger Ivar&apos;s Jack in the Box Jack&apos;s Jersey Mike&apos;s Subs Jimboy&apos;s Tacos Johnny Rockets Juan Pollo KFC Kopp&apos;s Frozen Custard Krispy Kreme Krystal LaMar&apos;s Donuts Larry&apos;s Giant Subs Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop Long John Silver&apos;s Lyon&apos;s Maid-Rite Manchu Wok McDonald&apos;s Mellow Mushroom Mighty Taco Milio&apos;s Sandwiches Milo&apos;s Hamburgers Mr. Hero Mrs. Winner&apos;s Chicken&amp;Biscuits Nathan&apos;s Famous Nedick&apos;s Nu-Way Weiners Nu Way Cafe Orange Julius The Original Hamburger Stand Original Tommy&apos;s Pal&apos;s Pioneer Chicken Popeyes Chicken&amp;Biscuits Portillo&apos;s Restaurants Port of Subs Quiznos Raising Cane&apos;s Chicken Fingers Ranch1 Roy Rogers Restaurants Runza Saladworks Schlotzsky&apos;s Sheetz Skippers Seafood&amp;Chowder House Smoothie King Sneaky Pete&apos;s Sonic Drive-In Spangles Steak Escape Steak &apos;n Shake Submarina Subway Taco Bell Taco Bueno Taco Cabana Taco del Mar Taco John&apos;s Taco Mayo Taco Tico Taco Time Ted&apos;s Hot Dogs Texadelphia The Hat The Whole Donut Togo&apos;s Tudor&apos;s Biscuit World The Varsity Wendy&apos;s Wetzel&apos;s Pretzels Whataburger White Castle Wienerschnitzel Winchell&apos;s Donuts Wingstop WingStreet Winstead&apos;s Wing Zone Woody&apos;s Chicago Style Yum-Yum Donuts 
 
 [ edit ] Puerto Rico 

 Martin&apos;s BBQ El Meson Sandwiches 

 [ edit ] Oceania 

 [ edit ] Australia 
 
 Chicken Treat Eagle Boys Fast Eddys Fasta Pasta Healthy Habits Henny Penny Hungry Jack&apos;s Pizza Hut La Porchetta Pronto Noodle Box Oporto Pancake Parlour Red Rooster Uncle Tony&apos;s Kebabs 
 
 [ edit ] New Zealand 

 Burger Fuel Georgie Pie - bought by McDonald&apos;s and closed Hell&apos;s Pizza 

 [ edit ] South America 

 [ edit ] Argentina 

 California Burrito Co. 

 [ edit ] Brazil 

 Bob&apos;s Giraffas Habib&apos;s Koni Store Mini Kalzone Rei do Mate Spoleto 

 [ edit ] Colombia 

 Pollos Frisby 

 [ edit ] Peru 

 Bembos Pasquale Hnos. 

 [ edit ] Parent companies 

 CKE Restaurants owns Carl&apos;s Jr. / Green Burrito , and Hardee&apos;s / Red Burrito dual-branded chains. Dunkin&apos; Brands owns Dunkin&apos; Donuts and Baskin-Robbins . Focus Brands owns Auntie Anne&apos;s , Carvel , Cinnabon , Moe&apos;s Southwest Grill , and Schlotzsky&apos;s . Yum! Brands (spin-off from PepsiCo in 1997) owns KFC , Taco Bell , Long John Silver&apos;s , A&amp;W Restaurants , and Pizza Hut franchises. 

 [ edit ] See also 

 List of restaurant chains List of revolving restaurants 

 [ edit ] References 
 
 
 
 v t e 
 Chicken-based restaurant chains Global 
 Chester&apos;s Chicken Cottage Church&apos;s Dixie Lee Fried Chicken Dixy Chicken Kenny Rogers Roasters KFC Nando&apos;s Pollo Campero Popeyes Southern Fried Chicken 
 Regional 
 Africa 
 Chicken Licken (ZA) Tastee Fried Chicken (NG) 
 Asia 
 Al Tazaj (SA) Bacolod Chicken Inasal (PH) Bonchon Chicken (KR) California Fried Chicken (ID) The Chicken Rice Shop (MY) KLG (MY) Kyochon (KR) Max&apos;s of Manila (PH) Mang Inasal (PH) Pioneer Chicken (CN) Wienerwald (TR) 
 Europe 
 Favorite Chicken (UK) Miss Millie&apos;s (UK) Wienerwald (DE) 
 North America 
 Boston Market Bojangles&apos; Brown&apos;s Chicken&amp;Pasta Buffalo Wild Wings Chick-fil-A Chicken Express Chicken Out Rotisserie Cluck-U El Pollo Loco Foosackly&apos;s Golden Chick Golden Skillet Guthrie&apos;s Harold&apos;s Chicken Shack Juan Pollo Kyochon Lee&apos;s Famous Louisiana Fried Chicken Mary Brown&apos;s Mrs. Winner&apos;s Chicken&amp;Biscuits Pioneer Chicken Pollo Palenque Pollo Tropical Raising Cane&apos;s Ranch1 Roscoe&apos;s House of Chicken and Waffles Roy Rogers Restaurants Scores St-Hubert Smithfield&apos;s Chicken &apos;N Bar-B-Q Swiss Chalet Tip-Top Wild Wing Restaurants Wingstop WingStreet Wing Zone Zankou Chicken Zaxby&apos;s 
 Oceania 
 Chicken Treat (AU) Chooks Fresh&amp;Tasty (AU) Oporto (AU) Red Rooster (AU) 
 South and
Central America 
 Pollos Frisby (CO) Rostipollos (CR) 
 
 
 

 
 
 v t e 
 Pizza chains (list) International 
 Boston Pizza California Pizza Kitchen Chuck E. Cheese&apos;s Domino&apos;s Pizza Little Caesars Papa John&apos;s Pizza Pizza Hut Pizza Inn Sandella&apos;s Flatbread Café Sbarro Shakey&apos;s Pizza Telepizza The Pizza Company Uno Chicago Grill Yellow Cab Pizza Co. 
 Regional 
 Asia 
 Smokin&apos; Joe&apos;s (IN) Pizza Corner (IN) Alleycat&apos;s Pizza (TW) Aoki&apos;s Pizza (JP) Greenwich Pizza (PH) Mr. Pizza (KR) Pizza-La (JP) 
 Europe 
 Ask (UK) Čili (LT) EasyPizza (UK) Four Star Pizza (Ireland) Kotipizza (FI) Peppes Pizza (NO) PizzaExpress (UK) Prezzo (UK) Spizzico (IT) Strada (UK) Zizzi (UK) 
 North America 
 241 Pizza (CA) America&apos;s Incredible Pizza Company (US) Anthony&apos;s Pizza ( AAFES ) Aurelio&apos;s Pizza (US) Benedetti&apos;s Pizza (MX) Bertucci&apos;s (US) CiCi&apos;s Pizza (US) Donatos Pizza (US) DoubleDave&apos;s Pizzaworks (US) East of Chicago Pizza (US) Flying Wedge Pizza (CA) Fox&apos;s Pizza Den (US) Freshslice Pizza (CA) Gatti&apos;s Pizza (US) Gino&apos;s East (US) Giordano&apos;s Pizzeria (US) Godfather&apos;s Pizza (US) Greco Pizza Restaurant (CA) Happy&apos;s Pizza (US) Happy Joe&apos;s (US) Hungry Howie&apos;s Pizza (US) Imo&apos;s Pizza (US) LaRosa&apos;s Pizzeria (US) Ledo Pizza (US) Lou Malnati&apos;s Pizzeria (US) Marco&apos;s Pizza (US) Mazzio&apos;s (US) Mellow Mushroom (US) Mikes (CA) Monical&apos;s Pizza (US) Mountain Mike&apos;s Pizza (US) Mr. Jim&apos;s Pizza (US) Noble Roman&apos;s (US) Panago (CA) Papa Gino&apos;s (US) Papa Murphy&apos;s (US) Peter Piper Pizza (US) Pizza 73 (CA) Pizza Delight (CA) Pizza Fusion (US) Pizza Nova (CA) Pizza Patrón (US) Pizza Pizza (CA) Pizza Ranch (US) Pizza Schmizza (US) Regina Pizzeria (US) Rocky Rococo (US) Round Table Pizza (US) Sal&apos;s Pizza (US) Upper Crust Pizzeria (US) Valentino&apos;s (US) Vocelli Pizza (US) 
 Oceania 
 Eagle Boys (AU) Hell Pizza (NZ) Pizza Haven (AU) 
 
 Franchises 
 Competitive Foods Australia Domino&apos;s Pizza Enterprises Domino&apos;s Pizza UK&amp;IRL 
 
 

 
 
 v t e 
 Fast food and fast casual restaurant chains in the United States 
 Chicken chains Pizza chains 
 Hamburgers 
 A&amp;W Arctic Circle Back Yard Burgers Big Boy Restaurants Blake&apos;s Lotaburger Burger King Burger Time Burgerville Carl&apos;s Jr. Checkers / Rally&apos;s Cook Out Culver&apos;s Fatburger Five Guys Freddy&apos;s Frozen Custard Fuddruckers George Webb Gino&apos;s Hamburgers Good Times Burgers&amp;Frozen Custard Hardee&apos;s Hot &apos;n Now In-N-Out Burger Jack in the Box Jack&apos;s Johnny Rockets Jollibee Krystal Maid-Rite McDonald&apos;s Nation&apos;s Giant Hamburgers Original Tommy&apos;s Roy Rogers Runza Shake Shack Smashburger Sonic Drive-In Spangles Steak &apos;n Shake Swensons Wendy&apos;s Whataburger What-A-Burger White Castle Winstead&apos;s Zippy&apos;s 
 Asian 
 Chowking (Filipino) Jollibee (Filipino) L&amp;L Hawaiian Barbecue Lee&apos;s Sandwiches (Vietnamese) Manchu Wok (Chinese) Max&apos;s of Manila (Filipino) Panda Express (Chinese) Pick Up Stix (Chinese) Sarku Japan (Japanese) Thaï Express (Thai) Yoshinoya (Japanese) 
 Baked
goods 
 Au Bon Pain Auntie Anne&apos;s Beard Papa&apos;s Cinnabon Dunkin&apos; Donuts Einstein Bros. Bagels Honey Dew Donuts Krispy Kreme Mister Donut Mrs. Fields Nestlé Toll House Café Pretzelmaker / Pretzel Time Shipley Do-Nuts Tim Hortons T.J. Cinnamons Wetzel&apos;s Pretzels Winchell&apos;s Donuts Yum-Yum Donuts 
 Beverages 
 Argo Tea Biggby Coffee Caribou Coffee The Coffee Bean&amp;Tea Leaf Coffee Beanery Dunn Bros Jamba Juice Max Brenner Orange Julius Peet&apos;s Coffee&amp;Tea Planet Smoothie Robeks Seattle&apos;s Best Coffee Smoothie King Starbucks Tully&apos;s Coffee 
 Frozen
desserts 
 Bahama Buck&apos;s Baskin-Robbins Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s Braum&apos;s Brigham&apos;s Ice Cream Bruster&apos;s Ice Cream Carvel Cold Stone Creamery Culver&apos;s Dairy Queen Dippin&apos; Dots Fosters Freeze Friendly&apos;s Golden Spoon Häagen-Dazs Handel&apos;s Homemade Ice Cream&amp;Yogurt MaggieMoo&apos;s Ice Cream and Treatery Marble Slab Creamery Menchie&apos;s Pinkberry Red Mango Rita&apos;s Italian Ice Tastee-Freez Tropical Sno TCBY Yogen Früz Yogurtland 
 Hot dogs 
 Casper&apos;s Dog n Suds Hot Dog on a Stick James Coney Island Nathan&apos;s Famous Portillo&apos;s Sneaky Pete&apos;s Ted&apos;s Hot Dogs Wienerschnitzel 
 Kebabs (Gyros) 
 Buffalo Wings and Rings Dino&apos;s Great Wraps Niko Niko&apos;s Showmars 
 Mexican-style  /
 Tex-Mex 
 Baja Fresh Boloco Cafe Rio California Tortilla Chipotle Mexican Grill Chronic Tacos Del Taco El Pollo Loco Freebirds World Burrito Green Burrito / Red Burrito Mighty Taco Moe&apos;s Southwest Grill Panchero&apos;s Mexican Grill Qdoba Mexican Grill Rubio&apos;s Fresh Mexican Grill Taco Bell Taco Bueno Taco Cabana Taco del Mar Taco John&apos;s Taco Mayo Taco Palenque Taco Tico Taco Time Wahoo&apos;s Fish Taco 
 Sandwiches 
 Arby&apos;s Blimpie Bojangles&apos; Famous Chicken &apos;n Biscuits Bruegger&apos;s Charley&apos;s Grilled Subs Chick-fil-A Così Cousins Subs D&apos;Angelo Sandwich Shops Daphne&apos;s California Greek Earl of Sandwich Erbert&amp;Gerbert&apos;s Firehouse Subs Hogi Yogi Jason&apos;s Deli Jersey Mike&apos;s Subs Jimmy John&apos;s Kelly&apos;s Roast Beef Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop Miami Subs Pizza and Grill Milio&apos;s Sandwiches Mr. Hero Panera Bread Penn Station Potbelly Sandwich Works Quiznos Rax Roast Beef Sandella&apos;s Flatbread Café Schlotzsky&apos;s Steak Escape Subway Texadelphia Togo&apos;s Tropical Smoothie Cafe Tubby&apos;s Tudor&apos;s Biscuit World Which Wich? 
 Seafood 
 Arthur Treacher&apos;s Captain D&apos;s H. Salt Esquire Ivar&apos;s Long John Silver&apos;s Skippers Seafood&amp;Chowder House 
 Former 
 Bess Eaton Burger Chef Carrols Druther&apos;s Naugles Pioneer Chicken Red Barn Sandy&apos;s 
 
 
 
 
 Twitter News Documents Weblinks 
 About Us Report a bug RSS syndicatie Privacy Policy Terms of Service Contact Us 

©2012 RTBot.net
	</body>
</document>
