<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009723" url="http://www.royalbaconsociety.com/2010/11/09/bacon-at-wendys/" time="2012-07-13-03:06" support="4" score="0.006239930451409245" bingtitle="Bacon at Wendy’s | Royal Bacon Society" webtitle="Bacon at Wendys | Royal Bacon Society">
			<query id="001446" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000653" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000649" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="000028" bing-rank="236"/>
	<description>However, that’s where the compliments end. I was ... was an overall good salad, especially for a fast food restaurant. ... The only real drawback here was the condiment mixture ...</description>
	<body>
		Categories 
 Bacon Porn International Bacon Day Bacon Reviews Team Bacon Bacon Cartoons Bacon Art Bacon Gifts Bacon News Bacon Photos Bacon Recipes Famous Bacons Funny Bacon Random Bacon Bacon Video Bacon Pet Products Uncategorized Bacon 
 Bacon Store 
 Accessories Apparel Archie McPhee Bacon Bacon Club Bacon Day Bacon Freak Bacon Jerky Bacon Salt Candy Cookbooks Gifts Grocery Home&amp;Office Kitchen Pet Products Royal Bacon Society Stocking Stuffers T-Shirts Toys&amp;Games 
 Bacon Day Free Bacon Become an Ambassador Contact 
 
 
 Search for: Home / Bacon Reviews / Bacon at Wendy’s 
 
 
 
 

 - Facebook Members WordPress Plugin 
 When you’re in my house you shall do as I do and believe who I believe in. So Bart, butter your bacon. —  Homer Simpson 
 
Popular Posts

 Top 10 Bacon Quotes from Homer Simpson Top 10 Gift Ideas For the Bacon Lover In Your Life Top 10 Quotes About Bacon From Television Bacon Scarves! The Price is…Bacon! Bacon Beer! Yes! Naughty Little Brownie Bacon Wrapped Elvish Cookies Scallops with Creamy Bacon Sauce Bacon Meatballs 
 
Recent Posts

 Help Make a Bacon Dream Come True WWBD? Maple Bacon Granola Celebrate Tax Day with Bacon Goodness Weekend Round-up: Now with Bacon! There Will Be Bacon I KNEW IT! The Price is…Bacon! Naughty Little Brownie Top 10 Gift Ideas For the Bacon Lover In Your Life 
 
Archives

 July 2012  (1) May 2012  (2) April 2012  (1) March 2012  (3) December 2011  (2) November 2011  (2) October 2011  (1) September 2011  (1) August 2011  (1) July 2011  (1) May 2011  (3) April 2011  (1) January 2011  (1) December 2010  (2) November 2010  (2) October 2010  (2) September 2010  (1) August 2010  (2) July 2010  (2) June 2010  (2) April 2010  (4) March 2010  (2) February 2010  (2) January 2010  (2) December 2009  (4) November 2009  (1) September 2009  (8) August 2009  (10) July 2009  (11) June 2009  (3) May 2009  (3) April 2009  (3) March 2009  (4) February 2009  (11) January 2009  (16) December 2008  (22) November 2008  (22) October 2008  (27) September 2008  (25) August 2008  (26) July 2008  (26) June 2008  (26) May 2008  (19) April 2008  (22) March 2008  (23) 
 
Amazing Bacon Things For Sale!
This is just a taste! Check out the RBS Bacon Store! Breakfast Dental Floss- Coffee, Waffle&amp;Bacon
 Buy it now! Ginch Gonch Women’s I Love Bacon–Gogo
 Buy it now! The Bacon Cookbook: More than 150 Recipes from Around the World for Everyone’s Favorite Food [Hardcover]
 Buy it now! Nueske Thick Sliced Applewood Smoked Bacon
 Buy it now! Bacon Bites–6/12Oz Bacon Bites
 Buy it now! Bacon Bubble Buddy
 Buy it now! Mr. Bacon–A handmade friend
 Buy it now! Everyone Wants Me Bacon Sticker
 Buy it now! Tac Bac–Tactical Canned Bacon
 Buy it now! Sparkle Bacon
 Buy it now! Bacon Squeezins Stainless Steel Water Bottle
 Buy it now! J&amp;A Bacon Dressing–12/16Oz J&amp;A Bacon Dressing: GR
 Buy it now! Post 
Bacon at Wendy’s
 
A representative of Wendy’s contacted us recently and asked if we’d like to try some of their menu items, particularly their new“Pick Two”promotion, where you get two items for $4.99. Neither Naseem nor I had been to Wendy’s in years, so we decided to give it a go.

 I decided to try their half BLT Cobb salad and a Junior Bacon Cheeseburger. I’ll start with the burger and keep it brief, as the less said, the better. I understand this is a“junior”burger, probably made with small children in mind. However, that was one seriously small, flat bun with an even smaller beef patty. The veggies were unimpressive and the flavor was bland. The one good thing I can say about this burger is that the bacon was crispy, and therefore stood out in texture and flavor on the sandwich. More often than not, fast food bacon is sort of limp and greasy; this bacon was an exception. However, that’s where the compliments end.

 

I was pleasantly surprised by the salad. The greens were fresh and plentiful, as were most of the other ingredients. The chicken breast was fairly moist and flavorful, and the bacon, again, was crisp. Sadly, there was only one small slice of bacon. For a salad claiming to have its roots in the noble BLT, bacon should probably get a more prominent role. That said, this was an overall good salad, especially for a fast food restaurant.

 Naseem went a different route and ordered the fabled Baconator. Her burger experience was much better than mine. First of all, the Baconator comes on a Kaiser bun, which was a nice touch. The beef  patty was actually larger than the bun, and there were three (crispy!) slices of bacon. Point and point. The only real drawback here was the condiment mixture of ketchup and mayo, but I’ll admit that’s a matter of preference. Neither of us likes the two mixed, especially on a burger with no veggies. I’m sure if ordered without the condiments, she would have liked it even better. I’m not sure this burger really deserves the name Baconator, but maybe if you added a few slices like some have done at Burger King …
	</body>
</document>
