<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009356" url="http://www.hotfrog.co.uk/Products/Take-Away-Food/Kent" time="2012-07-13-02:43" support="1" score="0.00199133439712939" bingtitle="Take Away Food in Kent - Hotfrog - your UK business directory" webtitle="Take Away Food in Kent">
			<query id="001153" bing-rank="117"/>
	<description>Take-Away Food in Kent ... the area…we challenge you to find a better cup! ... Fast Food Fast Food Restaurant</description>
	<body>
		Login 
 
 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 You may have forgotten a search term 
 Add your business 
 
Take Away Food in Kent
 Take-Away Food   Kent (178) 1 - 40 of 178 businesses results Sponsored links Take Away Food 
 www.chopsticksrestaurant.co.uk/ Tasty, Tempting&amp;In Your Area. We&apos;ll Takeaway Your Hunger. Buy Food Online at Tesco 
 www.tesco.com/Food_Drinks Shop Now at Tesco to Get 3 for 2, MultiBuys, Buy 1 Get 1 Free&amp;More! 
 Freshness Guarantee   Half Price Summer Deals   Buy 1 Get 1 Free 
 Order Takeaway Food 
 www.just-eat.co.uk/Take+Away+Food 12000+ Takeaways. 100% Safe Orders! Order Takeaway Food in UK 
 Get Chinese Delivery - Now   Get Indian Delivery - Now Get Pizza Delivery - Now   Get Thai Delivery - Now 
 Takeaway Food 
 www.oldhamsofwestcliff.co.uk/ Top Takeaway Near You. Call Us To Order Now. 
Related information
 Sandwich and Coffee Shop - Outside Catering 
E N A Sandwiches - 22/02/2011
 Located on top of West Hill, ENA Sandwiches has
quickly become a focal meeting point, providing a great menu and the finest
coffee in the area…we challenge you to find a better cup! We are now extending our delivery area so that
nobody misses out! Simply select your order (£12 min), call one of
our friendly staff on the order line below by 10 am and we’ll deliver it to you
between 12 – 1 pm. If you lose our menu, don’t panic! You can view it
online Order Line: 01322… E N A Sandwiches 
Dartford, Kent
 01322 281000 
Located on top of West Hill, ENA Sandwiches has
quickly become a focal meeting point, providing a great menu and the finest
coffee in the area…we challenge you to find a better cup! We are now extending our delivery a…
 
 Cafes And Snack Bars Take Away Food Shops Take-away Food Shops take away food 
 The Kings Ferry Tandoori 
Sheerness, Kent
 01795 667830 
We are a restaurant and takeaway that serve an Indian and Bangladeshi cuisine. The head chef/ manager has over 20 years experience. The Kings Ferry Tandoori only use the finest ingredients and spices. We hope you can vi…
 
 take away food Take away Indian Takeaway tandoori 
   Croft Tea Room CIC 
Orpington, Kent
 0208 462 4801 
The Croft Tea Room St Mary Cray,traditional tea room serving home baked cakes and locally produced foods
 
 cafe Tea Room coffee 
 takeaway2nite.com 
Rochester, Kent
 
takeaway2nite.com – UK takeaway menus online. NEW search directory for takeaways in your area. You&apos;ll never be without a menu again! Comprehensive searchable directory of takeaways throughout the UK. Search the director…
 
 Chicken Takeaway kebab takeaway take away food Menus Online 
 Pizza Point 
Dartford, Kent
 01322222222 
Pizza Point is a takeaway based in Dartford, Kent. The Pizza Point offer great tasting pizzas, burgers, kebabs, meal deals, chips, drinks, desserts and Much more. Order online at Pizza Point Dartford, Kent
 
 Take Away Food Shops take away food Take away Fast Food 
 Star Pizza 
Dover, Kent
 01304448202 
Star Pizza is a takeaway based in Dover, Kent. The Star Pizza offer great tasting pizzas, Southern Fried Chicken and Mouth Watering Desserts. Order online at Star Pizza Dover, Kent
 
 Take Away Food Shops take away food Take away pizza 
 Thailand 
London, Kent
 02086914040 
Thailand is a takeaway based in London, Kent. The Thailand offer great tasting currys, soups, vegetable dishes, rice dishes, chicken and duck dishes, seafood dishes and Much more . Order online at Thailand London, Kent
 
 Take Away Food Shops take away food Take away 
 Noodle and Rice 
London, Kent
 02086919175 
Noodle and Rice is a takeaway based in London, Kent. The Noodle and Rice offer great tasting currys, soup, chicken dishes, vegetable dishes, rice dishes and Much more. Order online at Noodle and Rice London, Kent
 
 Take Away Food Shops take away food Take away 
 Noodle and Rice 
London, Kent
 02086919175 
Noodle and Rice is a takeaway based in London, Kent. The Noodle and Rice offer great tasting currys, soup, chicken dishes, vegetable dishes, rice dishes and Much more. Order online at Noodle and Rice London, Kent
 
 Take Away Food Shops take away food Take away 
 Picnic Pantry 
Broadstairs, Kent
 01843 579799 
Picnic Pantry cafe in Broadstairs Kent UK for all your Breakfast, Lunch and snack needs. Why not visit this quaint seaside town and enjoy a nice picnic lunch by the sea or on the clifftop. Sandwiches, rolls, hot potatoe…
 
 Cafes And Snack Bars Take Away Food Shops take away food Take away 
 B B Q Express 
Welling, Kent
 020 8303 5979 
The BBQ Express chain of restaurants takes a new approach to healthy eating. With over 20 years experience we offer succulent tender grilled Piri Piri chicken with a variety of supplementary flavours and spices. Contact…
 
 Take-away Food Shops pizza kebabs pizzas 
 Nonnas Kitchen 
Broadstairs, Kent
 01843 579799 
We hope you will drop by the restaurant to experience perfectly cooked pasta, authentic Italian sauces and delcious crispy pizza
 
 Take-away Food Shops pizza 
 Caffe Nero Chislehurst 
Chislehurst, Kent
 020 8467 8100 
The Caffè Nero philosophy is really very simple: Premium Italian coffee. A warm and welcoming atmosphere. Good food and great personal service
 
 Take-away Food Shops mail order coffee coffee bar Italian Coffee 
 The Farmhouse Kitchen Catering Company 
Dartford, Kent
 01474 703930 
The Farmhouse Kitchen Catering Company We deliver individual breakfast and lunch orders of sandwiches, baguettes, lunches, snacks and cold drinks We have many satisfied local customers, several of whom we d…
 
 Cafes And Snack Bars cafe 
 Flamers Pizza&amp;Curry 
Rochester, Kent
 01634 711511 
Flamers Pizza&amp;Curry - Pizza and Curry Restaurant in the heart of Rochester. View our menu and order online here
 
 takeaway pizza 
 Cafe Rouge 
Tenterden, Kent
 01580 763029 
Café Rouge is a group of French restaurants serving a delicious all-day menu of classic French dishes with a contemporary twist
 
 Cafes And Snack Bars Take-away Food Shops cafe 
 Longfield Pizzaland&amp;Kebab House 
Longfield, Kent
 01474 872700 
Free Home Delivery To New Ash Green&apos; West Kingsdown Hartley&apos;Longfield,Fawkam,Newbarn,Brandshatch, Pizza&apos;s Kebab&apos;s burger&apos;s
Pastas deserts ice creams drinks
 
 Take-away Food Shops pizza 
 Akash Balti House 
Swanscombe, Kent
 01322 386808 
indian take away food from the Akash Balti House. Great food, great prices. A huge selection of quality food available for delivery or collection
 
 take away food Take away Indian Takeaway Tandoori Take Away 
 Nosh-up 
FOLKESTONE, Kent
 
You can arrange to either collect or have your food delivered, and enjoy the added convenience of paying online using our unique and secure payment engine Click to suggest a restaurant and we will be in contact…
 
 take away food takeaway Fried Chicken pizza 
 Saltmarsh 
Whitstable, Kent
 01227 272955 
The Duke of Cumberland Hotel, for quality accommodation, food and drink in Whitstable, Kent
 
 Cafes And Snack Bars Take-away Food Shops 
 Sponsored links the curry cottage 
 best indian in town 15% discount on all orders 
 www.thecurrycottage.co.uk/ Shakeaway Maidstone 
Maidstone, Kent
 01622 661010 
 Take-away Food Shops Milkshakes 
 Subway 
Sheerness, Kent
 01795 668733 
 Take-away Food Shops 
 Eva&apos;s Tea Room 
Birchington, Kent
 01843 845385 
 Take-away Food Shops take away food Take away Tea Room 
 Pizza Plus Chicken&amp;Cafe 
Gillingham, Kent
 01634 855535 
 Cafes And Snack Bars cafe pizza chicken 
 Marios Village Chip Shop 
Margate, Kent
 01843 836889 
 Take-away Food Shops 
 Willows Cafe 
Dartford, Kent
 01322 529084 
 Cafes And Snack Bars cafe 
 The King Fish Bar 
Sandwich, Kent
 01304 619267 
 Take-away Food Shops 
 Purple Chillies 
Gravesend, Kent
 01474 329888 
 Take-away Food Shops takeaway Indian Takeaway 
 Flamers Pizza 
Rochester, Kent
 01634 711123 
 pizza 
 Florence Rose Tea Room 
Margate, Kent
 01843 224005 
 Take-away Food Shops Tea Room coffee shops coffee 
 Piece Of Cake Tea Rooms 
Sandwich, Kent
 01304 612525 
 Cafes And Snack Bars Take-away Food Shops Tea rooms 
 Zenmor Take Away Food Shops 
Tonbridge, Kent
 01580 891447 
 Take Away Food Shops take away food 
 Poche Take Away Food Shops 
Dartford, Kent
 01322223380 
 Take Away Food Shops take away food 
 Cafe Lorenzo 
Swanley, Kent
 01322 665755 
 Cafes And Snack Bars Take Away Food Shops Take-away Food Shops take away food 
 Beltinge Takeaway 
Herne Bay, Kent
 01227 375314 
 Take Away Food Shops Take-away Food Shops take away food takeaway 
 Big Munchies 
Ashford, Kent
 01233 646464 
 Take Away Food Shops Take-away Food Shops take away food Take away 
 Spitfire Cafe 
Westerham, Kent
 01959 571676 
 Cafes And Snack Bars Take Away Food Shops Take-away Food Shops take away food 
 Queenborough Kebab&amp;Pizza 
Queenborough, Kent
 01795 665305 
 Take Away Food Shops Take-away Food Shops take away food Take away 
 Teke&apos;s Take Away Food Shops 
Gillingham, Kent
 01634576033 
 Take Away Food Shops take away food 
 Welling Sandwich Bar 
Welling, Kent
 020 8301 6810 
 Take-away Food Shops take away food Take away sandwich 
 Sponsored links Order lunch online 
 Software for ordering lunch online 
 www.butterware.co.uk/ Order Takeaways Online 
 Pizza Kebab Curry for Home Delivery Easy Online Ordering | Pay by Card 
 www.takeawaysrus.co.uk/ Food Takeaway Sale 
 Buy Food Takeaway And Save Big - Low UK Shipping&amp;Fast! 
 food-takeaway.supaprice.co.uk/ First page Prev 10 pages   1 2 3 4 5 Last page Next 10 pages 
Businesses (178) 
 Related keywords 
 Take-away Food Shops Take away Take Away Food Shops Cafes And Snack Bars Cafes bars snack bars cafe Take Away Meal Outlets takeaway 
 Take-Away Food by region 
 Cinque Ports 
 Take-Away Food by city/town 
 SHEERNESS, Kent MARGATE, Kent HERNE BAY, Kent WELLING, Kent DARTFORD, Kent GRAVESEND, Kent BROADSTAIRS, Kent ROCHESTER, Kent BELVEDERE, Kent BECKENHAM, Kent RAMSGATE, Kent HYTHE, Kent SIDCUP, Kent CHATHAM, Kent FOLKESTONE, Kent DEAL, Kent SANDWICH, Kent BIRCHINGTON, Kent ORPINGTON, Kent SWANLEY, Kent &amp;London&amp;, Kent GILLINGHAM, Kent AYLESFORD, Kent LONGFIELD, Kent WHITSTABLE, Kent MAIDSTONE, Kent TENTERDEN, Kent QUEENBOROUGH, Kent ASHFORD, Kent SWANSCOMBE, Kent FAVERSHAM, Kent DOVER, Kent WEST WICKHAM, Kent WESTERHAM, Kent NEW ROMNEY, Kent TONBRIDGE, Kent BEXLEYHEATH, Kent 
 Sponsored links Ready Meal Delivery 
 Free Whatever the Weather
By Our Caring&amp;Helpful Staff 
 www.wiltshirefarmfoods.com/Delivery Takeaway Menu 
 Find Takeaway Menu
Q&amp;A Takeaway Menu 
 www.ask.com/Takeaway+Menu Takeaway 
 Try Us for a Taste of India!
Top Indian Takeaway in Your Area. 
 www.essenceofasiabillingshurst.co.uk/ Food at Morrisons™ 
 Fresh Food Offers now on!
Fresh Food Is What We Do. 
 www.morrisons.co.uk/FreshFood morrisons.co.uk is rated Businesses that regularly add new information and match your search 
Most active

 This week All time 
 
 The Kings Ferry Tandoori 
 Products (1) 
 
 
 E N A Sandwiches 
 Products (1) 
 The Kings Ferry Tandoori 
 Products (1) 
 Croft Tea Room CIC 

 
 Business profiles just added to Hotfrog that match your search 
Just added
 
 E N A Sandwiches 21/01/2011 The Kings Ferry Tandoori 02/08/2010 Croft Tea Room CIC 16/04/2010 Ben Burgers 21/01/2008 takeaway2nite.com 14/03/2007 
 Most viewed businesses matching your search enquiry 
Most popular
 
 The Kings Ferry Tandoori E N A Sandwiches takeaway2nite.com 
 
 Small Business Hub 
 
Sharing tips, ideas and advice to help grow your small business
 View the Small Business Hub 
 Hotfrog AdVantage 
 
Hotfrog AdVantage ads appear above the rest in Hotfrog feature pages. By upgrading today your ad will appear in front of potential customers before they notice your competitors.
 Find out more 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 You may have forgotten a search term 
 
Create your free Hotfrog business profile
 Add your business 
Join the Hotfrog community on:
 
Share on:
 
 About Hotfrog Advertise with us Contact us Terms of Use Privacy Policy Help 
 
 Hotfrog Small Business Hub 

 Grow your business Case studies Hotfrog how tos 
 © Copyright Reed Business Information Pty Ltd 2005-2012 (v 11.5.7mvt.009 )
	</body>
</document>
