<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009589" url="http://www.freesamplesite.com/ydf/showthread.php/262250-New-Woman-Within-Code-30-off-entire-order" time="2012-07-13-03:00" support="4" score="0.004433727101822498" bingtitle="New Woman Within Code 30% off entire order" webtitle="New Woman Within Code 30% off entire order">
			<query id="000280" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000123" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000623" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000560" bing-rank="48"/>
	<description>... 30% discount will be applied to your ENTIRE order. ... combined with any other offer, except defer bill. ... Fast Food &amp; Restaurant Coupons; Drug Store &amp; Pharmacy Coupons</description>
	<body>
		Register Help Remember Me? 
 
 Home Forum 
 FAQ Calendar Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 

 
 Blogs What&apos;s New? 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum YDF Freebies - Discounts - Deals Freebies - Discounts - Deals New Woman Within Code 30% off entire order 
 
 If this is your first visit, be sure to
 check out the FAQ by clicking the
 link above. You may have to register before you can post: click the register link above to proceed. To start viewing messages,
 select the forum that you want to visit from the selection below. 
 + Reply to Thread Results 1 to 1 of 1 
Thread: New Woman Within Code 30% off entire order 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Search Thread 
 
   Advanced Search 
 
 
 09-02-2009,  08:01 PM #1 Mrs.&quot;G&quot; 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Aug 2007 Location Westport, CT Posts 433 
New Woman Within Code 30% off entire order
 *Here&apos;s how to redeem your offer:

Place one or more items in your shopping bag.
At check-out, type WW36437 in the Promotion Code box, then click Apply.
The 30% discount will be applied to your ENTIRE order.
Continue shopping or begin checkout.

 http://clickserve.cc-dt.com/link/tpl...00000000001052 

Restrictions: offer ends midnight EST 09/07/09. Cannot be combined with any other offer, except defer bill. One offer per purchase Does not include shipping and handling or taxes. Not redeemable for cash. Not valid on prior purchases, charges or for the purchase of E-Gift or Gift Cards. Please note: offer does not apply to Halloween Costumes, Home and Kitchen items. This coupon applies to both regular-price and clearance merchandise, which is already reduced up to 80% off.Adjustments will not be processed for previous orders. Last edited by Admin; 09-03-2009 at 06:39 AM . Reply With Quote
	</body>
</document>
