<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009010" url="http://web3.userinstinct.com/49337113-bills-news-confectionery-ltd.htm" time="2012-07-13-02:25" support="1" score="0.0006003644660227714" bingtitle="Bill&apos;s News &amp; Confectionery Ltd in Dawson Creek, British Columbia ..." webtitle="Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd in Dawson Creek, British Columbia. (bc.) #49337113">
			<query id="000686" bing-rank="33"/>
	<description>Name: Bill&apos;s News &amp; Confectionery Ltd Street: 10212 ... Friendly staff and owners, and a great place to work ... Other branches: Coffee &amp; Tea Shops | Fast Food Restaurant | Pizza ...</description>
	<body>
		Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd in Dawson Creek, British Columbia (bc)

 Name: Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd 
Street: 10212 10 Street
Dawson Creek, bc V1G3T4-
Phone: (250) 782-2933
 
4 Ratings: 
 
 Rate now: Please Select 6 - very good 5 4 3 2 1 - very bad 
Website of Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd: n/a - add the website 4free

Are you the Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd owner ? Modify or add information on your entry or ask to delete your entry for free here
 
Map to Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd
 
Blog
 
Help the Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd Blog of Dawson Creek

Click here and write a blogpost in the Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd Blog of Dawson Creek without signup!
 
Ratings
 
Ratings on Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd in Dawson Creek 
was rated as good by a Dawson Creek citizen.
 
Reviews 
 
Write a Review on Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd in the city Dawson Creek:
 
 Your name: 
 

 Your review: 
 

 Spam-Protection: Sum of 3 plus 9 
 
 
 Shawna posted on 11/12/2008: 
Bill&apos;s News is awesome. The second or third (I forget) largest magazine seller in B.C., they also have lots of candy, chocolate, pop, microwavable sandwiches (and a microwave in the store) also a large assortment of Novels and comic books. Friendly staff and owners, and a great place to work XD

 
Ads
   
General Information
 
General Information on Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd in Dawson Creek

In the branche &quot;Candy Stores&quot; in Dawson Creek, British Columbia 2 companies are listed. Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd in Dawson Creek is rated as avrg. good. 
 If you are the owner of &quot;Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd&quot; signup here and start your company press release room for free and get in touch with the Dawson Creek- people.
If you are a Dawson Creek-citizen, please write about your experiences about Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd in the Candy Stores-Blog or the Candy Stores-Forum.
   
Press-Releases
 
Press-Releases about Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd

The owner of Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd Dawson Creek didn´t use the free of charge press-release- room yet. If you are from Dawson Creek and in contact with Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd please tell them about this opportunity. Registered Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd owner: Go here .
   
Forum
 
Visit the Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd Forum of Dawson Creek

Click here and discuss with others in the Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd Forum of Dawson Creek Forum ! Quick signup!
   
Attention
 
The Dawson Creek Forum is currently viewed by 9 visitors. The Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd received 58 comments last month! Get in touch with the Dawson Creek citizens!
 Login | Join userinstinct 
       
 Business Pages Home &gt; Company-Search &gt; British Columbia business pages &gt; Dawson Creek business pages &gt; Candy Stores in Dawson Creek &gt;Bill&apos;s News&amp;Confectionery Ltd in Dawson Creek, British Columbia

 
 What?  
   Company or Industry   Where?  
   City,state    
Business in Dawson Creek:
 
 A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z
 
 Login | Join Userinstinct | Add Entry 4 free 
   
Related
 
 Ask to delete this entry | 
More Info on cities nearby: Delta | Duncan | Fort Nelson | Fort St John | Kamloops |
Other branches: Coffee&amp;Tea Shops | Fast Food Restaurant | Pizza Restaurant | Aircraft Charter Rental&amp;Leasing Svc | Automobile Rental&amp;Leasing |
Other companies: Fas Gas Mile O Service Dawson Creek | Shell Canada Products, Service Station Dawson Creek | Independence Networking Services Inc Dawson Creek | Step Up &apos;n&apos; Ride Society Dawson Creek | Tim Hortons Dawson Creek |
Dawson Creek business pages is organized in: Global Sitemap | Company Sitemap | City-Sitemap32 and Branches-Sitemap56817 .
	</body>
</document>
