<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009788" url="http://www.etstrategicmarketing.com/SmJan-Feb3/art10.html" time="2012-07-13-03:11" support="7" score="0.01440376210060324" bingtitle="Strategic Marketing" webtitle="Strategic Marketing">
			<query id="000788" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000536" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000913" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000787" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="001164" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000724" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000287" bing-rank="242"/>
	<description>The more shopper-employee contacts take place ... or less at the level of the cashiers face. Shopping ... The fast-food restaurant is zoned in such ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Inbox Archives Write 
 for Us Reader&apos;s 
 Articles Messageboard Feedback 

 
 
 * Strategic 
 Issues * Telecom 
 Special * Strategic 
 Brand Management * Agency-Related 
 Matters * Perspectives * Review * Foreword * Lets 
 Talk 

 
 Advertise 
 with us * Why SM? * Advertising rates 
 


   Magazines 
    Gen.Mgmt.Review 
 Investor&apos;s 
 Guide 
 Brand 
 Equity 
 Corporate 
 Dossier 
        ET 
 Headlines   Stocks   Forex   World   

 
 Why 
 People Buy 
 The Science 
 of Shopping 
___________________________________________
 Paco Underhill
 
 
 Branding 
 and traditional advertising build brand awareness 
 and purchase predisposition. However, these 
 do not always translate into sales. Brand value 
 is not the blind force it used to be. Many purchasing 
 decisions are made or can be heavily influenced 
 on the floor of the shop itself. Shoppers are 
 susceptible to the impressions and information 
 they acquire in stores. 
 Signage, shelf-position, display space and 
 special fixtures all make it either more likely 
 or less likely that a shopper will buy a particular 
 item. Meaningful growth, which Wall Street 
 demands, can be stimulated effectively at 
 the store level. Some underutilised means 
 to measure what happens inside the store are 
 as follows: 

 1. 
 Conversion Rate
The very concept of conversion rate implies 
 that shoppers need to be transformed into 
 buyers. Conversion rates vary widely depending 
 on what kind of store or product we&apos;re talking 
 about. In some sections of the supermarket, 
 conversion rate is probably 100% (dairy or 
 toilet paper). In an art gallery full of paintings, 
 probably the conversion will be less than 
 1%. Conversion rate measures what you make 
 of what you have - it shows how well or how 
 poorly the entire enterprise is functioning. 

 2. 
 Time spent in the store 
The amount of time spent in the store is the 
 single most important factor determining how 
 much the customer will buy. Over and over 
 again, studies show a direct correlation. 
 For instance, in an electronics store, buyers 
 spent 9 minutes 29 seconds, whereas non-buyers 
 spend 5 minutes and 6 seconds. In some stores, 
 buyers spend three times as much time as non-buyers.
 

 Once 
 the customer is inside the store, they 
 are busy making adjustments, simultaneously 
 slowing their pace, adjusting their eyes 
 to the change in light and scale, craning 
 their necks to take in all there is to 
 see 

 3. 
 Interception Rate 
The more shopper-employee contacts take place, 
 the greater the average sale. In a large clothing 
 chain studied, the interception rate was 25%, 
 which meant that three-quarters of all shoppers 
 never spoke a word to a salesperson. This 
 meant that in all probability, customers were 
 becoming frustrated, wandering around or just 
 plain confused or in need of information. 
 If the staff was not helping the store sell, 
 then what was it doing? 

 4. 
 Waiting time 
Few retailers realise that when shoppers are 
 made to wait too long in line, their impression 
 of overall service plunges. Busy executives 
 don&apos;t like to wait but many people don&apos;t realise 
 that normal people feel the same way too. 
 A household goods chain VP was startled when 
 he saw that a woman who had just spent 22 
 minutes shopping at the store joined a long 
 check-out line and stood there until it dawned 
 on her that she was in cashier hell and abandoned 
 her full cart and exited the place. 

 5. 
 Not knowing who the customers are 
This is a remarkable example of business ignorance. 
 Consider the pet treats manufacturer who stocks 
 his wares too high, unaware that his main 
 buyers are very old people! Worse still was 
 the restaurant owner, whose family outlet 
 had too many tables for two and too few tables 
 for four. The tables were empty even as diners 
 stood in line waiting for tables.
The above considerations clearly indicate 
 that shopping, like every science has its 
 own set of rules that retailers need to abide 
 by. 

 The 
 First Principle 
There are certain physical and anatomical 
 abilities, tendencies, limitations and needs 
 common to all people, and the retail environment 
 must be tailored to these characteristics. 
 In other words, banks, stores and restaurants 
 must be friendly to the specifications of 
 the human animal. Amenability and profitability 
 are inextricably linked.
The first principle goes into every aspect 
 of the shopping experience. Shoppers either 
 see merchandise and signs clearly or they 
 don&apos;t. They will reach objects either with 
 difficulty or with ease. They will move through 
 areas swiftly or slowly or not at all. All 
 of these physiological and anatomical factors 
 come into play simultaneously, forming a complex 
 matrix of behaviours, which must be understood 
 if the retail environment is to adapt itself 
 to successfully to the shopper.
For instance, retailers will charge manufacturers 
 for placing their name on the front door, 
 which sounds like a smart use of the marketing 
 dollar. And then you realise that when 
 shoppers approach the front door, all they 
 are looking for is a sign whether to push 
 or pull.
Once the customer is inside the store, they 
 are busy making adjustments, simultaneously 
 slowing their pace, adjusting their eyes to 
 the change in light and scale, craning their 
 necks to take in all there is to see. They 
 are not truly in the store yet. They are making 
 a transition and whatever they cross during 
 the transition is lost on them. Today, many 
 stores have automatic doors, which make life 
 easier for customers, especially those with 
 packages or baby strollers. The effortlessness 
 of entering only serves to enlarge the transition 
 zone because they is nothing to stop the shopper 
 even a little bit.
There are two things to be done to this zone, 
 either forget about accomplishing anything 
 there or bend the rules. A classic example 
 is that of a store which had placed a large 
 bin of deeply discounted merchandise, a deal 
 so good, it stopped shoppers in their tracks. 

 Shopfloor 
 Syndromes 
* THE BOOMERANG EFFECT
This is a measure of how often shoppers fail 
 to walk completely through an aisle from one 
 end to another. Sometimes, the shopper makes 
 it halfway down the aisle before turning back. 
 For the retailer, a good thing to do would 
 be to put the most popular products in the 
 middle of the aisle. The manufacturer on the 
 other hand has to keep his products as close 
 to the end of the aisle as possible.
* THE BUTT-BRUSH FACTOR
When merchandise is displayed in such a manner 
 that the customer gets bumped into or brushed 
 constantly against, they move away from it 
 even if they want to buy it. This is called 
 the butt-brush factor. Retailers have to ensure 
 that merchandise is placed properly. 

 Using 
 Signages Effectively 
The role of merchandising has become crucial 
 because shoppers with disposable income are 
 giving in to their impulses at every point. 
 In-store media cannot be dumped in empty spaces. 
 First, you have to get the customers attention 
 and having done that, present your message 
 in a clear logical fashion. Escalators are 
 a good option because the customer is moving 
 up slowly. For maximum exposure, a sign should 
 interrupt the natural line of sight in any 
 given area. The number one thing people look 
 at is other people. That is why some of the 
 most effective signs in fast food restaurants 
 are the ones sitting atop the cash registers-more 
 or less at the level of the cashiers face. 

 Shopping 
 Principles Applied to Various Industries 
* FAST FOOD
When a customer enters a restaurant, he is 
 looking for one of two things, the counter 
 or the bathroom. There&apos;s no point in placing 
 a sign for people to see on their way to the 
 bathroom because they have more important 
 things on their minds. But a sign facing people 
 as they leave the bathroom works fine.
McDonalds found that 75% of customers read 
 the menu board after they order, while they 
 wait for their food. That&apos;s a time when people 
 read anythingthey&apos;ve got their change 
 and there&apos;s nothing on their minds. That&apos;s 
 a perfect window for a longer message, something 
 you want you customer to know the next time 
 they come.
It is not important that every sign must stand 
 on its own and contain an entire message. 
 The fast-food restaurant is zoned in such 
 a manner that the deeper in the customer is, 
 the longer the message can be. 

 * 
 BANKS
Banks are probably the worst offenders of 
 sign placement. A California -based bank decided 
 that it would be smart to promote its new 
 free checking policy by hanging outdoor banners 
 visible from the heavily travelled road beyond 
 he door. The banner read&quot;please come 
 in and ask our banker to explain our wonderful 
 new free checking policy. A banner saying&quot;free checking&quot;would have been 
 enough.
Customer writing tables are zones where the 
 customer is concentrating on filling out a 
 deposit slip or endorsing cheques. He is concentrating 
 too hard to think about anything else and 
 once through, races to get into the line. 
 It&apos;s a bad place to tell them something. Customers 
 should pass racks containing brochures of 
 services offered as they exit, not as they 
 enter, because they are more relaxed and can 
 afford to take in external data.
Roads teach us the way to use signs. The similarity 
 between people walking and driving is that 
 the best signs are the ones that can be read 
 fast, and positioned so that you can read 
 them while moving.
 

 The 
 similarity between people walking and 
 driving is that the best signs are the 
 ones that can be read fast, and positioned 
 so that you can read them while moving 

 * 
 CLOTHING
The most obvious arena for touch and trial 
 is clothing. It&apos;s a truism that improving 
 the quality of dressing rooms increases sales. 
 The dressing room is not a convenience. It 
 is a selling tool, like a window display or 
 advertising. Shopper conversion increases 
 by 50% when there is a staff-initiated contact 
 and by 100% when there is a staff-initiated 
 contact with use of the dressing room. The 
 furnishings of the trial room should be what 
 you would want in your boudoir, the lighting 
 should make everyone look like a million bucks 
 and the mirrors should be large, plentiful 
 and first-rate. This is after all the &apos;closing 
 point&apos; of the sale. 

 Men 
 v/s Women 
Most purchasing traditionally falls to women 
 and they usually do it willingly. They take 
 pride in their ability to shop prudently and 
 well. Almost all women go to the supermarket 
 armed with a shopping list. Less than a quarter 
 of men do. 86% of women look at price tags 
 while only 72% of the men do.
Ignoring the price tag is almost a measure 
 of male virility. There is a high level of 
 impulse buying (almost 60 to 70% for both 
 sexes). Women love the experience of shopping 
 whereas men love the thrill of paying.
Male love of technology and gadgetry of course 
 can put women shoppers to shame. Men hate 
 to ask directions or for help, but they like 
 to get their information first-hand as from 
 written material, instructional videos or 
 computer screens. If a retailer were to put 
 up a women&apos;s clothing store next to a computer 
 software store, both the sexes would be most 
 grateful. 

 Kids 
Children consume even more mass media than 
 adults. The marketplace wants kids, needs 
 kids and children are flattered by the invitation 
 and want to oblige. A few important tips:
 

 Men 
 hate to ask directions or for help, but 
 they like to get their information first-hand 
 as from written material, instructional 
 videos or computer screens 

 1. If a store is unwelcoming to children, 
 parent-shoppers will get the message and stay 
 away. Stores that depend on female customers 
 need to ensure that all aisles and paths between 
 racks and fixtures are wide enough for a baby 
 stroller to pass.
 2. Children can be counted on to be 
 enthusiastic consumers or co-consumers as 
 long as their needs are considered. Conversely, 
 the retailer has to child-proof his shop in 
 order to prevent unhappy situations. The obvious 
 dangers are electrical outlets and sharp-edged 
 shelves.
 3. If the parents&apos; sustained attention 
 is required, say by a bank officer or by a 
 car salesman, someone has to take care of 
 a restless, bored child.
 4. It is good to have miniature seating 
 but remember that a child is used to the parental 
 lap. It would be advisable to have some comfy 
 armchairs around so that both the parent and 
 the child are comfortable.
The science of shopping is a hybrid discipline, 
 part physical science and part social science 
 and only part science at all because it is 
 also an art. It is a practical field concerned 
 with providing information that can improve 
 the retailer&apos;s edge and the odds of making 
 a wrong decision. Much of the value of the 
 science lies in the ability to go beyond collecting 
 data and making educated guesses about what 
 it means and how best to respond.
Even with all this learning, there are creative 
 merchants who throw this science to the wind. 
 Consider the 400 sq. foot store in Toronto 
 called No.6. In that miniscule space, everything 
 from hats, dresses, bags, jewellery, scarves 
 and music are sold. The store is a triumph 
 of energy over space and budget limitations 
 and it is tough not to buy something from 
 there.
For most scientists, the most exciting part 
 of research is the exact moment of discovery. 
 There is much more to be discovered and much 
 more to be learnt. 



 The 
 above article has been condensed from&quot;Why 
 We Buy: The Science of Shopping&quot;by Paco 
 Underhill published by Simon and Schuster, 
 New York. All rights of the author and the 
 publisher are reserved.

 

 
 TURNING 
 POINT 
 With 
 the advent of Shopping 
 Malls that offer multiple 
 brand choices, department 
 stores such as Shoppers 
 Stop have to reinvent 
 their USP or else they 
 are likely to lose business 
 to exclusive stores of 
 the same brands operating 
 in the same Malls (or 
 others in the close vicinity). 
 Arvind 
 Singhal
Chairman, KSA Technopak India 
 Pvt. Limited 
 

 
 

 Print 
 this Page Email 
 this Page Your 
 Opinion Rate 
 this article 
 


 

 
 

 Back 
 to top Copyright©Strategic Marketing All Rights Reserved. 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 Online 
 Forum What 
 do You want to say on
 Rural Marketing Click 
 here to let the world know... 
 
 
 
 Should stockbrokers be barred from 
 sharing client-specific information with third parties? 
 Vote 
 
 
 Choice 
 board Are 
 you
satisfied with Strategic Marketing
 (you can make difference) 
 
 Yes 
 
 No 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Times 
 Group Sites- The 
 Times Of India  |  The Economic Times  |  ET Invest  |  ETintelligence  |  Femina  |  Filmfare  |  Navbharat Times  |  Times Classifieds  |  Property Times  |  Education Times  |  Maharashtra Times  |  Responservice  |  Indianadsabroad  |  Jobs&amp;Careers  |  Times Multimedia
	</body>
</document>
