<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009112" url="http://findarticles.com/p/articles/mi_m0675/is_3_19/ai_75085428/" time="2012-07-13-02:30" support="2" score="0.001142092741116825" bingtitle="CUP `N&apos; POST Time Well Spent - keeping physically fit while ..." webtitle="CUP `NPOST Time Well Spent - keeping physically fit while maintaining a busy schedule | American Fitness | Find Articles">
			<query id="000711" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="001466" bing-rank="54"/>
	<description>CUP `N&apos; POST Time Well Spent - keeping physically ... However, a typical fast food restaurant will not provide the ... play a family game of touch football in the park?</description>
	<body>
		FIND ARTICLES IN THE INTERACTIVE BUSINESS NETWORK RESOURCE LIBRARY Money Library http://findarticles.com/ 
 Business Money Life&amp;Health 
 Search 
Departments

 Business Reference Technology News 
 
Popular Publications

 Economic Review Entrepreneur Business Wire Chief Executive, The Market Wire 
 
Departments

 Economy Careers Saving Spending Investing Retirement 
 
Popular Publications

 Better Nutrition Natural Health New American, The Encyclopedia of ... Real Estate Weekly 
 
Departments

 Arts Home&amp;Garden Autos Sports Health 
 
Popular Publications

 New York Times Upfront Health Management Technology Automotive Manufacturing&amp;... Sierra Automotive Industries 
 FindArticles / American Fitness / May, 2001 
CUP `N&apos; POST Time Well Spent - keeping physically fit while maintaining a busy schedule

by Michelle Brown
 Tweet 
 1 2 Next 
 More Articles of Interest 
 Mutual Fund Companies Don Yacktman&apos;s Wild Ride - fall of a fund manager The ABCs of RRSPs: contribution room, spousal plans, self-directed plans…they&apos;re all addressed here - RRSPs Best of the Premium Credit Cards Market Wire 
 
How to make fitness a priority in your busy everyday life.

Whether you are a stay-at-home mom, business executive, university student or just an average person, time is a precious commodity. Consequently, most people push exercise to the bottom of their to-do lists. Why must modern life dictate the neglect of your physical fitness? Here are 10 tips to help keep your body fit while maintaining your busy schedule.

1. Partner Up! A good exercise partner keeps you accountable and encourages you when the going gets tough. On those days when the call of jelly donuts and a comfortable armchair seem almost audible, a good partner will drag you out of the house. Not only will your partner help you be consistent, but someone who is more physically fit will push you to run faster, jump higher and leap farther than you would on your own. Finding a good exercise partner is the key to a consistent physical fitness regimen.

2. Get Your ZZZs. After exercise, sleep is usually the next item shoved off to-do lists. One of the worst things you can do for your body is neglect the pillow. Without proper rest, your body will not have the energy to expend on exercise. A regular bedtime and a consistent time of rising will do wonders for your sleep life. Not only will you find it easier to get up in the morning, you will also fall asleep more readily.

3. Eat Healthy. The busy American knows what is easy. Driving to the nearest McDonald&apos;s will save time, money and effort. However, a typical fast food restaurant will not provide the nutrients needed to maintain a healthy state of physical fitness. Instead of eating fast food, eat smart food. Plan ahead. Bring your lunch instead of buying greasy cafeteria food. Pack an apple instead of cookies. Avoid the temptation to grab dinner on your way home.

4. Set Realistic Goals. Do not tell yourself to lose 30 pounds by your 25th class reunion if the event is two weeks away. Try saying you will ride the stationary bike for 30 minutes a day until the reunion. This is an achievable goal (even with a busy schedule) and will make you feel great about yourself on the big night, regardless of how much weight you have lost. Remember, a lot of small goals will add up to noticeable progress. However, achieving true physical fitness takes time, patience and diligence.
 
5. Reward Yourself. Nobody ever said exercise is easy. If you find yourself unmotivated to make time for exercise, promise yourself a reward once you achieve a goal. For instance, if you are able to consistently jog three miles a day, five days a week for four weeks, you will buy yourself a new pair of jeans. Chances are, you will need smaller jeans anyway.

6. Group Exercise! Make use of your local resources! Most communities offer a variety of opportunities for fun exercise. Decide what type of activity suits you and find it ... or create it! Whether it&apos;s a church softball league, pickup basketball games at a nearby school gymnasium, a jogging club through a local athletic shoe store or a spinning class at a gym, everyone can find a type of exercise he or she enjoys. When you have fun being active, exercise seems less of a chore and you do not mind creating time in your schedule for it.

7. Schedule It. Get out your organizer. Boot up your Palm Pilot. The only way to fit a workout into a busy schedule is to schedule it. Once you&apos;ve done that, don&apos;t compromise on the block of time you have set aside.

8. &quot;Same Bat-Time ...&quot; Find the most convenient time to exercise. Exercise may come most naturally in the morning (when the weather is cooler and you&apos;ve had a full night of sleep), midday (because you are fully awake) or in the evening (to relieve the pressures of the day). As you plan your exercise, try to schedule it at the same time every day. This helps your body expect when to exercise. The routine also makes it easier for you to get out there and be active, despite your busy schedule.

9. Use Time Wisely. Any busy person knows that time management is the key to success. The same is true for your exercise time. Depending on what kind of activity you participate in, you can often double-use your time. Review a presentation in your head or think through a problem. Even if you cannot use your exercise time for &quot;practical&quot; mental activities, use it for personal meditation. Go over the day&apos;s activities or tomorrow&apos;s schedule. Everyone needs a little &quot;me&quot; time every day. Use your exercise time for this purpose.

10. Keep a Healthy Mindset. The purpose of being physically fit is not to look like a supermodel, but to be able to enjoy life to its fullest. Even if you don&apos;t look like Mister Universe or Miss America, can you climb the stairs without being winded? Can you easily play a family game of touch football in the park? Think of exercise as a means to an end, not as an end in itself.

Now you are mentally equipped to pursue and maintain an active lifestyle. No excuses! The only thing left to do is ... to do it! Even when your schedule overflows with appointments, remember that physical fitness helps give you the stamina needed to survive. Use these tips to keep your busy life from outrunnning your jogging shoes!

Michelle Brown is a freelance writer who will be graduating in May 2001 with a Bachelor of Arts degree in English education from Biola University in La Mirada, California.
 COPYRIGHT 2001 Aerobics and Fitness Association of America COPYRIGHT 2001 Gale Group Tweet 
 1 2 Next 
 Search 
 All ResourceLibrary 
 
Business

 Business Reference Technology News 
 
Money

 Economy Careers Saving Spending Investing Retirement 
 
Life&amp;Health

 Arts Home&amp;Garden Autos Sports Health 
 ie8 fix 
 Most Recent Publications 
 
 Encyclopedia of Alternative Medicine American Fitness Risk&amp;Insurance Real Estate Alert Running&amp;FitNews 
 
 Most Popular Articles 
 
 Mutual Fund Companies Don Yacktman&apos;s Wild Ride - fall of a fund manager The ABCs of RRSPs: contribution room, spousal plans, self-directed plans…they&apos;re all addressed here - RRSPs Best of the Premium Credit Cards Market Wire 
 
 Most Popular Publications 
 
 Money Digest Kiplinger&apos;s Personal Finance Magazine Financial Planning Real Estate Alert Market Wire 
 
Content provided in partnership with 
 
 Business Reference Technology Newspaper 

 Economy Careers Saving Spending 

 Investing Retirement Arts Home&amp;Garden 

 Auto Sports Health All RSS Feeds 
 Search ©2011 CBS Interactive. All rights reserved. Privacy Policy | Ad Choice | Terms of Use | Advertise | Jobs
	</body>
</document>
