<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009203" url="http://yamibakurasgirl.deviantart.com/" time="2012-07-13-02:35" support="1" score="0.0013282319919261166" bingtitle="YamiBakurasGirl on deviantART" webtitle="YamiBakurasGirl on deviantART">
			<query id="000518" bing-rank="157"/>
	<description>... someone I loved them and didn&apos;t get a clear ... [ ] I&apos;ve stolen a tray from a fast food restaurant. [ ] I open up to others ... Personal Quote: &quot;Bat Credit Card? RAPE MY CHILDHOOD ...</description>
	<body>
		deviantART 
 Browse Art Prints Shop T-Shirts&amp;Gear Groups Deviants 
 Sta.sh dA muro Chat Journals Today Forum Find More Art 
 Daily Deviations Discover beta Critiques Critiqueable Wallpaper Random 
 Random Deviant Random Deviation Random Group 
 
 Search Username or Email 

 Password 
 Stay logged in 
 Login 
 Join deviantART for FREE Take the Tour Lost Password? Deviant Login Buy Art Buy T-Shirts&amp;Gear Buy adCast Buy Premium Upgrade Shop   Join deviantART for FREE Take the Tour 
 
~ YamiBakurasGirl 
Glambert forever View Badges! + Watch Send a Note Give 
 Profile Gallery Prints Favourites Journal 
 About Me Varied / Student Member Kayla Female/United States Groups #The-NBC-Fanclub 
   Recent Activity Deviant for 3 Years Needs Premium Membership Statistics 1,144 Deviations 5,290 Comments 12,607 Pageviews 1,144 Deviations
 5,290 Comments
 12,607 Pageviews
 79 Scraps
 91 Watchers
 0 Critiques
 87 Forum Posts
 685 Favourites More Stats This deviant&apos;s full pageview
graph is unavailable. Member Kayla Female/United States Birthday November 6 # The-NBC-Fanclub 
   # Furbatics 
   # tgwtgandcmfanclub 
 that deviant with a fan club Online Now Glambert forever Art Zone Personal Zone Misc. Zone 
 This is the place where you can personalize your profile!
But, how? 
 By moving, adding and personalizing widgets. You can drag and drop to rearrange. You can edit widgets to customize them. The bottom has widgets you can add! Some widgets you can only access when you get a premium membership. Some widgets have options that are only available when you get a premium membership. 
 

 We&apos;ve split the page into zones! 
 Certain widgets can only be added to certain zones. &quot;Why,&quot; you ask? Because we want profile pages to have freedom of customization, but also to have some consistency. This way, when anyone visits a deviant, they know they can always find the art in the top left, and personal info in the top right. Don&apos;t forget, restraints can bring out the creativity in you! 
 

 Now go forth and astound us all with your devious profiles! 
 OK 
 
 
 Join Now  
 Buy T-Shirts&amp;Gear  
 Advertise Here 
 [x] 
 Critiques
 
 Featured Print
 
Dale says Welax
 Buy This Print 
 You better welax, bitch! 
 
 Newest Deviations
 Tokyo Mew Mew OC Template Tokyo Mew Mew Template

Basic Information and appearance
Name: (Last, First) Please give your charcter a name
Meaning: What does their name mean?
Mew Name: If they are human, alien or anything but a mew mew, do not fill this out.
Other Nicknames: Do they go by other nicknames? If so who calls them that?
Species: A mew mew, alien, human, or other?
Age: How old are they?
Birthday: When were they born?
Sex: Male, female or other?
Hair color: Red, pink, blue, green, or other?
Hair Length: How long is your hair? Long, short, medium or bald?
Hair Style(s): How do they keep their hair?
Eye color: Yellow, green, p Tokyo Mew Mew OC Template by ~ YamiBakurasGirl 0 Comments TGWTG: Monique&apos;s Favorite Stalker by ~ YamiBakurasGirl 0 Comments Pokemon Victoria bio Introduction

Name (last, first): Laten Verdanna, Victoria

Nickname(s): Vicky

Age: 37

Species: Human

Gender: Female

Sexual Orientation: Straight

Birthday: September fourteenth

Life Story: Victoria is the daughter of Harold Verdana, a Pokémon scientist. Once he became the age of sixty-three, he began going insane. He had heard about Pokémon being merged with human DNA, called Poke-merging. He decided to do the same, but he made them shiner using a new chemical that enhances Pokémon power. Before he was taken to an asylum, he had asked all six of his children to capture as many Pokémon as they could and inject them wi Pokemon Victoria bio by ~ YamiBakurasGirl 0 Comments Pokemon Drake Bio Introduction

Name (last, first): Verdana, Drake

Nickname(s): (None)

Age: 17

Species: Human

Gender: Male

Sexual Orientation: Gay

Birthday: March thirteenth

Life Story: Drake was born in the great, wealthy Verdana family. They lived in the Sinnoh region. His grandfather went a bit insane after discovering another scientist can merge human DNA with Pokémon called poke-merging. He decided to make his own poke-merging using not just the basic ingredients but something that made the Pokémon shiny and stronger. After a few months in this project, he was sent to an asylum, however he asked his youngest son, and his grand kids to do Pokemon Drake Bio by ~ YamiBakurasGirl 0 Comments Browse Gallery 
 Favourites
 Dragon Fire by ~ jellyfire 3 Comments Never Fall In Love With a Piano Player by ~ thedarklordkeisha 37 Comments Akatsuki Heaven-Silver Belt by ~ LadyZexion 1 Comment Plushie Paw by ~ Pinka-Starlight 3 Comments Browse Favourites 
 Groups
 
 Admin of 3 Groups Member of 176 Groups 
 
# tgwtgandcmfanclub 
# Furbatics 
# The-NBC-Fanclub 
# deviousSTAMPS 
# NaughtyFanfiction 
# Magical-Girl-Lit 
# SMFanFicManga All Groups 
 Friends
 
* KrisRix 
~ moniek-kuuper 
~ JesuOtaku 
~ ElwynWanderer 
~ TheOutsiderLover14xo 
~ WinxSparkle 
* Little-Red-XOXO 
~ Volts48 
* Danielle-chan 
* SpaceCaptSteve 
~ DrInsanoplz 
~ 90skidplz 
~ harveyfinevoiceplz 
~ Ma-Tiplz 
~ chesterabumplz 
~ Kickassiaplz 
~ Spoonyplz 
~ IAmAManplz 
~ kermityayplz 
* AnyaUribe All Friends 
 Journal History
 
 Jul 3, 2012 Writing Commissions...wtf? Jun 29, 2012 Anything For You Jun 29, 2012 Colors! Jun 27, 2012 This meme is so f**ked up Jun 22, 2012 Need more adventures Jun 21, 2012 Lets make this easier Jun 19, 2012 Sneak Preview of whats inside! Jun 19, 2012 Start of a New Beginning Jun 15, 2012 Devious Journal Entry Jun 13, 2012 Yet another Anti Yaoi/Yuri Rant 
 
 Previous 1 2 3 ... 33 Next 
 Go To Page: Go 
 Watchers
 
 ~ VectorGraphics * TheGr8estOne ~ AkatsukiCuties ~ Strawberry-Skittles * dirk-geijsbeek ~ sesamestreetfan ~ Ask-Syd ~ hetalia10111 ~ Dremare ~ BKA-Chief ~ SewedHeart ~ julioroving ~ Nightmaregrl101 ~ Ask-Pervert-Princess ~ MsBaconator ~ mitsukiuzumaki123 ~ AikoNi69 ~ gaijuba * Dangerman-1973 ~ unlabeledpunk 
 All Watchers 
 Writing Commissions...wtf? 

 

 1 week, 2 days ago by ~ YamiBakurasGirl Journals / Personal 
 I have decided to do a writing comission. Sign up now to be one of the lucky ten people that get a writing comission. But I have some rules:

1) No yaoi/yuri please
2) Only one OC per story
3) You can only sign up once, no telling me that you want a Yugioh, TGWTG AND a glee story
4) you must use one of the fandoms below. If I never heard of the fandom, or if I hate it too much I will not write your story.
5) Sign ups end September 10th, please sign up here or PM me.
6) If less than ten people sign up, this contest will close. 


Fandom List

-That Guy With The Glasses (TGWTG)
-Naruto
-Yugioh
-Soul Eater
-Winx Club
-Glee
-Sailor Moon
-Tokyo Mew Mew
-Code Geass
-Video On Trial
-Fruits Basket
-Death Note

Fandoms I can&apos;t/won&apos;t do:
-My Little Pony
-Hetalia
-Bleach
-Avengers
-Any Marvel or DC fandom
-Totally Spies
-Sonic

My Little Pony, Sonic, Totally Spies, and Hetalia I won&apos;t do becuase I simply don&apos;t care about the fandoms and do not wish to contribute to those fandoms. As for Avengers, Marvel/DC I don&apos;t know much about....so thats off my list as well.


Prices

Regular story without lemon or OC&apos;s 10 points
Lemon story 15 points
OC story 20 points (Its an extra 5 points per OC in use)
Lemon/OC combo 30 points
Regular Crossover 15 points
Lemon Crossover 15 points
Real Life/All OC 40 points (The reason this cost so much is becuase I need information on everything, from charcters to settings to way people think etc)
Lemon/OC/Crossover 30 points
Spin Off Series (Example: a new Sailor Moon squad, Naruto in the future) 40 points


*Please send me your OC&apos;s bio if you are requesting any type of OC story. Its very important. I reccomend using this one: [link] 

If you don&apos;t want your bio too long for whatever reason, please fill in important plot lines in your story such as age, gender, apperance, etc.


Slots open

1) ~ Imagine45 &apos;s Winx Family fic OC x OC (No lemon)
2) ~ Chastity-2006 &apos;s Winx/Death Note Pain lemon fic OC x ????
3) ~ Ask-Pervert-Princess Naruto Sweet Lemon fic OC x  Gaara
4) ~ ButterzXx Death Note Friendship fic Matt and Mello
5) * Little-Red-XOXO TGWTG Love fic Cinema Snob x OC (lemon)
6)
7)
8)
9)
10)

SIGN UPS CLOSED SEPTEMBER TENTH!

When You request your story it must contain the following:
-Fandom(s)
-Pairing
-One theme from 100 themes [link] 
-OC sheet (if the story has an OC, please PM me)
-Lemon or no?

*Update: If you want a crossover, please no more than two fandoms. Its hard enough to do two, so just stick to it.

*Also i&apos;m not very good at fighting scenes so if you want a 18+ story, just stick to sex becuase thats the type of writing style I use.


Accepted requests

User: Can i have a Sailor Moon/Death Note Crossover with a lemon and the theme I want is dark. I also want my pairing to be Usagi(Serena)Tsukino/L Lawiet.


Disqualified Requests

Can I have a naruto fic?

Notice how this request lacks in information. What pairing do you want me to do? What theme do you want? Do you want a lemon? If you have any questions feel free to PM me.


If you are using an OC...

Please stick to one OC per story unless you have more that are vital to the story, and not just pairing sake.

 Please don&apos;t do this... 
(Fandom used: Death Note) Simone is Misa&apos;s sister and has a crush on L and Pete is the tenth kira. Do the OCs have anything in common, no. Will they interact later NO!

 Or this... 
(Fandom used: Glee) Dan and Eric are twin brothers who each have a crush on different girls. Eric likes Mercedes, and Dan likes Rachel. However I only want the story being about Eric&apos;s relationship with Mercedes.

 This is okay 
(Fandom Used: Naruto) Riku, Miki, and Goru are part of team sixteen from the leaf village. Miki and Goro have no love intrest with anyone important, however Riku has a thing for Hinata.


OC sheets

Naruto Template: [link] 
Yugioh Template: [link] 
Sailor Moon Template: [link] 
Death Note Template: [link] 
General Template (everyone must have this filled out if you are using an OC) : [link] 
*I will create more templates for excess information 23 Comments 
 Mood: Optimism Listening to: Evanescence Playing: Fashion Solitare 
 Writing Commissions...wtf? July 3 23 Comments 2 Favourites More Journal Entries 
 deviantID
 ~ YamiBakurasGirl Kayla 
Artist | Student | Varied United States Fanfiction*Digital Media*Anime*Singing*Voice actor
 


My name is Kayla
I am a girl
Three words that describe me: shy, confused, mean
I am in between the ages of 15-18
I like
(x) Anime
(x) Manga
(x) Deviantart
( ) Facebook
(x) Youtube
(x) Draw/Paint traditionally
(x) Draw/Paint digitally
( ) Writing
(x) Video Games
(?) Navigating the internet
(x)Favorite art
(x) Comments
(x) Filled memes
(x) Getting tagged
( ) Trolls
My favorite color(s) is black, gold, and red.
Questions by 

 

╔══╗♫
║██║
║(o)║Post this on your channel if you
╚══╝think Adam Lambert is the best singer ever.

 
 
 
 
 
 
 by 




__♥__♥_____♥__♥__
_♥_____♥_♥_____♥_ Put This
_♥______♥______♥_ If You
__♥Adam Lambert♥__ Are Absolutely
___♥____ _____♥___ In LOVE
____♥___ ___♥____ With
______♥_ _♥____ Adam♥
________♥_______ Lambert♥

Current Residence: Los Angels
Favourite genre of music: alternative, dance, pop
Favourite style of art: manga
Operating System: mac
MP3 player of choice: ipod nano 3rd
Shell of choice: whats a shell?
Wallpaper of choice: anything with Adam lambert on it
Skin of choice: asian
Favourite cartoon character: Yami bakura
Personal Quote: &quot;Bat Credit Card? RAPE MY CHILDHOOD WILL YOU?!!!!!&quot;

 :thumb170887203: 
 
 
 
 
 

Stamps by In order of apperance:
 :iconloffeglu: :iconiiya-san: :iconmarlenestamps: :iconaizanwolfdoll: :iocntwistedxhearts: :iconxlove-chrstina-AX: :iconohhprettylights: :iconcalval: :iconpreuserian: :iconlenzeldorf: :iconfantsystockavatar: :iconabsolutly-narutard: :iconlianaodthesandlol: :iconnwfarystampstock: :icontreeDVeliocipitor: :iconmiako-chan33: :iconfellmeke: :iconmunkeeme: :iconchimikki: :iconjfg107: :iconloki-love-smith: 

 

:devunlimitedkitsune: 

 
 What Naruto Girl Are You? 
Hosted By theOtaku.com: Anime 
 
 Which Sailor Scout Are You? 
Hosted By theOtaku.com: Anime 

 
 What Cure Are You Most Like? 
Hosted By theOtaku.com: Anime 

 
 What Negima Girl Are You Most Like? 
Hosted By theOtaku.com: Anime 

 
 What Vocaloid Are You? 
Hosted By theOtaku.com: Anime 

 
 Who Is Your Ideal Soul Eater Boyfriend? 
Hosted By theOtaku.com: Anime bravome.com/publicpage.php?by=jennifers2 Interests Favorite visual artist Mia Ikumi Favorite movies House Bunny Favorite TV shows Glee, Americas got Talent, Video on Trial Favorite bands / musical artists Evanescence, Adam Lambert, Nickleback Favorite books Reality Check Favorite writers Amy Lee Favorite games Bratz rock angelz Favorite gaming platform game cube Tools of the Trade &quot;Ibrush and I movie&quot; Other Interests Anime, Drama, Pop culture, art 
 AdCast - Ads from the Community
 [x] 
 Donate
 ~ YamiBakurasGirl has started a donation pool! 0 / 2,400 
 I need a preniuem (12 month) membership 
 Donate! 
 You must be logged in to donate. No one has donated yet. Be the first! 
 My Prints
 Roses and PawDugan CaramellDancing Buy This Print My ice cream pillow and me Buy This Print CinemaSnob OanCitizin CaramellDancing Buy This Print Linksano Harvey FineVoice Caramelldancing Buy This Print 
 Webcam
 
 Comments
 
 Add a Comment:   Preview   Add Comment Emoticons Load All Images * KrisRix 23 hours ago   Professional General Artist Thank you very much for the watch!! 

--
Cheap and negotiable commissions starting at 3 USD! Reply ~ YamiBakurasGirl 22 hours ago   Student General Artist Your welcome. 

--
I Nostalgia Critic
I Linkara
I Adam Lambert
I Winx Club
❑Taken
❑Single
✔Mentally dating a person who does exist but doesn&apos;t know we are dating Reply ~ moniek-kuuper 1 day ago   Hobbyist Traditional Artist thanks for the watch 

--
--Ja, ik ben mij er eentje.
--Een ongeluk zit in een klein hoekje, geluk zit in de rest.
--Smile, it makes people wonder what you&apos;re thinking.
Freddy won.
No Shit Reply ~ YamiBakurasGirl 1 day ago   Student General Artist No problem, I watch all TGWTG fans.

--
I Nostalgia Critic
I Linkara
I Adam Lambert
I Winx Club
❑Taken
❑Single
✔Mentally dating a person who does exist but doesn&apos;t know we are dating Reply ~ moniek-kuuper 17 hours ago   Hobbyist Traditional Artist 

--
--Ja, ik ben mij er eentje.
--Een ongeluk zit in een klein hoekje, geluk zit in de rest.
--Smile, it makes people wonder what you&apos;re thinking.
Freddy won.
No Shit Reply ~ Paty-Longbottom21 Jun 21, 2012 You&apos;ve been hugged!
Spread the DA love around! (you can copy and paste this message on their profile!)

RULES:
1- You can hug the person who hugged you!
2- You -MUST- hug 6 other people, at least!
3- You should hug them in public! Paste it on their user page!
4- Random hugs are perfectly okay!
5- You should most definitely get started hugging right away!

Send This To All Your Friends, And Me If I Am 1, On Second thought, Please give one back.
If You Get 7 Back You Are Loved! Reply ~ pinkrangerwannabe Jun 21, 2012   Hobbyist Digital Artist Reply ~ YamiBakurasGirl Jun 21, 2012   Student General Artist No prob.

--
I Nostalgia Critic
I Linkara
I Adam Lambert
I Winx Club
❑Taken
❑Single
✔Mentally dating a person who does exist but doesn&apos;t know we are dating Reply ~ gaijuba Jun 21, 2012   Hobbyist Traditional Artist You&apos;ve been hugged! 
Spread the DA love around! (you can copy and paste this message on their profile!)

RULES:
1- You can hug the person who hugged you!
2- You -MUST- hug 6 other people, at least!
3- You should hug them in public! Paste it on their user page!
4- Random hugs are perfectly okay!
5- You should most definitely get started hugging right away!

Send This To All Your Friends, And Me If I Am 1, On Second thought, Please give one back.
If You Get 7 Back You Are Loved!

--
Don&apos;t ever click this [link] 
 By just giving me a llama , I would give you a llama back and watch you Reply ~ Thatnerdwithglasses Jun 11, 2012 thanks for the watch Reply 
 Previous 1 2 3 ... Next 
 Go To Page: Go Add a Comment:   Preview   Add Comment Emoticons ©2012 deviantART. All rights reserved About Us | Contact Us | Developers | Careers | Site Tour | Help&amp;FAQ Advertise | Premium Membership Etiquette | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | Copyright Policy
	</body>
</document>
