<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009716" url="http://www.shopping.com/salter-food-scale-model-6300-manual/products" time="2012-07-13-03:06" support="1" score="0.0013194810088806707" bingtitle="&quot;salter food scale model 6300 manual&quot; - Shopping.com" webtitle="salter food scale model 6300 manual- Shopping.com">
			<query id="001420" bing-rank="244"/>
	<description>When kitchen space is at a premium, count on this ... operation is checkweighing food portions in a fast-food restaurant ... MS20 baby scale comes with a plastic weighing tray ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to Shopping.com! Other Shopping.com sites: Close 
 
 
 
 
 
 Shop By Department 
 Clothing 
 Women Men Girls Boys Infants and Toddlers See all... Shop by Brands 
 Shoes 
 Womens Mens Kids See all... Shop by Brands 
 Computers 
 Cartridges and Toners Flash Memory Monitors PC Laptops PDAs Printers Software See all... Shop by Brands 
 Electronics 
 Camcorders Cellular Phones Digital Cameras GPS Devices MP3 Players Flat Panel Televisions Speakers and Subwoofers Buying Guides See all... Shop by Brands 
 At Home 
 Furniture Garden Home Furnishings Kitchen Pet Supplies Building Supplies See all... Shop by Brands 
 Health 
 Cosmetics Fragrances Health Aids Nutrition Personal Care See all... Shop by Brands 
 Kids 
 Baby Care Car Seats Cribs and Bassinets Strollers Toys Video Games See all... Shop by Brands 
 Community Shop by Brands See all 
 
 Sign In   Join   My Lists Search Related: Food scale    less» Shopping 
 salter food scale model 6300 manual 
 Showing results for &quot;
salter food scale model 6300 manual
&quot; Show on Sale Results 1 - 40 of 1500+ Sponsored Results Salter Lifestyle Digital Scale |... $59.95 Salter 1061SSR Electronic Kitchen... $28.25 
 Salter-Brecknell-235- 6S-220 (235-6S220) Mechanical Hanging Scale 
 Salter-Brecknell-235- 6S-220 (235-6S220) Mechanical Hanging Scale for Salter from $75.00 2 stores See Details 
 Salter-Brecknell-PS-1 000 (PS1000) Digital Multi Purpose Vet Floor Scale 
 Salter-Brecknell-PS-1 000 (PS1000) Digital Multi Purpose Vet Floor Scale for Salter from $560.00 Free Shipping 4 stores See Details 
 Salter -Brecknell-B220-60 (B22060) Digital Electronic Counting Scale 
 Salter -Brecknell-B220-60 (B22060) Digital Electronic Counting Scale from $295.00 Free Shipping 4 stores See Details 
 Food Portioning Scale - 6 Lb Cap, 0.001 Graduation Food Portioning Scale - 6 Lb Cap, 0.001 Graduation 
 New ( In stock ) 
The Ohaus Food Portioning Scale is a rugged, multi-use portioning scale designed for use in food service applications. Ideally suited for food portioning and checkweighing, the FD Food... More 

The Ohaus Food Portioning Scale is a rugged, multi-use portioning scale designed for use in food service applications. Ideally suited for food portioning and checkweighing, the FD Food portioning scale combines an easily cleaned design, fast display and high precision loadcell. Designed for use in restaurants, bakeries, food manufacturing and other areas requiring fast operation and flexibility, the Ohaus Food Portioning Scale offers durability and cleanliness in one economical design. 6 lbs. / 3 kg. capacity. 0.001 Graduation. 9&quot;W x 12&quot;D x 2-13/16&quot;H overall. 15.80 L. 12.60 W. 7.30 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /food-portioning-scale-6/v2qZ97bEK3NMDr5fGbRJ3A==/info $405.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store 
 Salter Lifestyle Digital Scale | Williams-Sonoma Salter Lifestyle Digital Scale | Williams-Sonoma 
 ( In stock ) 
Hailed for its precision and accuracy, this electronic scale lets you measure wet and dry ingredients by weight rather than by the cup or spoon. Weigh foods directly on the clear glass... More 

Hailed for its precision and accuracy, this electronic scale lets you measure wet and dry ingredients by weight rather than by the cup or spoon. Weigh foods directly on the clear glass platform or in a bowl.Measures dry and liquid ingredients by weight for the most reliable results.A single button toggles between U.S. and metric measurements. Large digital display.Sleek profile for convenient storage.Glass platform and stainless-steel base are stain and odor resistant. Less 
 Williams-Sonoma 19 store reviews See Store Info /salter-lifestyle-digital/182R70As8Bdr-lVPtA_s4Q==/info $59.95 +$11.50 shipping Visit Store 
 Salter Red Digital Scale | Williams-Sonoma Salter Red Digital Scale | Williams-Sonoma 
 ( In stock ) 
When kitchen space is at a premium, count on this ultra-slim scale to help you measure ingredients with ease and precision. Compact enough to fit into a drawer, yet handsome enough to... More 

When kitchen space is at a premium, count on this ultra-slim scale to help you measure ingredients with ease and precision. Compact enough to fit into a drawer, yet handsome enough to display on a countertop, it gives you the option of placing foods directly on the platform or weighing them in a bowl. Space-saving electronic scale makes it simple to measure wet or dry ingredients by weight. Digital display shows measurements in 1/8-oz. and 1-gram increments up to 11 lb. or 5 kg. &quot;Add&amp;Weigh&quot; feature lets you weigh multiple ingredients in a single container. Stain-resistant glass platform is hygienic and won&apos;t absorb flavors or odors. Sleek profile for convenient storage. Uses two AAA batteries (included). Less 
 Williams-Sonoma 19 store reviews See Store Info /salter-red-digital-scale/ex_Bfq-XaENGtIoSUWfD1A==/info $49.95 +$10.50 shipping Visit Store 
 Salter-Brecknell-CB-1 00 (CB100) Compact Balance 
 Salter-Brecknell-CB-1 00 (CB100) Compact Balance for Salter $113.95 1 store See Details 
 Salter Brecknell Gp 250lb. Portable Digital Bench Scale 
 Salter Brecknell Gp 250lb. Portable Digital Bench Scale from $15.85 Free Shipping 14 stores See Details http://di1-2.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/2c/e2/3e/92943772-100x100-0-0_Salter+Salter+Brecknell+C3255+30+C3255+Wipedown+Ch.jpg 
 Salter -Brecknell-C3255-30 (C3255) Wipedown Checkweighing Scale 
 Salter -Brecknell-C3255-30 (C3255) Wipedown Checkweighing Scale $447.00 1 store See Details http://img.shoppingshadow.com/jfe/product/no_image_100x100.jpg 
 Salter-Brecknell-7815 R-150BT (NCI 7815) Postal Scale Ball Top NTEP 
 Salter-Brecknell-7815 R-150BT (NCI 7815) Postal Scale Ball Top NTEP for Salter $521.81 1 store See Details http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/5a/33/66/6844757a787872544b6e7661656269702d4341-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 SALTER BRECKNELL Floor Scales SALTER BRECKNELL Floor Scales 
 ( In stock ) 
Heavy-duty SALTER BRECKNELL Floor Scale is constructed of 5&quot; channel steel supports giving it superior strength to standard floor scales. Allows for up to 300% safe overload. Engineered for... More 

Heavy-duty SALTER BRECKNELL Floor Scale is constructed of 5&quot; channel steel supports giving it superior strength to standard floor scales. Allows for up to 300% safe overload. Engineered for floor or in-ground applications and rated for use indoors or outdoors. Platform is 3.75&quot; off the floor and features 3/16&quot; thick safety diamond treadplate design. Large, easy-to-read LED display indicator is available in either plastic or stainless steel. NOTE: Scale weighs loads in the listed increments. For example, 2500-lb. capacity scale weighs in 0.5-lb. increments. Less 
 C&amp;H Distributors Store not rated See Store Info /salter-brecknell-floor/Z3fhDuzxxrTKnvaebip-CA==/info C&amp;H;Distributors $1,991.00 +$176.02 shipping Visit Store http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/31/bf/49/123715630-100x100-0-0_salter+salter+brecknell+pb500+handheld+balance+sca.jpg 
 Salter Brecknell PB500 Handheld balance scale, 2-1/2 x 3 platform 
 Salter Brecknell PB500 Handheld balance scale, 2-1/2 x 3 platform from $33.71 Free Shipping 6 stores See Details http://di1-2.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/85/a2/7f/118576980-100x100-0-0_salter+salter+brecknell+lightweight+electronic+pos.jpg 
 Salter Brecknell Lightweight Electronic Postal Floor Scale from... 
 Salter Brecknell Lightweight Electronic Postal Floor Scale from OfficeFurniture.com from $310.00 Free Shipping 4 stores See Details http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/67/6f/4a/4e337a4636375431744c304432586f704a5051-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Salter Brecknell Price Computing Scale - PC-60 Salter Brecknell Price Computing Scale - PC-60 
 ( In stock ) 
View unit weight, unit cost and total price from the front and back with the Saltner Brecknell Price Computing Scale. A must-have for farmer&apos;s markets. A Must-Have for Farmer&apos;s Markets!... More 

View unit weight, unit cost and total price from the front and back with the Saltner Brecknell Price Computing Scale. A must-have for farmer&apos;s markets. A Must-Have for Farmer&apos;s Markets! Great for farmer&apos;s markets, the Saltner Brecknell PC-60 Price Computing Scale is the perfect addition to any business where anything is sold by weight. Made with an ABS plastic base that includes leveling feet and a built-in leveling bubble, clear plastic cover and stainless steel top platter. Measures kg, lb or oz. Has six price look-up hot keys. Amounts can be viewed from both the front and back - so both you and your customers can see the weights and cost. Accuracy:   NTEP @ 3,000 divisions, Class III Capacity:   30kg/ 60lbs/960oz Display Resolution:   Max 3,000d Operator Keys:   Units, tare, accumulation, PLU, zero, tare, X2, X4 Operating Temp:  14 F to 104 F AC Power:   120/220 VAC US power adapter (included) Battery:   6V/4Ah rechargeable lead acid Battery Life:  70 hrs. without backlight; 35 hrs. with backlight Product Displays:  Unit weight, unit cost, total price Product Dimensions:  12.6 &quot; W x 13&quot; D x 1.9&quot; H Certifications:   NTEP CC #11-116 Less 
 QC Supply Store not rated See Store Info /salter-brecknell-price/goJN3zF67T1tL0D2XopJPQ==/info $295.40 +$11.73 shipping Visit Store http://di1-2.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/ef/bb/b9/107239182-100x100-0-0_salter+salter+brecknell+405+405+6kg+12lb+digital+s.jpg 
 Salter-Brecknell-405 (405-6kg/12Lb) Digital Scale 
 Salter-Brecknell-405 (405-6kg/12Lb) Digital Scale for Salter from $99.95 Free Shipping 2 stores See Details http://di1-2.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/d3/30/d3/106946375-100x100-0-0_salter+salter+11+lb+aquatronic+kitchen+scale.jpg 
 Salter 11-lb. Aquatronic Kitchen Scale 
 Salter 11-lb. Aquatronic Kitchen Scale from $32.91 Free Shipping 15 stores See Details http://di1-1.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/b3/03/9f/88396796-100x100-0-0_Salter+Salter+Brecknell+GP100+Bench+Scale+Scale+P+.jpg 
 Salter Brecknell GP100 Bench Scale Scale P N... 
 Salter Brecknell GP100 Bench Scale Scale P N 816965001095 from $67.09 Free Shipping 12 stores See Details http://di1-2.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/c5/e9/30/97481680-100x100-0-0_Salter+Digital+Scale+Display+LED+Readout.jpg 
 Digital Scale Display - LED Readout 
 Digital Scale Display - LED Readout $169.87 1 store See Details http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/f8/0e/fd/88396758-100x100-0-0_Salter+Salter+Brecknell+B120+60+Counting+Scale+Sca.jpg 
 Salter Brecknell B120 60 Counting Scale Scale P N... 
 Salter Brecknell B120 60 Counting Scale Scale P N 816965001545 from $285.99 3 stores See Details http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/5f/57/50/3372374656655f7034564d73496d75434c4267-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Salter Brecknell General Purpose Scale, 150-Lb Capacity Salter Brecknell General Purpose Scale, 150-Lb Capacity 
 ( In stock ) 
With RS-232 interface for simple non-trade weighing applications Weight hold feature for larger packages that cover the display. Large bright LED display for easy viewing. Built-in... More 

With RS-232 interface for simple non-trade weighing applications Weight hold feature for larger packages that cover the display. Large bright LED display for easy viewing. Built-in rechargeable battery for long-lasting use. Automatic shut-off feature conserves battery power. Salter Brecknell General Purpose Scale, 150-Lb Capacity is one of many Health Scales &amp;Measures available through Office Depot. Made by Salter Brecknell. Less 
 Office Depot 137 store reviews See Store Info /salter-brecknell-general/_WP3r7FVe_p4VMsImuCLBg==/info $390.59 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/bd/12/44/107760656-100x100-0-0_salter+salter+brecknell+250+6s+11+11+lb+mechanical.jpg 
 Salter-Brecknell-250- 6S-11 11 lb Mechanical Portion Control Top Loading 
 Salter-Brecknell-250- 6S-11 11 lb Mechanical Portion Control Top Loading for Salter from $59.75 Free Shipping 2 stores See Details http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6f/50/62/66354f6a664f47674930464f44347448796577-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Salter Professional Large Dial Mechanical Scale Model ... Salter Professional Large Dial Mechanical Scale Model 200 1 ea 
 Free Shipping for all items over $25! ( In stock ) Bath Scale Find a wide variety of Diet&amp;Fitness Products at drugstore.com, where you get 5% back and free shipping! drugstore.com 613 store reviews See Store Info /salter-professional-large/oPbf5OjfOGgI0FOD4tHyew==/info drugstore.com $59.99 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di1-4.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/30/e3/8e/92918176-100x100-0-0_Salter+Salter+Brecknell+SA3N340+ElectroSamson+Port.jpg 
 Salter -Brecknell-SA3N340 ElectroSamson Portable Hanging Scale 
 Salter -Brecknell-SA3N340 ElectroSamson Portable Hanging Scale from $89.99 Free Shipping 6 stores See Details http://di1-1.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/92/09/7b/107897460-100x100-0-0_salter+salter+brecknell+7815r+150pp+nci+7815+posta.jpg 
 Salter-Brecknell-7815 R-150PP (NCI 7815) Postal Scale Plastic Platter NTEP 
 Salter-Brecknell-7815 R-150PP (NCI 7815) Postal Scale Plastic Platter NTEP for Salter $403.22 1 store See Details http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/4a/48/4a/373767367477776b3365754c57426869356f77-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 SALTER BRECKNELL Floor Scales SALTER BRECKNELL Floor Scales 
 ( In stock ) 
Heavy-duty SALTER BRECKNELL Floor Scale is constructed of 5&quot; channel steel supports giving it superior strength to standard floor scales. Allows for up to 300% safe overload. Engineered for... More 

Heavy-duty SALTER BRECKNELL Floor Scale is constructed of 5&quot; channel steel supports giving it superior strength to standard floor scales. Allows for up to 300% safe overload. Engineered for floor or in-ground applications and rated for use indoors or outdoors. Platform is 3.75&quot; off the floor and features 3/16&quot; thick safety diamond treadplate design. Large, easy-to-read LED display indicator is available in either plastic or stainless steel. NOTE: Scale weighs loads in the listed increments. For example, 2500-lb. capacity scale weighs in 0.5-lb. increments. Less 
 C&amp;H Distributors Store not rated See Store Info /salter-brecknell-floor/JHJ77g6twwk3euLWBhi5ow==/info C&amp;H;Distributors $1,991.00 +$137.71 shipping Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/5f/38/2d/4a4e54797968766e685f724546674171476f67-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Push Button Zero Portion Control Scale - 160 Oz Capacity Push Button Zero Portion Control Scale - 160 Oz Capacity 
 New ( In stock ) 
 Salter Brecknell Push Button Zero Portion Control Scale - 160 oz Capacity Great for use in food service operations to build consistent products and help control costs, thereby maximizing... More 

 Salter Brecknell Push Button Zero Portion Control Scale - 160 oz Capacity Great for use in food service operations to build consistent products and help control costs, thereby maximizing customer satisfaction and profitability. 15.00 L. 9.50 W. 9.00 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /push-button-zero-portion/_8-JNTyyhvnh_rEFgAqGog==/info $476.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/61/79/30/575a444b4d6a384e507278446f4b45366d6567-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Salter Ultra Thin Glass Kitchen Scale, Weighs to 11-Pound Salter Ultra Thin Glass Kitchen Scale, Weighs to 11-Pound 
 Get free shipping on orders over $25! ( In stock ) 
 Salter scales with a tradition of excellence for the past 250-year. Full featured kitchen scales for the home chef and everyday cook or baker. Innovative designs, all with a touch of class... More 

 Salter scales with a tradition of excellence for the past 250-year. Full featured kitchen scales for the home chef and everyday cook or baker. Innovative designs, all with a touch of class and innovation. An English tradition since 1760. Ultra slim design is sleek and easy to store. Brilliant led readout on black back painted glass platform. Touch sensitive buttons. Add and weigh tare function. Manual and auto shut off. Operates on aaa batteries, included. Less 
 Amazon 1,806 store reviews See Store Info /salter-ultra-thin-glass/ay0WZDKMj8NPrxDoKE6meg==/info $32.29 Free Shipping Visit Store -10% http://di104.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/5f/76/73/614d516b78744d395036644735504243525277-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 FD Series Food Scale Model FD6 FD Series Food Scale Model FD6 
 Special Features: All stainless steel high quality formed construction for sanitary cleaning and durability Checkweighing function for food packaging and preparation Internal rechargeable battery assures excellent portability The Ohaus FD Series is a rugged, multi-use portioning scale designed for use in food service applications. Ideally suited for food portioning and checkweighing, the FD Series combines an easily cleaned design, fast display and high precision load cell. Designed for use in restaurants, bakeries, food manufacturing and other areas requiring fast operation and flexibility, the Ohaus FD Series offers durability and cleanliness in one economical design. Stainless steel housing and pan with non-slip rubber feet Checkweighing mode with 3-LED indicator and audible alarm Bright backlit LCD display Stable weight display within 2 seconds Multiple weighing units:lb, decimal/fractional oz, kg, g, and lb:oz AC power or internal rechargeable lead acid battery NSF certified, USDA-AMS accepted, supports ( In stock ) 
Special Features: All stainless steel high quality formed construction for sanitary cleaning and durability Checkweighing function for food packaging and preparation Internal rechargeable... More 

Special Features: All stainless steel high quality formed construction for sanitary cleaning and durability Checkweighing function for food packaging and preparation Internal rechargeable battery assures excellent portability The Ohaus FD Series is a rugged, multi-use portioning scale designed for use in food service applications. Ideally suited for food portioning and checkweighing, the FD Series combines an easily cleaned design, fast display and high precision load cell. Designed for use in restaurants, bakeries, food manufacturing and other areas requiring fast operation and flexibility, the Ohaus FD Series offers durability and cleanliness in one economical design. Stainless steel housing and pan with non-slip rubber feet Checkweighing mode with 3-LED indicator and audible alarm Bright backlit LCD display Stable weight display within 2 seconds Multiple weighing units:lb, decimal/fractiona l oz, kg, g, and lb:oz AC power or internal rechargeable lead acid battery NSF certified, USDA-AMS accepted, supports HACCP compliance EC/OIML Type approvedSpecifica tions:Capacity (metric): 6 kgReadability (metric): 0.001 kgCapacity (avoirdupois): 15 lbReadability (avoirdupois): 0.002 lbNon LFT Resolution: 1:7500NTEP Resolution: 1:3000 (approval pending)Weighing units: lb, kg, g, oz, lb:oz -- oz units decimal or fractionalDisplay (in/cm): 5-digit, 7-segment, 0.75 / 1.9 high digits, backlit LCDCheckweighing: 3-LED indication with user- configurable software and alert beeperKeyboard: 4 Function membrane switchesStabiliza tion time (seconds): Within 2 secondsAuto Zero Tracking: Off, 0.5, 1 or 3 divisionsSafe overload capacity (as percent of the rated load): 150%Power Requirements: AC or internal rechargeable lead acid battery (both included)Battery life (typical): 120 hoursCalibration: User selectable external span or linearity calibrationOperat ing Temperature Range: 14ºF to 104ºF / -10ºC to 40ºCPan size (in/cm): 8.2 x 8.2 / 20.9 x 20.9Platform Construction: Stainless steelHousing: Stainless steelProtection: IP43, wipe- downDimensions WxHxD (in/cm): 9 x 12 x 2.8 / 30 x 22.3 x 7.1Net Wt. (lb/kg): 8 / 3.6Shipping Wt. (lb/kg): 11 / 5Shipping dimensions (WxDxH) (in/cm): 15.8 x 12.6 x 7.3 / 40 x 32 x 18.5 Less 
 Instawares, LLC 371 store reviews See Store Info /fd-series-food-scale/_vsaMQkxtM9P6dG5PBCRRw==/info $499.00 $449.10 10% Off +$31.44 shipping Visit Store http://di1-2.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/43/db/ed/92943684-100x100-0-0_Salter+Salter+Brecknell+RGT+160+RGT160+Mechanical+.jpg 
 Salter -Brecknell-RGT-160 (RGT160) Mechanical Medical Beam Scale 
 Salter -Brecknell-RGT-160 (RGT160) Mechanical Medical Beam Scale $220.00 1 store See Details -39% http://di101.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/37/55/4f/58667a384355784b6c6e624a4164366a783667-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Salter Brecknell LPS400 Portable Shipping Scale 400 lb Capacity 12w x 15d... Salter Brecknell LPS400 Portable Shipping Scale 400 lb Capacity 12w x 15d Platform - SBWLPS400 
 Free shipping on most orders over $50 ( In stock ) 
Portable shipping scale is well-suited for shipping or warehouse applications and general-purpose weighing with computer interface. The scale accurately weighs up to 400 lb. and is... More 

Portable shipping scale is well-suited for shipping or warehouse applications and general-purpose weighing with computer interface. The scale accurately weighs up to 400 lb. and is compatible with UPS Shipping software. The dual power modes enable portability or permanent installation. Scale includes an AC adapter and four AAA batteries. A large easy-to-read 0.65&quot; LCD screen can be wall-mounted or desk-mounted for easy visibility. The large keyboard switches work with gloved hands. This four-load cell design provides weight accurate for all major carrier shipments. Scale includes an RS232 link that is compatible with most carrier-provided shipping systems as well as a PC Serial Interface Cable. Less 
 Business-Supply 988 store reviews See Store Info /salter-brecknell-lps400/7UOXfz8CUxKlnbJAd6jx6g==/info Business-Supply $242.00 $148.50 39% Off Free Shipping Visit Store http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/53/6f/58/3152584d4874686759374538445f7269354151-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Push Button Zero Portion Control Scale W/ Swivel Display - 160 Oz Capacity Push Button Zero Portion Control Scale W/ Swivel Display - 160 Oz Capacity 
 New ( In stock ) 
 Salter Brecknell Push Button Zero Portion Control Scale w/ Swivel Display - 160 oz Capacity Great for use in food service operations to build consistent products and help control costs,... More 

 Salter Brecknell Push Button Zero Portion Control Scale w/ Swivel Display - 160 oz Capacity Great for use in food service operations to build consistent products and help control costs, thereby maximizing customer satisfaction and profitability. 15.13 L. 14.13 W. 9.50 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /push-button-zero-portion/SoX1RXMHthgY7E8D_ri5AQ==/info $440.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di110.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/4e/48/31/626974785a56664d30484630587153514c6f51-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Salter Brecknell Brecknell 6000g Precision Lab Balance Scale Salter Brecknell Brecknell 6000g Precision Lab Balance Scale 
 ( In stock ) 
When you need a reliable lab balance for a reasonable price, choose the Brecknell 6000g Precision Lab Balance Scale. Accuracy up to + or 2 divisions at full load. Platform size is 6.9&apos;&apos;W x... More 

When you need a reliable lab balance for a reasonable price, choose the Brecknell 6000g Precision Lab Balance Scale. Accuracy up to + or 2 divisions at full load. Platform size is 6.9&apos;&apos;W x 6.9&apos;&apos;D x 0.3&apos;&apos;H. Backlit LCD display is front facing and features 6 1/2 digits, 0.75&apos;&apos;H. Features external calibration and bidirectional RS232 interface so the scale can communicate data to a PC.Constructed of robust plastic housing and a stainless steel top place. Includes draft shield. Powered by 8 AA batteries (not included) or AC adapter (included). Battery life is approximately 15 hours. Manufacturer&apos;s warranty applies. Scale has a 1 year product warranty. Ships fully assembled. MBS-81696500492 Less 
 National Business Furniture Store not rated See Store Info /salter-brecknell/NH1bitxZVfM0HF0XqSQLoQ==/info $298.00 +$19.95 shipping Visit Store -46% http://di110.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/33/77/48/322d7971546e336b4d72674c44444f52766477-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Salter- Brecknell 6720 Shipping Scale - 9504-16647 Salter- Brecknell 6720 Shipping Scale - 9504-16647 
 Ships Same Day ( In stock ) Scale, Retail/Grocery 15LB RS-232 DB-9F Cable /Internal Display Barcode Giant 37 store reviews See Store Info /salterbrecknell-6720/3wH2-yqTn3kMrgLDDORvdw==/info $745.00 $401.40 46% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/70/5f/59/6a4251675933752d7a6465384a455257617351-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Salter Brecknell CB50 Reloading Scale Salter Brecknell CB50 Reloading Scale 
 $5 Shipping on $150+ until 7.17 with Code: 72HOT ( In stock ) 
From an indusTR leader in scientific, postal and medical scales comes this precision reloading-bench instrument. 750-grain capacity, with .3-grain accuracy. Includes weighing dish,... More 

From an indusTR leader in scientific, postal and medical scales comes this precision reloading-bench instrument. 750-grain capacity, with .3-grain accuracy. Includes weighing dish, calibration weight and double-ended scoop. Battery- conserving auto shutoff. CR2032 batteries included. Sports and Outdoors &gt; Sport and Outdoor Less 
 Cabela&apos;s 78 store reviews See Store Info /salter-brecknell-cb50/p_YjBQgY3u-zde8JERWasQ==/info Cabela&apos;s $31.99 +$8.95 shipping Visit Store http://di101.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/57/46/61/3657737a7178676c395166544b485369555677-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Salter- Brecknell-7880-10 0 Postal Shipping Scale NTEP Salter- Brecknell-7880-10 0 Postal Shipping Scale NTEP 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
The Model 7880-100 Bench Scale provides the most accurate and reliable weight measurement for static or in-line shipping. The weighing solution for any applicaion requiring a durable bench... More 

The Model 7880-100 Bench Scale provides the most accurate and reliable weight measurement for static or in-line shipping. The weighing solution for any applicaion requiring a durable bench scale. Specifications: Power- AC power Operator Keys- Zero and Test Construction- Stainless steel weight platter, painted mild steel base enclosure Display Controls- ZERO: Includes Auto Zero Tracking or Manual push button to re-establish zero reference. TEST: Runs a diagnostic test to ensure scales is fully functional, and allows a real-time view of internal settings. Construction- Stainless steel weight platter, painted mild steel base enclosure Field Calibration- Alternate span points can simplify field calibration by using less than full capacity weights. Can be setup as either decimal pound or kilogram. RS-232 Cable- Included with each scale, DB 9-pin, null modem, female connector allows you to connect to a PC Emulation Protocols- Standard NCI default with field configurable settings of 8213, 3835, SMA, and Auto Weight Send. This allows you to select compatible scale communication settings or scale drivers during field installation when interfacing with shipping software programs or host devices. Power Supply- Recessed power supply with standard wall plug Durabridge® Technology- Reduces overall scale deflection when a full load is applied Internal Display- 1/2&quot; H, 6 digit LCD display Dimensions- 18&quot; L x 18&quot; W x 4.5&quot; H/457 mm (L) x 457 mm (W) x 114 mm (H) Power- 120 VAC (+10% -15%), 60 Hz, standard 3-wire ground Operating Environment- Temperature: 42° F to 104° F (5° C to 40° C)/Relative Humidity: 10 to 95% (non- condensing). Input/Output- RS-232, bi-directional, configurable 1200- 19.2K baud. Transmits weight and ... Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /salterbrecknell7880100/WFa6Wszqxgl9QfTKHSiUVw==/info $913.17 +$28.45 shipping Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/47/39/78/385f345462784d6d6b747235664a6d45364467-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Salter PS1000 / PS2000 Animal Floor Scales Salter PS1000 / PS2000 Animal Floor Scales 
 Ships Next Day ( In stock ) 
 Salter Brecknell PS1000 veterinary scale was built with portability in mind. Weighing only 60 lbs, two easy access carry handles makes this scale convenient to relocate. No need for ramps... More 

 Salter Brecknell PS1000 veterinary scale was built with portability in mind. Weighing only 60 lbs, two easy access carry handles makes this scale convenient to relocate. No need for ramps or recessed floors, as this unit comes with ramped ends. It boasts a 1000 Lb Capacity with Mild Steel construction to ensure a long life span. Thiese are ideal veterinary scales for weighing larger animals. Less 
 Quick Supply Store not rated See Store Info /salter-ps1000-ps2000/G9x8_4TbxMmktr5fJmE6Dg==/info $515.00 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di1-1.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/be/4f/be/106946183-100x100-0-0_salter+salter+5+lb+electronic+kitchen+scale.jpg 
 Salter 5-lb. Electronic Kitchen Scale 
 Salter 5-lb. Electronic Kitchen Scale from $27.99 Free Shipping 9 stores See Details http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/36/65/64/63425135477069516c75507753306251564867-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Salter 9037 Extra Large, Extra Capacity Lithium Scale Salter 9037 Extra Large, Extra Capacity Lithium Scale 
 ( In stock ) 
The Salter tradition lives on since the late 1700&apos;s . Quality scales with European designs and unmatched Salter quality. The 9037 upholds this tradition with one of the largest , thinnest... More 

The Salter tradition lives on since the late 1700&apos;s . Quality scales with European designs and unmatched Salter quality. The 9037 upholds this tradition with one of the largest , thinnest platforms in the industry. This scale weighs up to 400 pounds( 180kg) in increments of .2 pounds(.1 kg)The soft curved shape and large angled readout makes this scale easy to use and easy to read. The low profile is easily stored. The scale features auto zero as well as instant on.Features include Less 
 Soap.com Store not rated See Store Info /salter-9037-extra-large/6edcBQ5GpiQluPwS0bQVHg==/info Soap.com $45.99 +$2.99 shipping Visit Store http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/76/69/2d/6f372d774961356a496445687877555a684567-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 SALTER BRECKNELL Floor Scales SALTER BRECKNELL Floor Scales 
 ( In stock ) 
Heavy-duty SALTER BRECKNELL Floor Scale is constructed of 5&quot; channel steel supports giving it superior strength to standard floor scales. Allows for up to 300% safe overload. Engineered for... More 

Heavy-duty SALTER BRECKNELL Floor Scale is constructed of 5&quot; channel steel supports giving it superior strength to standard floor scales. Allows for up to 300% safe overload. Engineered for floor or in-ground applications and rated for use indoors or outdoors. Platform is 3.75&quot; off the floor and features 3/16&quot; thick safety diamond treadplate design. Large, easy-to-read LED display indicator is available in either plastic or stainless steel. NOTE: Scale weighs loads in the listed increments. For example, 2500-lb. capacity scale weighs in 0.5-lb. increments. Less 
 C&amp;H Distributors Store not rated See Store Info /salter-brecknell-floor/vi-o7-wIa5jIdEhxwUZhEg==/info C&amp;H;Distributors $1,800.00 +$173.43 shipping Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/4e/78/4d/415a5a52696c4870566d4f76502d6e64765951-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Salter Brecknell Brecknell 1200g Precision Lab Balance Scale Salter Brecknell Brecknell 1200g Precision Lab Balance Scale 
 ( In stock ) 
When you need a reliable lab balance for a reasonable price, choose the Brecknell 1200g Precision Lab Balance Scale. Accuracy up to + or 2 divisions at full load. Platform size is 6.9&apos;&apos;W x... More 

When you need a reliable lab balance for a reasonable price, choose the Brecknell 1200g Precision Lab Balance Scale. Accuracy up to + or 2 divisions at full load. Platform size is 6.9&apos;&apos;W x 6.9&apos;&apos;D x 0.3&apos;&apos;H. Backlit LCD display is front facing and features 6 1/2 digits, 0.75&apos;&apos;H. Features external calibration and bidirectional RS232 interface so the scale can communicate data to a PC.Constructed of robust plastic housing and a stainless steel top place. Includes draft shield. Powered by 8 AA batteries (not included) or AC adapter (included). Battery life is approximately 15 hours. Manufacturer&apos;s warranty applies. Scale has a 1 year product warranty. Ships fully assembled. MBS-81696500490 Less 
 National Business Furniture Store not rated See Store Info /salter-brecknell/NxMAZZRilHpVmOvP-ndvYQ==/info $279.00 +$19.95 shipping Visit Store 1 2 3 4 5 ... 38 Next  » Why are these stores listed?   
 
Sponsored Listings
 
   
 Salter bis zu -70% 
 Salter online bestellen. Jetzt kostenlos&amp;einfach anmelden! 
 www.westwing.de/Salter 
 Salter Haushaltswaren 
 Küchenzubehör und Waagen von Salter - riesen Auswahl, günstige Preise! 
 www.salter.ladenzeile.de/Küche 
 Salter 
 Die günstigsten Preise vergleichen. Bis zu 85% bei Produkten sparen 
 www.delupe.de/Salter 
 Manual noch günstiger 
 Preisvergleich, der sich lohnt! Manual zum Schnäppchenpreis. 
 www.guenstiger.de/ 
 Salter 
 Ihr Lieblingsduft bis 50% günstiger im kostenlosen Preisvergleich! 
 www.kelkoo.de/ 
 
   
Related Guides:
 
 Top 10 Luggage Scales 
 by Staff_Contributor Travelling can be a wonderful experience. Yet, an... 0 
Prices are provided by the merchants. We assume no responsibility for accuracy of price information provided by merchants. Please alert us to any pricing discrepancies and we will alert the merchant. Sales taxes are estimated at the zip code level. Shipping costs are estimates. Please check store for exact shipping costs. To learn more about why certain stores are listed on the site, click here 

Product specifications are obtained from third parties, and while we make every effort to assure the accuracy of product information, we do not assume any liability for inaccuracies. Store ratings and product reviews are written and submitted by online shoppers to assist you as you shop. They do not reflect our opinions. We take no responsibility for the content of ratings and reviews submitted by users.
 
Products on Sale
 -46% Salter Slim Nutritional Scale $47.95 $87.99 Wayfair -39% Salter 11-lb. Digital Glass Top $54.95 $90.00 cutleryandmore.com -25% Salter Hi Capacity Aquatronic $57.17 $76.00 Wayfair -33% Salter 11-lb. Digital $39.99 $60.00 cutleryandmore.com 
 
 
About
 Home About Us Jobs Contact Us Privacy User Agreement 
Work with us
 Join our Partner Program Merchant Login Join our Merchant Program Advertise with Us 
Helpful Stuff
 Merchant Directory Brand Directory Site Index Popular Pages Shopping Guides 
eBay Family
 eBay Free Local Classifieds PayPal Apartments for Rent Tickets 
Shopping Sites
   France   Germany   United Kingdom   Australia   USA 
Copyright©2000-2012 Shopping.com
 http://img.shoppingshadow.com/jfe/JavaFrontEnd-fe121.rtb15.dt_seotags-9068 http://img.shopping.com/jfe/JavaFrontEnd-fe121.rtb15.dt_seotags-9068
	</body>
</document>
