<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009761" url="http://www.slashfood.com/2010/10/13/mcdonalds-brings-back-mcrib-introducing-chicken-flatbreads/" time="2012-07-13-03:09" support="1" score="0.0015866053204581399" bingtitle="McDonalds Brings Back McRib, Introducing Chicken Flatbreads ..." webtitle="McDonalds Brings Back McRib, Introducing Chicken Flatbreads - Slashfood">
			<query id="000912" bing-rank="117"/>
	<description>Filed Under: Fast Food, Chain Stores / Restaurants Tags: ... Check out The Condiment Bible for an easy, homemade McRib ... Visit http://mcriblocator.weebly.com/ and leave a ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to main content Skip to main content 
Slashfood has a new home! Huffpost Food .
 Click here to visit the new home of Slashfood! 
Hot on HuffPost Food:

 Famous Death Row Last Meals Food Fights: The Biggest Culinary Scandals Of 2011 
 See More Stories 
 MAIL You might also like KitchenDaily , ParentDish , and More 
 More Sites You Might Like 
 Aisledash DIY Life Holidash Horoscopes My Daily Patch Paw Nation ShelterPop Shortcuts Stylelist That&apos;s Fit Wow.com 
 Tell us what you think for a chance at $1000! slashfood.com SEARCH 
 home news 
 Business Newspapers Farming On the Blogs Food News Science Health&amp;Medical Television&amp;Film Magazines Trends 
 chefs&amp;restaurants 
 Bakeries Coffee Shops Celebrities Interviews Chains Restaurants 
 reviews 
 Books New Products Cookbook Spotlight Reviews Fast Food Stores&amp;Shopping 
 recipes 
 Drink Recipes Ingredients Entertaining Methods 
 features 
 Drinks Lists Feast your Eyes Local Delicacies Holidays Taste Tests How To Tip of the Day Ingredient Spotlight Quizzes 
 all categories 
 Budget Cuisine Feast Your Eyes Restaurants Celebrities Food Politics Science Cookbook Spotlight Gadgets Taste Tests Drinks Holidays Television&amp;Film Entertaining Interviews Tip of the Day Events Lists Fast Food Local Delicacies Quizzes 

 View All Categories Send Us Feedback 
 
 
 McDonalds Brings Back McRib, Introducing Chicken Flatbreads 
 
by Jennifer Lawinski , Posted Oct 13th 2010 @ 4:00PM 
 Share 
 Photo: Mullenkedheim, Flickr 
 
 McDonald&apos;s is trying something old and something new this fall at its U.S. locations. But it has nothing to do with the McWeddings they&apos;re throwing in Hong Kong (see yesterday&apos;s post ).

The fast-food chain is bringing back its much lauded (by some) McRib sandwich on November 2 for a six-week run at its stores across the U.S. -- the first time in 16 years the sandwich will be available nationwide, the Wall Street Journal reported. &quot;It doesn&apos;t sell well all year long because people get tired of it,&quot; McDonald&apos;s USA President Jan Fields told the Journal . Weary customers, you&apos;ve had your break, and now your ribs are back.

McDonald&apos;s franchises in Nebraska, Maryland and New Mexico will also be testing the company&apos;s new chicken flatbreads this fall, Nation&apos;s Restaurant News reported. 
The flatbreads--grilled chicken wrapped in a grilled flatbread--come in four varieties, each with less than 300 calories and costing $1.89 in most markets, NRN reported.
 
 Tuscan Tomato Basil, with basil pesto, tomato and garlic aioli Four Cheese, with garlic aioli and a blend of cheddar, Monterey Jack, mozzarella and fontina cheese Southwest, with guacamole and pico de gallo BBQ Bacon Ranch, with bacon, barbecue ranch sauce and the four-cheese blend. 

The McRib, meanwhile, has been around since 1981, and is sporadically found at different restaurants around the country.
And, believe it or not, it has developed a bit of a cult following.
 
McRib enthusiast Alan Klein, who has loved the pork sandwich since his days growing up on a hog farm in South Dakota, launched a &quot; McRib Locator &quot; to help others find the sandwich after returning home from Minnesota and finding it on the menu, the Journal reported.

&quot;It rekindled my love of McRibs and made me start thinking it would be nice to know where they were,&quot; he told the paper.

The locator gets 300 to 400 hits weekly and recently posted McRib sightings in the Chicago and Detroit areas, although site user Tom Russomano, from Morristown, N.J., said he&apos;s also received &quot;false positives&quot; from the tool. He trekked to New York City after the locator said it was being sold there, only to find himself emptyhanded, the Journal reported.

&quot;The only reason I would ever set foot in a McDonald&apos;s is for the McRib,&quot; Russomano said. We just hope that as long as he was in Manhattan during his failed mission, he at least headed over to Blue Smoke restaurant, where barbecue ribs are never in short supply. 
Filed Under: Fast Food , Chain Stores / Restaurants 
 Tags: chicken flatbread sandwich , mcdonalds , mcrib 
 Share 
Related Videos
   McDonalds Mashup Menu 
 
Chew on This
 
 Royal Wedding Cake Details Revealed! - YumSugar 

 Make Your Own Pop Tarts - CHOW Denny&apos;s Introduces a Maple Bacon Sundae - Eater Whole Foods Opening Bars in Stores - USA Today Rules Of Bar Etiquette -- For The Bartender - HuffPost Food 
 
Sponsored Links
 
Reader comments (Page 1 of 2)
 
 10-13-2010 @ 9:43PM xiaoxin said... Very happy to be here, this siteed hardy is very good, very happy to share with everyone here, I will share with my friends, Thank you for sharing!
 Reply 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-16-2010 @ 3:08PM shelia said... i&apos;ve never tried the mcrib and can&apos;t say i plan to unless i can find a free coupon or something. as much as i love real ribs, i&apos;m not imagining these to be so good as a sandwich from mcdonalds. well, anyways, here&apos;s some freebies i did find - http://bit.ly/cmcDLl - enjoy!
 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-14-2010 @ 9:37AM Condiment Bible said... Check out The Condiment Bible for an easy, homemade McRib recipe:

 http://www.condimentbible.com/2010/09/recipe-how-to-make-homemade-mcribs.html 


 Reply 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-14-2010 @ 3:43PM LoriJ said... I was in the hospital lately and they served me something very similar to the McRib...It was just the same but without the sauce. Honestly, I had to look on the little card they send with each meal to see what kind of meat it was, but once I tasted it I realized it was a McRib without the sauce. It was pretty good!
 Reply 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-14-2010 @ 4:47PM Irish Mist said... At Sam&apos;s Club I have bought a like sandwich to the McRib. I can&apos;t recall the brand name but there are (I think) 6 to the box and only have a touch of sauce on them. One can always dress them up as you want once they are heated up.
Here in Hawaii we have the apple pies as well as other varieties of pie as well. Right now they have the fried Blueberry pies on sale. Havae yet to see an old fav of mine..fried cherry pie. I am lookoing forwarad to the McRib and do hope that we get it next month as well.
 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-14-2010 @ 4:18PM Thomas Swist said... Banquet makes a boneless rib deal that is almost like a McRib, but with mashed potatoes and no bun, alas.
 Reply 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-14-2010 @ 4:21PM Sin D said... Something is fishy (porky?) here. Here in Ohio, the Mc rib is served with ONLY the sauce, pickles and onions...VERY GOOD. The above pic is wrong. No lettuce..AND the rib patty has the shape of a rib and is formed with &quot;bones&quot;. Now I&apos;m hungry...
 Reply 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 11-03-2010 @ 4:38AM LA said... i&apos;m pretty sure the picture is of the aforementioned new chicken flatbreads. the mcrib with sauce, onions, and 2 pickles is a standard recipe nationwide (i believe).
 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-14-2010 @ 4:55PM Lisa said... People get tired of it???? Are you kidding me??? It&apos;s the BOMB!!!!
 Reply 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-18-2010 @ 4:05PM Gilmore said... Why? Please help me to understand. Visit http://mcriblocator.weebly.com/ and leave a comment please to educate me. Much appreciated.
 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-14-2010 @ 5:12PM Jo said... McRib is great but years ago McDonalds also had a steak sandwich that was even better. Haven&apos;t seen it since the &apos;70s but always hoping they would bring it around again. My friends and I would drive several miles to the nearest town with a McDonalds just to get one. Also, I think they ruined the apple and cherry pies when they went to the baked crust instead of the crispy fried crust they used to have. Maybe more calories, but who cares if you only have it once in a while for a treat!
 Reply 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-15-2010 @ 5:11AM Leigh said... The McRib is so vile and disgusting, that if served in a school cafeteria, kids would throw it against the walls. Worse yet, scrape off the sauce and see what&apos;s underneath the &apos;skin&apos;.
 Reply 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-14-2010 @ 5:31PM E. Martinez said... While those other places may have something &quot;similar&quot; to the McRib, to me, a McRib ISN&apos;T a McRib WITHOUT the Mickey D&apos;s sauce!!! Whenever they&apos;re out, I always get them which isn&apos;t good for my bod but sure is good for my taste buds, lol. However, sometimes they come a little dry, even if you ask for extra sauce, trust me, I ask for it everytime and when I go to use their BBQ sauce for their nuggets or the BBQ sauce in my frig (I&apos;ve used different brands to boot), the McRib&apos;s just don&apos;t taste the same!! :( I would love to know what type of sauce they use so I could have a McRib whenever I wanted one. To bad I don&apos;t know anyone who works at a Mickey D&apos;s. If I did, I&apos;d be having one right now. LOL

So happy about this news. Marking the date now!! Enjoy your McRib&apos;s peeps. You know I&apos;m gonna...... :D
 Reply 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-28-2010 @ 9:13AM bellagrlxitalia@aol.com said... i think they use bullseye hickory smoked sauce.
 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-14-2010 @ 6:49PM Ris said... I&apos;m so glad they&apos;re bringing McRib back. I don&apos;t understand why they wouldn&apos;t keep it on the menu forever. &quot;It doesn&apos;t sell because people get tired of it?&quot; Come on, people get tired of Big Macs too. I wish they had those burgers with melted cheese on rye all the time too. I love those. I don&apos;t go to McDonald&apos;s much anymore. Too many calories. But hey, I don&apos;t care about the McRib calories at this juncture!
 Reply 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-14-2010 @ 8:50PM Debbie said... Get tired of the Mcrib (NOT), Love It ! That is the only reason I stop at a Mcdonalds other then something to drink. Can&apos;t wait til they come back here.
 Reply 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-14-2010 @ 7:13PM Mary. said... the Mc Ribb is nothing new. remember the &quot;chopped beefsteak&quot; sandwich? they should bring that one back too!
 Reply 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-14-2010 @ 7:22PM Curt said... The McRib is a good sandwich but when will McDonalds bring back the McDLT? Now THAT was a great sandwich !!!!!!!!!!!!!! Remember..........the HOT side stays hot.....and the COOL side stays cool !!!!!!!!!!!!!!! Please bring this sandwich back for a limited time.
 Reply 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-14-2010 @ 7:25PM Patti said... Sooooooooooooo happy the McRib is coming back to more locations. Should be forever though. Not just 6 weeks. I&apos;ve had sandwiches similar but still haven&apos;t found any quite as great as the McRib from McDonalds! Thank you McD!!!
 Reply 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 
 10-15-2010 @ 4:51AM Angela said... McDonalds needs to bring back the chicken fajitas!
 Reply 
 Vote up Vote down Report 
 
 27 Comments / 2 Pages 
 1 2 Next 
 
 HuffPost AOL Social News Most Popular 
 
 This Charlie&apos;s Angel Turns 61 Today Like 
 79
 While We&apos;re Up&apos;s Zach Booher Killed in Car Accident Like 
 119
 PHOTOS: Most And Least Catholic States In America Like 
 287
 LA Superintendent John Deasy Removes Entire School Staff Over Teacher Sex Scandal Like 
 14
 Brides Say &apos;Yes&apos; to Selling Their Dress ... Before the Wedding! Like 
 111
 PHOTOS: Giant 100-Foot-Deep Sinkhole&apos;s Origin Determined Like 
 573
 Officer Fired After Entering Woman&apos;s Bedroom to Serve Notice for Overgrown Lawn Like 
 55
 Get the Best Bargain on Perfect Pillows -- Savings Experiment Like 
 69
 LOOK: Athlete Fashion On ESPY Red Carpet Like 
 24
 Chumbawamba Break Up: &apos;Tubthumping&apos; Rockers Split After 30 Years Like 
 378
 Liquids Surrendered At Airport Security: Is There An Afterlife? Like 
 8
 Former Miss New Hampshire USA Accused Of Assault - AGAIN Like 
 173
 The LIBOR Scandal Explained in One Simple Infographic Like 
 752
 Dennis Flemion Missing, Presumed Dead: Frogs Drummer Disappeared Saturday in Wisconsin Like 
 70
 Woman Catches Shark! Like 
 2K
 Jennifer Hudson, Son David Jr.: Is Baby Number Two on the Way? -- Potent Quotables Like 
 6
 Lottery Officials Want $1 Million Winnings Back Like 
 184
 &apos;Strange Sex&apos; Features Woman With 102ZZZ Breasts Like 
 5K
 Target Won&apos;t Sell Frank Ocean&apos;s Album Like 
 2K
 Jackson Jr.&apos;s Office Denies Report Of Alcohol Addiction Treatment Like 
 398
 PHOTOS: Adorable Baby Elephant Saved By Mother Like 
 2K
 Kristin Chenoweth Recovering After &apos;The Good Wife&apos; Injury Like 
 87
 World&apos;s Heaviest Woman Credits Sex For 98-Pound Weight Loss Like 
 10K
 LOOK: Tiny Baby Born Smaller Than A Soda Can Goes Home From Hospital Like 
 240
 10 Free Programs Every Windows User Should Install Immediately Like 
 615
 Susan Boyle&apos;s Neighbors File Noise Complaint, Call Singing &apos;Unbearable&apos; Like 
 178
 Chris Christie Makes Fun Of Fat Jokes Like 
 147
 WATCH: Snake Venom Does Terrifying Thing To Human Blood Like 
 2K
 PHOTOS: Teepee Poles Impale Camry, Woman Escapes Serious Injury Like 
 212
 Comedians Defend Daniel Tosh Like 
 816
 PHOTOS: Dinosaur Sex Similar Across Species, Scientists Say Like 
 3K
 Honest Toddler&apos;s Greatest Hits On Twitter Like 
 1K
 
 
 Follow Us 

  Newsletter Facebook Twitter RSS 
 
Hungry for news about fast food, slow food, food politics, food personalities, and food controversies? Then sign up for our weekly newsletter.
 

 
Most Popular Stories
	</body>
</document>
