<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009288" url="http://chicago.menupages.com/restaurants/downtown/all-neighborhoods/chinese/" time="2012-07-13-02:40" support="1" score="0.008783164977553846" bingtitle="Downtown, Chinese Restaurants - Chicago, Menus, Ratings, Reviews ..." webtitle="Downtown,ChineseRestaurants - Chicago, Menus, Ratings, Reviews, Chicago - MenuPages Restaurant Search">
			<query id="000413" bing-rank="250"/>
	<description>36 Tsang Chinese Food548 N Wells St | Btwn W Ohio St &amp; W ... Order From This Restaurant $$ 12: 39 Yu Shan584 N Wells St ... You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you selected.</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to MenuPages - Please Select a city:

 New York City San Francisco Los Angeles Philadelphia Boston Chicago Washington, DC South Florida 
 New Menupages Desintations London   Paris 
 hide 
 
 Home Blog My MenuPages Restaurateurs Submit a Menu Change City Food Delivery Login 
 
 MenuPages 

Now Serving: 4288 Menus for Chicago Restaurants
 
 Search Advanced Find-A-Food 
 
 Areas Neighborhood All Areas Downtown North Side Northwest Side South Side Southwest Side West Side All Neighborhoods Albany Park / North Park Archer Hts / Brighton Pk Bridgeport-McKinley Park Bronzeville / Douglas Chicago Lawn / Ashburn Chinatown / Pilsen Edgewater / Andersonville Far NW Chicago Far SE Chicago Far SW Chicago Gold Coast Hermosa Humboldt-Austin-Garfield Hyde Park / Kenwood Irving Park Lawndale Lincoln Park / DePaul Lincoln Sq / Ravenswood Logan Square / Avondale Loop Midway Montclare / Cragin Near West New City / Chatham Old Town / Goose Island Portage Park / Dunning River North Rogers Park / Devon Ave Roscoe Village / North Ctr South Loop / Near South South Shore / Woodlawn Streeterville Ukranian Village Uptown West Loop / Greektown Wicker Park / Bucktown Wrigleyville / Lakeview Cuisines All Cusines Afghan African American (New) American (Traditional) Argentinean Asian (other) Asian Fusion Australian Austrian Bagels Bakeries Bar Food Barbecue Belgian Bistro Brazilian British (Modern) British (Traditional) Burgers Cafes&amp;Coffeehouses Cajun&amp;Creole Californian Caribbean Central American Central Asian Cheesesteaks Chicago Grill Chicken Chinese Cocktails Crepes Cuban Delis Desserts Dim Sum Diners&amp;Coffee Shops Dutch Eastern European Eclectic&amp;International Ethiopian Filipino Fish&amp;Chips French Gastropub German Greek Haitian Hawaiian Health Food Hot Dogs Indian Indonesian Irish Italian Jamaican Japanese Korean Kosher Latin American Local/Organic Mediterranean Mexican Middle Eastern Moroccan Noodle Shops Nuevo Latino Other Pakistani Persian Peruvian Pizza Polish Puerto Rican/Dominican Russian Salads Sandwiches Scandinavian Seafood Small Plates/Tapas Smoothies/Juice Bar Soups South American Southern&amp;Soul Southwestern Spanish Steakhouses Sushi Teahouses Thai Tibetan Turkish Vegan Vegetarian-Friendly Venezuelan Vietnamese Wild Game Wine Bar Wings Street Zip code Cross street Restaurant name 
 
Hold down Control (PC) or Command (Mac) key + mouseclick to select more than one option
 
 
 Home &gt; Downtown &gt;Chinese
 
 Chicago Restaurants: Downtown, Chinese 
 
 Filter by Meal: --Select-- Breakfast Dinner Lunch Feature: --Select-- Accepts Credit Cards BYOB Bar Scene Catering Cheap Eats Delivery Gluten Free Items Group Dining Kid-friendly Lunch Special Online Ordering Online Reservations Open Late Outdoor Dining Private Parties Prix Fixe Romantic Take Out Trendy Wheelchair Friendly WiFi 
 
 Map these results 
 
 1 - 40 of 40 Results Results Per Page: 25 50 100 
 
 Restaurant Name Rating Price Reviews 1 AsiaGo Express 176 N Wells St | At W Couch Pl $ 4 2 Baisi Thai 900 N Michigan Ave | At E Delaware Pl Order From This Restaurant $ 2 3 Beijing&amp;Bangkok 1512 N LaSalle Blvd | Btwn W North Ave&amp;W Schiller St Order From This Restaurant $$ 0 4 Big Bowl Cafe 6 E Cedar St | At N State St $$$ 2 5 Big Bowl Cafe 60 E Ohio St | Btwn N Rush&amp;N Wabash St $$$ 2 6 Chen&apos;s Chinese Express 17 S Wabash Ave | Btwn E Madison&amp;E Monroe St $$$ 1 7 China Doll 1246 N Wells St | At W Scott St Order From This Restaurant $$ 2 8 China Grill (CLOSED) 230 N Michigan Ave | At E Lake St $$$$$ 2 9 Eat&amp;Drink 212 W Randolph St | At N Wells St Order From This Restaurant $ 2 10 Empire Restaurant 49 W Division St | At N Dearborn St $$ 8 11 Fast Foo&apos;s 28 E Jackson Blvd | Btwn N State St&amp;N Wabash Ave $ 5 12 Friendship Chinese Restaurant 200 E Lake Front Dr | Btwn Jackson&amp;Lake Shore Dr Order From This Restaurant $$ 0 13 Hong Kong Cafe (CLOSED) 5 S Wabash Ave | At E Madison St $$ 0 14 Lan&apos;s China Bistro 1507 N Sedgwick St | At W Blackhawk St Order From This Restaurant $$ 0 15 Lan&apos;s Old Town 1507 Sedgwick St | Btwn W North Ave&amp;W Division St Order From This Restaurant $$ 0 16 Max Orient 520 N Michigan Ave #427 | At E Grand Ave $ 0 17 Mei&apos;s Corner 101 E Delaware Pl | At N Ernst Ct $$ 6 18 P F Chang&apos;s China Bistro 530 N Wabash Ave | At E Grand Ave $$$ 3 19 Panda Express 302 S Wells St | At W Jackson St $ 0 20 Panda Express 29 E Madison St | Btwn S State St&amp;S Wabash Ave $ 0 21 Panda Express 100 W Randolph St | At N Clark St $ 1 22 Panda Express 520 N Michigan Ave | At E Grand Ave $ 0 23 Panda Express 110 W Monroe St | Btwn S La Salle&amp;S Clark St $ 0 24 Panda Express 515 S State St | Btwn E Harrison St&amp;E Congress Pkwy $ 0 25 Panda Express 130 E Randolph St | Btwn N Beaubien Ct&amp;N Stetson Ave $ 0 26 Panda Express 77 E Adams St | At S Michigan Ave $ 0 27 Red Violet 121 W Hubbard St | At N La Salle Dr Order From This Restaurant $$$ 0 28 Shanghai Terrace 108 E Superior St | Btwn N Rush St&amp;N Michigan Ave $$$$$ 3 29 Silk Road 19 S La Salle St # 1 | Btwn W Madison St and W Arcade Pl $ 8 30 Silk Road (CLOSED) 216 W Jackson Blvd | At S Wells St $ 2 31 Sixty Five Chinese Restaurant 336 N Michigan Ave | Btwn N Macchesney Ct&amp;E Wacker Pl $$ 2 32 Sixty Five Chinese Restaurant 201 W Madison St | At S Wells St $$ 4 33 Sixty Five Chinese Restaurant 111 W Jackson Blvd | Btwn S Clark&amp;S LaSalle St Order From This Restaurant $$ 1 34 The Original Tsang Pan Asian 1512 N La Salle St | At W Burton Pl Order From This Restaurant $$ 0 35 Top Wok 58 E Ontario St | At N Rush St $$$ 0 36 Triple 1 Chinese Resturant 177 N State St | At E Lake St $$ 1 37 Tsang Chinese Food 548 N Wells St | Btwn W Ohio St&amp;W Grand Ave Order From This Restaurant $$ 1 38 Yang 28 E Roosevelt Rd | Btwn S Wabash Ave&amp;State St Order From This Restaurant $$ 12 39 Yu Choy 548 N Wells St | At W Ohio St Order From This Restaurant $$ 12 40 Yu Shan 584 N Wells St | At Ohio St Order From This Restaurant $$ 8 
 
 1 
 
Neighborhood
 
 Gold Coast (2) Loop (16) Old Town / Goose Island (6) River North (8) South Loop / Near South (4) Streeterville (4) 
 
Meals
 
 Breakfast (4) Dinner (35) Lunch (37) 
 
Features
 
 Accepts Credit Cards (26) BYOB (1) Bar Scene (1) Catering (7) Cheap Eats (5) Delivery (20) Gluten Free Items (3) Group Dining (3) Kid-friendly (4) Lunch Special (11) Online Ordering (14) Online Reservations (4) Open Late (9) Outdoor Dining (1) Private Parties (4) Prix Fixe (3) Romantic (1) Take Out (30) Trendy (1) Wheelchair Friendly (6) WiFi (1) 
 
Advertising
 
Hot and Fresh Restaurant News Delivered Weekly
 You are signing up to receive: Weekly updates delivered straight to your inbox covering the latest restaurant news, menus, openings, closings, and food events Menupages Chicago Newsletter You may also be interested in: Hear about special offers from MenuPages or its partners about future events, promotions and features. Offers&amp;Promotions Sign Up 
Thanks for subscribing!

You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you selected.

To enjoy more benefits and personalization available on MenuPages.com, register now! 
 Checkbox is required 
 About Us Careers Contact Us Advertise With Us Restaurateurs Privacy Policy Legal Notices Copyright Notice 

©2002-2012 Slick City Media, Inc. All Rights Reserved. MenuPages®is a trademark of Slick City Media, Inc. Disclaimer
	</body>
</document>
