<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009327" url="http://www.insiderpages.com/b/3714894884/deffenbaugh-industries-inc-kansas-city" time="2012-07-13-02:42" support="8" score="0.007255029874862398" bingtitle="Deffenbaugh Industries Inc - Kansas City - Insider Pages ..." webtitle="Deffenbaugh Industries Inc - Kansas City">
			<query id="001241" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="001246" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="001251" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="001248" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="001312" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000935" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="001232" bing-rank="11"/>
	<description>... worked for this company for damn near 5 ... as he removed a bottle from the container and placed it behind the back tire of my car. ... around; they may stay where they throw ...</description>
	<body>
		join sign in 
 Find Near Browse Categories 
recommendations that matter most 
 Health&amp;Medical Home&amp;Garden Hair&amp;Beauty Auto
 Services Pets follow us Advertise With Us 
 Kansas City, KS &gt; Waste Removal &gt; Garbage Collection Services &gt;Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 

 

 

 

 
Deffenbaugh Industries Inc
 ★★☆☆☆ 16 Reviews Write a Review 
913-631-3300
 2601 Midwest Dr Kansas City , KS 66111 deffenbaughindustries.com 

 
 Add Photo Edit Business Claim Business 
 
About Deffenbaugh Industries Inc
 Categories 
 Garbage Collection Services 
 
Communications&amp;Utilities
 More choices in Kansas City: 
 North Kansas City Iron&amp;Metal 
1222 Iron St Kansas City, MO
 
 North Kansas City Hauling 
901 E 13th Ave Kansas City, MO
 
 Reviews 
 
Insider Pages Reviews for Deffenbaugh Industries Inc

Have experience with this business? Write a Review. 
 ★★★★★ Deffenbaugh is a Saint! 
 Gina b. 5 Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 
 
This company is a saint! I read all of these complaints and wonder&quot;what are you tinking?&quot;. Why do people place these insane expectations on this service provider? Try calling your cable company and asking for a discount because you didn&apos;t watch all the channels last week. Try calling your internet provider and ask for faster speeds and better connectivity for a lower price. Try going to the post office with a parcel that is incorrectly packaged and tell them they need to take it no matter what.All of these companies would laugh at you. People would never consider doing these things, but they do similar things to Deffenbaugh. People need to view and appreciate deffenbaugh as a quality service provider, not your indentured servant.
 April 25, 2012 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★★★★ To all you who complain...... 
 jami b. 5 Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 
 
My Husband has worked for this company for damn near 5 years....I have read all of the bullcrap reviews.....yes some helpers can be asses but if you have a bad trash collector get their name and call customer service......or get the truck number.......and call! While you are sittin there complaining did you ever take in consideration all the crap they go through just to pick up your nasty ass trash?!?!?!? Rain, Sleet, Hail, or Snow, They ONLY get 12 cents....12 CENTS a stop.....so for ALL your trash and bad mouthing they put up with they only get 12 cents......Try being nice....you might just get better service!
 January 10, 2011 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★☆☆☆☆ BAIT&amp;SWITCH 
 Frannie T. 1 Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 
 
I used this company for recycling (they had a monopoly) and another for trash. I got a call offering me a cheaper price for trash so I signed up. When I got a bill after one week of pickup, it was much higher than the deal I was offered. They acted like I&apos;d made it up when I called because I couldn&apos;t give them the name of the salesperson. Who remembers that? So I cancelled. DON&apos;T USE DEFFENBAUGH!!!
 January 06, 2011 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★★★★ Thank You 
 Alda C. 5 Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 
 
I read the bad reviews about Deffenbaugh and had to add a good one. Yesterday was the day after Labor Day, so the truck got here a little early. I heard it coming down the street and hurried to get some garbage out. I took out a bag and motioned to the driver that I had a little more. He waited, and when I came out of the garage with the rest of my garbage, he met me half-way up the driveway and took my garbage from me. I was VERY impressed!
 September 08, 2010 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★☆☆☆☆ POOR CUSTOMER SERVICE 
 Pamela W. 1 Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 
 
Before you decide to hand your HARD EARNED MONEY to this so called business make sure you are not ONE DAY LATE or they will sure enough cut you off without any notice or courtesy call.
 March 15, 2010 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★☆☆☆☆ A Waste of Taxpayers Money 
 David W. 1 Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 
 
I am tired of my container being left in the street EVER WEEK!! i call Deffenbaugh and the city of Mission every week but never get a response. This week I plan to leave the containers in the street until someone from Deffenbaugh or the city come and place it back on the driveway
 October 05, 2009 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★☆☆☆☆ Service that Stinks... 
 Ruth S. 1 Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 
 
THE worst disposal company. I wondered why no one else on my street used Deffenbaugh. Now I know. Not long after starting trash pick-up one of the drivers broke the wheel off my brand new barrel. Then after about 1 year of mediocre service, they switched our pick-day from Wednesday to Thursday without ever letting us know, and then raised their prices. They never arrived at a consistent time- sometimes as early as 7 in the morning and other times as late as 5pm. One particular morning, the truck pulled up and we had forgotten to put our trash out, so my husband ran outside and pulled the barrel to the road. The truck sat there for a second, but no one got out. I could see from the house that there was only ONE person in the truck. My husband started throwing the bags into the truck, since the guy obviously wasn&apos;t getting out, and the jerk DROVE OFF while my husband was still emptying the barrel!! After Labor Day, ALL the other disposal companies in the neighborhood were still right on time, but not DEFFENBAUGH! Oh no! They were a day late. This last week they didn&apos;t even pick up the trash. In fact they never drove down the street at all. So are trash sat out a whole week, while we wondered if they had changed our pick-up day yet again. But they did come the next Thursday. But when I went out to pull in the barrel, I found a bag of trash left inside. That was the last straw. I called up the company to complain, and the lady was extremely rude. She was huffing and sighing into the phone the whole time, never once apologized, and tried to blame me, saying that the driver reported that I didn&apos;t have my trash out on time the week before. Bull Crap. He didn&apos;t even bother to drive down my street to check. When I told her that they left a bag of trash in the barrel she said,&quot;Well, how many bags did you have out there?!&quot;When I told her that it was enough to fit in the barrel with the lid closed she said nothing. And of course, didn&apos;t apologize. I told her that was going to switch my trash service and she got all testy with me. Deffenbaugh raised their prices three different times while I used their service and I am more than happy to switch to AAA (who was very friendly and has great reviews, by the way).
 September 25, 2009 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★☆☆☆☆ A WASTE of time and energy... 
 Steve B. 1 Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 
 
Many complaints... I changed the brakes on my car and threw the old ones in the trash. Some up and coming young star in the waste management field actually crawled into the truck and threw the brakes back into my yard and told me they&quot;do NOT accept auto parts!&quot;I can understand fenders, engines or transmissions, but brake shoes???Another time I set my trash out for pick-up and found a branch (about 2 feet long and maybe 3/4&quot;thick) had fallen and I placed it in the can, which was placed about 3&apos; from the curb. They refused my trash stating that yard waste must be set beside the curb! Another time I placed my recycling out for pick-up and it was not collected. I called to ask why and I was told that an animal had crapped in the container. I apologized and told them I would clean it out. I inspected the container and there was no animal feces anywhere near it. The next week my recycling was once again refused. I called in and they again said an animal had crapped in the container. I looked again and there was no feces anywhere to be found. The following week I waited for the the driver and I watched as he removed a bottle from the container and placed it behind the back tire of my car. I ran after him and he sped away. I looked at the bottle and there were some small bugs that had crawled inside (maybe to drink up the residue?) and had died. I assume this was the animal feces that had created such an unbearable issue...Want some more??? How about picking up the rolling $50 trash can above the collectors head and slamming it on the driveway shattering the plastic wheel into pieces? No, not just mine, every rolling container in my neighborhood was the same. Or how about the rule about not accepting recycling containers with broken glass (safety hazard) which I can agree with. But how about some moron pulling his gloves off and removing pieces of a broken bottle (broken overnight) and throwing the pieces into my yard and then picking up the container and dumping the contents into the back of the truck???Believe it or not, I have more but I&apos;ll spare you the gruesome details and tell you that this morning they just didn&apos;t pick up my trash. No reason, no explanation, they just didn&apos;t do it. So, I have finally had enough and found a new company in my area....Hopefully SUPERIOR DISPOSAL will provide a little known spice in this industry called CUSTOMER SATISFACTION!!!
 March 07, 2008 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★☆☆☆ Definitely Delinquent Service 
 Robin O. 2 Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 
 
Trash pick up is scheduled weekly. They do offer recycling of 1&amp;2 plastic, aluminum, tin, carboard, newspapers, magazines, chipboard, for an additional fee. Frequently recycling is not picked up or the container is spilled and items left to blow around the area. Customer service is unresponsive to consumer questions. It also is more expensive than neighboring communities trash service.
 August 05, 2006 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★☆☆☆☆ Deffenbaugh Disposal - unfortunately no other service to use!! 
 Dave F. 1 Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 
 
Deffenbaugh Disposal - unfortunately no other service to use!! I live in KC KS and unfortunately Deffenbaugh is the only service that is available. Trash pickup is sloppy, leaving messes on the road, ripping bags and letting the litter fall on the ground without picking up after themselves. Trash cans are thrown around; they may stay where they throw them or roll back out in the street. I have actually seen my trash can roll back out into the street and when the truck finished it&apos;s route on our cul-de-sac the truck actually drove up through part of my neighbors yard to go around it. I put out a wooden shelf unit, approximately 3 ft by 3.5 ft and they did not take it even though I have seen them take washers/dryers/dish washers and throw them into the trash truck... I guess that wood doesn&apos;t sound as neat as metal does when they crush it. The workers also get to decide if the refuse is construction material or not; like they are the experts. Cleaning out my garage/basement I had left over pieces of sheet rock and wood from old home projects. I broke them up and put in seperate boxes to make it light enough for them. They did not take the boxes as they deemed it construction materials. Yeah, right... 3 boxes of maybe 15 lbs. maximum each... lot of construction going on there!!! I despise Deffenbaugh! They know that we are stuck with them and they will take advantage of it to the fullest extent!!!
 November 28, 2005 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★★☆☆ They do mediocre service 
 Erica S. | Insider Expert
| Rank: 5,585 3 Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 
 
This company has a city contract so they do all the disposal for this area. They do a mediocre job and that all depends on where you live. They service my place of business and my residence. They are pretty expensive for businesses, but there really is nothing you can do because of the the contract ehy hold with the city. Wouldn&apos;t recommend if we had a choose.
 July 11, 2005 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 
Latest reviews from Citysearch .
 ★☆☆☆☆ Worst Ever!! 
by timhoop at Citysearch 1 Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 
 March 14, 2009 
Everything about this company is awful from the customer service to the drivers. I ordered a roll off and was transferred to someone named Tom in dispatch. Talk about rude. He was mean and nasty over the phone. He was not able to answer any of my questions. I will never be using this company again.

Pros: None


 ★☆☆☆☆ Lousy service and lousy company 
by DisFan at Citysearch 1 Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 
 January 29, 2009 
We all have known for years that Deffenbaugh stinks. They are rude, do a lousy job, break trashcans, leave messes, etc. And now I&apos;ve heard (via an ex employee) that they don&apos;t really recycle - instead all the &quot;recycling&quot; stuff ends up in the same landfill as everything else. I&apos;d love to get more scoop on that. I would change to A-1 in a heartbeat, but my homeowner&apos;s association contracts with Deffenbaugh.


 ★☆☆☆☆ Worst company to ever work for. DO NOT APPLY HERE YOU WILL GET SCREWED!!! 
by Gdogs at Citysearch 1 Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 
 January 12, 2009 
DO NOT APPLY HERE YOU WILL GET SCREWED!!! What kind of company fires someone without a reason. A company that spent all their money and now can&apos;t afford to pay their people. 21 people fired before Christmas and 15-20 after Christmas. Some were fired for medical disabilities, which they had worked their already listed as handicap. That&apos;s really sick to do what they have done to these people. Some of these people have been there 20 or more years. And to get even a hi, by or nothing. Just YOUR FIRED! Many of these are people that were close to retiring. And screwed out of their retirement. If you see an ad about them hiring, DO NOT APPLY WITH THEM, UNLESS YOU WANT CRAPPY PAY, AND TO BE ABUSED. Just do a search and you will see what I&apos;m saying is true.

Pros: NONE

Cons: CRAPPY PAY, DO NOT GET PAID FOR HOURS WORKED ON THE JOHNNY ON THE SPOT SIDE.


 ★☆☆☆☆ POOR POOR SERVICE 
by Baseball25 at Citysearch 1 Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 
 December 30, 2008 
This is the worst service I have ever seen. I get the trash out by 6am and they still can&apos;t pick it up. I have had to call them 5 times in the past two months because they keep passing up my trash. Does anyone else in the shawnee KS area have the trouble with their service?


 ★☆☆☆☆ Find another trash service 
by Jess87247 at Citysearch 1 Deffenbaugh Industries Inc 
 July 24, 2008 
We bought a house and the previous owners had Deffenbaugh as their trash service. We figured that we would go ahead and keep it. After three monthes of being on the phone with them many many times the trash service is still not in our name it is in the previous owners name, along with us they have been on the phone trying to get this matter taken care of also. We finally recieved papers to sign to get the service put in our name. It was a 60 month contract in which you can&apos;t get out of. We decided not to sign it and find another trash company. I called and it seemed like no one could help me at first then they directed me to a man that finally could and once he found out that we weren&apos;t going to sign the contract and wanted to discontinue the service he was flat out rude. I have never had customer service this bad in my life. I would not recommend them to anyone!


 Write a Review Get Map&amp;Directions 
Modify or Try Another Search For:
 
Garbage Collection Services - Kansas City, KS
 Find Near Home | About Us | FAQ | Blog | Help/Contact Us | Feedback | Store Finder | Doctor Finder | Sitemap | Privacy Policy (updated) | Terms &amp; Conditions ©2004–2012 Insider Pages. All rights reserved. Partner Sites: MyAutismTeam | Ask Answers | Ask Kids | Life123 | Citysearch | MerchantCircle | Urbanspoon
	</body>
</document>
