<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009468" url="http://krvr.org/index.php?option=com_joomlaboard&amp;Itemid=26&amp;func=view&amp;id=14942&amp;catid=16" time="2012-07-13-02:50" support="6" score="0.006162755058919925" bingtitle="krvr.org - Re:Abundant Harvest Organics now delivers to the KRV ..." webtitle="krvr.org - Re:Abundant Harvest Organics now delivers to the KRV - KRVR Community Forums">
			<query id="000458" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="000953" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000965" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000961" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="001432" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000678" bing-rank="247"/>
	<description>... middle of a vast parking lot next to a fast food ... box and add-ons will be available for pick up ... will be donated to a local shelter or food bank. A donation receipt ...</description>
	<body>
		facilitating the social, natural, and financial health of the Kern River Valley for this and future generations. 
 
   
 
 Home What is KRVR? 
 KRVR UPDATE E-MAIL KRVR Documents KRVR&apos;s Non-Profit Profile 
 KRVR Meeting 
 Next Monthly Meeting Agendas Minutes 
 Community Issues 
 FIRE INFORMATION TRANSIT INFORMATION KRVR Community Calendar Living Green in the KRV DARK SKY Upper Kern River Fishery Management Grant Resources 
 Links Community Forums Contact Us EMERGENCY CONTACTS 
 
    
FIRE INFO
 
Webcam views around the KRV

 

 Webcam Views around KRV 


 Kern River Valley Weather Info  
 
KRVR Community Forums
 home post reply threaded view help   
 
 Forum List Forum Category Living Green&amp;Sustainably 
 
 KRVR.org Website Admin. 
 Admin
 
Admin

 Posts: 4164 
 Karma: 5  
 Abundant Harvest Organics - 2008/08/16 17:02 Bakersfield Californian 7-14-08: FROM FARM TO TABLE: ORGANICS TAKE ROOT

 SOURCE: http://www.bakersfield.com/102/story/494386.html 

 FROM FARM TO TABLE: ORGANICS TAKE ROOT 
 By JEFF NACHTIGAL, Californian staff writer jnachtigal@bakersfield.com 

Every Saturday morning a semi truck rolls to a stop next to the In-N-Out Burger on Stockdale Highway and hundreds of boxes of organic fruit and produce are stacked in the parking lot.

Theres a flurry of activity as people arrive to pick up their pre-ordered boxes that might include fresh peaches, dill, spinach, cherries, potatoes or tomatoes whatever is in season at the time.

Its an incongruous sight: organic produce plopped down in the middle of a vast parking lot next to a fast food restaurant. But no one seems to mind. An hour later the truck pulls out, and all but a few of the boxes are claimed. The extras will go to charity.

This is the Abundant Harvest Organics model, one that cuts out the middleman and delivers fresh-picked produce direct from farmer to customer, sometimes via a parking lot.

 Abundant Harvest Organics : 
 www.abundantharvestorganics.com 
Subscriptions, big box: $33.80; small box: $19.80 per week

Mirroring consumer interest in locally grown, fresh food, Abundant Harvest Organics has grown from 50 delivery boxes per week to more than 1,000 in just more than 10 months. Boxes are packed, then delivered to 20 cities between Tulare and Simi Valley.

Organic reckoning came to Vernon Peterson six years ago.

The man behind Abundant Harvest Organics, Peterson has always worked the 150-acre chicken and stone fruit farm that his Swedish great-grandfather established in Kingsburg in 1892.

But the year came when Peterson knew the competition had grown too steep; the family farm wasnt going to make it much longer by growing the conventional, or nonorganic, peaches, plums and nectarines it had been turning out for decades.

So Peterson made the switch.

Converting to organic is a three-year process, but the bigger hurdle is finding a niche market to sell the organic products.

The organic market, for all the hype, is incredibly small, Peterson said as he walked a 12-acre patch of organic Zee Fire nectarines on a recent morning.

If I produce it and I dont have a way to market it for a significant premium, Im not going to be here long, Peterson said.

When big wholesale buyers push low prices on small growers, family farms often look for alternative methods to sell their products. Farmers markets and subscription services, also referred to as community supported agriculture, are common avenues to diversify beyond the wholesale market.

 SMALL FARM HURDLES 

Shermain Hardesty, director of the small farm program at the University of California, Davis, ticked off the hurdles small farms face selling products.

Marketing, developing a customer base, offering a steady variety of products in the box, and coming at the venture with a customer service mentality are important elements, Hardesty said.

Theres growing interest in local foods. So hes taking advantage of the locally produced, and the identity about whos produced what in the box, Hardesty said.

While the national food market was only 2.5 percent organic in 2005 according to the Organic Trade Association, the tide is shifting.

Organic sales in California are growing at double-digit rates without an increase in the number of growers, according to a recent study, Riding the Organic Wave, by the University of California, Davis Karen Klonsky.

A couple of miles down the road from the Peterson farm, Kyle and Michele Reynolds are looking to join the shifting tide. They grow dozens of crops, from green pepper plants to avocado trees on their 38-acre farm. For 11 years theyve sold produce at farmers markets, and a self-serve, weigh-and-pay stand at the edge of the farm.

But with gentle prodding from Peterson, theyve made the decision to go organic. With the paperwork filed, they plan to contribute to the all-organic Abundant Harvest boxes.

It gives us a guaranteed home at a fair price, so we can grow more crops, and count on some income coming back so we can invest back into our people and the farm, said Kyle Reynolds.

Giving family farms a guaranteed home for their products is a key part of Petersons model. Peterson talks about creating a win-win system where, farmers can do what they do best farm, and consumers get great produce.

Local farmers are talking, Reynolds said.

I think Vernons created quite a stir. Its different, and I see growers jumping on board, and I see growers that think hes crazy, he said.

A few miles away in Reedley, Ginger Balakians family has grown heirloom tomatoes, squash, grapes and pomegranates since 1939. She was one of the first farmers Peterson contacted when he began looking for organic sources. He wanted her heirloom tomatoes for the boxes.

Balakian said she sells as many of her tomatoes and squash as she can to Whole Foods, a major organic buyer. But when Whole Foods says no more, she sends pallets of squash for the Abundant Harvest boxes.

I really believe in what hes doing. It benefits the farmer and the customer. Theres such a difference from whats in the store and whats picked the day before, Balakian said.

 LONG VISION 

A deeply spiritual man quick with a joke and a smile, Peterson lost his calm in the nectarine patch when conversation shifted from organic farming techniques to economics.

Stomping his work boot and spitting his words, Peterson described small organic farmers struggling to survive in a marketplace that rewards size and volume over almost all else.

Abundant Harvest Organics is Petersons stab at leveling the playing field for family farms.

So far the farmers hes talked to have been an easy sell. They like the idea of reconnecting with consumers.

Consumers like Sam Herbert, a subscriber for several months, appreciate organic food that comes from the United States, as opposed to overseas.

And subscriber Bruce Cook likes the idea hes supporting local farmers, and eating food picked at its ripest.

As he took a bite from a Zee Fire nectarine, Peterson wondered aloud how, given a choice, anyone would choose to eat a fungicide-treated piece of fruit over an organic nectarine with more nutritional value and taste.

Were giving them fresh organic for what theyre paying for not-so-fresh conventional, Peterson said.

 HOW ORGANICS BOX STACKS UP 
Last weekend the small Abundant Harvest Organics box included 10 organic items.

Total: $19.80

Compared to the nonorganic produce at a local grocery store, the box came out on top (grocery store prices in parentheses):

Peaches 2, ($2.50)
Red plums 6, ($3.75)
Cantaloupe, ($2.99)
Corn, 6 ears, ($3)
Carrots, 4, ($0.79)
Red leaf lettuce, ($1.79)
Basil, ($3.29)
Green peppers, 6, ($1.50)
Eggplant, 1, ($0.75)
Onions, 2 ($0.99)

 TOTAL: ($21.35) vs. $19.80 @ Abundant Harvest Organics
 PHOTOS by Casey Christie/The Californian 

 Emily Hall helps unload a truck as part of the Abundant Harvest Organics produce operation where customers come every Saturday and pick up their fresh produce. 
 http://static.bakersfield.com/smedia/2008/04/26/10/255-
MARKETFOURCC.standalone.prod_affiliate.25.jpg 
 Customers line up to pick up their weekly produce supply. 
 http://static.bakersfield.com/smedia/2008/04/26/10/46-MARKETSEVENCC.standalone.prod_affiliate.25.jpg 
 Customers lined up for their produce. Abundant Harvest Organics operates a subscription-based program where customers pick up a box of fresh produce on Saturdays. 
 http://static.bakersfield.com/smedia/2008/04/26/10/874-
MARKETTHREECC.standalone.prod_affiliate.25.jpg 

 PHOTO BELOW: 

 A customer picks up a box of fresh produce from the back of the Abundant Harvest Organics truck in the parking lot of Sports Chalet on Stockdale Highway. 
 http://static.bakersfield.com/smedia/2008/04/26/10/987-MARKETSIXCC.standalone.prod_affiliate.25.jpg 


 

Post edited by: KRVR.org Website Admin., at: 2008/09/07 11:02 Administrator , KRVR.org
eworinkrv@mchsi.com   | | The administrator has disabled public write access. 

 KRVR.org Website Admin. 
 Admin
 
Admin

 Posts: 4164 
 Karma: 5  
 Abundant Harvest Organics in the KRV - 2008/08/16 17:07 Abundant Harvest Organics www.abundantharvestorganics.com is an alliance of small family farmers in Central California dedicated to growing superior organic produce and delivering at a fair price, with minimal packaging, directly to local consumers. In addition to the generous box of in-season produce you can add organic dairy products, eggs, poultry, grains, nuts, and more. Currently this on-line, year-round subscription service is delivered weekly to Bakersfield.

A small group of KRV families has banded together to participate in a very green way, taking turns driving on Saturday mornings to pick up for the whole group and distributing to three central drop points in the Valley.

 Rebecca Rozenberg is the point person for this group and her plan is to duplicate this healthy, green concept and coordinate other small groups to serve all the communities in the KRV. The long-range plan is to build the subscriptions to a point where the company can deliver to us.

If interested, contact Rebecca Rozenberg at (760) 376-2342 rebecca@livinginbalance.net. Administrator , KRVR.org
eworinkrv@mchsi.com   | | The administrator has disabled public write access. 

 KRVR.org Website Admin. 
 Admin
 
Admin

 Posts: 4164 
 Karma: 5  
 :Abundant Harvest Organics in the KRV - 2008/09/06 18:47 Example of SMALL BOX Administrator , KRVR.org
eworinkrv@mchsi.com   | | The administrator has disabled public write access. 

 KRVR.org Website Admin. 
 Admin
 
Admin

 Posts: 4164 
 Karma: 5  
 Re::Abundant Harvest Organics in the KRV - 2008/09/06 18:48 Small box next to large one Administrator , KRVR.org
eworinkrv@mchsi.com   | | The administrator has disabled public write access. 

 KRVR.org Website Admin. 
 Admin
 
Admin

 Posts: 4164 
 Karma: 5  
 Abundant Harvest Organics now delivers to the KRV - 2008/09/07 11:01 Abundant Harvest Organics now delivers to the KRV 

Before, KRV subscribers had to take turns driving to Bakersfield on Saturday Mornings to fetch all the boxes. Now, there are enough subscribers so that we dont have to take that extra step.

 Rebecca Rozenberg is the point person for this group in the KRV. She is working on a location where the Abundant Harvest truck will show up every Saturday from 9 to 10am so subscribers can pick up their weekly box of food. That will probably be someplace in Wofford Heights. Well announce the location here, once it is set.

Another feature of Abundant Harvest is that there are optional ADD ONS every week, including things like almonds, apricot jam, cream, dried beans, organic chicken, organic raw cream&amp;cheese, cream, Quick Oats for Oatmeal (3 lbs. for $3.20)

 This weeks Abundant Harvest Organics ADD ONS 
 https://www.abundantharvestorganics.com/addons.php 

To be part of Abundant Harvest Organics , you sign up online, paying via charge card. You can manage your account online and select weekly add-ons online too. You can go on vacation too if you are away or getting too much food (good option for single person subscribers).

 Abundant Harvest Organics Sign-up page 
 https://www.abundantharvestorganics.com/customers/register.php 

If interested, contact Rebecca Rozenberg at (760) 376-2342 or rebecca@livinginbalance.net. Administrator , KRVR.org
eworinkrv@mchsi.com   | | The administrator has disabled public write access. 

 Rebecca Rozenberg 
 Admin
 
Admin

 Posts: 4164 
 Karma: 5  
 Re:Abundant Harvest Organics now delivers to the KRV - 2008/09/11 15:36 I am Rebecca Rozenberg , your Abundant Harvest Organics Community Host .

I am writing to let you know that delivery is now available to Wofford Heights for this wonderful, subscription organic produce. We will be bringing your fresh, organic produce to Wofford Heights from Bakersfield on Saturday mornings. Our meeting place is the parking lot next door to Charlies Market , located at 6801 Wofford Blvd, between Panorama and Oak . See map below.

 Your subscription box and add-ons will be available for pick up between 9:30 am and 10:30 am each Saturday. 

You have already signed up on the website ( www.AbundantHarvestOrganics.com ) and you can now log in, enter your payment information, and place your order.

 If you do so before 9:00 am on Monday 9/15/08 , you will receive your first order on Saturday 9/20/08 . 

If you have forgotten your password, select &quot;Need or Forgot Password&quot; on the login page. Please allow time for the company to respond.

Your selection of a large or small subscription box becomes your standing order until you change it or schedule a vacation week. You can schedule vacation weeks up to a year in advance on the website. This needs to be done 10 days in advance of delivery. You can use this feature to suspend your subscription for one or more weeks to meet your needs. You can cancel at anytime, 10 days in advance of delivery.

We will transport chicken and dairy products packed in ice, so feel free to order any of the add-ons offered on the website. To order add-ons, be sure to go to the website by 9:00 am on the Monday before delivery. Add-ons are not standing orders and need to be selected each week.

If you are unable to pick up your box at the meet point, please arrange for someone else to get it for you. Let me know who will be coming to pick up and their phone contact information. If your box has not been picked up, I will attempt to contact you. Orphan boxes will be donated to a local shelter or food bank. A donation receipt will be provided upon request.

My husband John and I have been so inspired by our involvement with Abundant Harvest as subscribers for the last 5 months that we have chosen to become the Host for our community and to take responsibility for transporting here each week. The food is so alive and full of flavor, and the feeling of being more closely connected to our food and where it is grown has been so amazing. Check out the videos on the website for a wonderful glimpse of where your food is coming from, and to meet the great people at Abundant Harvest who are making all this possible.

I am excited to provide this opportunity for more healthy eating to everyone in our community. I strongly believe in supporting local family farmers, and in the health benefits of eating seasonal, locally grown, organic produce. Just like Abundant Harvest, we are committed to reducing transportation costs and emissions, and we make our own biodiesel fuel for our truck.

We also support the company&apos;s commitment to reusable packaging. If you don&apos;t have a use for it, please return the paper liner with your crate each week. New member Michelle Maring will be using it for art projects at her Montessori Preschool in Kernville.

Please share this opportunity for healthier eating in the Kern River Valley with friends, family, and co-workers. Together we can make a difference in the health and well-being of our community.

If you have any questions or need to reach me for any reason, my phone numbers are 760-376-2342 ( home) and 323-376-8121 (cell). My email address is Rebecca@LivingInBalance.net. I send out a short weekly update by email. Please make sure my address is authorized by your email program, so my messages don&apos;t go to your junk box.

Welcome to the Abundant Harvest Organics Kern Valley Coop!

Happy eating!

 Rebecca and John Rozenberg 
Kern River Valley Community Host Administrator , KRVR.org
eworinkrv@mchsi.com   | | The administrator has disabled public write access. 
 

 Forum List Forum Category Living Green&amp;Sustainably 
 Joomlaboard Forum Component 1.1.4 Stable
 Two Shoes M-Factory 
 Website Design by: SEQUOIA STUDIOS
	</body>
</document>
