<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009750" url="http://cudacoffee.com/catalog-product.php?p_ref=2023" time="2012-07-13-03:08" support="1" score="0.006732622600603365" bingtitle="Crathco Mini Cold Beverage Dispenser for Premix 2 Bowl (Cold ..." webtitle="Crathco Mini Cold Beverage Dispenser for Premix 2 Bowl (Cold Beverage Dispenser) - Cuda Coffee">
			<query id="000501" bing-rank="215"/>
	<description>... impulse sales at your snack bar, buffet, or fast food restaurant. Has plastic side panels and drip tray. This dual bowl premix cold beverage dispenser is as easy to clean ...</description>
	<body>
		Toll Free: (866) 411-2832
  Shopping Cart  Secure Shopping 
 
 
 
 Home Contact Shipping Site Map Links  Search July 12, 2012 
 
 Commercial 
 Bar Refrigeration Systems 
 Beverage&amp;Juice Dispensers 
 Coffee / Espresso Parts 
 Coffee Equipment 
 Coffee Grinders 
 Coffee-Espresso Vending Machines 
 Dispensers, Organizers&amp;Accessories 
 Espresso Machines 
 Frozen Drink Machines 
 Hot Drink / Oatmeal / Soup Dispensers 
 Iced Tea Brewers / Dispensers 
 Signs / Displays / Posters 
 Water Boilers&amp;Dispensers 
 Water Dispensers&amp;Coolers 

 Household 
 Coffee&amp;Espresso Machines 
 Coffee Accessories 
 Coffee Grinders / Roasters 
 Cups / Mugs / Saucers / Tumblers 
 Frothers&amp;Hot Chocolate Makers 
 Gift Baskets 
 Gift Packages 
 Storage / Containers / Dispensers 
 Tea Pots&amp;Water Kettles 

 Supplies 
 Coffee Cleaning Supplies 
 Coffee Supplies 
 Gourmet Coffee Blends 
 Sauces / Toppings / BBQ Sauces 
 Tea Blends&amp;Accoutrements 
 Water Filters&amp;Scale Interceptors 

 Let us bring the deals to you... Sign up for our mail list! 
   

 
 

 Online Payments You Are Here: Home &gt; Commercial &gt; Beverage&amp;Juice Dispensers 


 
 images/newproducts1/gmc-e29-4.jpg 
Crathco Mini Cold Beverage Dispenser for Premix 2 Bowl

 Product # GMC-E29-4 by GMC 
 
 Ordering Options Choose Product:   E29-4 w/ plastic panels&amp;drip tray (as shown) E29-3 w/ stainless steel (Add $115.00) 
 List: $ 1,368.00 

Your Price: $717.99

 Savings: $650 

Qty:    
 Each Cost: $717.99 


 Overview Specifications 

 This Crathco Mini Twin E29-3 2.4 gallon double bowl cold beverage dispenser is a simple and effective way to boost impulse sales at your snack bar, buffet, or fast food restaurant. Has plastic side panels and drip tray.
This dual bowl premix cold beverage dispenser is as easy to clean as any in the industry! With fewer parts for a fast, easy cleanup and a stainless steel surface that is easy to cleanse, this dispenser makes it easier than ever to give your fruit juice, iced tea, and iced coffee the exposure they deserve.
The Crathco Classic Bubblers Mini Twin E-293 beverage dispenser&apos;s 1/6 hp compressor uses R134A refrigerant that will keep your beverages chilled and ready for consumption for hours at a time. It requires a 120V electrical connection and is UL and NSF Listed.

 Features: 
 Has plastic side panels and drip tray Compact size saves valuable counter space Dispenses 2 flavors in less than one square foot Famous two-piece, stainless steel, dripless pouring valves are sanitary and easy to use and maintain Large capacity drip pan holds more Generous, yet compact, 9 liter (2.4 gallon) easy clean bowls Unique evaporator and high efficiency pump design cools faster and more efficiently for faster start-ups Superior engineering allows full beverage cooling right down to the last drink Modern styling, better design and more use of stainless steel allow easier cleaning and less maintenance Super-strong, virtually unbreakable polycarbonate bowls and covers give lasting durability Down-to-earth design engineering makes routine servicing easier and simpler Second-to-none quality control with &quot;field condition&quot; testing Agitators are included with each unit for fresh juices, coffees or teas World-wide sales and service assure customer satisfaction 


 We may also suggest...

 
 Gourmet Coffee Grinder 
Only  $37.99 
 Qty: 
 Cecilware &quot;S&quot; Series 5 Gallon Stainless Steel Iced Tea Dispenser 
Only  $119.99
	</body>
</document>
