<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009289" url="http://babesrockinmami.com/2012/03/realistic-eating-flab-to-fab/" time="2012-07-13-02:40" support="1" score="0.0018856153454469538" bingtitle="Realistic Eating {Flab to Fab}" webtitle="Realistic Eating {Flab to Fab}">
			<query id="000536" bing-rank="130"/>
	<description>... chocolate again or you will NEVER eat at a fast food restaurant ... sour candy and it just carried over and in order ... have the calories of their food right on the menu board ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Meet Us! Sponsors Button Love PR&amp;Disclosure I Care About People 
 
 Babe&apos;s Rockin&apos;Mami 

a rock mama, a loving wife, a makeup fanatic and tree hugger
 You are here: Home / exercise / Realistic Eating {Flab to Fab} 
Realistic Eating {Flab to Fab}
 March 16, 2012 2 Comments Hello there! If you are new here, you might want to subscribe to the RSS feed for updates on this topic. Powered by WP Greet Box WordPress Plugin 
 

You CAN eat out or enjoy your favorite foods when you are‘dieting’, I really hate that term‘dieting’, it implies that one day you will not be eating the way you are to lose weight.  You need to make a lifestyle change (I know some of you hate that term haha).  It just isn’t realistic that you will NEVER eat chocolate again or you will NEVER eat at a fast food restaurant again, you will.  Another reason not to completely deprive yourself is because when you finally do get that sweet treat you will eat another one and another one and before you know it the bag of whatever it was is gone.  I want to give you a few ideas of how to eat out or how to get that treat and still be under your calorie goal.

Think fun size, this is a trick Chris and I used in the beginning of our journey to eat healthier.  During my pregnancy and in the several months after I would eat a couple cookies each night (or a dozen at times, can’t lie about it) or chocolate.  When I was pregnant I craved sweets and sour candy and it just carried over and in order to sort of wean myself off of that we would buy bags of mini candy bars to keep in the freezer.  Oh, quick side tip, freeze your chocolate, you eat less and slower plus it tastes delicious cold!  So we would buy the mini bars or hershey kisses.  You can do two kisses for 50 calories or a mini candy bar for 80 calories, you get that sweet that you want and since it’s small you aren’t blowing your calorie budget.

You can take that smaller size mentality over to fast food, order a kids meal, they will let you!  Chick-fil-A has a grilled nugget kids meal you can get with a fruit cup and a diet soda and it is around 300 calories.  Those grilled nuggets look weird but they taste better then breaded in my opinion.  But, don’t assume that just because you ordered the kids meal that you are getting less calories, at Hardee’s they have a cheeseburger kids meal and no options of subbing fries for something else, that will run you around 800 calories.  They expect you to feed that to your kid!

If you have a smartphone look up the place you are eating at to get calories.  I will actually google‘chick fil a kids meal’to get the calories.  If you know ahead of time where you are going, take a minute to look up the menu and browse what you could eat so you know ahead of time.  In my experience asking for calorie information is met with a blank stare even though they are supposed to have it handy.  Panera Bread is AWESOME because they have the calories of their food right on the menu board next to the item and it isn’t in tiny print.  It’s big and easy to see.  Also, don’t be afraid to ask for substitutions, you can substitute a black bean patty at Buffalo Wild Wings for a regular beef patty.  When you have your wait person there ask if you can get veggies subbed for a starch or can you get your sandwich grilled instead of fried.  You are in charge of your food.  Another trick is ask for a bag when you get your food and box up half of it before you even get started, you have lunch for tomorrow and it won’t be sitting on your plate tempting you.  I have given into the call of food sitting in front of me while I wait for a box too many times!

I hope these tips will help you guys a little bit (or a lot a bit)!!  Don’t forget to go visit The Random Blogette aka Jayme to read another story, this week is Alison!
 Filed Under: exercise , fitness , flab to fab , weight loss Tagged With: babes rockin mami , buffalo wild wings , eating out , exercsie , flab to fab , kisses , the random blogette , weight loss 
Comments

 Kristy @PampersandPinot says: March 16, 2012 at 10:05 am 
That portion control is the most important thing, and the hardest sometimes!
 Kristy @PampersandPinot recently posted.. Being a Mommy Takes Ninja Mind Tricks 
 Danielle says: March 16, 2012 at 1:10 pm 
Great tips! I do the Chic-fil-A kids meal too, and the box thing. It also makes your money go farther! Double WIN!
 Danielle recently posted.. Green Everywhere!! 
 
 
Speak Your Mind Cancel reply 
 
 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
advertisers!
 
 Online Discount
Codes 
 
 Shop Top Brands 
 GlassesShop Coupons Comlax.com Coupons College Book Renter Duncraft Wild
Bird CanadaVet
Deals 
 
 
Sponsors
	</body>
</document>
