<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009190" url="http://www.ktla.com/news/landing/ktla-irvine-chick-fil-a-receipt-rage,0,4017634.story" time="2012-07-13-02:35" support="10" score="0.023347660506975128" bingtitle="Chick-fil-A: Cashier at Chick-fil-A Fired After Writing &apos;Ching ..." webtitle="Chick-fil-A: Cashier at Chick-fil-A Fired After Writing &apos;Ching&apos; and &apos;Chong&apos; on Customer Receipts - ktla.com">
			<query id="001102" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000349" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="000678" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="000162" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000662" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000411" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000365" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="000694" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000709" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="001118" bing-rank="219"/>
	<description>Chick-fil-A Cashier Fired After Writing &apos;Ching,&apos; &apos;Chong ... resident assistant at the university, went to the fast food ... Eat Beat; Fashion; Green; Travel Features; Legal Help Center</description>
	<body>
		TV Schedule Mobile Apps Classifieds Antenna TV Advertise Contact Us Blogs THIS TV 
   
 

75°F
 
 Home 
 Local News Popular Stories Contests Send Your Video&amp;Pics E-Mail Alerts Text Alerts Talent Bios Poll THIS TV 
 News 
 Local News Nation/World Popular Stories Special Reports Politics Talent Bios Poll KTLA Twitter Facebook 
 Weather 
   
 Traffic 
 Main Traffic Page Lowest Gas Prices One-Tank Trips 
 Sports 
 College Sports Auto Racing LA Marathon 
 Entertainment 
 Entertainment News Movies Music Academy Awards Emmy Awards Rose Parade 
 Health 
 Parenting Green 
 Info 
 Viewer Info Page Technology Gayle Anderson Allie Mac Kay John&amp;Ken Car Pro Show Inside the Law 
 Alerts 
 Mobile Text Alerts E-mail Newsletters Facebook KTLA Twitter 
 Video 
 Local Viral Morning News Nation/World Entertainment Heroes at Home Special Reports Upload 
 Blogs 
   
 Travel 
 Travel Features Vacation Starter 
 Contests 
 Main Contest Page Anchor Challenge Stan Chambers Journalism Awards 
 TV Schedule Mobile Apps Classifieds Antenna TV Advertise Contact Us Blogs THIS TV 
 
 HOT TOPICS Kissing Teacher Penn State Probe Yahoo Hacked Pursuit Head-On Crash Baby Burned 
 
 
 
 
 Advanced Search 
Advanced Search
 X 
 include all of these words: include any of these words: include this exact phrase: exclude: Select a date range this week past 30 days past 3 months past year Create a custom date range From: To: 
 Home  &gt;  News  &gt;  Stories 
Chick-fil-A Cashier Fired After Writing &apos;Ching,&apos; &apos;Chong&apos; on Customer Receipts
 
 Comments 100 

 
 
 
A cashier at an Irvine-area Chick-fil-A was fired after writing disparaging names on customers&apos; receipts. (Tumblr user cakeninjak)
 
 
 Related Ex-UCLA Student&apos;s Racist Rant on YouTube Inspires Asian Food Service Topics University of California, Irvine Human Mishaps 
 KTLA News 
 4:03 a.m. PST , December 13, 2011 
 IRVINE, Calif. (KTLA) -- A cashier at an Orange County Chick-fil-A is out of a job after she wrote offensive names mocking Asian customers.

Instead of taking the name of two Asian customers, the cashier wrote &quot;Ching&quot; and &quot;Chong&quot; on their receipt, UC Irvine student Kevin Lee said.

Lee raised attention to the incident last week after posting the incident on his Tumblr account .

 Sign up for KTLA 5 Breaking News Email Alerts 
Lee wrote that his friend, a resident assistant at the university, went to the fast food restaurant near the school with another friend. After receiving their receipts, the friend complained to the manager.

&quot;I went to talk to the manager, and I told him that this cannot happen ever again,&quot; the friend said. &quot;I made it known that it wasn&apos;t okay, and that I didn&apos;t appreciate it whatsoever.&quot;

Chick-fil-A officials said the incident didn&apos;t reflect corporate views.

In a statement to the L.A. Times, Chick-fil-A&apos;s vice president for public relations Don Perry said it was &quot;simply [a] case of immaturity, failed judgment and human error.&quot;

Perry said the customers were regulars and the cashier, only identified as &quot;Lia&quot; on the receipt, was dismissed soon after the incident.

Lee responded to all the media attention on his blog , saying he didn&apos;t wish for his post to act as a witch hunt against the entire franchise.

&quot;I don&apos;t think the horrible mistake on the part of one individual is reason enough to launch a witch hunt,&quot; Lee wrote.

&quot;All I ask is that people be respectful and THINK.&quot; ktla-irvine-chick-fil-a-receipt-rage 
 Comments 100 

 
 
Featured Stories
 
Comments (100)
 Add / View comments | Discussion FAQ operator 7227 at 2:17 PM December 20, 2011 
Terminated over this? Let&apos;s all think should we hire Larry H. Parker or leave it up to judge judy?
 snoopy2b at 10:22 PM December 18, 2011 
According to the receipts, there is a place for the name..... did anyone ask if these customers were in fact called Ching and Chong? I think a more offensive remark would be to have written Chink or something to that flavor, but Chong is a real name, and so is Ching. I know a lawyer named Ching Chow... and I don&apos;t see anyone getting fired about it.

The guy who felt offensive, is obviously a girly man.... and a sissy for crying like a girl over spilt milk. If it turns out Lia did nothing wrong, I hope she sues the cr** out of the company for wrongful termination.
 Oldtech at 1:35 PM December 17, 2011 
Maybe it was the &quot;Schity Chicken&quot; they didn&apos;t like. (South Park fans? Anyone?)
 
Video gallery
 
 
 
 
Popular Pics
 
 
 
 Pictures: George Zimmerman charged with 2nd-degree murder 
 
 
 
 10 Most-Watched YouTube Videos of 2011 
 
 
 
 PHOTOS: Home Invasion Family Massacre (Graphic Content) 
 
 
 
 More Faces of Meth ( New Photos ) 
 
 
 
 PHOTOS: California&apos;s Most Notorious Killers 
 
 
 
 Mug shots of the rich and infamous 
 
 
 
 Popular Stories Local News Nation/World 
 
 Baby Badly Burned After Falling Into Hot Washing Machine 
 
 Boyfriend Ejected Through Sunroof After Argument Ends in Crash 
 
 Parents Arrested After Trying to Hide Baby in Carry-on Bag 
 
 Teacher Accused of Lewd Acts Hospitalized After Wild Pursuit 
 
 Man Dies in Crash After Running Over Wife 
 
 19 Kids Found Alone in Filthy, Hot Kentucky Home 
 
 Girl Mauled by Friend&apos;s Dog at Sleepover 
 
 2 Children Found in Sweltering Cars, 1 Dead 
 
 Boy, 8, Shoots 5-year-old Friend, Leaves Him to Die 
 
 Falling Headstone Kills 4-year old Boy at Cemetery 
 More Popular Stories 
 Cops: AutoZone Workers Foil Attack by Sex Offender in Parking Lot 
 
 Exonerated Stow Beating Suspect Sues City, LAPD Chief 
 
 Arrest Made in Shooting Death of LAPD Officer&apos;s Mother 
 
 Clipper&apos;s Blake Griffin Injures Knee at Team USA Practice 
 
 Tom Cruise&apos;s Lawyer May Sue National Enquirer Over &quot;Monster&quot; Story 
 
 Glendora Doctor Arrested in Drugs for Cash Scheme 
 
 Junior Seau&apos;s Brain Tissue to be Studied, Coroner says 
 
 Cops: Anaheim Teacher Caught Kissing Underage Teen in Car 
 
 Pursuit Ends In Two Crashes, Over-turned Truck In Inglewood 
 
 Fontana Teacher Pleads Not Guilty in Hazing Scandal 
 More Local News 
 Yahoo Passwords Hacked, 450,000 Posted Online 
 
 Woman Kept Boyfriend&apos;s Corpse in House to Watch NASCAR 
 
 Officials Failed To Protect Boys From Sandusky, Report Says 
 
 FBI: Zimmerman Has &apos;Little Hero Complex&apos; but Not Racist 
 
 Reporter&apos;s Live Shot Gets Rudely Interrupted [VIDEO] 
 
 Judge Lets Mississippi&apos;s Only Abortion Clinic Stay Open 
 
 French Avalanche Kills At Least Nine People, Police Say 
 
 Rep. Jesse Jackson Jr. Hospitalized for &apos;Mood Disorder&apos; 
 
 U.S. Deploys Sea Drones To Persian Gulf To Clear Iranian Mines 
 
 Baby Badly Burned After Falling Into Hot Washing Machine 
 
More Pictures

 
 Super Drunk People 
 
 LOL cat pictures 
 
 Guess Whose Assets? 
 
 The Faces of Meth: Before&amp;After 
 
 Mug shots of the rich and infamous 
 
 
 News 
 Local News Nation/World Popular Stories Picture Galleries Talent Bios Business&amp;Tech News Consumer Confidential Politics LA Crime Maps Special Reports Poll KTLA Blogs KTLA Twitter Facebook 
 

 Info&amp;Alerts 
 Viewer Info Page Gayle Anderson Allie Mac Kay Car Pro Show Inside the Law CW Shows Promotions&amp;Contests Consumer Safety Community Calendar Community Affairs Closed Captioning TV Schedule THIS TV Mobile Text Alerts E-mail Newsletters 
 

 Video 
 Local Viral Morning News Nation/World Entertainment Most Popular Heroes at Home Special Reports Sports Upload 
 

 Lifestyle 
 Pets Eat Beat Fashion Green Travel Features Marketplace Cars&amp;Autos Car Pro Show Wedding Horoscopes Games Do It Yourself 
 

 Shows 
 All Shows Nikita 90210 America&apos;s Next Top Model Vampire Diaries Gossip Girl Supernatural Antenna TV TV Schedule 
 

 Weather/Traffic 
 Weather Traffic Find the Lowest Gas Prices in Your Area One-Tank Trips 
 

 Sports 
 College Sports Auto Racing LA Marathon 
 

 Entertainment 
 Entertainment News Movies Music Academy Awards Emmy Awards Rose Parade 
 

 Health 
 Parenting Green Consumer Safety 
 
 
 
 Advertise Talent Bios Community Affairs Community Calendar Rose Parade 2012 

 About KTLA Contact Us KTLA Jobs Closed Captioning Privacy Policy Terms of Service About Our Ads Montage KTLA-TV, 5800 Sunset Blvd., Los Angeles, CA, 90028 
 
 A Tribune Broadcasting website
	</body>
</document>
