<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009391" url="http://vehicles.wheels.ca/silver-2004-cadillac-srx-520674-deltaautogroup/" time="2012-07-13-02:45" support="2" score="0.0006921741909878244" bingtitle="2004 Cadillac SRX Silver | DELTA AUTO GROUP | Wheels.ca" webtitle="Vehicle Details">
			<query id="001144" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="000798" bing-rank="132"/>
	<description>Pass-Through Rear Seat Power Driver Seat Power Passenger Seat Power Steering ... But by offering near 5 Series room at less than 3 Series prices, it actually sold ...</description>
	<body>
		5 4 6 0 4 New&amp;Used Vehicles Listed All Provinces Change Province Within: All 10 KM 20 KM 50 KM 100 KM 250 KM CHOOSE PROVINCE 
 All Provinces alberta british columbia manitoba new brunswick newfoundland and labrador northwest territories nova scotia ontario prince edward island quebec saskatchewan 
 
 Home News&amp;Features Vehicles&amp;Reviews Guides Used Cars Compare (3) 
 
Inside

 Green Wheels Motorsports Wheels Smackdown Columns&amp;Advice News&amp;Information Cool Cars&amp;Tech 
 
Headlines

 Dart hits the bull’s-eye This little Honda grows on you Honda NC700X and S are economical and green, unlike most motorcycles 2013 Interceptor looks likely to replace Crown Vic as a police standard Hyundai-Kia creeping up on GM 
 
Features

 Columns&amp;Advice Green Wheels Cool Cars&amp;Tech 
 
Inside

 Vehicles Reviews 
 
Popular Vehicles

 BMW 3 Series Honda Civic Suzuki Kizashi Ford F150 ANissan Altima Volkswagen Jetta 
 
Features

 
2012 Mercedes Benz SL-Class
 
2012 Chevrolet Sonic LT
 
Porsche 911
 
 
Inside

 Insurance Guide Tire Guide Used Car Guide 
 
Headlines

 Have I damaged my tires? When using winter tires all year is a good idea Buy used winter tires for commuter car that isn’t expected to last Summer tires needed for duration of a lease Tire talk: Even with some grip left, it may be time for new tires 
 
Our Experts

 Norris McDonald Can Toyota&apos;s &quot;Jesus
 Car&quot; change its bland reputation? Jim Kenzie Can Toyota&apos;s &quot;Jesus
 Car&quot; change its bland reputation? Ian Law Can Toyota&apos;s &quot;Jesus
 Car&quot; change its bland reputation? Eric Lai Can Toyota&apos;s &quot;Jesus
 Car&quot; change its bland reputation? 
 
Inside

 Latest Vehicle Profiles Reviews How-To 
 
Latest Videos

 
2012 Mercedes GLK
 
2012 Mercedes GLK
 
2012 Mercedes GLK
 
2012 Mercedes GLK
 
2012 Mercedes GLK
 Sponsored 
 
INSIDE

 Search Used Cars Dealers Sell Your Vehicle 
 Home Search Result Details Page Back to Home Could not find this vehicle. 
 news&amp;features Industry News Rumours&amp;Scoops Events 

 vehicles&amp;reviews Vehicles Reviews 

 guides maintenance how-to winter driving buying guide 

 videos used cars about contact us 

 contact and share join us on facebook follow us on twitter watch us on youTube 
 ©Copyright Metroland 2012 |  Metroland Media Group Ltd.  |  Corporate Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
