<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009232" url="http://restaurantmanagementa.truewealthguide.com/" time="2012-07-13-02:37" support="14" score="0.02099589990325834" bingtitle="Restaurant Management" webtitle="Restaurant Management">
			<query id="000142" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000516" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="000579" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="000590" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="000506" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="001250" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000767" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="001259" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000154" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000144" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000131" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="001272" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000779" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="001270" bing-rank="244"/>
	<description>... and duvets; mats, towels and flannels; items from restaurants, such as tablecloths, napkins ... need a resume to become the assistant manager of a fast food restaurant?</description>
	<body>
		Restaurant Management 
 
 Contact Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 Browsing: / Home Shortlink 
 Restaurant Management 
 By on May 22, 2012 in Restaurant Management 
Restaurant management is extremely demanding and high pressured. There are very few people who can do this job correctly. This does not mean that inappropriate people don&apos;t end up in the job now and again; the fact is though that the tough environment of a restaurant quickly weeds out the less able. To be a successful at restaurant management you need to have to have a particular skill set and many of these skills will be in relation to managing staff correctly.

If you want to be effective at restaurant management you must be able to deal with pressure without it causing you to become overwhelmed. If you get overtaking by events too easily then this can be a really poor example for your staff, and they are unlikely to have any faith in your judgement. Things will go wrong on almost every shift and sometimes it will all seem impossible to manage, but your role in restaurant management means that you treat all of these problems in a calm effective manner and back this with decisive action. You should be at your best when everything is going wrong, and you should have a reputation for thriving due to adversity.

Another important aspect of restaurant management is that you don&apos;t second guess yourself all the time. If you keep on changing your mind about things it will cause the staff to lose confidence in you, and possibly they may even begin undermining you. Of course it is good to question decisions and learn from them, but appearing indecisive to staff is not wise and will be seen as weakness. If you are successful at restaurant management your staff should almost begin to think that you always know what to do. It is also important that the decisions you make are viewed as fair and well thought out; if you continuously make unpopular decisions you will turn the staff against you.

Effective restaurant management is not only about being a boss; there should also be an element of respect for the individual employees. It is important that people are treated like people and not as a means to an end. If staff members have problems they should feel confident enough to be able to approach you and they should feel that you will treat them respectfully. It is also important that they are not afraid to offer constructive ideas and criticisms. Some old-school restaurant management involves ruling by fear, but this is no longer viewed as an effective management strategy.

The best managers are good examples for their employees. They will work harder than everyone else, and will approach their work with complete professionalism. The most skilled at restaurant management will know the business inside out; everything from cleaning the toilets to the prices for dishes. This ensures that they know what everyone should be doing, and they can deal with any eventually that arises. This is not to suggest that the manager needs to necessarily go clean the toilets, but they should understand what is needed to do this completely.
 
Frequently Asked Questions

 
 QUESTION: 
Restaurant Management?
I want to know about restaurant management. I want to know wich books can i read for getting a good information about risks involved and how to succeed in a restaurant business. Am opening it up in India.

 
 ANSWER: 
A great web site that just started for the food and beverage community has a lot of great information, and they seem to keep putting up more and more. http://www.foodandbeverageunderground.com
They have different sections for managers. owners, servers, wine and opening restaurants. I suggest getting all the free info you can before spending cash on books etc.

Good luck and cheers

Scott
 
 
 QUESTION: 
Anyone ever been in restaurant management and changed professions with the skills they already had?
I&apos;m thinking about changing professions, but I&apos;m looking for ideas and opinions about what I could get into after leaving restaurant management, WITHOUT having to go to college or more training. Anyone else ever been in restaurant management and changed to something else that was more fulfilling?

 
 ANSWER: 
yes, my dad did that. he handled a restaurant in the past and shifted to a marketing career. there were, of course, some difficulties and a lot of adjustments but he managed pretty well maybe because of his customer-orientation exposure. You might want to consider marketing, selling or customer service careers.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
What is the best way to sell Restaurant Management System in North America?
Hi,

Our company finish writing a software and decided to sell it on the market. It is a point of sale software design specifically for restaurant. However, I have no ideas where to find customer. I need people&apos;s insight on what can I do to reach people who will give me a chance to show them the product and tell how will this restaurant management software help them to grow their business.

Any comments is nice!

Thank you everyone in advanced

 
 ANSWER: 
You are going to run into a few barriers. First, there&apos;s lots of competition, and many of these have been around quite a while. And, your product is brand new with no credibility. Second, the economy is down, and this isn&apos;t a good time for the software industry.

You will need to find something that will disrupt the market. You will need to find a niche that others don&apos;t do or don&apos;t do very well. Maybe find some small restaurants and offer the product to them at a very big discount (or, free) in exchange for them providing testimonials.

Good luck ... this will be a huge challenge.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
assist me for a site where I can find stuff for restaurant management?
I want some sites where i can get solved my quarries regarding restaurant management.Iam planning to start soon.Iwant that all my work should be well managed.A layout for kitchen (restaurant multi-cuisine) is also required with equipments.All the resuilts should be basically Indian.

 
 ANSWER: 
www.bestrestaurant.com
www.fyc.com
www.acds-restaurant.com

good luck
 
 
 QUESTION: 
What is the best thesis topic of restaurant management?
am a MBA student and working in a restaurant. want to find a related MBA thesis topic of restaurant management. Please give your opinions!

 
 ANSWER: 
How about plan for success that can not fail!
 
 
 
 



 Share this on: Mixx Delicious Digg Facebook Twitter Shortlink 
 Restaurant Operation Management 
 By on May 21, 2012 in Restaurant Management 
Restaurant equipment and supplies are essential for successfully operating a restaurant business. Restaurant can work efficiently by stocking restaurant equipment and supplies to face every customer demand and is needed to prepare, store and serve food and beverages. Restaurant equipment and supplies comprises of products that are required for food preparation, preservation, storage and consumption. Restaurants require good management and adequate equipments and supplies to function competently. Restaurant supplies such as refrigerators, food processors, dishwashers and cutlery need to be maintained and repaired regularly. This will prevent sudden breakdown of equipment and help in smooth operation of the restaurant business.

Restaurants have a unique dAcor and furnishing that not only help them to maintain individuality but also attract customers with its unique style and elegance. It is important that all the equipment and supplies in a restaurant function to their full capacity. Restaurants purchase supplies for sanitation, maintenance, dinnerware and serving trolleys. Restaurant equipment includes heaters, food warming devices and storage units. Detailed training is imparted to the restaurant staff regarding maintenance of equipment and supplies so as to ensure longevity and productivity from these equipment and supplies.

During the start of restaurant business, one of the biggest expenses is of restaurant equipment and supplies. Choosing right and appropriate restaurant equipment and supplies is also a complex process since different kinds of restaurants require different things. The best place to start search for best restaurant equipment and supplies is to visit online shops on the Internet. One can check online equipment dealers that offer quality and affordable restaurant equipment and supplies.

Some of the restaurant equipment that one will need is bakery equipment, bar equipment, refrigeration, ice machines, steam equipment, coffee and tea equipment, service kitchen, ventilation equipment, dishwashers etc. It will mostly depend on the kind of restaurant and the budget one has for starting a restaurant business. Restaurant supplies that will be needed is kitchen supplies like cutting boards, mashers, measuring cups, measuring spoons, pan grates, peelers, tongs, and whips, bakery supplies, bar supplies, cookware sets, cutlery etc. Restaurant supplies are essential in preparing recipes and while serving dishes to customers.

Management of the restaurants regularly supervises available restaurant equipment and supplies. Daily analysis allows them to order sufficient equipment and supplies that are needed on a regular basis. There are strict policies and procedures in restaurants regarding the usage of equipment and supplies and it should be effectively implemented in order to generate profits for the restaurants.
 
Frequently Asked Questions

 
 QUESTION: 
Is there any quality literature about restaurant operations and management, particularly involving chains ?

 
 ANSWER: 
define quality and what is it you seek?

Each chain has literature for its managers and libraries have
books on management and on how to start and run restaurants.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
What recommendation would you give to th owner / management to further improve the operation of the restaurant?
Urgent answer pls. Tq

 
 ANSWER: 
Always serve FRESH food.
Keep everything extremely clean.
Have the help wear uniforms, even if they are casual: black pants, white shirt, for example.
Nothing replaces YOUR presence in the establishment.
Keep your help wanting MORE hours (they are less likely to report off)
 
 
 QUESTION: 
Why so many jobs on stores and restaurant management positions?
I noticed that when I look for a job on a website or get emails from Career Builders, Snag A Job, etc that there are so many stores and restaurants that are hiring for a management positions. What I want to know is why is it that they are hiring for that position and why people won&apos;t take advantage of that opportunity? Is it too much responsibilities to be in charge of the whole operation, is it the pay, or is it lack of experience?

 
 ANSWER: 
What&apos;s up Al. I believe it&apos;s a bit of all 3. Most of them pay qell but the responsibilty is inmense, therefore causing too much stress to even handle.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
Where can I download articles and other information regarding hotel and restaurant management,&amp;operations?
Kindly limit web addresses that provides articles and tips for free. Thank you.

 
 ANSWER: 
Search Google for this. These types of articles are all over the internet.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
What salary/benefits can one expect with a Hospitality Management degree?
I will be graduating from Virginia Tech next year with a B.A. in Hospitality Management (concentration in hotel and restaurant operations). What is my career outlook? What lifestyle can I expect? What entry level salary will be offered and can I negotiate for?

 
 ANSWER: 
I worked for ten years in the hotel industry (and my wife still does), and you can expect to have no life! You will enter as an assistant manager, and be expected to work every lousy shift imaginable.

Restaurant companies pay better than hotels (,000 v. ,000) and generally speaking the benefits are better as well (though still not that great). However, rooms division operations of a hotel (which was my area of expertise) is fun and intense.

Good luck!
 
 
 
 



 Share this on: Mixx Delicious Digg Facebook Twitter Shortlink 
 Supply Chain Management Restaurant 
 By on May 21, 2012 in Restaurant Management 
 Question 1: Push and Pull Supply Chain Strategies and Centralized vs decentralized strategies 

a) MBD should consider implementing a push-pull strategy. This is because the company is in such a position where it needs to inform other book retailers about the services that it offers hence the need for the push strategy. However, in order to curb demand uncertainty, the company could only be delivering the books that have been requested for by the retailers. (Harrison, Hau&amp;Neale, 2005)

In order to deal with the push aspect of their distribution strategies, the company ought to invest in a lot of advertisement to its retail booksellers. It also requires a forecast of long term issues affecting the company. On top of that, it would be necessary to examine all the past orders made by customers with regard to certain warehouses so as to understand how the demand patterns works. This would also mean that the company will require large production batches and large safety stock in order to meet client requirements.

However, in order to curb the negative effects of the push system, it will also be favorable to include the pull system. This is because the books delivered to specific book retailers will be the ones that are actually needed by them and what the company thinks should be sold. This aspect will require fewer inventories for the company. Additionally, MBD will need to spread their knowledge across other supply chain partners. This may require serious coordination levels but will eventually reduce the lead times that have been assigned to a specific book type.

b) MBD has the option of maintaining their intermediaries through the Distribution centers when tackling distribution to superstores. Additionally, they could choose to deliver the books to these superstores personally. While the distribution centers have been enhancing communication and encouraging greater flow of money, they have been rendered powerless by the power of the retailers. Most of these superstores are dictating terms to MBD thus minimizing their profit margins. In order to reduce the losses experienced by these companies in the specific area under consideration, it would be favorable for MBD to do direct selling where they can negotiate terms and curb extra expenses.

However, when dealing with the online stores, it would be favorable for the company to adopt a different distribution strategy. Since these companies usually assign MBD with the task of delivering goods to their clientele directly, then it would be favorable for the company to consider provision of certain wholesaling functions alone. In other words, in order to enhance efficiency, then it would be favorable to adopt a streamlined system for the production of most of their products.

c) MBD can benefit from changes in its distribution strategies by reducing the amount of lead time that the company needs to take in order to deliver books to their clientele. Additionally, the company will benefit from greater accuracy in their distributional approach because their work will be more coordinated. It would be plausible to consider changes in distribution because it can encourage greater returns to the company. Supply chains are just as important as any other aspect of production and if managed properly, they can lead to greater output levels. Lastly, changes in distribution can also cause lead to other non-financial benefits such as increased safety or better ergonomics. (IIMM, 2007)

d) Having fewer ware houses and greater centralization can add to the value offered by any given company due to the following reasons. First of all, it allows greater understanding of the logistics process thus allowing an identification of the strengths and weakness inherent in that particular company. Additionally, it allows a given company to control volumes present in its warehouses. This means that changes in inventory levels can be adequately monitored. This also implies that turn rates can also be assessed. Through these analyses, companies can then determine types of materials that are needed to meet client needs. (Gallagher, ODwyer&amp;Maher, 2000)

On the other hand, decentralization may also benefit the company because it allows greater customization of service provision. This is because there is a high degree of personalization by the company&apos;s representatives since logistical decisions do not have to pass through central logistics mangers or leaders alone.

 Logistics strategy 

a) Sometimes, internal logistics may be the best way to go for a company if supply chain management serves as a value additional point. If the latter part of production plays an important role in sustaining competitive advantage, then it would be wiser to stick to internal logistics.

In other scenarios, a company&apos;s internal capabilities may be sufficient enough to handle supply chain logistics. Consequently, the need to employ external parties may not be necessary. In other words, when the technology, infrastructure and core competencies within a certain company have not been surpassed, then it is advisable to continue utilizing internal logistics expertise. (Hamilton, 2008)

Sometimes, the culture within a specific company may not fall in line with that respective company&apos;s logistical strategies. This means that even if a company has assessed its logistics requirements and found that there is a need to employ external parties, prevailing organizational culture may make it impossible to do so and this may undermine the success of outsourcing. Consequently, such companies would rather stick to what they know best i.e. internal logistics expertise.

b) Acquiring a company with this expertise may also be another option owing to the fact that certain challenges or opportunities may occur within a given company thus heightening the need to consult with other categories or persons. Usually, this may be necessary when the firm under consideration has specialized in a certain logistical areas. One such example is a technological company. In order to optimize large supply chains, it may be necessary for respective companies to consider alternatives such as automation or the use of information technology. Such functions may eventually become part of supply chain management and will need to be constantly monitored by those respective providers. It would therefore be plausible to acquire such companies. By doing this, companies can deliver goods at a faster pace and a lower price.
 
Frequently Asked Questions

 
 QUESTION: 
Choosing a major in college
I am confused as to which field to get into.
i have 3 choices.

-Creative art&amp;Technology; animation, music production, commercials, advertising, music production, artist representation, animation, film&amp;TV production, film animation/special effects and etc.

- Business Administration- Business management, supply chain management, human resources management, hotel and restaurant management and etc.

-English- Communication (broadcast journalism)

Realistically, would it even be wise to go into the creative arts and technology field? i don&apos;t want to get stuck with a dead end major, where i wouldn&apos;t be able to find a job.

which one should i do? any advice? THANKS

 
 ANSWER: 
Why don&apos;t you do a double major. Choose one major that your really love or are interested in and another major in something you feel will lead to a good job opportunity.

I can see the Creative art&amp;Technology working very well with Business studies. You can then take jobs in marketing for instance.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
i need help with this assignment?
2.Club IT, Part Two
Over the last few months of your internship at Club IT, you have learned much about the nightclub business and have discovered opportunities for Club IT to improve its information technology capabilities. Ruben and Lisa have asked you to meet with them next week to provide an assessment of their current information systems and a recommendation for upgrading and improving their information management capabilities. You have some definite ideas on how IT could be improved at Club IT, and you also realize it takes thorough analysis and planning to be successful.
You have interviewed Ruben and the rest of the staff at Club IT and have compiled the following notes:
•Club IT’s customers are mostly net generation and millennials. They regularly use mobile technologies such as Blackberrys, PDAs, camera phones, and other wireless communication devices. Online shopping is a regular part of their lives.
•Few nightclubs have taken advantage of various e-commerce activities, and Ruben sees this as an opportunity to gain a competitive advantage in dealing with suppliers and guests. Ruben asks you to identify some new e-commerce technologies and applications to help build Club IT’s clientele and community, and to make their business processes more efficient.
•Currently, Club IT sells advance tickets to its special Friday and Saturday night concerts by phone or in person. Ruben wants to set up a Web site to sell tickets, so guests may have unlimited self-service access.
•Opportunities exist for streamlining the ordering process through B2B ecommerce. Sysco, for example, is a major restaurant supplier in North America, which has an extensive Web site (http://www.sysco.com/customer/order_entry.asp) with many online products and services for small and large food and beverage operations.
Using the information you have gathered from your review of the Club IT Web site and interviews with Ruben and the staff, evaluate the IT status of the business.
•Prepare a 700- to 1050-word essay identifying three business problems that you see at Club IT.
oEvaluate Club IT’s resources, customers, and supply chain.
oDefine three IT solutions to resolve the three problems.
oIncorporate enterprise resource planning (ERP), customer relationship management (CRM), and supply chain management (SCM) software into your solutions.
oDiscuss how the various departments within Club IT may use your solutions.
•Include an introduction and a conclusion, clearly identify three business problems, and provide detailed solutions for the three problems.

 
 ANSWER: 
Review your text and do an internet search for ERP, CRM and SCM. Explain the differences and how it can help the business. I explained a part of each and how they related to each other.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
HELP! Pls Tell Me What Would be a BETTER COURSE to take.?
I&apos;am an INDUSTRIAL ENGINEER MINOR IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY student and im planning to shift between being a PURE INDUSTRIAL ENGINEER or into BS INDUSTRIAL MANAGEMENT ENGINEERING MINOR IN SERVICE MANAGEMENT.

They are off the same courses except that when we get to our 4th year in college, some units might be taken in IE minor in service management that are not gonna be taken in pure IE.

In PURE INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING: We are going to Master our taken subjects from our 3rd year such as; Operations Research, Industrial Financial Management,Manufacturing Systems Engineering and a lot more. same goes for BS I.E. minor in SM... except that we would take some units that will cover our minor in service management, so instead of matering our previous taken subject.. we would have this:

Call Center Management (2 units)
This course discusses thoroughly the issues in call center operations. Appropriate IE tools to solve the problems in these areas will be discussed. The trends and studies done in these areas will be used as basis of discussion.

Banking and Financial Services Management (2 units)
This course covers banking operations and practices of different financial institutions. The emphasis of the course is more on operations and its products.

Food Service Management (2 units)
This course discusses in detail the issues in basic food creation, storage, and delivery. Discussions on the use of facilities planning tools and statistical tools will be covered.

Healthcare Management (2 units)
This course focuses on the problems currently faced in the area of health care management, which also covers public health care. The application of IE tools, such as methods improvement and optimization will be tackled in the context of these two services.

Retail Management (2 units)
This course discusses in detail the issues in financial service and food service management. Optimization tools that may be employed in these areas will be tackled.

Operations Planning and Control (3 units)
This course is an introduction to the concepts, quantitative techniques, and the decision-making process in the planning and control of production systems centering on demand forecasting, capacity planning, inventory management, material requirements planning, introduction to Just-in-Time concept, scheduling and aggregate planning.

CAREER OPTIONS:
Aside from being able to pursue a career as an Industrial Engineer, Operations Research Analyst, Inventory Control Analyst, Facilities Engineer, Ergonomics Auditor and Analyst, Methods Engineer, Production and Warehouse Managers, Production and Operations Manager, Quality Control Officers, Supply Chain Analyst, and Human Resource Officer, graduates of this program are to have a career or become entrepreneurs in Restaurant Services, Selling and Retail Operations, Call Center Operations, Health Care Management, Public Administration and Services, and Airport Operations Management

--YOU SEE, ITS THE SAME OPPORUNITY FOR BOTH SIDE, but i&apos;m not sure which course is better... haha! ) please HELP!

 
 ANSWER: 
Diversify what you are being exposed to in school. Take some foreign language, Art history or Math course. Just make it something outside the required flow of your curriculum.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
Help, I need a name and slogan for our new business.
The business is a website and professional consulting services for the food and beverage industry. The website is a portal type that is intended to connect everyone from suppliers (wine growers, farmer, pasta maker etc) to on trade distributors and customers such like restaurants, hotels, etc.

Our consultants are available to map and reengineering business process, create a technological infrastructure for the information exchange, create a legal infrastructure for the sale process, implement other services such like CRM or accounting.

The name should reflect the integratration the Food&amp;Beverage Supply chain process. I&apos;ve been coming up with names like:
Ambrosia Consulting
Grape Vine Solutions
Savory Technical Services
Grape Vine Network Consulting
Ambrosia Architecture Services
Culinary Matrix Solutions
Culinary Market Integration
Culinary Interlink Management
Linkedin Culinary Management
Cullinary Connections Interlink

But I am being told that &quot;Culinary Interlink Market&quot; and the other names sound nice but are probably too long (not immediate and difficult to remeber) it would be better to put all in a word.... may be missing some calrity something like: Culinarylink
My other concern now is to incorporate the concept of wine food and beverage not just food.
The word culinary is more related to food.

So Perhaps Epicure is a good word then, it is not limited to food and has good resonance among a particular class of aficionado of food and drink. Let me try out a few more on you:

Epicure Colaboration = Epicurlaboration (may be difficult to remember)

Interlinked Epicures

Epilink

Integrated Epicurean

Integrated Vines

Epicurean Harvest

I cant seem to find a word that is inclusive of everyone from growers to suppliers and buyers. Epicurean is about as close as I can get. Another thing that comes to mind is that much can be inferred with the logo that will accompany the company name. So the name may not need to bear the entire burden of conveying the depth of the services offered.

Your thoughts? help?

 
 ANSWER: 
FandBchain.com
grapeandgrain.com
 
 
 QUESTION: 
I need a name for our Business, and a slogan
The business is a website and professional consulting services for the food and beverage industry. The website is a portal type that is intended to connect everyone from suppliers (wine growers, farmer, pasta maker etc) to on trade distributors and customers such like restaurants, hotels, etc.

Our consultants are available to map and reengineering business process, create a technological infrastructure for the information exchange, create a legal infrastructure for the sale process, implement other services such like CRM or accounting.

The name should reflect the integratration the Food&amp;Beverage Supply chain process. I&apos;ve been coming up with names like:
Ambrosia Consulting
Grape Vine Solutions
Savory Technical Services
Grape Vine Network Consulting
Ambrosia Architecture Services
Culinary Matrix Solutions
Culinary Market Integration
Culinary Interlink Management
Linkedin Culinary Management
Cullinary Connections Interlink

But I am being told that &quot;Culinary Interlink Market&quot; and the other names sound nice but are probably too long (not immediate and difficult to remeber) it would be better to put all in a word.... may be missing some calrity something like: Culinarylink
My other concern now is to incorporate the concept of wine food and beverage not just food.
The word culinary is more related to food.

So Perhaps Epicure is a good word then, it is not limited to food and has good resonance among a particular class of aficionado of food and drink. Let me try out a few more on you:

Epicure Colaboration = Epicurlaboration (may be difficult to remember)

Interlinked Epicures

Epilink

Integrated Epicurean

Integrated Vines

Epicurean Harvest

I cant seem to find a word that is inclusive of everyone from growers to suppliers and buyers. Epicurean is about as close as I can get. Another thing that comes to mind is that much can be inferred with the logo that will accompany the company name. So the name may not need to bear the entire burden of conveying the depth of the services offered.

Your thoughts? help?

 
 ANSWER: 
&quot;Food-Link&quot;
&quot;Field to Table&quot;
&quot;Farm to Kitchen&quot;
&quot;Chef&amp;Farmer Network&quot;
&quot;Epicurion&quot;
&quot;Vine&amp;Branches&quot;
 
 
 
 



 Share this on: Mixx Delicious Digg Facebook Twitter Shortlink 
 Inventory Management Restaurant 
 By on May 20, 2012 in Restaurant Management 
Managing retail inventory is a huge responsibility and one that can have devastating repercussions if it&apos;s not done correctly. Managers everywhere report that inventory management is one of their biggest concerns. The truth of the matter is that it is a huge, tedious job that no one really likes to do. It is almost impossible for one person to manage and it&apos;s almost always necessary to delegate responsibilities in order to get the job done.

It may be surprising to find out that smaller retail stores and boutiques actually have a tougher time doing inventory than big department stores. This is generally because boutiques try to inventory everything at once with only one or two employees working on it. Department stores categorize everything, creating smaller and smaller categories, and then put one person in charge of a tiny section of the store. The employees are not overwhelmed and generally give an accurate count of the section that they are responsible for.

Boutiques and smaller retail stores should take the big department stores&apos; advice to heart. Delegate the responsibility by dividing your store into different categories and subcategories. Hire an inventory specialist team if you don&apos;t have the employees or the time to do it right.

If you are having your employees take responsibility for each section, offer a reward for accuracy. If you have managers and supervisors, you may want to have them go in behind the lower level employee and double check. If you warn the first person that their count will be checked, they are less likely to make mistakes.

Consider doing your inventory counts outside of your regular business hours so that there aren&apos;t customers there to distract the counters. This will also keep your boutique or retail store looking nice and neat when you&apos;re making that all-important first impression on your customers. You may need to motivate the employees to show up when it is normally their time off. Many companies make inventory count participation mandatory.

You can make it mandatory, but you may risk losing employees that have other obligations, other jobs, college classes, or trips that were planned in advance. Instead, consider offering rewards, like bonus money for participating. Play music, order pizza, and make it fun. You could give people with accurate counts longer breaks or lunches during business hours, or even a deeper discount on their next purchase.

Make sure that everyone has equal responsibilities. People that finish first should help you get the store back in order. Have them straighten the clothing racks so that the store is ready for opening time. A messy&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; onclick=&quot;javascript:_gaq.push([&apos;_trackPageview&apos;, &apos;/outgoing/article_exit_link/2636582&apos;]);&quot; href=&quot;http://onlygarmentracks.com/ecommerce/home/onlygarmentracks/&quot;title=&quot;Clothing Rack&quot;&gt;clothing rack&lt;/a&gt;or window display can make a bad impression and negatively impact the effort that was put forth to accomplish this task outside of your business hours.
 
Frequently Asked Questions

 
 QUESTION: 
QSR-POS: What are the base minimum requirement for a system to be considered a QSR enabled POS?
Quick Service Restaurant POS systems usually requires a lot of interactivity, reporting, and inventory management. What are the other possible features that are required for a QSR POS to succeed in the market?

 
 ANSWER: 
Inventory management is actually a third tier requirement. I would suggest some of the following to be extremely critical in a quick service restaurant environment:

- a bump-bar capability (the taco bell style screens that display what was ordered so that the food may be prepared) or at least the ability to print to a kitchen printer once the order is taken.

- If the restaurant has a drive-thru window, you need to be able to queue payment rather than expect payment at the time the order is complete.

- Easy and quick abilty to modify items (e.g. hold the tomoatoes).

- fast, internet based credit card authorizations

- employee scheduling / time clock

Hopefully this helps!
 
 
 QUESTION: 
I just started a new management job and I am overloaded with paper work?
This is near the end of my second week and I have really learned a lot but im really struggling with inventory.oh I can count everything and write it down but the paper work in the end where I have to deduct sales tax , calculate usage and all that I struggle with.My boss has tried to explain it but she is always in a hurry and I think Im going to have to learn on my own.She keeps saying she will come help me then she doesnt so I have to learn this kind of restaurant paperwork quick.I also have a bunch of computer work I have to do to but is there a site or anyone who can exsplain this to me .How long does it take most people to get ?Im giving it my all.

 
 ANSWER: 
Carefully and patiently explain to your supervisor that there is no way humanly possible for a person to learn the paperwork in such a short time. Assure her that once she trains you, you&apos;ll be much more efficient but you need the knowledge to do your job.

It was the paperwork that drove my husband away from his desk job. He was overwhelmed with it and ended up quitting for something he liked much better. You have to speak up for yourself or people will assume you&apos;ll eventually pick up what you&apos;re supposed to do. Good luck!
 
 
 QUESTION: 
iam a qualified hotel manager restaurent ,management , i need advice on immigration to canada ireland?
Muralbodi@gmail.com

91-9952266390

Objective : Seek Position of Restaurant manager

Summary :

Had been a part of the family business of managing a chain of restaurants with more than 15 years of great experience in the day to day management of a restaurant and its staff committed to profitability

Setting up a family held south Indian restaurant in the town of dindugal, planning project execution financial planning purchase of latest catering equipments and is now the leading restaurant down south Tamilnadu

Had been involved intensively in family held businesses cardamom plantation salt pans and prawn Hatcheries

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATION

Over 15 years of experience under the pioneer in restaurant field in south tamilnadu Mr.Chellappan (My Father)

Through Knowledge of all hotel operations

Excellent oral, written and training communication skills

Excellent customer relation’s skills especially in creating a stronger bond with the customers

Strong analytical skills including trend analysis and ability to develop new tactics to resolve problems

Excellent eye for details can identify and carry out actions to improve the appearance of the property and employees as well as establish a concrete action that binds the customer to the restaurant

Positive, energetic, offbeat approach to employee relations and customer complaints

Excellent computer skills

Removable ability to ensure proper selection training motivating and counseling of all employees

Notable ability to ensure professional positive employee attitude and attentiveness

A passion in Executing a mass out-door catering order

A workaholic, which had been inherited from the family

A passion a love to be in the field of restaurants

Disciplined to the core of towards worth and Business

Characterized to perfection morally and mentally

Operations Management

Developing and Implementing procedures control systems for maintaining hygiene&amp;quality standards as well as standard operating procedures leading efforts for streamlining process and generating cost savings in operations Managing out door catering schedules with constant tie-ups with major corporate and Implementing sales promotional strategies to increase sales volumes and achieving maximum customer satisfaction Ensure profitability of operations and supervise all aspects of kitchen management including menu – planning monitoring food production to ensure compliance with quality and Hygiene standards

Preparation 7 monitoring of food and beverages budgets and responsible for sales costs and inventory control as well as marketing and PR plans in coordination with sales team

Handling pre-opening opening to operation as well as preplanning accurate and comprehensive banquet event orders and resumes in a timely manner and distribute to all involved department

Professional Experience:

For 15 Years proprietor in 3 restaurants in the town of Bodinayakanur (All leased and sold as of march 2009)

Partner in a closely family held leading restaurant in dindugal

A Trend setter in out – door catering Implementing novel menus and have a passion and love to execute a mass out-door catering order.

Proven track record of developing procedures service standards and operational policies&amp;Implementing effective control measures to reduce/maintain running costly of unit

Experience in creating south Indian and north India recipes preparations of elaborate meals with proficiency in preparing producing a high quality food A Self motivated and consistent performers with proven track record of increasing revenue and streamlining workflow

Educational Qualification

Course in hotel management at the central institute of hotel management and catering technology – Taramani Chennai

Bachelors degree in commerce

Personal details

Date of Birth – 23.07.1970

Fathers Name : S.Chellppan

Sex – Male

Marital Status : Happily Married with a daughter aged 9 and son a 6

References: C.Rajkumar-( Brother)

Balajee Bhavan – Restaurant

Near bus stand, Dindugal.

S.Chellappan (father)

Balajee Bhavan –Restaurant

Near Bus stand, Dindugal.

Languages known –spoken English and Tamil

 
 ANSWER: 
By posting this on there, you are only setting yourself up to be contacted by scammers who will offer you a fake job and try to scam you out of visa fees. Please be careful

Your best bet would be to get a job in India with an international hotel group like Best Western, Intercontinental, etc then try to do an intercompany transfer to one of their hotels in Ireland or Canada
 
 
 QUESTION: 
Can I get College credit from life experience as a Restaurant Manager&amp;Training Manager?
I have had over 20 years of management in the restaurant field managing from 15 to 30 employees and also as a training manager for new hires into the Management field? Example of training, hiring and training of new hourly employees, Inventory, cash control, purchasing, Preventive Maintenance, P&amp;L&apos;s, OSHA standard, safety, sanatation, food handling procedures, daily, weekly, and monthly inventories, Public Relations etc. All aspects of what it takes to maintain and run properly a restaurant and minimize costs and increase profits.

 
 ANSWER: 
 
 
 QUESTION: 
HELP! Pls Tell Me What Would be a BETTER COURSE to take.?
I&apos;am an INDUSTRIAL ENGINEER MINOR IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY student and im planning to shift between being a PURE INDUSTRIAL ENGINEER or into BS INDUSTRIAL MANAGEMENT ENGINEERING MINOR IN SERVICE MANAGEMENT.

They are off the same courses except that when we get to our 4th year in college, some units might be taken in IE minor in service management that are not gonna be taken in pure IE.

In PURE INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING: We are going to Master our taken subjects from our 3rd year such as; Operations Research, Industrial Financial Management,Manufacturing Systems Engineering and a lot more. same goes for BS I.E. minor in SM... except that we would take some units that will cover our minor in service management, so instead of matering our previous taken subject.. we would have this:

Call Center Management (2 units)
This course discusses thoroughly the issues in call center operations. Appropriate IE tools to solve the problems in these areas will be discussed. The trends and studies done in these areas will be used as basis of discussion.

Banking and Financial Services Management (2 units)
This course covers banking operations and practices of different financial institutions. The emphasis of the course is more on operations and its products.

Food Service Management (2 units)
This course discusses in detail the issues in basic food creation, storage, and delivery. Discussions on the use of facilities planning tools and statistical tools will be covered.

Healthcare Management (2 units)
This course focuses on the problems currently faced in the area of health care management, which also covers public health care. The application of IE tools, such as methods improvement and optimization will be tackled in the context of these two services.

Retail Management (2 units)
This course discusses in detail the issues in financial service and food service management. Optimization tools that may be employed in these areas will be tackled.

Operations Planning and Control (3 units)
This course is an introduction to the concepts, quantitative techniques, and the decision-making process in the planning and control of production systems centering on demand forecasting, capacity planning, inventory management, material requirements planning, introduction to Just-in-Time concept, scheduling and aggregate planning.

CAREER OPTIONS:
Aside from being able to pursue a career as an Industrial Engineer, Operations Research Analyst, Inventory Control Analyst, Facilities Engineer, Ergonomics Auditor and Analyst, Methods Engineer, Production and Warehouse Managers, Production and Operations Manager, Quality Control Officers, Supply Chain Analyst, and Human Resource Officer, graduates of this program are to have a career or become entrepreneurs in Restaurant Services, Selling and Retail Operations, Call Center Operations, Health Care Management, Public Administration and Services, and Airport Operations Management

--YOU SEE, ITS THE SAME OPPORUNITY FOR BOTH SIDE, but i&apos;m not sure which course is better... haha! ) please HELP!

 
 ANSWER: 
Diversify what you are being exposed to in school. Take some foreign language, Art history or Math course. Just make it something outside the required flow of your curriculum.
 
 
 
 



 Share this on: Mixx Delicious Digg Facebook Twitter Shortlink 
 Restaurant Manager Assistant 
 By on May 20, 2012 in Restaurant Management 
Some restaurant businesses fail rather quickly within the first two years of operation. The restaurant owner may have failed to understand the keys to managing time efficiently and implementing strategic plans effectively. Without this keen understanding, a restaurant owner subsequently misuses business tools, such as form restaurant checklists and restaurant inventory sheets. Thus, business growth and productivity elude the unprepared restaurateur.

For the wise restaurateur like you, however, preparation begins with knowing the three keys to time management. Aside from that, you should know how to use business tools, such as as form restaurant checklists, which you can download free from helpful websites for restaurant owners and managers like you. With the aid of these planning and financial tools, restaurant management becomes a breeze.

 1. Understand How Your Business Works Inside and Out 

The first key to efficient time management is a deep understanding of your restaurant business. Managing a restaurant requires multitasking skills and interdisciplinary knowledge. This means that as a restaurant owner you need to understand not only how your business works, but also how each of your employees functions within your business.

The more you understand, the more you can do to improve your restaurant&apos;s numerous processes, such as food preparation, inventory control, and customer service management. With the use of as form restaurant checklists, you can eliminate unnecessary steps and delegate tasks for efficiency.
 
Frequently Asked Questions

 
 QUESTION: 
what is correct word of this position- Restaurant Assistant Manager or Restaurant Assistant to the Manager?
it&apos;s kinda confused arrange the word of this position. i will be the assistant manager of the restaurant in hotel. which word is correct? thanks for all answer.

 
 ANSWER: 
restaurant assistant manager
 
 
 QUESTION: 
Restaurant Floor Manager - What is the difference from assistant manager? Is &quot;Restaurant floor manager&quot; title?
Restaurant Floor Manager - What is the difference from assistant manager?
Is &quot;Restaurant floor manager&quot; title properly used in resume. What&apos;s below General Manager and above manager in restaurant job hierarchy.Thanks a lot

 
 ANSWER: 
Company will give title and job descriptions as they so choose. The Floor manager would be responsible for what happens on &quot;his&quot; floor. Assistant Manager as the title says is subordinate, that is an aid to the Manager - the person who is responsible for the workings of the establishment. Job description would vary per business.

I suppose it would be Assistant Manager to the General Manager. I doubt the Floor Manager would have an assistant.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
fast food restaurant assistant manager. what do you know about this position?
is a good one to have?
does being a single mother make a difference whether the job is still good or not?
What did you have to do?
Anything else u can share?

 
 ANSWER: 
Anyone can be an assistant manager. Even the dishwasher if the manager wants to appoint him/her to that position.

Basically, you&apos;ll be doing manager duties (ordering supplies and doing inventory control, hiring and firing, scheduling workers, etc), getting all the blame for anything that goes wrong, none of the praises if everything goes right, but will get paid a little more than the head cook.

You&apos;ll have to interview for the job and prepare a bunch of questions that you want answers to. But I think it would be a great way to learn the restaurant business and maybe in the future open your own.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
How do I convince my manager to promote me to the assistant manager position of the restaurant I work at?
I currently work at a corporation run restaurant. I started in the kitchen and within 8 months have learned things that people there years have never learned. I&apos;m the hardest worker and I&apos;ll be graduating college in under a year. The assistant general manager and the regional supervisor ABOVE the general manager of the restaurant are both on board with me becoming an assistant manager. However, the general manager of this restaurant is taking his time and is trying to make things seem fair because I&apos;ve advanced so quickly; even though I deserve it. I&apos;ve contemplated designing a written paper to my general manager voicing all of the opinions and facts that are surrounding every reason why I should be getting this promotion. Does anyone have any ideas for me? The restaurant is Vinny T&apos;s of Boston, if that helps anyone.

 
 ANSWER: 
Only thing I can say is keep bugging him about it. Continue doing a good job, and start asking about what exactly the managers do. Volunteer to learn how to do merchandise ordering for the restaurant, ask about how the IVR&apos;s doing (customer feedback), get involved with helping track labor and sales by the hour. All of this is requirements of a manager, and if they see you are taking initiative all these factors, you will be in the door.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
Franchised restaurant assistant manager age requirements?
I&apos;m 17 and I work at an Arby&apos;s that is not company owned but franchised, and they are trying to find a new assistant manager and I was wondering if anybody knows if there is a law stating that you HAVE to be at least 18.

A domino&apos;s I used to work at had an assistant manager that was only 17 so I&apos;m not sure.

PLEASE HELP!!!

 
 ANSWER: 
you must be at least 18 to slice roast beef and for that reason alone they probably won&apos;t have anyone under 18 as an assistant (because legally someone under 18 could not perform all the duties involved).

there are numerous other issues such as safe responsibility, asset protection, allowed hours of employment etcetera that make it impossible for someone under 18 to be an assistant manager, legally.

they have other management/supervisor positions such as a crew leader, front-line supervisor, shift supervisor etcetera (titles vary from one franchisee and company to another) but with these there will always be a more senior member of management also working during the shift.

in many states the law requires at least one employee/manager at any time be at least 18.
 
 
 
 



 Share this on: Mixx Delicious Digg Facebook Twitter Shortlink 
 0631 Restaurant And Food Service Managers 
 By on May 20, 2012 in Restaurant Management 
Restaurant POS provides exceptional food service management and marketing for establishments of all sizes; including: cafAs, sub shops, multi-store chains, bakeries, sub shops, delivery only, pizzerias, and more. This unique product provides computerized management and marketing that removes human error and increases the profit margin. Learn more about how this product can benefit your establishment.

Restaurant POS is an exceptional food service management and marketing software tool. This unique product provides revolutionizing business management for restaurants of all sizes including: pizzerias, sub shops, bakeries, cafAs, diners, cafeterias, and multi-store chains. This unique tool provides management of every aspect within the business providing smooth transactions without the complications created by human error. It generates an exceptional atmosphere where employees are able to flourish and customers are invited to return again and again. The staff benefits from the employee handbook, which is included in the restaurant POS system materials. This handbook provides unique training opportunities as employees learn to handle situations before they ever have an opportunity to occur. This pro active training provides exceptional customer care and alleviates many issues before they have an opportunity to break out and it is designed by management experts who specialize in the food industry. Quality service, wisdom, and a great attitude are taught in a way that can be caught by the employees. Catch your employees up into an atmosphere of enjoyment and professionalism. This work environment will prove to be conducive to exceptional customer care, products, and word-of-mouth.

The POS systems provide a remarkable marketing strategy as well as management strategy. This combined tool creates a smooth running business that simultaneously generates growth. Customers are invited through customer incentives to return to the establishment repeatedly. This generates a growth in return customers and ultimately creates word-of-mouth advertisement. Automated coupons are printed on the back of receipts, automated e-mails are sent, and automated birthday incentives are provided, through the customer appreciation/marketing plan provided through the point of sale. This concept is being utilized in franchise organizations and through the restaurant POS it can be utilized by you. It is proven to be seven times easier to maintain a customer than it is to obtain a new one. Why waste money on mass mailings that utilize snail mail, when you can utilize technology that will capture the attention of your customers. Customers appreciate this high-tech form of communicative invitations to receive discounts, bonuses, and specials. This is a powerful marketing tool that focuses on achieving a strong return customer base.

The restaurant POS is a comprehensive tool that provides both marketing and management tools. This affective package increases profit lines while providing payroll options, shift and employee hour organization, supply ordering, food supply management, fast credit card transactions, order and delivery organization, and more. The customized tool allows individuals to select which options will provide them with the results needed. The restaurant POS can be installed on pre existing equipment or it can arrive preinstalled on state-of-the-art, brand-new equipment. There are many reasons to choose this product some of them include: positive community attention, boosted employee morale, increased profit margin, reduced waste, customer incentives, and product ordering control. Provide a smooth running, customer pleasing, community known establishment through the use of the POS. Contact a specialist today to learn more about the many customized options available to meet your needs.

 



 Share this on: Mixx Delicious Digg Facebook Twitter Shortlink 
 Manager Restaurant Job Description 
 By on May 19, 2012 in Restaurant Management 
After the grueling years spent in school, the next thing one has to face is the proper choosing of his or her career. And it is important that one should be able to choose the right career for him or her because it is that career that would define his long-term status in life. This article aims to help you on how you could decide properly on which career you would pursue. But the basic thing here is that the career you would choose would somehow be related to the type of education you had during your schooling years. However, there are some who shift careers to different ones, even if that career is very new to them, because of lay-offs or job changes. But nevertheless, it would be an advantage for you if you are informed about the different descriptions of different careers or jobs. With this, you would be aware of what you have to do if you choose that career, and what is expected of you once you are on that career. Job descriptions not only help those who are looking for careers, but also the employers since these job descriptions could help them determine which functions their company would need. A typical job description would contain information such as career description, employers expectation, educational requirements, and more.

There are numerous careers to choose from but you could narrow them down to the ones that you are qualified for or to the ones you are capable of doing. You should be able to choose your career correctly because it would be a lifelong commitment that you have to maintain and make the best out of. It would greatly affect your life and the life of your family.

For most careers, a higher degree of education is preferred. They could demand you to have higher degrees of education or get certifications or gaining more experiences regarding that career. Other than that, your career would also require financial commitment. Your career choice would describe you and the type of lifestyle you expect.

To give you more ideas on careers, there are those which could be achieved easily because they only require certain trainings or college units. These careers even offer the training on the job itself. These careers cater to people who have not been able to achieve college education. Careers like lawn workers, cashiers, and fast food restaurant workers are among the list. Generally, they would provide low income at first but it would eventually increase as you get promoted with hard work and dedication.

There are also careers that would require a higher degree of educational attainment. These careers require specialization and extensive training before you could take on that career. These careers include being a physician, lawyer, accountant, and scientist. These careers would require you to spend a fair amount of time studying and training in college.

There are those careers that are not only financially rewarding, but emotionally rewarding as well. Law enforcers, medics, and fire fighters are careers that belong to this category.
 
Frequently Asked Questions

 
 QUESTION: 
what is the job description of a restaurant manager?
I would like to know the role of a restaurant manager

 
 ANSWER: 
know how to manage the restaurant
 
 
 QUESTION: 
Can anyone give me a job description of a restaurant manager?
How many hours, working conditions, earnings, etc.? And also if you&apos;re involved in this career could you tell me if you like it and any other opinions or advice on it? Thanks!

 
 ANSWER: 
Usually, they would decide the work schedules, oversee the upkeep of the restaurant, and do the books. If they are anything like my old boss, they will also lock themselves in the office and do coke for hours then come out screaming at everyone.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
I&apos;m an Assistant Manager at a restaurant and I&apos;m working on my resume and need help on my job description.?

 
 ANSWER: 
ok- what exactly do you do? Just write it down. Manage people...inventory control...process deposits..customer service. There is also a job description somewhere in a manual if this is a chain restaurant that can help also. Just write down all of your responsibilities.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
whats the job resposbilities of a statistical executive and statistics and logistics manager in a restaurant ?
wanted to know their job description also but these jobs are in hospitality industries.

 
 ANSWER: 
The link below should provide you with information regarding a statistician.

As for as what you are asking for in a restaurant, it sounds like you are describing a host/hostess or an event/party planner?

 
 
 
 QUESTION: 
With what actions do I wow a Hiring manager?
I applied for an assistant manager job and I am very serious about this job. The job description calls for food service experience or the equivalent, I have none of which.

However, the job did call for retail experience which I noted I have. I also have a college degree, an awesome reference who could speak very well on my customer service skills.

I wrote a cover letter where I showed how flexible I am and how I am willing to work long hours. I highlighted my degree and retail experience and my immediate availability. I pointed out only the positives of why I am the right canidate.

How much of an influence do you think having no food/ restaurant experience will hinder my chances? Do you think the positive will outweight the negative? What can I do to show how serious I am without going overboard. I plan to call this company on Tuesday to confirm they recieved my application and resume. What else could I say to gaurentee an interview and hopefully land the job?

 
 ANSWER: 
i would study their menu / company information.

the description states food service exp OR equivalent.

i think customer service would be equivalent.

consider if you might have any food service experience through volunteer work ? did you ever volunteer to plan a church picnic ? wedding for a freind ? cocktail party for a business ? company luncheon ? home parties / entertaining ? do not look at anything as negative ... always see the positive and be able to show the positive . you are quick learner and you come to the interview well prepared.

i think you can&apos;t be too pushy or you will sound desperate. it&apos;s a fine line to balance. just be honest and say that you are really intersted in meeting them and can work around their schedule.
 
 
 


 Share this on: Mixx Delicious Digg Facebook Twitter Shortlink 
 Duties Of Assistant Manager In Restaurant 
 By on May 19, 2012 in Restaurant Management 
A number of job positions are available at Chili&apos;s, including servers and cooks. The application process is easy. Simply print out the application found online, fill it out and drop it off at your local Chili&apos;s location.

The first thing that will be asked of you is your personal information. You will need to fill in your social security number and provide a permanent address, as well as a current phone number. Ensure that this information is correct and up to date, otherwise representatives for Chili&apos;s will not be able to reach you and your application will be discarded. You will be required to provide proof of identity to work in the United States as well proof that you are legal age to serve alcohol.

Job Listings Click here
 
Frequently Asked Questions

 
 QUESTION: 
What are the duties of a shift manager or assistant manager in a restaurant?
What is generally the difference?
So if they don&apos;t run shifts at wendys what do they do?

 
 ANSWER: 
I manage a Wendys fast food Rest.
The difference for us is major.
Shifts: Are hourly employee that do not run lunch/dinner shifts alone)
AM: Responsible for cash, employees, property, speed of service, plus they are salaried employees that work 50 hrs. a week (10 hr. days 5 days wk)
 
 
 QUESTION: 
Do you need a resume to become the assistant manager of a fast food restaurant?
I am moving to a slightly bigger city than the one I work in now. I&apos;ve been working at Subway for about six months. We are small enough that we have no assistant manager salary. Instead, my manager gave me assistant manager duties and said I could tell my next employer I was the A.M. When I move I need a job that pays approximately 8-10 dollars an hour and gives me about 35-40 hours a week.
Therefore I thought it would be ideal to become the real assistant manager of a Subway restaurant in the new city. But I don&apos;t know whether I should bring a resume with me when I apply.

What do you think?

 
 ANSWER: 
Oh , yes....you could bring not only a resume, but a cover letter as well. It doesn&apos;t matter the job yu apply for, as long as you really want it, bring those two because it is professional. They make the difference and you do want that difference to be made, right?

http://www.cvtips.com/cover_letter_advice.html
 
 
 QUESTION: 
I want this mail is scam or original...please help me....?
I had forwarded mail from my friend there is job at Genesco company....the following is the mail...

Dear Applicants,

This is to inform you that there is a job vacancy in Genesco Company. Place of vacancy is located in, LONDON, USA, EUROPE AND ASIA and Resort in the big city of UNITED KINGDOM LABOUR CONSULTANT: RECRUITMENT AGENCY: CONTINENTAL RECRUITMENT We have employment opportunities in all Hospitality and Catering positions. We are manufacturers of cloths, electronics, footwares, etc. we need to fill up all the positions with experienced and qualified candidates.

1. Business Manager
2. Asst Manager
3. Marketing/Manager/Asst
4. Landscape Engineer
5. Public Relations/Manager/Asst
6. Chef De Parties
7. Executive Sours Chef / Chef De Cuisine
8. Souse Chef
9. Banquet Sales Executive / Manager
10. Front Desk Supervisor

11. F&amp;B Manager
12. Customer Relation Officer
13.. Housekeeping Executive / Assistant
14. Team Leader Manager/Asst
15. Front Office / Guest Relations Executive / Manager
16. Travel Desk Manager
17. Loddy / Duty Manager
18. Asst Manager/F&amp;B
19. Head / VP / GM-F&amp;B
20. Head / VP / GM / National Manager - Sales

21. Operation Manager
22. Head / VP / GM-Accounts
23. Health Cloud Assistant / Manager
24. Junior Relationship Manager
25. Electric/electronic Engineers
26. Office Administration/ Manager
27. Business Analyst
28. Sales and Marketing Manager/Assistant
29. Assistant Restaurant Manager
30. Finance Manager

31. HR Operations Manager
32. Senior Relationship Manager
33. Executive / Master Chef

If you are interested to start up employment where a nice monthly salary, accommodation, free insurances, free staff private car and many more benefits will be use in making your months/years a very wonderful experiences in the field of Hospitality and Catering.

DETAILS:
GENESCO RECRUITMENT INC: with the mandate to recruit expatriate services employees&apos; for the fulfillment of the requirements of GENESCO COMPANY; &quot;Hospitality FLARING PROJECT in LONDON, seek to write your consent after recommendation from our labour consultants (based on recent expatriate vacancies with our client.

Kindly send in your Current CV/Resume and application letter stating the particular position where you will like to take up in this GENESCO COMPANY.

CONTRACT DURATION:
Level 1: 12 Months, (One Year) and renewable only on satisfactory performance by employee.Level 2: Full time Interested candidates must have not less than 2 or 4 years experience in any of the above listed fields. Interested candidates should forward their resumes/CV with verifiable reference(s) as word attached document to:

E-Mail: genesco_recruitment@mail2recruiter.com
website: www.genesco.com
Contact Person: Mr. James Gulmi.

Best Wishes.
Director/Chief Recruiter.
JOB RECRUITMENT/CAREER DEPARTMENT
GENESCO COMPANY LONDON
2-24 Kensington High St | London W8 4PT

 
 ANSWER: 
You can tell its spam because of the informal language and bad grammar used. The whole e-mail has quite a poor structure and this is just not the way companies go about recruiting people.

Also, the domain of the contact email would be &quot;genesco.com&quot; or similar and not &quot;mail2recruiter.com&quot; - which is a free e-mail service often used by scammers.

Its best to forward the e-mail to the company.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
Manager playing favorites, fear of losing my job, etc!?
I work in a restaurant and I have a GM and 3 Assistant managers. My duties as the Administrative Assistant are being given to this girl that everyone thinks he is sleeping with and she is getting paid more an hour. He also is great friends with this other girl who he has known for 7 years. He lets them 2(they are just servers)do whatever they want,&amp;he even gives manager duties&amp;my duties to them&amp;doesn&apos;t even tell us he&apos;s doing it. The one girl that we think he is sleeping with pretty much screws with people and gets them fired. She is gunning for my job as well. My manager is really rude to all the employees&amp;even other managers except for those 2 girls. He tells them &quot;Good job, Thank You&quot;&amp;all the rest of us get nothing. I am supposed to have an office key,&amp;I don&apos;t but she does(for what?). I have no idea what to do. I talked to some corporate trainers and they said I should go to my OD, who is above my GM. I&apos;m afraid it will backfire&amp;the situation will get worse. HELP!!!
A problem also is that in the big scheme of things (IE handling food cost and other restaurant quotas) he does a good job, so it worries me that even though he is a skeez, my OD won&apos;t want to risk losing him as a GM because he performs in certain areas.

 
 ANSWER: 
Start searching for another job, and quite gracefully. That is a very toxic work enviornment. Plus, you want a god reference and its never good to burn bridges even though these people are obviously unprofessional, rotten and no good to work for!
Sadly, this is happening in so many work enviornments. I work for the federal government, and we have these types of problems. If there is someone over their heads, I would speak with them, even if you are scared. We had a human resources rep come to our work and do an investigation. They interview EVERYONE in confidence so the truth may come out! If nothing happens, then leave this place in the dust before you lose your job for no good reason.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
Manager playing favorites, fear of job security, etc!!!?
I work in a restaurant and I have a GM and 3 Assistant managers. My duties as the Administrative Assistant are being given to this girl that everyone thinks he is sleeping with and she is getting paid more an hour. He also is great friends with this other girl who he has known for 7 years. He lets them 2(they are just servers)do whatever they want,&amp;he even gives manager duties&amp;my duties to them&amp;doesn&apos;t even tell us he&apos;s doing it. The one girl that we think he is sleeping with pretty much screws with people and gets them fired. She is gunning for my job as well. My manager is really rude to all the employees&amp;even other managers except for those 2 girls. He tells them &quot;Good job, Thank You&quot;&amp;all the rest of us get nothing. I am supposed to have an office key,&amp;I don&apos;t but she does(for what?). I have no idea what to do. I talked to some corporate trainers and they said I should go to my OD, who is above my GM. I&apos;m afraid it will backfire&amp;the situation will get worse. HELP!!!

 
 ANSWER: 
The best thing to do is to write every incident down with dates and exactly what happened who was there that witnessed it and so on.

I would then contact an employment lawyer in your area and tell them of your intentions of raising questions about your GM and that you suspect you will be fired.

They will probably give you some technical advise during a consultation--- of what or how to bring it to the OD or corporate trainers attention) and if you do get fired you have everything written down and the consultation of lawyer(s) before that fact...

You will probably have a great case that these lawyers would love to take.

Especially if others have also been fired and this restaurant is a chain or has ($$$$$$$) and I suspect since you have corporate that they have $$$$.

The lawyers will love you.

DON&apos;T say a word to your Job or anyone at corporate that you have consulted with lawyers.

Good luck--Get em&apos; girl!
 
 
 


 Share this on: Mixx Delicious Digg Facebook Twitter Shortlink 
 Restaurant Food Service Management 
 By on May 18, 2012 in Restaurant Management 
Often running a restaurant, eatery or catering operation comes down to simple routines and a well laid out manual and procedure. You might think its &apos;fun&quot; to run a &quot;management by crisis&quot; environment , however both customers , and clients may not appreciate it and when such a company in a service and hospitality industry its more than difficult to retain and attract good staff as well maintain good staffing ration and turnouts. Your local health department and inspector will certainly appreciate your attention to process and detail.

Nothing can take the place , in the whole scheme of your business plan, of your eatery or catering service of cleanliness and thoroughness to detail. It can be simply said that during the &quot;opening&quot; process and procedure that you are confirming that everything is up to snuff and &quot;Bristol shipping standards&quot;, and that your establishment or ready to prepare meals for the upcoming day , event or events. On the converse during the closing, you preserve and retain any products for the next shift or shifts in line. In the same vein you are ensuring that you are taking care of things - It only takes a crumb or two in the garbage for problems to start , and then you are at the mercy of your local pest control service. Once kitchen pests have infested your areas they are most difficult to eradicate. In the food services and hospitality industries prevention if key and first and foremost. Lastly you are making sure that all is neat and clean, that all surfaces are free of grease, dirt and grime for best appearances as well as for safety to avoid slips and spills on the next working shift or event, or hosted events

On finishing when it does to the other end of the setup - You can call the person in charge boss , supervisor or manager . Their role is to monitor and maintain the standards of your stated cleanup policy and procedures manual and staff manuals. Policies and procedures both for opening and closing have to be clearly written and expounded on paper. Assign a specific person to have the task of &quot;closing and opening&quot; supervisor. It is their stated responsibility and responsibilities that all stated procedures are followed to the letter and order. Simple as that.

Nothing takes the place of a well laid out series of steps for opening and closing routines and schedules in the operation of your food preparation organization - be it a restaurant, bar, eatery or caterer depends if not directly based upon the establishment, application and enforcement of clearly written and followed &quot;opening and closing &quot;procedures. .
 
Frequently Asked Questions

 
 QUESTION: 
Would I be able to get a job as a restaurant health inspector with a bachelors in food service management?
I am a college senior majoring in hospitality management with a concentration in restaurant/foodservice management with a couple years experience working in restaurants. This semester I am taking a sanitation course and getting servsafe certified and am thinking this is something I am really interested in and would enjoy doing. However with 1 semester left there is no way I would consider changing majors. Would this be something I could go into right after graduating (assuming they are hiring) or would I need to get some additional certification or work experience?

 
 ANSWER: 
You should be able to get a job like that. However there isn&apos;t very many restaurant health inspectors. I rural areas there might be one or two per county. In cities maybe 15 total.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
Book about food delivery service?
I need a good book about food delivery service. Or restaurant management with food delivery service. Or anything related with food delivery service.

Would be better if you can provide a download link. 

 
 ANSWER: 
All you need is a handle on state and city codes and a code deliver vehicle and commercial driver&apos;s license. Your health department codes need to be followed.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
What are the best colleges/universities in the US so far in the field of restaurant services / food serv.?
Please help me out with this. I did a search over some culinary art schools and they were quite good. But this is a totally different aspect of food management. Thanks a bunch to anyone who can help me with this question!! When I become the most renowned chef in my country I&apos;ll thank you once again heheee. (just kiddin though!)

 
 ANSWER: 
Probably the best &quot;school&quot; in this field is what used to be called &quot;the school of hard knocks&quot;....

That being said, there are many available, but depend a lot on what you want. If the kitchen is your goal, the culinary school is best. If service is the key a hospitality program. Check out Petersons.com or another school guide that rates programs, but also check out professional associations.

Make sure whatever program has a &quot;hands on&quot; component - internship, field experience...something that gains you experience and a network!
 
 
 QUESTION: 
What would be the best college degree for openeing a bakery?
Accounting/Business Management?
Business - General?
Business Administration/Management?
Business/Managerial Economics?
Entrepreneurial Studies?
Hospitality Administration/Management?
Restaurant/Food Services Management?
Small Business Administration?

or is there one I&apos;m not thinking of?

 
 ANSWER: 
I would do a management degree or small business. Look at the courses required and see which set you like better. You need to take accounting, management and economic classes.
 
 
 QUESTION: 
I am moving to Las Vegas in March, what kind of jobs are available besides food and bar service?
I will be 23, moving with a few friends. I have a background in food service and customer service and a year of salaried restaurant management. I know that all points back to food service but if there is anything else booming in the are I would like to try that out. Also any advice on any other aspect of Las Vegas would be appreciated.

 
 ANSWER: 
Good luck. There just aren&apos;t many jobs here. Have you been reading the paper or watching the news? Vegas has the highest unemployment in the nation. People continue to move here and soon find themselves stranded or finding ways to get out. Keep in mind you can&apos;t get unemployment if you can&apos;t find a job when you move here so when you money runs out how are you going to survive?
 
 
 
 



 Share this on: Mixx Delicious Digg Facebook Twitter Shortlink 
 Hotel Management Guide 
 By on May 18, 2012 in Restaurant Management 
The perception of visitors of an unspoiled environment underpins the tourism industry making environment protection one of the greatest challenges.

The tourism industry has an important role to play for management of environment.

 What is Environmental Management? 

The term &apos;environmental management&apos; not only means managing the environment but managing the interaction of human societies with the environment and its impact.

Thus, environmental management is not only for the sake of environment but it is for the sake of mankind.

 What does Environmental Management involve? 

Managing all components of the environment: biotic and aboitic is what Environmental Management involves.

Management of all the components of environment becomes necessary because of relationships between the species and their habitats.

 Why Environmental Management? 

Hotels and resorts all over the country consume large amounts of water, energy and other items. Lot of waste whether wastewater or solid waste is generated from hotels.

The reason why Environmental Management has become important is that it is a systematic approach to find practical ways or methods that can be used to save water, energy etc and reduce their negative impacts on environment.

A proper environmental management program can be a win-win situation as it helps to save money and preserve environment.

 Environmental Management: Win-Win situation 

Proper Environmental Management is a win-win situation for both you and your property. It helps to reduce operating costs and improves profitability.

Substantial cost savings can be done with a modest investment.

Apart from cost savings, environmental management guarantees that you will stand out from competition and will be recognized. Environmental Management helps you to get recognized through certification programs, awards and other promotions.

Other benefit is the image of your property gets enhanced with guests that are conscious about environment.

 Environmental Walk-Through is from where you should start 

The process of managing the environment and its components starts from An Environmental Walk-Through involving assessment of opportunities for improvement.

A walkthrough may be conducted by a single assessor or a team that inspects facilities and operations and identifies the key areas for environmental improvement.

 Steps towards Environmental Management 

The following steps when followed properly or kept in mind can make you save enormously:

 Adoption of an environmental policy Appointment of an environmental officer, Establishment of a team known as The Green Team, Establishment of a maintenance program, Adoption of practices that conserve the environment and minimize the production of waste Development of a monitoring program for utilities. 

 Environmental Management System 

To make your hotel environment friendly what is required is improvement of the facilities provided by the property and its equipments.

The effort required is to improve the standard of operating procedures and training and motivating the staff members for efficient use of resources.

The system that helps you achieve above goals is Environmental Management System.

Environmental Management System(EMS)can be said as a framework that helps the management to assign responsibilities, motivate the staff members, implement the best practices and monitor the performance as a whole.

Other activities included in the Environmental Management System include conducting meetings, training the staff members and monitoring and reporting progress.
 
Frequently Asked Questions

 
 QUESTION: 
i want to do post graduation in Hotel Management plz guide me..?
hello sir/madam,,
my name is Raman nath and i m from new delhi..right now i have complete my graduation B.A programe from delhi university and now i want to do post graduation in hotel management plz guide me where is the best college or institute for hotel management in delhi..plz give me also the website if u have.. and tell me that is it a better option for my future i want to do this becz i was never serious for my future but now i am and thats why i chose it becz i love to cook food and want to learn different idea of cook food.. i have a interest in cooking thats why i choose hotel management course.. plz guide plz plz
thanks and take care...

 
 ANSWER: 
 
 
 QUESTION: 
HI FRIENDS, my friend is going to singapore for education in hotel management, can any one help or guide him ?
he doesn&apos;t know anyone in singapore, and is coming from india to singapore.
As a YAHOO ANSWERS memeber i ask all of you to guide or support him those who live in singapore or have any attachment with singapore.

hope you all will guide him, because you all are my GOOD FRIENDS.

please let me know, if you are really intrested to guide him.

thank you

 
 ANSWER: 
I&apos;ll be visiting Singapore too this May for vacation. Hope I would be able to meet some Yahoo! Answers members there too. ;]
 
 
 QUESTION: 
i wana pursue higher studies in hotel management in abroad.please guide me through it.?
iam a 2nd year student in B.R Ambedkar institute of hotel management,chandigarh.

 
 ANSWER: 
Some of the best hotel management programs in the USA are found at these universities:

Cornell University (New York)
New York University
The George Washington University (DC)
University of New Orleans
University of Central Florida (Orlando)
University of Houston

Check these universities and their hotel management programs, and decide which is the best for you. For more information about studying abroad, visit http://www.macquil.com
 
 
 QUESTION: 
could anyone guide me how can i do hotel management from oberoi hotel ?

 
 ANSWER: 
There is no such course in a hotel but you can get a job in Obroi Hotel by getting Hotel Management Degree from a reputed institute in various states of India .

pl contact

HOTEL MANAGEMENT - Other Courses And Institutes
List of Institutions In India

Institute Affiliated to NATIONAL COUNCIL FOR HOTEL MANAGEMENT&amp;CATERING TECHNOLOGY - NCHMCT Website: www.nchmct.org

1.Institute of Hotel Management,Bhaijipura, Patia Adalaj, Kudasan, Gandhinagar –382 421 Tel.: 079-23276656/ 57 / 58 e-mail: ihmahd @vsnl.net

2.Institute of Hotel Management,S.J.Polytechnic Campus, Seshadri Road,Bangalore – 560001 Tel.: 080-22262960 Fax: 080-22268562 e-mail:ihm@vsnl. Com

3.Institute of Hotel Management,1100 Quarters, Near Academy of Administration,Bhopal – 462016 Tel.: 0755-2464397 Fax: 0755-2468046 e-mail: ihmbh@ sancharnet.in

4.Institute of Hotel Management, Veer Surendra Sai Nagar, Bhubaneswar – 751004 Tel.: 0674-2581864 Fax: 0674-2581241 e-mail: hospitalty @ihmbbs.org

5.Dr.Ambedkar Institute of Hotel Management, Sector 42 D, Chandigarh – 160036 Tel.: 0172-2604833 Fax: 0172-2611956 e-mail: ihmchd@sify. Com

6.Institute of Hotel Management, CIT Campus, TTTI-Tharamani, Chennai – 600113 Tel.: 044-22542029 Fax: 044-22541615

7.Institute of Hotel Management, Library Avenue, Pusa Complex, New Delhi – 110012 Tel.: 011-25842429 / 25840147 Fax: 011-25843177 e-mail: ihmpusa @rediffmail.com

8. Delhi Institute of Hotel Management, Behind Lady Sriram College, Lajpat Nagar IV, New Delhi – 110024 Tel.: 011-26435883 / 26422174 Fax: 011-26214812

9.Institute of Hotel Management, Dara Gaon, Tadong Gangtok – 737102 Tel.: 03592-270735 Fax: 03592-222707 e-mail : ihmgangtok@rediffmail .com

10. Institute of Hotel Management, Alto Porvorim, Bardez, Goa – 403521 Tel.: 0832-2417252 Fax: 0832-2417209 e-mail: ihmgoa @sancharnet.in

11. Institute of Hotel Management, Village Bariar, GT Road, Gurdaspur – 143521 Tel.: 01874-222501 Fax: 01874-222502 e-mail: ihmgsp @jla.vsnl.net.in

12. Institute of Hotel Management, G.S.Road, Bhangagarh, Guwahati – 781005 Tel.: 0361-2452273 E-Mail: ihmctanghy @hotmail .com

13. Institute of Hotel Management, Catering&amp;Applied Nutrition, Garhi Cantt. Near ONGC Helipad Dehradun-248001 Tel.: 0135-3257003 Fax:0135-2550271/2550272 E-Mail: ihm_ddn@hotmail .com

14. Institute of Hotel Management, Airport Road, Maharajpura PO, Gwalior – 474020 Tel.: 0751-2471477, 2471250 Fax: 0751-2471230 e-mail: ihmgwl@ sanchar net.in

15. Institute of Hotel Management, F’ Row, Durgabai Deshmukh Colony, Vidyanagar, Hyderabad – 500007 Tel.: 040-27427569 Fax: 040-27427898 e-mail: ihm hyderabad@ rediff mail.com

16. Institute of Hotel Management, Near Bani Park Police Station, Sikar Road, Jaipur – 302016 Tel.: 0141-2202812, 2200402 Fax: 0141-2200402 e-mail: ihmjpr-jp1 @sancharnet.in

17. Institute of Hotel Management, Govt. Polytechnic Campus, Jodhpur – 342001 Tel.: 0291-2616929, e-mail: sihm @rediff mail.com

18.Institute of Hotel Management, P-16, Taratola Road, Kolkata – 700088 Tel.: 033-24014218 / 24014353 Fax: 033-24014281 e-mail: ihmcal@ .vsnl.net.

19. Institute of Hotel Management, Seed Farm, Sector G, Aliganj, Lucknow – 226024 Tel.: 0522-2326772 Fax:2221776 e-mail: ihm@ sancharnet.in

20. Institute of Hotel Management, Veer Sawarkar Marg, Dadar (W), Mumbai – 400028 Tel.: 022-24457241 / 24457242 Fax: 022-24449779 e-mail: mumcat@vsnl. Com

21. Institute of Hotel Management, Near Ramashish Chowk Opp. State Circuit House Hazipur ,Vaishali (Bihar) Ph: 06224- 274937; 275354 Fax: 276486

22. Institute of Hotel Management, “Lumpyngad”, Bishop Cotton Road, Shillong – 793001 Tel.: 0364-2501616 e-mail: msootingl@ hotmail.com

23. Institute of Hotel Management, Kufri, Shimla – 171012 Tel.: 0177-2648322 Fax: 0177-2648208 e-mail: hmkufri @sancharnet.in

24. Institute of Hotel Management, Bouleward Road, Nehru Park, Srinagar – 190001 Tel.: 0194-2474828 Fax: 2474828 E-Mail: dnasa2001 @yahoo.com

25. Institute of Hotel Management, G.V.Raja Road, Kovalam PO, Thiruvananthapuram – 695527 Tel.: 0471-2480283 E-Mail : ihmctkov@ eth.net

26. Chandigarh Institute of Hotel Management Sector 42-D Chandigarh-160036 Tel.: 0172-2609472 Fax:0172-2610037/2662740 E-Mail: fcichd@hotmail .com Webasite : www.foodcraftchandigarh.com

27. SRM Institute of Hotel Management, SRM Nagar, Kattankulathur, Kancheepuram - 603203 Tamil Nadu Tel.: 044-27453147, 27453148 e-mail: srmihmnationalcouncil@yahoo.com

28. Institute of Hotel Management&amp;Catering Technology, 11, R.A. Lines, Dogra Mandir Lane, Meerut Cantt. (U.P.) Tel.: 0121-2643590, 2656096 e-mail: info@ihmmeerut.com

29. Shri Shakti College of Hotel Management, Venus Plaza, Adjacent to Airport Exit Road, Begumpet, Hyderabad – 500016 Tel.: 040-27908585, 27908787, 66906504 e-mail: sschm-hyd@eth.net Website: www.sschm.com

30. Oriental School of Hotel Management, Valley View, Lakkidi P.O. - 673576 Vythiri Taluk, Wayand (Kerala
 
 
 QUESTION: 
I want to be a chef.I am going to be opt for B.Sc(hotel management).Is it right option?please guide me.?
I am student of 12 standard.I love cooking. I want to be a chef.i am opt for B.SC .Is it right option?please guide me

 
 ANSWER: 
YES U R CHOOSING THE RIGHT OPTION.I THINK ITS THE RIGHT ONE FOR U.
 
 
 
 



 Share this on: Mixx Delicious Digg Facebook Twitter 1 2 ... 78 Next»
	</body>
</document>
