<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009631" url="http://wirral.askalo.co.uk/tag/restaurants/" time="2012-07-13-03:02" support="3" score="0.01554252234795506" bingtitle="Restaurants Wirral - askalo™ tips" webtitle="Restaurants Wirral - askalo™ tips">
			<query id="000096" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="001161" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="000658" bing-rank="125"/>
	<description>I don&apos;t like to wait for my food. I just like to order and start eating a few minutes after I order. Where is the best fast food restaurant ... I am looking for a place to ...</description>
	<body>
		restaurants Wirral
 Where is the best restaurant in Wirral? 
 I love going to the best restaurants in every city. What is the most popular restaurant overall in Wirral in terms of good tasting food, service, and cost? 
 0   Add Category: Dining Out Wirral Tags: restaurants best restaurant Where is the best place in Wirral to eat fast food? 
 I love fast food. I don&apos;t like to wait for my food. I just like to order and start eating a few minutes after I order. Where is the best fast food restaurant in Wirral? 
 0   Add Category: Dining Out Wirral Tags: restaurants fast food What is the healthiest restaurant in Wirral? 
 I prefer to eat healthy meals over meals that simply taste good which is why I am looking for a restaurant in Wirral that is well-known for providing healthy cuisine. 
 0   Add Category: Dining Out Wirral Tags: healthy dining restaurants I want to know where is the best place to eat Spanish food in Wirral? 
 I like Spanish food, especially tapas, so I am searching for the best Spanish restaurant in Wirral. 
 0   Add Category: Dining Out Wirral Tags: restaurants spanish food What is the best family restaurant in Wirral? 
 My family and I eat out often, and prefer to go to more family-oriented restaurants. Is there a most family-oriented restaurant in the Wirral area? 
 0   Add Category: Dining Out Wirral Tags: restaurants family restaurant Would you tell me please where is the best place to eat Chinese food in Wirral? 
 I am looking for a place to eat some good Chinese food in Wirral. Is there a particular place that makes really good chicken fried rice? 
 0   Add Category: Dining Out Wirral Tags: restaurants chinese food Where is the best place to eat Italian food in Wirral? 
 I love to eat different kinds of pasta, and would very much love to find a place in Wirral that serves great-tasting Italian food. 
 0   Add Category: Dining Out Wirral Tags: restaurants italian restaurants Do you know where is the most luxurious restaurant in Wirral? 
 The most expensive restaurants usually have the best quality and service, and I don&apos;t mind spending a good amount of money for a great tasting dish. I also always meet the most ... 
 0   Add Category: Dining Out Wirral Tags: restaurants luxurious restaurant Adjust your search 
 Search nearby 
 Wirral + 0 2 5 10 25 mi 
 Go! Category Going Out Beauty&amp;Wellness Education&amp;Care Services Shopping New in Town Sports&amp;Activities Tourism Everything Else Tags for Wirral accessories bank bars cars central Wirral clinics consultants discounts entertainment gifts home services Wirral hospital hotel imported lawyers nightclub restaurants school second-hand service shop sports store transportation travel      ... more Change location askalo Wirral Results 1 - 8 of 8 for restaurants in Wirral Sort by date Sort by distance 
 Fri 13 Jul 2012 02:02:11 Results 1 - 8 of 8 for restaurants in Wirral 
 askalo tips Check out the „ unanswered questions “ to find questions that haven&apos;t received an answer yet.

Show your knowledge and receive an award for being the first to answer questions! Ask a question for free about restaurants Wirral . Ask a Question 
 ( 0 ) | Help | | Change location | My askalo 
 Ask a Question Going Out Beauty Education Services Shopping New in Town Sports Tourism Everything Else &gt; Browse: unanswered | answered | popular Last viewed 
 Terms of Use Privacy Policy Blog Contact Spread the word Points&amp;Awards 


 Copyright © 2012 askalo ™ 

    sun3
	</body>
</document>
