<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009341" url="http://mopixie.com/flash-education-games/fast-food-restaurant-game/" time="2012-07-13-02:42" support="10" score="0.02726964799280833" bingtitle="Fast Food Restaurant | Play Fast Food Restaurant Games Online ..." webtitle="Fast Food Restaurant | Play   Fast Food Restaurant Games Online | Funtoosh Flash Games">
			<query id="000950" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000964" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000732" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000556" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000544" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000965" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="001358" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000953" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000922" bing-rank="49"/>
	<description>... You just graduated out of work in a fast-food restaurant to find a ... every seconds, there are so many customers to order ... Show off your number-one cleaning abilities by ...</description>
	<body>
		Home 
 Mopixie interested in buying game rights/source code. 
 Fast Food Restaurant Game - Play Fast Food Restaurant Flash Games Online 
 
 Action Games Adventure Games Board Games Coins Games Customize Games Dress-Up Games Driving Games Education Games Featured Games Fighting Games Other Games Premium Puzzles Games Rhythm Games Shooting Games Sports Games Strategy Games 
 Login to submit your scores Username: Password: Remember me Register for free! Play! 
 Fast Food Restaurant 
 Fast Food Restaurant Game 
 Fast Food Restaurant


Instructions
Use your mouse to play
Control Scheme:

 * movement: mouse


Game Control Scheme


Tags

 fast , food , restaurant 

Game Categories
 Education Games , Other Games , Puzzles Games 
More Games ... More Fun

Kids Who Played This Game Also Played

 Miami restaurant Welcome to Miami, the place where the sun is always shining! You have to help Rebecca with running her summer restaurant. Serve visitors, bring ordered food and drinks, earn money and upgrade the restaurant with new features after each level. Try to make your guests happy! Sit the visitor down at the table. Take visitor&apos;s order. Wait for food be prepared. Bring it to a visitor. Pick up money and clean the table after visitors. After each level you can buy upgrades for you and for your restaurant. Matching Dinner Mobile You just graduated out of work in a fast-food restaurant to find a waiter job. Not think that this restaurant crowds as Bay, business and more red, various forms of customer tap a wide variety of dishes, how can you quickly these meals dishes, accurate to all customers before it?

You work in a fast food shop. This fast food shop is so acclaime. In every seconds, there are so many customers to order a wide variety of dishes. Will you bring the dishes to all customers quickly and also accurately? Casual Western Restaurant Your friends will come your western restaurant today. You have to choose the best things to show. Putting the most beautiful flowers, table cloth and so on. The important is you should pick the delicous food and let&apos;s will be happy! Restless Restaurant You can have your own burger restaurant with Restless Restaurant. Don&apos;t let the customers wait too long or you will loose them! Undeath restaurant Help the undeath cheft to cook the horror food. Dolphin Restaurant Play this cute Dolphin Restaurant game. Serve underwater animal customers to make them happy. Decorate your Restaurant to make it more attractive. Fastfood Rapidly Mary is running a fastfood restaurant, the things she made is very delicious. More and more people like to order her fastfood. Today she is really very busy and has to need your help. Please help her now! Give her a fastfood rapidly. Mahjong Restaurant 2 Find the partners of each food. You can only delete it if you have the free right or left side. I really like this Mahjong. It has many levels. Humburger Restaurant Humburger Restaurant Diner Chef 2 The first restaurant was a big success. everyone loved the food and begged for more. of course, the diner chef responded to the public demand and opened a second restaurant. He is counting on your help! Castle Restaurant In this service game the castle hotel has been expanded with a fantastic restaurant, you can bring your customers to their table, take their order and prepare their dinner. By making money you can upgrade and make your restaurant the nicest one in town. In this game you can use mochi coins to buy special items and extra levels. Noodle Restaurant Run and manage your own noodle restaurant in compliance with noodles and make your customers happy. The Restaurant Manager After 4 years of hard studying, you become the manager of this Restaurant, you are the one to manage this spacial dinner place! Good Luck. Mahjong Restaurant you&apos;re in a restaurant. you must find a pair of each meal of a very special way. A mahjong. The instructions to find within the game. Very funny. Hayley restaurant design Hayley restaurant design Game. New Year Restaurant Have you ever tried New Year Restaurant Dresses? You would be really gentle, comfortable and stylish in this Dresses for this season. 
Try out these dresses in this collection then you believe in my words Colors Restaurant Have you ever tried Colors Restaurant Dresses? You would be really gentle, comfortable and stylish in this Dresses for this season. 
Try out these dresses in this collection then you believe in my words. Burger XXL Restaurant You are responsible for the best burger in town. Serve the customers as fast as possible. Each day that passes you have more customers you have to respond faster. Chef Boy Dressup Cooking in a restaurant is an all different way of cooking, there is art, when you own or work in a restaurant, you should take care of everything, from the food, to the way you serve, and to the way the waiter and the chef boy are dress up. So in this game you will have to take care of their dresses, make sure you pick the right clothes for your chefs! Pretty Restaurant Girl Having a dinner in a seaside restaurant is a nice thing. There are not only many delicious dishes but the charming seascape. It&apos;s so attractive. Let&apos;s go to experience this life. Remember you are the focus all the time. Dress up please, you will give us a big surprise,won&apos;t you? My First Restaurant My First Restaurant Matching Dinner You just graduated out of work in a restaurant to find a waiter job. Not think that this restaurant crowds as Bay, business and more red, various forms of customer tap a wide variety of dishes, how can you quickly these meals dishes, accurate to all customers before it?

You work in a restaurant! This restaurant is so acclaime. In every seconds, there are so many customers to order a wide variety of dishes. Will you bring the dishes to all customers quickly and also accurately? Fast Food Services Ever try to dress Fast Food Services? You are so gentle and comfortable to wear stylish dress is this season. Then you believe me, try this dress from this collection. Fast Food Word Search Can you find all the yummy fast food words in this free word search puzzle game. Pizza Restaurant feed the people! Japanese Restaurant Japanese Cuisine Sushi Restaurant Sushi Restaurants Restaurant 2012 Restauran 2012 Fast Food Kitchen In the hustle and bustle of the fast-food world, it&apos;s easy to get behind in your cleaning duties. Show off your number-one cleaning abilities by whipping this kitchen to tip-top shape in less than a minute. Your coworkers will thank you for it, and maybe they&apos;ll take your shift, so you can go to that concert on Friday! Jennifer Rose: Restaurant Love Jennifer Rose is in love with her boyfriend and she always tries to spend her time with him. But Jenny has to work in the restaurant and she almost has no time for paying attention to her friend when he visits her at work. Moreover, the manager of the restaurant and the chief are always trying to catch Jennifer flirting with her boyfriend. Baby Sakura Restaurant 3 Baby Sakura Restaurant Restaurant Business Your customers have a limited amount of patience, and taking too long to prepare orders means bad business. Get ready to serve customers foods and earn money! Seafood Lovers Do you love seafood? this time you run your own seafood restaurant, serve customers to become a successful seafood restaurant. Be a seafood lovers! :D The Waiter I–My New Job You&apos;re the new employer in the unfamous restaurant, so you should make the restaurant get famous, and you should finishing the goal too. if you not finish the goal in frequently time, you will got lose. enjoy this games. Box Versus Bear Dodge the bears. Protect the Burgers. A local fast food restaurant is constantly burglarized by bears for the burgers. The manager hangs the patty meat high from a tree to protect it. In response, the bears build a catapult with their engineering skills. Play as the box (more likely the manager controlling the rope) and dodge flung bears. Protect the burgers for as long as possible. Monkey Diner After 4 years of hard studying , you need a vacation. But your study was so expensive that you are out of money. You need to work in a restaurant to chaise your dream. Work yourself up in the restaurant business to earn more money for your vacation yingbaobao Restaurant 3 finding fault version This game is one of the series yingbaobao finding fault games, test your eyesight, all the two images to find out all the differences, the challenge to see it! Chef Girl Dress Up You had just opened a new restaurant, and you have some cute girls to serve and few other chef girls that works for you. What you will have to do is to dress them up, and make them look really beautiful in order to represent your restaurant as best as they can and make a good impression to the customers that will come here to eat. Enjoy! Finding fault Games (yingbaobao fast food) Test your eyesight, all of the 2 pictures of the differences, all to find out, come on Katpow Express Why should you go for an asian restaurant when you are able run one!Be it within the alley, kitchen, or front counter you have to be careful for the stock, burnt products or angry clients! Go ahead and take helm of the beginning asian restaurant franchise and function many clients as possible, as quickly as you are able to! Time is money my buddies! and also the more income you receive, the closer you arrived at getting PI.M.P.! Have A Great Time! 
 Click here to cancel reply. 
Leave a Reply
 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 
 
 

 
 CAPTCHA Code * 
 
 
 
Link This Game

It would be nice of you if you link back to us and show your appreciation - we will show ours too!
 &lt;a href=&quot;http://mopixie.com/flash-education-games/fast-food-restaurant-game/&quot;title=&quot;Play Fast Food Restaurant Game&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fast Food Restaurant - Play Flash Games&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
Seasonal Games
 
 Zombie Games Christmas Games Coloring Games Cute Barbie Girl Games Fairy Games Football Games 
 
 Halloween Games Hidden Games Santa Games Snowman Games Valentine Games XMAS Games 
 
  SIGN UP FOR UPDATES 
 Email: 
 We respect your email privacy 
 
Share Mopixie Games with friends :)
 Play Mopixie Free Games on Facebook 
Become A Mopxie Fan
 
 Twitter Facebook Youtube Plurk Digg Livejournal 
 
 Multiply Tumblr Posterous Blogger Typepad Friendfeed 
 
Play Games on Facebook
 
Mopixie.com goes Mobile

 Mopixie Games for Android Mobiles ... go now !
 Mobile Games , http://m.mopixie.com/ . 
 
 
Newest Games

 Lee-Lee’s Quest 2 Monster Trucks Unleashed Flooded Village Wonderland Cosa Nostra Paraverse Pharaoh’s Second Life Trophiends Slush Invaders Monkey Go Happy Marathon 3 Catastrophic Construction 3! 
 
 
 
Top Flash Games

 Santa sleigh Santa and his naughty Papa&apos;s Burgeria Narnia 3 Dress Up Bloons Tower Defense 4 Mass Mayhem 2 Strategic Mayhem 2 Wrapping Gifts Paper Train Strategic Mayhem 2 
 
 
 Home Game Web Directory Contact Us Submit a Game linkus Sitemap Subscribe Flash Game Guides Resources 

 All flash games on Mopixie.com are copyrighted or trademarked by their respective owners or authors.
Copyright 2010-12 Mopixie.com, site of free flash game . All Rights Reserved. Sitemap 
MoPixie Site of Flash Games last updated July 12, 2012 @ 12:37 pm; This content last updated November 3, 2010 @ 7:08 pm
	</body>
</document>
