<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009141" url="http://www.couponcorner.net/book.html" time="2012-07-13-02:32" support="2" score="0.001449276339905146" bingtitle="Coupon Corner Column" webtitle="Coupon Corner Column">
			<query id="000435" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000186" bing-rank="151"/>
	<description>For less than the price of a meal at a fast food restaurant, you can learn tips to save money on your grocery bill. Purchase your copy of &quot;How to Receive Free Groceries&quot; ...</description>
	<body>
		Home 

  About 
 Book Daily Deals Fan Page 
 

  Columns 
 Feb. 17th 2010 March 10th 2010 March 31st 2010 April 7th 2010 April 14th 2010 
 

  Contact 
 
 home | contact 

 Coupon Corner Column 

&quot;Imagine Free Groceries In Your Shopping Cart.&quot;
 
About
 
 How to Receive Free Groceries Daily Deals Facebook Fan Page 
 
Sarah Holmes

Sarah Holmes is a stay-at-home mom in Mahomet, IL. She writes a weekly column for Central Illinois&apos; newspaper, The News Gazette. 
 
How to Receive Free Groceries
 
People love saving money on groceries, unfortunately, they&apos;ve found that clipping coupons, matching these to sales fliers and sending in rebates is too time consuming. With their patience wearing thin, people will&quot;give in&quot;and pay the full retail price to maintain their sanity, reaching for their favorite convenient foods too -- often already prepared food which are steeper in price.

Sarah Holmes, Coupon Corner columnist and former publisher of Freebie Coupon Corner Newsletter, faced the same challenges, and she sought a solution. Now in How to Receive Free Groceries, Holmes provides information to help make your grocery budget go farther without all the hassle and the fuss. Kiss your coupon clipping days good-bye and welcome in the savings.

For less than the price of a meal at a fast food restaurant, you can learn tips to save money on your grocery bill. Purchase your copy of &quot;How to Receive Free Groceries&quot; at Amazon today!
 home | contact | html | css |©2008 Sarah Holmes | Design by www.mitchinson.net | Layout Design is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License
	</body>
</document>
