<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009512" url="http://www.propagandamatrix.com/articles/june2008/260608Madison.htm" time="2012-07-13-02:53" support="2" score="0.0014332980942593316" bingtitle="Mike Ivey: Should Madison ban the drive-through?" webtitle="Mike Ivey: Should Madison ban the drive-through?">
			<query id="000549" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000581" bing-rank="235"/>
	<description>... coffee shop or stand-alone fast food restaurant (www ... help our fight against the New World Order by giving a ... pay securely by either credit card ...</description>
	<body>
		(Advertisement) 

 

 
 News 
 Front Page Advertise Forum Newsgroup News 
 Sources Link 
 To Us Contact Donate Newsletter 
 
 
 

 
 


 
 
 Web PM 
 
 
 
 
 Web PM 
 
 
 
 
 Web PM 
 
 
 

 

 

 
 


   
 Mike Ivey: Should Madison ban the 
 drive-through? 
 Mike Ivey
 The Capital Times 
Thursday, June 26, 2008 

First it was a proposed ban on plastic bags.

Now, a member of the influential Madison Plan Commission wants to ban 
 the restaurant drive-through -- or at least restrict the ubiquitous symbol 
 of America&apos;s auto-centric lifestyle.

&quot;Given the concern about all the carbon going into the atmosphere, 
 I&apos;m not sure we should be building more places for people to sit idling 
 in their cars,&quot;says Eric Sundquist, who was appointed to the citizen 
 panel by Mayor Dave Cieslewicz this spring.

A former newspaper reporter in Atlanta now working as a researcher at 
 the UW-Madison&apos;s Center on Wisconsin Strategy, Sundquist notes that several 
 cities in Canada have recently moved to ban the drive-through coffee shop 
 or stand-alone fast food restaurant (www.ecospace.cc/culture/drive-thru-ban.htm).

&quot;Bans haven&apos;t gotten as far in the U.S., although I know San Luis 
 Obispo, Calif., has one,&quot;he says.

The issue came up last week during discussions over a conditional use 
 permit for a new Starbucks coffee shop along a congested frontage road 
 across from East Towne Mall.

The site at 4302 E. Washington Ave., in front of the Crowne Plaza Hotel, 
 formerly housed the Frame Workshop retail store but has been vacant for 
 more than a year. Property owner Tim Neitzel now wants to lease half of 
 the 3,300 square foot retail building for a Starbucks that will also feature 
 indoor and outdoor seating.

To facilitate the drive-through, developers are using a portion of the 
 Crowne Plaza parking lot. Drivers picking up their morning coffee will 
 have to make a circle route through the property to avoid potential traffic 
 backups.

But nearby business owners are concerned about bringing more cars through 
 the already congested intersection of East Washington and Continental 
 Lane. The owner of a gas station on the frontage road said it&apos;s not uncommon 
 for cars to wait through three traffic signal cycles to get across East 
 Washington.

East Towne area Ald. Joe Clausius admitted the intersection is a problem 
 and said with the Starbucks it&quot;could get very backed up.&quot;Still, 
 he said the corridor is badly in need of some redevelopment.

&quot;I&apos;m constantly getting peppered with questions from people about 
 what is happening there and when will it happen,&quot;he says.

City officials have given their lukewarm support to the Starbucks, which 
 is scheduled for a November opening. They say it could help create a more 
 pedestrian-friendly atmosphere near the Crowne Plaza.

&quot;While many future customers will likely be driving automobiles, 
 hotel guests and residents to the north represent a potential walking 
 customer,&quot;says city planner Heather Stouder.

Sundquist is planning to bring the issue up before the city&apos;s Long Range 
 Transportation Planning Commission on which he also serves.

&quot;I know a ban might be difficult so a better approach might be to 
 restrict them,&quot;he says, noting an ordinance in Davis, Calif., puts 
 a number of restrictions on drive-throughs, including one relating to 
 air pollution.

Middleton hotel

There are no signs of economic distress in Middleton, where developers 
 continue to pursue major projects.

The latest is from Central Place Real Estate, which is proposing an ambitious 
 redevelopment of the 3.9-acre former Prefinished Millwork site at the 
 southwest corner of University Avenue and the Beltline.

A concept plan submitted to the city of Middleton earlier this month 
 calls for demolishing the existing buildings and replacing them with a 
 six-story, 125-room hotel built over 32,000 square feet of retail space. 
 A three-story office building would anchor the other end of the project.

Parking would be provided in 130 underground spaces and 150 surface stalls.

Given the poor soil and water table conditions, developers have been 
 talking with the city about TIF assistance, according to Central Place 
 president Rob Zache.

Northgate update

The Madison-based Alexander Company is currently finalizing purchase 
 of the venerable Northgate Shopping Center on North Sherman Avenue, home 
 of Dorn Hardware and the Frugal Muse Bookstore, in addition to 19 other 
 tenants.

Currently owned by the Northgate Partnership, the property is assessed 
 at $4.1 million.

The purchase would be the first foray into Madison&apos;s north side for the 
 Alexander Company, which has specialized in urban infill redevelopment 
 projects.

Detailed plans for the center haven&apos;t been released but could include 
 building and site improvements, Randall Alexander told the Northside News 
 recently.
 
 Click 
 here to discuss this story in our forum 

 Print 
 Friendly Page Yahoo! MyWeb Del.icio.us Digg Reddit 
 Email This Page to: 
 
 Prison 
 Planet.tv: The Premier Multimedia Subscription Package: Download 
 and Share the Truth! 

 Please 
 help our fight against the New World Order by giving a donation. 
 As bandwidth costs increase, the only way we can stay online and 
 expand is with your support. Please consider giving a monthly 
 or one-off donation for whatever you can afford. You can pay securely 
 by either credit card or Paypal. Click 
 here to donate.

 FAIR 
 USE NOTICE
	</body>
</document>
