<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009250" url="http://www.loopnet.com/Connecticut_Restaurants-For-Lease/" time="2012-07-13-02:38" support="1" score="0.001408227464399398" bingtitle="Connecticut Restaurants For Lease on LoopNet.com" webtitle="Connecticut Restaurants For Lease on LoopNet.com">
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="127"/>
	<description>A well established convenience store, restaurant and deli that includes, gas pumps, all equipment, a one-bedroom apartment and is the only type of...</description>
	<body>
		For Sale For Lease Sales Comps Property Records Local Info Add Listing My LoopNet 
 My Listings Saved Searches&amp;Alerts My Watch List Saved Sales Comps My Profile My Account 
 
 
 #1 in Commercial Real Estate Online 
 
 Become a free member Help Log In 
 
 Connecticut Restaurants For Lease on LoopNet.com 

 Become a Free Member to Search the #1 Commercial Real Estate Marketplace Online 
 
Connecticut Restaurants for Lease and Rent. To View More Connecticut Lease Listings, Start a New Search.
 
 For Sale For Lease Sales Comps Property Records 
 All Property Types 
 All properties for sale Multifamily Office Industrial Retail Land Agricultural Hotel&amp;Motel Senior Housing Health Care Sport&amp;Entertainment Special Purpose Residential Income 

 All properties for lease Industrial Office Retail Land Special Purpose 

 All sales comps Multifamily Office Industrial Retail Land Agricultural Hotel&amp;Motel Senior Housing Health Care Sport&amp;Entertainment Special Purpose Residential Income 

 All property records Multifamily Office Industrial Retail Land Agricultural Hotel&amp;Motel Senior Housing Health Care Sport&amp;Entertainment Special Purpose Commercial Other 
 
You may enter a US or Canadian location in the following formats:

 Address, City, State Zip Code City, State State 

For additional search options, go to Advanced Search Advanced Search Advanced Search Advanced Search .
 Search Search Advanced search Advanced search Advanced search Advanced search Edit property subtypes Show property subtypes
	</body>
</document>
