<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009476" url="http://www.webstaurantstore.com/wna-comet-a18petdm-checkmate-18-clear-dome-lid-for-round-catering-trays-25-cs/625A18PETDM.html" time="2012-07-13-02:51" support="2" score="0.006907735774409079" bingtitle="WNA Comet A18PETDM Checkmate 18&quot; Clear Dome Lid for Round Catering ..." webtitle="WNA Comet A18PETDM Checkmate 18&quot; Clear Dome Lid for Round Catering Trays 25/CS">
			<query id="000949" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="001168" bing-rank="3"/>
	<description>See Companion Items for compatible catering trays. ... 2 Ply - 1000 / CS: 4&quot; Frilled Club Food Pick Assorted ... In order to offer you the best possible deal, we ask that ...</description>
	<body>
		Home My Account Food Service Help About Us Blog 
 
 
 
 Policies Help FAQs Track Order 
 
 

 
Your Shopping Cart:

Your Cart is Empty
 
 

 You are not currently logged in. 
 Login  |  Register 

Product Search
 
 
 
Browse by Category

 Restaurant Equipment Smallwares Storage / Transport Tabletop Disposables Furniture Ware Washing/Laundry Restaurant Dinnerware Consumables Janitorial Supplies Equipment Parts Customizable Supplies 

Browse by Business Type

 Bakery Supplies Bar Supplies Buffet Supplies Catering Supplies Coffee Shop Supplies Concession Supplies Cupcake Supplies Grocery / Deli Supplies Pizza Supplies Sandwich Shop Additional Businesses 

 

 

 

Or
 Live Support   
 

 
 
 
 
 We Securely Accept 
 for all your restaurant supply needs!

 
 
 The WEBstaurant Store  &gt;  Disposables  &gt;  Deli / Food Trays&amp;Lids  &gt;  Plastic Deli Trays and Catering Trays  &gt;  Plastic Deli/Catering Tray Lids  &gt;  WNA Comet A18PETDM Checkmate 18&quot; Clear Dome Lid for Round Catering Trays 25/CS 
 

 
 WNA Comet A18PETDM Checkmate 18&quot; Clear Dome Lid for Round Catering Trays 25/CS 
 

 0&quot; 0&quot; See Image Comment 
More images - rollover for full size- click to view larger image 

 
 
 
 
 

 | | 
 
 
 Easy locking tabs 
 
 Stackable 
 

 
Companion Items
 
Item Added to Cart

The following item is now in your cart.

 Item #: Quantity: 

 Close this window 
 
 WNA Comet A518PBL Caterline Casuals 18&quot; Round Catering Tray - Black 25 / CS $38.49/CS 
 
 WNA Comet A918BL 18&quot; Checkmate Round Catering Tray with High Edge - Black 25/CS $42.99/CS 
 
 WNA Comet A928BL Checkmate 18&quot; Round 6 Compartment Catering Tray - Black 25/CS $49.99/CS 
 

 
 18&quot; x 18&quot; x 5&quot; Insulated Nylon Deli Tray / Pizza Bag $13.99/EA 
 
 WNA Comet ADEEP518BL CaterLine Casuals Black 18&quot; Deep Tray/Platter 25 / Pack $43.99/Pack 
 
 WNA Comet ADEEP518BL CaterLine Casuals 18&quot; Deep Tray / Platter 5 / Pack $12.49/Pack 
 
 
 
 
 Details 
 
Highlight the freshness of prepared vegetable, fruit, or sandwich platters in your deli or market with the WNA Comet A18PETDM Checkmate round 18&quot; clear dome lid!

Made of PET plastic, the Checkmate 18&quot; dome lid also provides a sturdy, stackable surface for your catering trays, making transport to your next catered event simple.

Dual &quot;press-n-lift&quot; tabs allow you to easily attach and remove the lid without damaging the tray. The Checkmate clear dome lid has a height of 2 3/4&quot;. Sold 25 per case. See Companion Items for compatible catering trays.

 
 
 

 Buy 3 or more: $29.06 /CS Buy 2 or less: $30.99 /CS 
 
 Quantity: 
 
 
 
Customer Rating: 
 Our Item #: 625A18PETDM 
 Units: CS
Usually Ships 1 Business Day
 When will I receive my Item? 

Manufacturer&apos;s Item #:
 A18PETDM 

 
View all WNA Comet Plastic Deli/Catering Tray Lids 
 

 
 Customer Reviews 

 
These lids are an excellent product. They allow the customers to see the food before they open it, and also…
 Read More» 
These dome lids go great with the checkmate catering trays. They&apos;re tall enough that you can really pile product on…
 Read More» 

 see all user reviews» 
 
 Related items for WNA Comet A18PETDM Checkmate 18 inch Clear Dome Lid for Round Catering Trays 25/CS: 
 
 WNA Comet Classicware EcoSense Biodegradable Plastic Dinnerware Plastic Serving Utensils Hoffmaster 180544 Marina15&quot; x 17&quot; Paper Dinner Napkins
2 Ply - 1000 / CS 4&quot; Frilled Club Food Pick Assorted Colors 

 Sandwich Wrap Paper 
 
 Customers Who Purchased This Product Also Purchased: 
 
 WNA Comet A912BL Checkmate 12&quot; Round Catering Tray - Black 25/CS WNA Comet A928BL Checkmate 18&quot; Round 6 Compartment Catering Tray - Black 25/CS WNA Comet A918BL 18&quot; Checkmate Round Catering Tray with High Edge - Black 25/CS 320 oz. Black Plastic Bowl - 25/CS 

 Carlisle 10726 22 Qt. Clear Square Carlisle StorPlus Container Flairware Black 10 1/4&quot; Plastic Plate
144 / CS Silver Visions 7 1/2&quot; Heavy Weight Silver Plastic Knife 600 / Case Dart 60HT1 6&quot; x 6&quot; x 3&quot; White Foam Hinged Lid Container 500/CS 
 
 
 

Have you used this product?

Login to write your own review and earn $2.00!
 
Customer Reviews for WNA Comet A18PETDM Checkmate 18 inch Clear Dome Lid for Round Catering Trays 25/CS 

 Overall User Rating:   ( 4.8 stars from 5 reviews) 
 
 
 Rating By Allyson S. Posted on 03/30/12 

These lids are an excellent product. They allow the customers to see the food before they open it, and also hold in heat from the food. They securely click into their companion tray which makes them excellent for transporting. I highly recommend all this company&apos;s tray/lid products!!
 
 WNA Comet A18PETDM Checkmate 18&quot; Clear Dome Lid for Round Catering Trays 25/CS 
 
 Rating By Nancy M. Posted on 01/25/12 

I like the fact that this cover has two tabs to lock it onto the tray. It was also easy to take off the tray without damaging the cover. I wish the cover was an inch taller.
 
 WNA Comet A18PETDM Checkmate 18&quot; Clear Dome Lid for Round Catering Trays 25/CS 
 User Photos 
Tray and cover
 
 Rating By Michael R. Posted on 03/08/11 

These dome lids go great with the checkmate catering trays. They&apos;re tall enough that you can really pile product on the tray without worrying. The client was very impressed.
 
 WNA Comet A18PETDM Checkmate 18&quot; Clear Dome Lid for Round Catering Trays 25/CS 
 
 Rating By Lisa C. From Calliope&apos;s Po-Boy Posted on 11/11/10 

I used to order my trays from the local companies and they often broke on me. Yours is Awesome stuff and the price is great!
 
 WNA Comet A18PETDM Checkmate 18&quot; Clear Dome Lid for Round Catering Trays 25/CS 
 
 Rating By Anna R. Posted on 06/07/10 

This Comet Clear Dome Lid was ordered to accompany the Comet 18&quot; platter. Product arrived neatly packaged and fit the platter perfectly. The lid was easier to use than other products I have tried.
 
 WNA Comet A18PETDM Checkmate 18&quot; Clear Dome Lid for Round Catering Trays 25/CS 


 
 
Why don&apos;t we show the price for this item?

Some manufacturers do not like it when we sell their products below their required minimums. In order to offer you the best possible deal, we ask that you simply place the item in your shopping cart to see our great price!
 
Why don&apos;t we show the price for this item?

We can sell this product for less than we&apos;re allowed to advertise!
 
One of our friendly Customer Service reps will be happy to give you a lowest possible price for this item! Click here for live chat, or call 717-392-7472 Monday through Friday, 8 a.m. to 8 p.m. EST.
 
Click here for live chat, or call 717-392-7472 Monday through Friday, 8 a.m. to 8 p.m. EST.
 
Call 717-392-7472 (Monday - Friday, 8 AM - 8 PM EST)
 
 

 

 
 All Material Copyright©2003-2012 The WEBstaurant Store
Food Service Equipment and Supply Company
All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
