<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009291" url="http://www.solargains.co.uk/about-us.asp" time="2012-07-13-02:40" support="1" score="0.0003445346400301986" bingtitle="Solar Panel Birmingham | Solar Panel Installation Birmingham ..." webtitle="Solar Panel Birmingham | Solar Panel Installation Birmingham | Solar Panels Birmingham | Solargains">
			<query id="000623" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>In order for you the customer to benefit from the ... all aspects of Microgeneration services and products ... Green Approach To Fast Food Restaurant﻿ The owner of a Swindon ...</description>
	<body>
		Solar Gains 
 See how much you can save today! Reduce your fuels bills today with a green technology, call us on 0844 08 08 08 
 Home About Us 
 Existing Customers External Consumer Code 
 What is Solar PV? 
 What is Solar PV? Reasons to use Solar PV 
 Sectors Using 
 Domestic Commercial Farm&amp;Landowners Public Sectors 
 Other renewable energies 
 Air Source Heat Pumps Solar Thermal Collectors Rainwater Harvesting 
 Feed in tariff 
 Solar Calculator 
 FAQ&apos;s Case Studies News Contact us 
 
 About Us 
 
 About us Existing customers External consumer code 
       About our company&amp;our certifications As fully accredited suppliers and installers of Solar Panels Birmingham you have peace of mind for your Solar PV project from start to finish. Having built a reputation for exceptional customer service standards since the formation of the PASSWORD group in 1998 we are dedicated to delivering a customer focused service from survey; design through to final installation and maintenance service. Solargains is the renewable energy division of the PASSWORD group. We have several renewable energy working examples on site at our Head Office in Worcestershire for customer viewing, offering Solar Panel Installation Birmingham .

We supply and install a full range of domestic and commercial PV solar panels from market leading accredited manufacturers which can be installed in or on- roof, facade, flat roof or ground installation.

 Microgeneration Certification Scheme 
The Microgeneration Certification Scheme (MCS) is an independent scheme that certifies microgeneration products and installers for greater protection for the consumer. In order for you the customer to benefit from the Government approved feed in tariffs (FIT) you must use an MCS approved contractor.
We are accredited under the Microgeneration Certification Scheme (MCS) for Solar PV.

MCS has support from the Department of Energy and Climate Change industry and non-governmental groups as a prime method for making a substantial contribution to cutting the UK&apos;s dependency on fossil fuels and carbon dioxide emissions. It is the only scheme to cover all aspects of Microgeneration services and products, for solar panel Birmingham.   Would you like a free site visit&amp;quotation? 
 
   Mcdonalds Restaurant Swindon - 10-Apr-2012 Green Approach To Fast Food Restaurant﻿The owner of a Swindon franchise of McDonald’s, Mr Paul Booth, operates a truly green approach t... Read more on this article here Energy Performance Certificate - 9-Apr-2012 From the 01 April 2012 to 30 June 2012
All customers looking to install Solar Electricity will need to ensure their property has an Energy Performanc... Read more on this article here UK energy bills are likely to rise, say energy bosses - 8-Apr-2012 Bosses of the UK&apos;s leading energy companies have told a committee of MPs that bills are likely to rise in years to come. They told the Energy Committee t Read more on this article here next prev View our parent site: www.passwordservices.co.uk   View here In partnership with Solargains View here MdDonalds Endorsement 
Solargains helping the restaurant&apos;s impact on the environment. View here IWA BIZ Mitsubishi Electronic Approved Installer REAL Ecodan SOLARGAINS is a part of the Password Services Group 
 Home About Us What is Solar PV? Sectors using Other renewable energies 

 Feed in tariff FAQ&apos;s News Request a call back Contact us 

 Consumer code Site map Privacy Policy Accessibility Website Design Stourbridge - design bp
	</body>
</document>
