<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009182" url="http://blog.txreco.com/" time="2012-07-13-02:34" support="10" score="0.012110375798648645" bingtitle="Texas Real Estate &amp; Co." webtitle="Texas Real EstateCo.">
			<query id="000644" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="000640" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000635" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000018" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000379" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000566" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000651" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="000692" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="000643" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000255" bing-rank="87"/>
	<description>Most impressive are the condiments ... Pick your poison. Either way, just ... by a parking lot for 664 cars and additional retail spaces for a bank, fast-food restaurant and ...</description>
	<body>
		Texas Real Estate&amp;Co. 


 Search 
Main menu
 Skip to primary content Skip to secondary content 
 Home About Us Career Opportunities 
 
Post navigation
 ← Older posts 
 Washington Corridor Newsletter June 2012 Edition 
 Posted on June 18, 2012 by admin Reply 
 –What’s the buzz on the Washington Corridor? 

 Because we love real estate so much I could not pass on sending this article out to everyone. This month’s newsletter reports on something out of the Washington Corridor but because I am always intrigued by Houston’s History I just could not resist sharing this amazing house story. 

 I hope y’all like it as much as I did. 

Swankienda, indeed: 1957 time capsule house in historic Houston, first time on the market — 24 photos

 Wow, here is the latest notable time capsule house to come my way. It’s a gorgeous 1957 ranch house in Houston, listed by agent Robert Searcy , who gave me permission to use all of these great photos by TK Images Real Estate Photography . Thanks, also, to Yasmine , who tipped me off about this house — keep those tips coming, amazing readers!!! The photos were also just loaded on the MLS, so this time capsule loveliness is hot hot hot. Here’s how Robert describes this special home in the listing: 

 One of Glenbrook’s most important signature homes, custom-built in 1957 for local lumber barons Joseph&amp;Sadie Butera Montalbano. An amazing mid-century modern swankienda with lots of wow factor. Centered around a giant ROUND rotunda sunken living area with domed ceiling&amp;round double-sided flagstone fireplace in the center. Tons of gorgeous architectural details. Flagstone walls, zoomy vintage light fixtures, ultra-swank baths, sunken tub&amp;poured terrazzo. 

 In a followup email, he also told me: 
 
 Montalbano lumber is still in business. The Buteras had deli’s and grocery stores in town as well, so both names are known in Houston. According to their son Phillip, the house was designed by J.D. Dansby and cost $10,000 for the lot and $63,000 in additional construction costs at the time. The original owners kept it up until about 10 years ago, when it was sold privately to a neighbor. This is the first time it has been offered publicly for sale. 

 The tax rolls list it at 4,664 sq. ft. on one level. It has lots of great features like the liberal use of flagstone both in and out, a built in prayer shrine, which was a common feature in the custom Glenbrook Valley homes of the period since this was a heavily Italian-Catholic neighborhood originally. 3 bedrooms, 2.5 baths, inside utility, original turquoise counters in the kitchen, aquamarine tile in the master bath, waterfall cabinets with the original Lucite hardware in the hall bath. Poured terrazzo, of course the round rotunda living area with the domed ceiling and see through fireplace. 

 Glenbrook Valley was named a protected historic district last year. It is the largest locally designated post WWII historic district that we know of. 1250+ homes. It is Houston’s largest historic district of any kind. 
 
 First, I’ll give you a sneak peek at the spotlighted spaces. Left: A view to how the round living room works. That’s the entrance at about 11 o’clock. Front window at 9 o’clock, second seating area at 3 o’clock. Look at those feature divider walls — these are amazing, they all seem to be a little bit different…And, as Robert mentioned, that’s a double-sided flagstone fireplace in the center of the space. Another feature to note: The dropped ceiling above the entry way, to add intimacy and divide the space – nice. 

 Read the full article 

 Article from Retro Renovation 

 - YOUR Inner Loop Real Estate Team FEATURED LISTING!!!! 

 
 408 EICHWURZEL LN E 
 407 ASBURY
 
 1816 WOODBEND CREEK
 3 bedrooms, 2 full&amp;1 half bath
Property located within walking distance from New Metro, and within a couple minutes from Downtown!
Price reduced! Never lived in! 3 bedrooms, 3 full&amp;1 half bath
High quality stone and stucco home built by custon builder Keith Malloy!!
Home features high 12′ceilings, stone, marble and wood floors throughout.
 3 bedrooms, 2 full&amp;1 half bath
Beautiful open floor plan with hardwood floors, gourmet kitchen with breakfast nook and granite counterops
This home has the largest lot in the neighborhood with a nice size back yard For Sale: $235,000 
 MLS# 2090341 For Sale: $469,900 
 MLS# 12913411 For Sale: $224,900 
 MLS# 49099149 

 –Real Estate News 

 A new survey has confirmed what many in the local property market have been saying for years: A lot of Mexican nationals are in the market for homes in the Houston area. 

 In the last year, 39 percent of Houston-area real estate agents surveyed said they dealt with international clients, with people from Mexico making up the largest portion of shoppers from one country, according to the results of the 2012 International Real Estate Business Survey conducted by the Houston Association of Realtors . 

 The next largest group reportedly came from India, followed by the United Kingdom, China and Canada. More than 1,300 members of the local realty association participated in the survey, which was based on activity during the 12 months ending in April. 

 Houston’s real estate market has always attracted Mexican buyers. But their reasons for coming here have changed, said Mariana Saldaña , owner of Uptown Real Estate Group . 

 In the past, affluent Mexicans would buy high-rise condominiums to have a place to live when they came here to shop. 

 Now, amid increased levels of crime in their country, they’re coming to stay. 

 The Woodlands, a master-planned community north of Houston, seems to get the lion’s share of Mexican buyers, agents say. 

 “Last year, we sold 47 new homes in The Woodlands, and every one of them was to a Mexican client,”Saldaña said. 

 She said The Woodlands is popular because of its size and proximity to shopping, hospitals and Bush Intercontinental Airport . 

 Royal Oaks is another active neighborhood, she said, as is the Galleria area with all of its residential high-rises. 

 International business related to the energy industry, Texas Medical Center and Port of Houston also fuels property transactions involving foreign buyers, said Ward Arendt of Marilyn Arendt Properties. 

 Some coming here for short-term work stints, however, are renting. 

 “Unless they’re here longer than three years, it doesn’t make any sense for them to buy a house economically,”said Arendt, a past chairman for both the Houston Association of Realtors’ International Advisory Group and International Council of the Texas Association of Realtors . 

 Other highlights of the survey include: 

 1 Of the international clients looking for residential real estate, 79 percent want single-family homes, followed by 10 percent who are seeking residential leases. Townhouses, condominiums and resort properties were also of interest. 

 1 The majority of those who purchased properties spent between $100,000 and $400,000. 

 1 Of the respondents, 32 percent said clients bought homes with cash. In comparison, about 11 percent of domestic buyers in Houston paid cash, the association said, citing data from the National Association of Realtors . 

 Some respondents cited a lack of available financing for borrowers without U.S. credit history. 

 To a lesser extent, some said their buyers couldn’t find properties. 

 Saldaña recently represented a Mexican buyer who purchased in Tanglewood. He had been looking for a couple of years but couldn’t find the right house, so he decided to buy a lot and build. 

 Saldaña said“Mexican nationals want certain features that many homes here do not have.” 

 “They always want guest quarters,”she said.“They always want big dining rooms.” 

 They also want all their bedrooms, including the master, upstairs, she said:“They want to be together.” 

 Article from Chron.com By Nancy Sarnoff 
 
 As dedicated and experienced mortgage professionals, our goal is to assist as many homeowners as possible reach their dream of home ownership. Our company…ENVOY doesn’t simply offer some of the most competitive rates in the mortgage industry; we provide impeccable LOCAL service from start to close. We also provide borrowers with a hassle-free experience via the most technologically-advanced tools available, including electronic signatures (eSign by Envoy), digital documents, an online application process, secure online loan status updates (24/7), a fully electronic closing and most importantly, around the clock attention to your loan.

———————————————————————————————————————
 Posted in Washington Corridor Newsletter | Tagged corridor , newsletter , washington | Leave a reply 
 Washington Corridor Newsletter May 2012 Edition 
 Posted on May 15, 2012 by admin Reply 
 –What’s the buzz on the Washington Corridor? 

 Washington Corridor is home to The Beer Can House ( www.beercanhouse.org ) which is one of Houston’s landmarks. Creator, John Milkovisch, considered his work an enjoyable pastime rather than a work of art. This unique attraction is located at 222 Malone Street, between Memorial Drive and Washington Avenue and has been nestled away in the Rice Military neighborhood since 1968.

The house and landscape are adorned with many different types of beer cans that yes John, himself drank (thought his neighbors and his wife, Mary, were always glad to lend a hand). The Beer Can House was named BEST Landmark in 2010 by Click2Houston’s Best and was also featured in Ripley’s Believe It or Not.

The Washington Corridor is full of fun and intriguing destinations.

Article from http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beer_Can_House 
 
 
 
 Great Savings — Our rates are among the most competitive in the Texas Oncor Service Territory.
 Fixed-Rate Plans — Prefer to lock in a rate and budget your expenses?
 Month-to-Month Plans — Choose the flexibility and freedom of a variable price plan
 Green Plans — Our green plans are 100% renewable wind energy and are Green-e Energy™ Certified.

 Great Rewards 

 Enjoy two nights of hotel accommodations at one of more than 25 destinations as a welcome gift Accumulate points for travel rewards based on the energy you use each month Earn additional travel rewards by referring customers 

 Excellent Service 

 Bilingual Customer Care Center is based in Texas Satisfaction guarantee FREE switch in 4-7 business days Self-selected switch and move-in activations available at special rates 

 

 Contact
Stephanie Lang
for more info. 

 –YOUR Inner Loop Real Estate Team FEATURED LISTING!!!! 

 
 5652 PETTY ST 
 6507 MINOLA ST
 
 PATTERSON ST
 3 bedrooms, 3 full&amp;1 half bath 
 New Construction Home!! Will Sell Quickly! 
 Please call agent for additional information!! 3 bedrooms, 2 full 1 half bath 
 Beautiful Stucco Townhouse just blocks from Memorial Park!! 
 Granite Countertops, Fireplace, Hardwood Floors, High Ceilings, Good-Sized Backyard and Patio with Spa Pool!
 3 bedrooms, 3 full&amp;1 half bath 
 Not too late to customize or upgrade! Plans are subject to change 
 Spacious Master Bathroom with separate tub, shower and commode room For Sale: $299,900 
 MLS# 53758148 For Sale: $549,500 
 MLS# 1836235 For Sale: $279,000 
 MLS# 11255264 

 –Real Estate News 

The Federal Reserve and Mortgage Rates

Understanding What Causes Interest Rate Movement

 Consumers are often misled when it comes to the subject of the Federal Reserve and how it affects mortgage interest rates. Often the media is the culprit causing the confusion. Many times, the Fed has taken action that caused mortgage interest rates to move in a direction other than what consumers expected, because the media provided weak reporting on the subject.

The Federal Reserve affects short-term interest rate maturities, the Fed Funds rate, and the Overnight Lending rate. These factors have a direct impact on the Prime rate. If you took only this into consideration, you may mistakenly conclude that changes made by the Fed will cause a similar movement in mortgage interest rates. However, mortgage interest rates are dictated by the trading of mortgage-backed securities, which trade on a daily basis. The real dynamic at the heart of interest rate movement is the relationship between stocks and bonds.

Stocks and bonds compete for the same investment dollar on a daily basis. There is literally only so much money to be invested. When the Federal Reserve feels that interest rates need to be decreased in an effort to stimulate the economy, this reduction in rates can often cause a stock market rally. When the market becomes bullish, the money to invest in stocks comes from the selling of mortgage-backed securities.

Unfortunately, selling mortgage-backed securities to fuel stock market rallies causes interest rates to go up, not down.

Historically, there have been many times when the Federal Reserve has increased interest rates. Stocks then sell off in fear that the increase will affect corporate profit margins, and the liquidated stock assets need a place to park until the next rally comes along. The safe haven is found in mortgage-backed securities which cause mortgage rates to drop.

The daily ebb and flow of money is what matters most when it comes to the movement of mortgage interest rates. I make it a point to continuosly monitor interest rates for my clients, and advise them of opportunities to manage their mortgage debt at a better rate. This is the foundation of my business model as a Trusted Advisor.

 
———————————————————————————————————————
 Posted in Washington Corridor Newsletter | Tagged corridor , newsletter , washington | Leave a reply 
 Washington Corridor Newsletter April 2012 Edition 
 Posted on April 17, 2012 by admin Reply 
 –What’s the buzz on the Washington Corridor? 

Get Ready for a Studemont Kroger

 First the Washington/Heights Corridor was introduced to Target and many other successful franchises off Taylor.  Then it was the news about Wal-Mart coming into our neighborhood.  Now Kroger has purchased and started to develop a grocery store which is much needed in our area.  All the transition and change is transforming a once blighted area into a place we are all proud to call home.

 KROGER HAS bought 8.5 acres of former industrial land on Studemont, just south of I-10 , the Chronicle‘s Purva Patel reports. The land, which was once part of Houston’s Sixth Ward, sits just north of Arne’s Warehouse and Party Store and across the street from Grocers Supply. Kroger closed on the larger portion — a 7.2-acre cleared parcel at 1400 Studewood, listed for sale at $15.7 million — just last week. A spokesperson for the grocery chain wasn’t ready to announce a new store on the site, but did say the company had already taken possession of 1.3 acres just to the south, at 1200 Givens St. If Kroger does build a new supermarket there, the parking lot would have 450 ft. of frontage on Studemont; other industrial properties, many of them accessed from Summer St., would still be sandwiched between it and the Sawyer Heights Target.

Article from Swamplot 

Images: Wheless Properties 

 –YOUR Inner Loop Real Estate Team FEATURED LISTING!!!! 

 
 5652 PETTY ST 
 4122 A FLOYD ST
 
 PATTERSON ST
 3 bedrooms, 3 full&amp;1 half bath 
 New Construction Home!! Will Sell Quickly! 
 Please call agent for additional information!! 3 bedrooms, 3 full 1 half bath 
 Oversized kitchen with island and built in appliances 
 Large Master bedroom with fireplace. Master bath with double vanity and walk-in shower
 3 bedrooms, 3 full&amp;1 half bath 
 Not too late to customize or upgrade! Plans are subject to change 
 Spacious Master Bathroom with separate tub, shower and commode room For Sale: $299,900 
 MLS# 53758148 For Sale: $436,000 
 MLS# 20085100 For Sale: $279,000 
 MLS# 11255264 

 –Real Estate News 

 Shopping for the Right Mortgage

Finding a mortgage that’s right for you should be easy. But there are often many different programs to choose from, as well as a myriad of ways to structure the loan in terms of the amount, term, payment, rate, closing costs…the list of options may seem endless.

However, because there are so many options available, it’s important to seek advice from an experienced mortgage professional who has your best interest at heart. The first step in determining which program is right for you is to ask yourself the important questions listed below. These questions can also help you confirm that you’ve chosen the right mortgage professional as well, because he or she should be asking you the same questions before trying to put any mortgage in place:

 How long do you anticipate living in your home? Do you expect any changes over the next few years, such as expanding your family or having children go off to college or even move away? Do you expect any changes in income due to promotions, relocations, retirement, inheritance, or pensions? Are you expecting a change with regard to your investments? When it comes to investment strategies, are you conservative, aggressive, or somewhere in between? 

The reason these questions are so important is that different loan programs will offer specific benefits that will appeal to borrowers at different stages of life. What one homeowner might find desirable might cause another to reach for the Rolaids®.

In the end, be sure you are given a complete picture of exactly how much your mortgage will cost you over the period of time you anticipate having the loan in place. This is the single most important factor you should consider when shopping for a mortgage. Not only does this data illustrate the bigger picture of your financial goals, it allows for adjustments should things change a little sooner than expected. A good time frame for this projection is anywhere from three, five, or even up to seven years.

When shopping for a mortgage, you should always evaluate your choices carefully and consider how they will fit in with your long-term financial plan. Answer the important questions listed above and call me for a free consultation. Together, we’ll find the program that’s best for you.

 
———————————————————————————————————————
 Posted in Washington Corridor Newsletter | Tagged corridor , newsletter , washington | Leave a reply 
 Washington Corridor Newsletter March 2012 Edition 
 Posted on March 15, 2012 by admin Reply 
 –What’s the buzz on the Washington Corridor? 
 The experts seem to agree Houston’s economy is fueling up and getting stronger along with the Houston’s housing market. Many recent articles like the one cited below confirm the direction of the Houston’s housing market. Hey Readers … it should come as no surprise that the Washington Corridor is one of the submarkets in Houston that is experiencing product demand. I hope you enjoy the article as much as we did!! Buyers flocking to buy homes in some city neighborhoods 
 Houston, a seller’s market?

For John Mallon it was.

The Friday before the Super Bowl, he listed his 1950s-era updated ranch-style house in Spring Valley for $509,000. That Monday, he had a buyer.

 “I think we had a total of eight showings the first day,”said Mallon, who accepted an offer from a young couple.

Consider other examples.

A two-bedroom Crafstman-style bungalow in the Heights went on the market last Friday. On Saturday, a couple agreed to pay almost the full $425,000 asking price.

Properties in West University , the Memorial villages and Bellaire, too, are getting snapped up fast, agents say. Some sell at or close to asking price within days.

While it’s not true everywhere, in some parts of town“you better show up with a check,”said Evert Crawford , director of the Institute for Regional Forecasting at the University of Houston’s Hobby Center for Public Policy .

Homes can be slower to sell in outlying areas where older properties compete with newly built homes and foreclosures.

Crawford and others say inventory has fallen in some close-in areas and when something nice comes on the market, it can be a feeding frenzy.

“There are multiple offers because you’ve got five people looking for the same thing. It’s crazy,”said Holley Madden , the agent who listed Mallon’s home in Spring Valley.

During the housing downturn of the last several years, homeowners have been reluctant to put their properties on the market unless they had to. And new construction, which is starting to get active again, is still far from its peak.

 Some areas lagging 

The inventory of single-family homes dropped to its lowest level since December 2009, to 5.7 months, compared with 7.2 months a year earlier, according to new data from the Houston Association of Realtors . That means it would take 5.7 months to sell all the single-family homes on the market based on sales activity over the past year.

Experts consider six months of inventory to be a balanced market where neither the buyer nor seller has the upper hand.

In some areas, sellers clearly have an edge.

Months of inventory in January was down more than 25 percent in a number of close-in subdivisions, according to real-estate firm Greenwood King .

To be sure, the housing frenzy isn’t happening everywhere.
 It took Linda Gonzales a year to sell her 1,200-square-foot home in Pearland. She had to drop her $135,000 asking price by about 27 percent to sell the house, which is less than two miles from where she moved into a neighborhood with all new construction. Even in the Heights and other hot areas, a new listing doesn’t automatically mean a bidding war. How fast a house sells has a lot to do with its location and condition. The Heights bungalow that went“option pending”a day after it was listed has an architectural style buyers are looking for, said Melissa Kubala , the listing agent. “The house has to deliver,”she said. Mortgage rates low Crawford worries that other potential problems, such as rising gas prices or a new wave of foreclosures related to the ongoing mortgage-lending woes, could hinder the housing market’s recovery. But for now, low mortgage rates and a feeling that the overall economy is getting back on track are helping the market. “More and more people that were sitting on the sidelines are now beginning to get serious about buying,”Crawford said. Real-estate agents sold 3,049 single-family homes in January. That’s a 9.2 percent increase from a year earlier and the eighth consecutive monthly increase, according to the realty association, which tracks properties sold through the Multiple Listing Service . Prices were relatively flat. January’s single-family home median price–the figure at which half of the homes sold for more and half sold for less–inched up 0.9 percent year-over-year to $139,900. Article from: Chron.com by: Nancy Sarnoff Houston home, property sales build more momentum The volume of single-family home sales in the Houston area rose for a seventh consecutive month in December, and finished the year 4 percent higher than 2010. Statistics released Tuesday by the Houston Association of Realtors show that sales of 53,606 single-family homes were recorded through HAR’s multiple listing service in 2011, compared to 51,556 the prior year. Total property sales — including townhomes and condos — climbed 4.3 percent year over year, to 63,610 from 61,005. Total dollar volume increased 5.2 percent, to $13 million from $12.4 million. Still, the average price for single-family homes gained only 0.9 percent year over year, to $213,723 from $211,765 in 2010. “We spent a good part of the year struggling to accurately gauge the market because we were comparing to accelerated sales in 2010 that resulted from the homebuyer tax credit,” Wayne Stroman , HAR chairman, said in a statement. “Once we distanced ourselves from that period, we saw clear indications of a healthy market with a balanced supply of housing inventory and strong pricing conditions that put Houston in an enviable position compared to many housing markets around the country.” Looking at December’s sales activity, the median price for single-family homes — at $160,000 — reached an all-time high for a December in Houston. There was 5.8 months worth of inventory available for sale in December, which was the lowest level recorded in the last two years. That compares to 7.2 months of inventory nationwide. Meanwhile, foreclosure property sales reported in the multiple listing service increased 6.1 percent in December compared to December 2010. Just over 20 percent of all property sales in the Houston area in December were foreclosures, which had a median sales price of $82,500. Article From: Houston Business Journal by Jennifer Dawson, Reporter 
What is OurBlok Rewards?

 ”A thousand Loyalty Programs rolled into one simple card..” 

OurBlok Rewards is a loyalty rewards concept rolled out to empower consumers, support local causes and encourage consumer patronage to small-to-medium sized businesses. How do we do this? It all starts with the recognition of some very basic needs: 

 Consumers need to save 

 Merchants need business from consumers. Non-profits&amp;causes need charitable support.. 

The OurBlok Rewards card facilitates the exchange of these basic needs in a number of ways:
 Help merchants offer immediate rewards&amp;incentives to new consumers. 
 Help merchants provide continued rewards for their most loyal customers. Help merchants support local causes that consumers care about. Consolidating several of efforts into one rewards card for the consumer 

 There is no longer a need to carry around dozens of loyalty rewards cards. 
“…The best way for merchants to say‘thanks’, without breaking the bank…”

It’s the best way for merchants to say“thanks”, without breaking the bank. As a matter of fact, with OurBlok Rewards, ROI is 100% track-able! Consumers gain the benefit of knowing they can passively support local causes and non-profits simply by shopping at the places that they love the most. They can see in real time the who, what, where and when of their card’s activity online. They can see the immediate rewards coming their way to shop new businesses and the accumulated amount of loyalty rewards that they’ve earned at their favorite places.
These rewards can be redeemed at ANY TIME. Finally, local causes and non-profits gain the much-needed continued support that they need to keep doing work for the greater community.

OurBlok is a socially conscious organization that above all recognizes the individual need to know we are doing good things in the world. OurBlok Rewards is a program that allows us to fulfill this need while rewarding ourselves at the same time.

OurBlok Rewards: Giving has never felt so much like receiving…

 –YOUR Inner Loop Real Estate Team FEATURED LISTING!!!! 

 
 6507 MINOLA ST 
 4122 A FLOYD ST
 
 1816 WOODBEND GREEK
 3 bedrooms, 3 full&amp;1 half bath 
 Beautiful stucco townhouse just blocks from Memorial Park!! 
 Hardwood floors, high ceilings, good-sized backyard and patio with spa pool! 3 bedrooms, 3 full 1 half bath 
 Oversized kitchen with island and built in appliances 
 Large Master bedroom with fireplace. Master bath with double vanity and walk-in shower for two!! 14 foot long Master walk-in closet! 3 bedrooms, 2 full&amp;1 half bath 
 This home has the largest lot in the neighborhood with a nice size back yard 
 Beautiful open floor plan with hardwood floors, gourmet kitchen with breakfast nook, granite counterops,undermount sink, and gas range For Sale: $579,500 
 MLS# 1836235 For Sale: $436,000 
 MLS# 20085100 For Sale: $234,900 
 MLS# 49099149 

 –Real Estate News 

 How Much Money Should You Borrow? 

 While it might be tempting to borrow whatever amount of money your lender is willing to give you, it’s important to think carefully about how much you’ll actually need to borrow in order to purchase a new home. From the down payment to taxes to insurance and interest rates, there are many factors to consider when making this important, life-changing decision.

Contrary to popular sentiment, there is no standard formula for accurately calculating the specific dollar amount you should borrow when purchasing a new home. Many websites do offer special borrower calculators that claim to factor in important variables, and yet final results vary vastly from one site to the next. Other websites offer general rules of thumb, suggesting that you should never borrow more than 2 1/2 to 3 times your gross annual income, or that 28%, 32%, or even 40% is the maximum amount of debt you should ever take on.

And, while these insights may be helpful as you begin thinking about the overall borrowing process, meeting with a reputable loan professional and getting yourself pre-approved (not pre-qualified) is really the only way to know the exact amount of money you can and should borrow. By getting pre-approved, you not only increase the chance of finding the perfect house for your needs, you also become a“cash buyer”, instantly increasing your bargaining power.

As a mortgage professional, I see my role differently than a traditional loan officer. While my job is to match you with the best mortgage available for your specific needs, I feel that it’s also my duty to make sure it’s the most responsible product as well. After all, what if something unforeseen or unexpected were to occur? What if you have an accident or you lose your job?

Whether you choose to work with me or not, be aware. A lender will often offer you the maximum amount of money that you qualify for, whether you actually need the full amount or not. Because of this, it’s vital to sit down with a professional you can trust to figure out your complete financial picture.

If you or someone you know could benefit from this type of free consultation, give me a call. I would be happy to assist you!
 
——————————————————————————————————————— 
 Posted in Washington Corridor Newsletter | Tagged corridor , newsletter , washington | Leave a reply 
 Washington Corridor Newsletter February 2012 Edition 
 Posted on February 17, 2012 by admin Reply 
 –What’s the buzz on the Washington Corridor? 

On June 29, Houston City Council designated three new City of Houston historic districts. As you may have heard there was a lot of controversy about these historic district designations.

I personally believe a landowner should be able to choose to preserve the property they own, or not. For example, builders typically opted to build new construction in the Heights because the buyers demanded larger homes with larger bedrooms and closets. These new designations will most likely lead to less investments by the builders in historic districts because they are accustomed to new construction and not remodeling and expansions. With that said I always try to make the best out of every situation or outcome.

 
Once a Classic,

Always a Classic!!
 YES, New Construction is Popular and in Demand. BUT, Remodels are also Desired by Many and Can be VERY Profitable for Builders As Well! 

After all … the bones of old homes can teach us Houston’s history, tell us important stories and remind us of where we all came from.

City Council creates 3 new historic districts

 On June 29, Houston City Council designated three new City of Houston historic districts: Glenbrook Valley, Heights South and Woodland Heights. A majority of homeowners in each of these neighborhoods signed and submitted petitions requesting the district designations.

 Glenbrook Valley becomes the only City of Houston historic district outside of Loop 610. The southeast Houston neighborhood is on the west side of the Gulf Freeway and contains an extensive collection of Mid-Century Modern homes, including distinctive houses built for the 1956 Parade of Homes.

 Heights South Historic District is south of 11th Street and east of Yale Street in Houston Heights. Woodland Heights Historic District is on the north and south sides of Bayland Street on the west side of Houston Avenue. Historic houses in these two new districts date primarily from the first decades of the 20th century and include a variety of traditional styles.

Congratulations to the homeowners who worked so diligently so that their neighborhoods could share the benefits and protections of historic district designation.

Thanks to Mayor Annise Parker , District H Council Member Ed Gonzalez and District I Council Member James Rodriguez , whose Council districts include the new historic districts, and all of the City Council members who voted to accept the homeowners’ requests and designated the three new districts.

Thanks also to the members of Greater Houston Preservation Alliance as well as the members of Houston Mod , the Historic Districts Coalition and local members of the National Trust for Historic Preservation and Preservation Texas who contacted their Council members in support of the new historic districts.

 City Council votes 

 Glenbrook Valley Historic District 

FOR: Mayor Annise Parker, District A Brenda Stardig, District D Wanda Adams, District E Mike Sullivan, District F Al Hoang, District H Ed Gonzales, District I James Rodriguez, At Large 1 Stephen Costello, At Large 2 Sue Lovell, At Large 3 Melissa Noriega

AGAINST: District C Anne Clutterbuck, District G Oliver Pennington, At Large 4 Brad Bradford, At Large 5 Jolanda Jones.

 Heights South Historic District 

FOR: Parker, Stardig, Adams, Hoang, Gonzales, Rodriguez, Costello, Lovell, Noriega

AGAINST: Clutterbuck, Sullivan, Pennington, Bradford, Jones

 Woodland Heights Historic District 

FOR: Parker, Stardig, Adams, Hoang, Gonzales, Rodriguez, Costello, Lovell, Noriega

AGAINST: Clutterbuck, Sullivan, Pennington, Bradford, Jones

District B Council Member Jarvis Johnson was absent.

 From left, Woodland Heights Historic District, Glenbrook Valley Historic District, Heights South Historic District. Photos by Jim Parsons, Robert Searcy and David Bush. 

From GHPA News. For more information… http://www.ghpa.org/news/?p=86 

 –YOUR Inner Loop Real Estate Team FEATURED LISTING!!!! 

 
 7123 WINDWATER 
 2314 WALNUT BEND
 
 32310 SPINNAKER RUN
 4 bedrooms, 2 full bath&amp;1 half bath 
 Fantastic master suite with spa like master bathroom! 
 Spacious bedrooms complete this great home! 4 bedrooms, 2 full 1 half bath 
 Beautiful 1 1/2 story Southwestern home 
 Recently updated 
 Outdoors is sparkling pool&amp;wood deck 4/5 bedrooms, 3 full&amp;1 half bath 
 On the large 115 acre lake in lake Windcrest with boat dock! 
 Recent improvements include; double pane windows and doors, new pool equipment, outdoor lighting and speakers For Sale: $238,000 
 MLS# 82628838 For Sale: $228,900 
 MLS# 5684975 For Sale: $500,000 
 MLS# 58876249 

 –Real Estate News 

Stop Paying Your Landlord’s Mortgage!

 It’s staggering when you think about the cost of living, especially if you’re a renter and not a home owner. If you are currently paying $1,000 a month for rented housing, then over the next three years, your property management company will effectively have reaped $36,000 of your hard earned cash! You’re paying their mortgage when you could be building equity in your own property.

 What if I don’t have the money to buy a home right now? 

There are loan programs available that offer low down payment options. Some programs permit gift money as a down payment, and often sellers are willing to make a contribution to your purchase if they want to sell the home quickly.

There are many benefits of home ownership to consider, most of all, tax deductions. Let’s take a look at how advantageous this can be as a homeowner:

 How much is tax deductible? 

Tax deductions vary, but the IRS has laid out solid rules. They also have several tax publications full of helpful information worth taking the time to read. Publication 530, Tax Information for First-Time Homeowners, is very thorough, as is Publication 936, Home Mortgage Interest Deduction. For quick reference, you can refer to Tax Topics 505, Interest Expense, and 504, Home Mortgage Points.

These publications often refer to local and state guidelines, so you may want to consult a CPA to answer all the questions that arise from reading these materials. Here are a few tips you should know up front:

 Real Estate taxes are deductible on a primary residence. 

Real Estate taxes are paid at settlement or closing, or through an escrow account. Mortgage interest is deductible on a loan to purchase, build or improve your home. Your lender will provide you with a Mortgage Interest Statement (Form 1098) to list the total interest paid during the year. This should include any deductible points paid for that year.

Pre-paid interest is deductible in the year it is paid. At the close of a real estate transaction, borrowers usually pay for the interest on their loan that falls between the closing period and the first of the next month. Mortgage payments are made“in arrears”so when a loan is closed mid-month, there is interest due to the new lender which must be paid in advance.

If you are building a home, the interest on the construction loan is deductible. The construction period cannot exceed 24 months prior to the date that you move in if you claim this as your primary residence.

Call me to discuss your specific needs and we’ll find the program that’s right for you. We have a variety of low down payment programs available.
 
——————————————————————————————————————— 
 Posted in Washington Corridor Newsletter | Tagged corridor , newsletter , washington | Leave a reply 
 Washington Corridor Newsletter January 2012 Edition 
 Posted on January 20, 2012 by admin Reply 
 –What’s the buzz on the Washington Corridor? 

Pollo Campero–We’ve been making tastebuds dance since 1971.

 Washington Corridor continues to be the new Commercial development and franchise selections.

We take the greatest flavors from all over Latin America&amp;mix them for an experience that gets tastebuds dancing.

We started with an ancient Guatemalan recipe that gave our chicken the most delicious flavor. But to make it a true treat for the senses, we blended together popular flavors from all over Latin America for a unique taste all our own. Today, our chicken is still marinated in robust seasonings and a hint of citrus for tangy flavor that dances on the tip of your tongue.

 But there’s more to us than just heavenly chicken. We offer delectable food from all over Latin America like Campero beans, Latin Mashed Potatoes, Golden Yuca Fries, Hand-rolled Empanadas and more. The different combinations of sweet, smoky and spicy will get your whole body singing and dancing and lining up for more.

So come into Pollo Campero today for a blend of Latin flavor that gets your toes tapping and your tastebuds doing the cha-cha.

Coming soon!–4701 Washington Ave– http://houston.campero.com/home 
 
Coming to One End of Washington Ave: Vegetables

 Over the weekend, volunteers placed reclaimed clay tiles next to the I-45 overpass at the northern end of Downtown to create raised beds for a new city garden, Houston’s third. The garden is meant for employees of the city’s new permitting center at 1002 Washington — there’ll be one raised bed for each floor.

 How to Build a Raised Garden Bed: City of Houston Edition [East End Escapades]
 Houston Permitting Center Employee Garden (PDF) [Houston Permitting Center]

Article from Swamplot: http://swamplot.com/coming-to-one-end-of-washington-ave-vegetables/2012-01-10/ 

 –YOUR Inner Loop Real Estate Team FEATURED LISTING!!!! 

 
 8307 Crescent Knolls Dr
 
 1820 Oakdale St
 
 32310 Spinnaker Run
 5 bedrooms, 3 full bath&amp;1 half bath 
 Stainless steel appliances, gourmet kitchen and a media room! 
 All furniture is also available for sale 6 bedrooms, 3 full baths! 
 Kitchen is open with breakfast bar 
 Hardwood floors, formal dining 
 Huge master suite with a sitting room 4/5 bedrooms, 3 full&amp;1 half bath 
 On the large 115 acre lake in lake Windcrest with boat dock! 
 Recent improvements include; double pane windows and doors, new pool equipment, outdoor lighting and speakers For Sale: $399,900 
 MLS# 75006764 For Sale: $355,000 
 MLS# 26300838 For Sale: $520,000 
 MLS# 23697648 

 –Real Estate News 

Write-offs to Remember
Deductions in the Loan Process

 Write-offs are the government’s way of rewarding taxpayers when they’ve done something the government likes. And to judge by the write-offs, the government likes it when people borrow money to buy a house. There are write-offs aplenty, many of which people often forget.

Make sure your clients take advantage of every break the IRS will give. Here are a few they tend to forget:

 Points: 
According to the IRS, origination fees charged as points must be paid for the use of money, (for example, to obtain a lower interest rate) in order to be tax deductible. Origination fees that constitute a“service fee”are not tax deductible. The question must be asked,“Does the fee apply to the use of money, or is it a service charge?”

 Pre-payment penalties: 
Unforeseen circumstances often cause borrowers to pull out of their mortgages sooner than expected. Fortunately, pre-payment penalties are tax deductible, which helps ease the pain.

 Pro-rated real estate taxes: 
Even if the seller sent the tax collector the check, chances are the buyer paid a pro-rated portion of the taxes for the year at closing. Be sure they know to deduct their fair share.

 Pro-rated mortgage interest: 
Depending on when in the month the home sale closes, buyers pay either a hefty or a tiny amount of pro-rated mortgage interest for that month. Big or small, they can write that off. The Final Closing/Settlement Statement will show just how much they’ve paid.

 Home construction loan interest: 
As long as the construction period doesn’t last more than two years before they make the new place their“principal residence,”they can write off the interest for that construction loan.

It pays to pay attention – all these write-offs can add up to some serious savings when tax time comes around.

 
——————————————————————————————————————— 
 Posted in Washington Corridor Newsletter | Tagged corridor , newsletter , washington | Leave a reply 
 Washington Corridor Newsletter December 2011 Edition 
 Posted on December 7, 2011 by admin Reply 
 –What’s the buzz on the Washington Corridor? 

 Please Share Your Thoughts with Parking Management 

The City of Houston’s Parking Management division is discussing options to improve mobility along the Washington corridor and is seeking input from area residents. Please take a few minutes to provide feedback on a parking solution for Washington Avenue.

Visit http://www.houstontx.gov/parking/washingtonavenue.html to review the three proposals and then take a few minutes to tell us what you think. Please provide your feedback by noon, Friday, November 4, 2011.

For more information or technical assistance with your submission, email parking@houstontx.gov.

 Washington Avenue Parking Solution 

On September 14, 2011, Mayor Annise Parker and various City departments met with Washington Avenue stakeholders to discuss parking solutions. View the presentation and map and then take time to give us your feedback on each of the plans. Thank you!

 Minutes 
 Washington Avenue Stakeholder Meeting 
 September 14, 2011 

Mayor opened the meeting with introductions of CM Ed Gonzalez and staff in attendance. Stated the purpose of the meeting was to solicit input in regards to on‐street and off‐street parking for Washington Avenue.

Don Pagel gave a presentation in regards to parking concerns and proposed 3 parking plan options:

1. New signage
2. New signage and meters
3. Establish a parking benefit district

The proposal for alternatives 2&amp;3 could more than double the number of available parking spaces – currently 225 spaces with a net result of 603 open spaces.

One year ago the planning department analyzed all the bars/clubs along Washington Ave and they are all currently meeting the parking requirements.

Several residents in attendance expressed concern in regards to employees who work for the establishments in the area who park in private business parking lots and school parking lots.

Concern was also raised in regards to valet parking – the Mayor stated that the city could consider expanding the valet parking ordinance to the Washington Corridor.

One citizen suggested that the installation of taxi cab stands could prevent cabs from circling blocks along Washington waiting for fares.

Consensus of stakeholders in attendance was to move forward with new signage. The Mayor authorized Jeff Weatherford to proceed immediately with the installation of new signage which allows off street parking along Washington Avenue installing new signs which allows parking along Washington Avenue only during off‐peak hours.

CM Gonzalez spoke on the benefits of creating a Parking Benefits District. Creation of the district would put more boots on the ground for parking management. The funds collected by the Parking Benefits District are distributed 60% back to the community and 40% for administrative costs. The district would provide for improved sidewalks/crosswalks and provide for more walk‐ability.

In conclusion, new signage will be installed immediately; the Mayor tasked Marlene Gafrick with getting more accurate numbers on parking capacity along Washington Avenue; creation of a website where feedback can be gathered; The Mayor asked for an evaluation of Center Street.

 Washington Avenue Parking Zone Configuration and Zone Locations (click for map) 

 –YOUR Inner Loop Real Estate Team FEATURED LISTING!!!! 

 
 5634 Darling St
 
 5621 Darling St
 
 5128 Allum Rd
 2 bedrooms, 1 full bath 
 Updated bathroom and kitchen 
 Outdoor fireplace and bar 
 Wide drive way. Automatic drive thru gate Great land for builders!! 
 13,375 SF LOT!!! 
 New Construction in the area 
 Bring ALL offers!! 6 bedrooms, 4 full&amp;1 half bath 
 Tile flooring, crown molding, custom paint 
 Island kitchen features custom cabinets, granite counter tops&amp;back splash For Sale: $199,900 
 MLS# 25904254 For Sale: $350,000 
 MLS# 45853884 For Sale: $349,900 
 MLS# 4775728 

 –Real Estate News 

 Identity Theft: 
 5 Tips to Protect Your Privacy 

 The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) estimates that as many as 9 million Americans have their identities stolen each year. This means that an identity is stolen every 3 seconds, costing the average victim nearly $4,000 and nearly 175 hours to straighten out their problems and their credit. How can you protect yourself from the dangers of identity theft? Here are some suggestions.

Conduct a Credit Check-up – Visit www.annualcreditreport.com to obtain a free credit report every 12 months. Review all three of your credit reports and look for any suspicious activity, unusual or inaccurate names or addresses, or any inquiries that were done without your knowledge. In many states, you may place a 90-day“Fraud Alert”on your credit report, which further restricts access to your credit information. Simply call one of the three main credit bureaus to activate the alert. Here are the toll-free numbers: Equifax 1-800-525-6285; Experian® 1-888-397-3742; or TransUnion® 1-800-680-7289.

Don’t Give It Up – Avoid falling prey to phishing scams, both over the phone and through email. In a phishing scam, identity thieves pretend to be someone from your bank or a credit institution and simply ask you for your personal information. If someone contacts you and requests any personal information, don’t give it to them. Verify who is requesting the data and why, and then call the institution yourself. One extra phone call could save you a lot of trouble and money.

Stay off the Pharm – While phishing enables thieves to pilfer information from you, pharming is another kind of scam that consists of hijacking your computer and stealing your personal information. A pharming site is designed to look just like the website you’re trying to visit. However, enter your information on this fake site and not only can it track your moves within it, it may also direct your computer to give up other personal information at a later time. Be sure you are visiting the correct site, that the address in the navigation bar is correct before entering any information.

Return to Sender – Some scammers simply fill out a change of address form and divert your mail to another location. Others simply steal the mail they want right from your mailbox. The key to avoiding this scam is to know your statement delivery dates and pay close attention to any unusual delays in delivery. A lot of identity thieves do things the old-fashioned way: They rummage through your trash to collect your information that way. Be sure to shred any junk mail or other documents that may contain your personal information before you throw it away.

Opt-out of Special Offers – Visit www.optoutprescreen.com to cut down on the pre-approved offers from credit card and insurance companies. It’s also good idea to have your clients opt out as well, especially if they’re thinking about buying a home. When people apply for a mortgage, they often become“trigger leads”to the credit bureau, who sell your clients’information to any number of companies. It only takes a few minutes to opt out, but it could spare your clients a ton of junk mail and could possibly save them from identity theft.

 
——————————————————————————————————————— 
 Posted in Washington Corridor Newsletter | Tagged corridor , newsletter , washington | Leave a reply 
 Washington Corridor Newsletter November 2011 Edition 
 Posted on November 17, 2011 by admin Reply 
 –What’s the buzz on the Washington Corridor? 

Since November 1st (the opening day of hunting season), us girls have noticed a drop in the number of boys in our Washington Corridor nightlife! Our boys have been abandoning their city homes for a weekend out on the ranch riding Kubota RTVs and engaging in other manly activities, like eating what you kill. FINALLY, someone has brought the country game into the city limits! Where else can you find Rattle Snake Chili Fries, Pulled Wild Boar Sandwiches, and Kangaroo meat along with other wild game options?

It comes as no surprise that this new innovative concept would set up fort on Washington Avenue. This wild game movement is not only delicious, but also a healthy alternative to the so-yesterday beef. So next time after you finish your jog down Memorial Dr., stop by Sammy’s Wild Game Grill to experience what they have to offer for yourself! For the menu, please click the following link: http://www.sammyswildgamegrill.com/menu.html 

 Give your taste buds a special treat. Step in to the Wild side and experience Burgers, Sausage Dogs&amp;Sandwiches at a higher level. Sammy’s Wild Game Grill is committed to bringing you only the finest exotic meats, including Antelope, Venison, Elk, Ostrich, Buffalo and many other all natural and farm-raised game meats. We use high quality meat products free of growth hormones, antibiotics or preservatives.

Wild Game Meat brings exciting new gourmet flavors, while providing a healthy eating alternative to the usual fare of poultry, pork or beef.

As an added benefit, wild game meats are extremely high in protein and low in carbohydrates and cholesterol.

 Surveys show that domesticated animals have 25 to 30% fat while the average fat content of wild game animals is only 4.3%. Not only is the fat lower in game, but is also healthier. Fat from wild game contains a much higher proportion of polyunsaturated fatty acids, good fat and is lower in saturated fat, bad fat.Checkout their website for more info: http://www.sammyswildgamegrill.com 

 –YOUR Inner Loop Real Estate Team FEATURED LISTING!!!! 

 
 1820 Oakdale
 
 3522 Colmar
 
 1316 Cleburne 6 bedrooms, 3 full baths 
 Kitchen is open with breakfast bar 
 Hardwood floors, formal dining, huge master suite with a sitting room 3 bedroom, 2 full baths 
 Tile floors, faux blinds 
 Refrigerator, dishwasher, washer&amp;dryer 
 Katy School District 3 bedrooms, 2 full baths&amp;1 half bath 
 Granite island kitchen with custom cabinets&amp;stainless steel appliances 
 Between Medical Center&amp;Downtown For Sale: $355,000 
 MLS# 26300838 For Sale: $124,500 
 MLS# 4334846 For Sale: $299,999 
 MLS# 17563406 

 –Real Estate News 

 A Qualified Mortgage Consultant Can Outline Your Options 
 Renters Have Much to Gain by Pursuing Home Ownership 

By Denise Wargo, Loan Consultant
Network Funding, LP

Houston, TX – Buying a home vs. renting is a big decision that takes careful consideration, as most mortgage consultants will agree. But the rewards of home ownership are great. For many years, purchasing real estate has been considered an extremely profitable investment. It is an achievement that offers a sense of pride, financial stability and potential tax advantages.

Yes, there are certain responsibilities associated with owning a home. Landlords will often argue the benefits of renting, and for obvious reason. If you are renting, you’re helping them make their mortgage payment.

The numbers are staggering if you look at it this way. If you are paying $1,000 per month for an apartment, and you know your rent will increase 5% every year, then over the next five years you will pay your landlord $66,309. If you are currently renting a house, you may be paying much more than that each month. Either way, you gain no equity by shelling out this monthly housing expense and you certainly won’t benefit when the property value goes up!

However, if you were to purchase your own home or condominium in Texas, you would be on your way toward building equity. By choosing a fixed-rate loan program, you can have the comfort of knowing that your monthly mortgage payment will never go up. In fact, you would have the option of refinancing to a lower interest rate at some point in the future should interest rates drop lower than the rate you’d currently be locked in at, and this would cause your monthly mortgage commitment to go down.

And not only would your own home give you added space, your own back yard and overall privacy—home ownership would also give you some tax advantages. Depending on your tax bracket, owning a home is often less expensive than renting after taxes. Interest payments on a mortgage below $1 million are tax-deductible, and your mortgage consultant should help you evaluate the tax advantages of various loan scenarios, and share this information with your tax consultant to glean feedback on your behalf.

To find the loan program that is right for you, your mortgage consultant will need to evaluate your monthly household income, current assets and savings, as well as any monthly obligations you may have for credit card payments, car payments, child support, etc. These prequalification factors, along with the report of your credit score, will determine how much house you can afford and what interest rate you will pay for financing. It is also important to let your mortgage consultant know what your future goals are, because this will help narrow down which loan option is the best fit for your long-term needs.

There are many different types of loan programs available, including“low”down payment mortgage programs. The most common and beneficial loan for people buying their first home is the FHA loan, which only requires a 3.5% down payment. In addition, FHA allows a seller to cover up to 6% of a buyer’s closing costs which really helps decrease the amount of money it takes to buy a home. Many people also don’t know that FHA allows the lowest credit scores of any loan available today, only needing a 640 score in most cases.

If there is any time to buy it is NOW! Why? Because home prices are low today. Low home values are surely not good for people selling homes but they are great news for people wanting to buy a home. Don’t miss this opportunity to take advantage of the current market before home values rise. Call Denise 832-724-0740 today for your no cost, no obligation consultation.

 
——————————————————————————————————————— 
 Posted in Washington Corridor Newsletter | Tagged corridor , newsletter , washington | Leave a reply 
 Washington Corridor Newsletter October 2011 Edition 
 Posted on October 6, 2011 by admin Reply 
 –What’s the buzz on the Washington Corridor? 

Breaking the stigma of “Roach Coach”, gourmet food trucks have become a growing trend nationally for the past few years. We’ve noticed these trucks gain popularity in the Washington Corridor and throughout Houston. In harder economic times, it seems to be cheaper and easier for talented chefs to run a food truck versus open a restaurant. However, their growing numbers are paying a toll on the City and local businesses. The question is … how do you feel about food trucks?

Some business owners are huge food truck supporters and have jumped on the opportunity to better serve their customers. For example, Liberty Station and Kung Fu, our fellow bars here on Washington Avenue, generally have one to two food trucks parked on site. Many of Liberty’s patrons now expect these food trucks to be there and comment that in addition to the atmosphere Liberty Station provides, people go there for the food these food trucks serve. These bar owners have found a way to keep their tipsy and hungry guests at their location without having to run a full kitchen or have customers complain about boring bar food.

However, most restaurant and bar owners generally do not support food trucks because they feel the food trucks take away money from their pockets. Some restaurant owners feel it is not fair that the food trucks can park free, minimize the initial start-up cost, AND avoid the overhead restaurants have to carry.

In addition, the City of Houston is not a big fan of food trucks. One reason for the disapproval and/or food truck disliking is that since there are now over 600 food trucks in the City of Houston, the City Health Department is having a headache trying to monitor them all. Are they all sanitary? Please use your own discretion, but remember a mobile kitchen can easily hide from the City.

Even though it may seem truck owners have it easy, it is not always rainbows and sunshine for these food truck owners who are dependent on weather. Who wants to wait in the rain for delicious grub from a truck? Or worse, wait in Houston’s humid summer heat?? Another challenge is getting people out to find their trucks. By relying partially on Tweeter (a social media not everyone has grasped) to “tweet” their location, food trucks are having a hard time pulling in crowds of people.

There are always solutions to every problem. Since Houston loves permits, maybe a solution for health codes is to create a food truck permit. Or we could always mirror our fellow hippies in Austin and form a food truck park. Or why don’t currently operating restaurants take to the streets of Houston with their own fleet of trucks?…because if you can’t beat them, join them! It might take a few years to work out the kinks, but eventually Houston can become a food truck-friendly city!

My personal opinion is don’t knock anything until you try it! So before you approve or disapprove, why not stop by one of the food trucks and experience it for yourself!! For a list of popular food trucks with their locations in Houston, please go to http://houstonfoodtrucks.com/index.php 

 Want a Treat. • • Head to the Street 

By Gerald Melancon (From the Heights Pages: http://www.heightspages.com )

My first job was in 1973, a part-time job I secured as I attended the University of Houston. Working in a warehouse for a major industrial supply house after classes, it allowed me to earn enough income to stay just below poverty level. Those were the days!

Sadly enough, one of the highlights of the day was the visit from the“roach coach”. Cold drinks, candy, gum and an assortment of stale, pre-packaged sandwiches were always the mainstays of these units. Eating at one was like eating at all of them. Thankfully, something akin to natural selection has bred out those knuckle-draggers, to be replaced with a more evolved animal.

Some of the best, most innovative cooking now seems to be done in the backs of converted delivery vans. A growing pool of talented, motivated chefs, lured by the lower cost of entry (as opposed to a brick-and-mortar establishment), are given an outlet for their talents. Most having had restaurant management experience, having done the hard work, decided to apply that effort for their own benefit. There are about 30+ units in our area, classified as“gourmet food-trucks.”

 The one thing that really jumps out is the amount of work involved in operating a food truck. Chewy and K wang of the“Rolling Hunger”truck, which fuses their Korean and Latin backgrounds in their dishes, begin prepping about 9am. They end serving the late night, after clubbing crowd in the small hours of the night. Summer days of triple digit heat pound the body. Like great teammates, they make it look easy and food arrives quickly.

If you’re lucky enough to catch them try the namesake“Rolling Taco”. Stuffed with truffle fries, pork, Korean slaw, pico de gallo and special sauce, this is one of their signature dishes. The Banh Mi, another standard, is a Vietnamese, sandwich built on a French baguette, stuffed with fresh veggies and marinated pork, and salsa verde for a kick! They can be found at Dirk’s Coffee House, 4005 Montrose, most weekday lunches. Otherwise log onto www.therollinghunger.com and check out their GPS powered locator.

The City of Houston says“A mobile food unit is defined by the Houston Food Ordinance as a food service establishment that is vehicle mounted or wheeled and is capable of being readily moveable.”

Under this ordinance, they also define the two types of trucks allowed to operate on the streets of Houston;“restricted”and“unrestricted”units. The first“a restricted mobile food unit is one that serves only foods that were prepared and packaged in individual servings at an approved commissary and kept at required temperatures on the unit until served.”

An example of a restricted unit is Porch Swing Desserts, serving single sized, packaged sweets from their refurbished 1948 International panel van. Jennifer Diaz, the owner wanted to go the least prohibitive route, opting to go with the“restricted unit”, making and packaging her goods in a certified commercial kitchen. Restricted trucks are also allowed to serve“Non-potentially hazardous beverages (coffee, tea) from protected equipment or pasteurized, individually packaged milk.”Ice cream trucks, push carts and the old“roach coach”would fit under this definition.

Restoring and certifying the van has been a real challenge, with issues over getting a clean title from the state of Nevada, retrofitting for current safety standards (rear view mirrors, seat belts and turn signals). Not easy for a truck that is over 60 years old. She named Desserts to portray her type of Southern style desserts. The truck is named Hazel in memory of her grandmother, who was also the inspiration of the business. Starting out as a catering company, Jennifer has decided to hit the road, after taking some time off to have her daughter. She has confided that she is pregnant again. Don’t know how that will work, but we wish her all the best!

 “We anticipate baking at a commercial kitchen in the very early morning, each day that we operate for about 4-5 hours. Our plan is to be on the road selling mid-day to afternoon Wednesday through Friday, events and private parties on the weekends.”Jennifer also states it would be great for Houston’s food truck scene to be more like Austin, which allows for stationary set-up and operation of the trucks. Currently in the city of Houston, trucks have to be parked overnight at their“commissary”, where they are allowed to dump wastewater, clean their trucks and otherwise service the vehicle. Trucks have to return to these areas every night, and not remain on the streets of the city.

In a recent trip to Austin, we visited someof the food truck“parks”of the city. Areas where food trucks set-up on a more permanent basis, and can be found at that location everyday. One such location is at the 1300 block of South 1″Street, just across the river from town, in a nicely wooded“trailer park”. Anchoring this“park”was Torchy’s Tacos, one of the award-winning trucks of Austin. The park sets under large oak trees, with several large picnic tables and benches as well as a restroom. We managed to eat breakfast there every morning. I recommend the migas, and theirchorizo (I’m a chorizo fan) tacos. Such“parks”are not allowed in Houston, under current city ordinances.

An unrestricted unit serves food prepared or portioned on the unit. Examples of this type of unit are mobile taco stands, barbeque trucks or trailers, mobile snow cone stands, and catering trucks. Trucks serving meals fall under this category. Good Dog Hot Dog would be one of these trucks. Operated by Daniel Caballero and Amalia Pferd, they put a new wrinkle on the old hot dog. Amalia, a formally trained chef, makes all of their pickles, condiments and sauces. They nestle their premium hot dogs in bread, which looks like a slice out of loaf, acquired from the Slow Dough Bread Company. It is crispy, chewy and pillow soft.

 Most impressive are the condiments. Homemade sriracha ketchup, pickles and jalapenos are used. The Sloppy Slaw Dog, garnished with a mostly apple slaw is flavored with a horseradish spiked mayo, my wife’s favorite. The Chillin’Dog, made with beef and chorizo chili, is also a crowd favorite. Amalia is professionally under several of Houston’s elite chefs. They can be found at Buchanan’s Native Plants, on 11 th Street in the Heights.

The entry cost of these businesses varied greatly. The most economical way to get into the business seems to be, find a used truck, which has already been outfitted. Even then, costs for the truck alone may run in the $30,000 to $40,000 range after the inevitable repairs required of many of these neglected vehicles. Almost all of the operators stressed the importance of getting a unit that is mechanically sound. The days it spends in the garage only add to costs, and prevent you from being at work (making money).

There are several“manufacturers”in Houston, outfitting each unit to customers’specifications. These companies, whose main clientele were the“taco truck”operators, now have a new life in building units for the new breed. Most have both fresh and wastewater tanks, electric and gas cooking surfaces. Electric cooking is necessary to operate downtown, Midtown and the Medical Center, as gas cylinders are forbidden in these areas. Each truck can be customized with either refrigeration or large ice chest assemblies built in. New trucks can now be manufactured with battery/fuel cell electrical systems, making generators unnecessary. Such high-end units can start around $80,000 and can be outfitted to exceed $150,000 with all of the bells and whistles.

 Van Pham of the Pharnily Bites truck loves the business he is in. Serving their take of Vietnamese foods from their truck, they have been in business now for about 6 months. Having worked for other high-end restaurants, he too was eager to get his interpretation of food to the streets. They choose to service the late night crowds, at locations such as Liberty Station and The Drinkery on Washington Avenue, as well as regular gigs on the Kirby and the Richmond strip.

When asked what he considers the best and the worst parts of operating a food-truck, he was quick to answer both. As many other good cooks and chefs have stated, he takes joy in seeing others eat and appreciate his creations. As the cook in my house, this is a sentiment I understand. When asked what is the worst thing, he emphatically stated“THE HEAT!”At times, temperatures reach near 130 degrees in the truck.

As a personal observation, at the photo shoot for the cover, as the operator of four of these trucks gathered, there was a great feeling of camaraderie amongst them. Even after the shoot, they hung around for quite a while, discussing some upcoming ordinance changes as well as other“gossip”of the trade. They shared stories of their triumphs and mutual challenges.

So, go out and find one of the above trucks we have discussed, or others operating in the area. The food is unique, almost all delicious and an economical way to treat yourself to something really good. Many of the best meals I have eaten the last few weeks have come from them, and I assume many more will. Google“Houston Food Trucks”, there are several sites listing the leading trucks of the area, with regular updates and links to info on schedules and locations.

 So for a great, affordable meal, hit the road! 

By Gerald Melancon (From the Heights Pages: http://www.heightspages.com )

 –YOUR Inner Loop Real Estate Team FEATURED LISTING!!!! 

 
 5414 Darling St 
 3522 Colmar
 
 1316 Cleburne 3 bedrooms, 2 full baths&amp;1 half bath 
 NEW floors, A/C, and appliances in 2011!!! 
 Backyard w/ stone patio&amp;fenced in 
 Cottage Grove neighborhood 3 Bedroom, 2 full baths 
 Tile floors, faux blinds 
 Refrigerator, dishwasher, washer&amp;dryer 
 Katy School District 3 bedrooms, 2 full baths&amp;1 half bath 
 Granite island kitchen with custom cabinets&amp;stainless steel appliances 
 Between Medical Center&amp;Downtown For Sale: $269,900 
 MLS# 99244214 For Sale: $124,500 
 MLS# 4334846 For Lease: $299,999 
 MLS# 17563406 

 –Real Estate News 

The Difference Between Pre-Qualification and Pre-Approval

 Pre-qualification is the first step in obtaining mortgage financing. A potential borrower answers a few questions to provide the loan consultant with a quick snapshot of the borrower’s income, existing debt, accumulated savings and whether or not there is a co-borrower. Signature(s) allow the loan consultant to run a credit report and begin to determine what loans are good candidates for this particular client. However, there are literally thousands of loan programs available. It is important for the loan professional to know the long-term financial objectives of the prospective homeowner.

Pre-approval is a written documentation that proves the borrower has full support of a lender. It means the form 1003 Uniform Residential Loan Application has been completed and reviewed by an underwriter. Based on the borrower’s income, debt ratio and savings, the underwriter will provide a dollar amount this borrower is eligible for. Now the borrower has the convenience of shopping for a home in the price range agreed upon by the lender.

Pre-approval allows potential homeowners to shop as cash buyers, and that means negotiating power. Sellers will take an offer from a pre-approved shopper much more seriously and may even accept a lower bid because they know the financing is in place and the deal is secure.

 
 Posted in Washington Corridor Newsletter | Tagged corridor , newsletter , washington | Leave a reply 
 Washington Corridor Newsletter September 2011 Edition 
 Posted on September 6, 2011 by admin Reply 
 –What’s the buzz on the Washington Corridor? 

Washington Avenue is home to many successful businesses which include offices, trendy restaurants and wine bars.

One success story is that of 360 Sports Lounge which is located just east of Shepherd at the former site of Clark Motors is the 50,000 square-foot retail and office project called Washington Centre. Business owners Jesse Botello and Brandon Grissom are both native Houstonians and met at Del Frisco’s restaurant and together developed 360’s business plan. Their success is proof that two best friends can actually make it in the bar business together.

Article from 002houston Magazine– http://002mag.com 

 THE PHRASE“CUT OUT THE MIDDLEMAN”HAS BECOME A BADGE OF HONOR IN THE BUSINESS WORLD, THIS CALL TO ARMS TO CUT THE FAT IS USUALLY A GOOD THING, BUT OVER TIME, IT HAS ELIMINATED A GRAY AREA THAT CAN BE PRETTY DARNED INTERESTING. WHILE THE MANTRA HAS DRIVEN PLENTY OF PEOPLE AND PLACES TO BE ONE THING OR THE OTHER, BLACK-TIE OR BLUE JEANS, BEATLES OR STONES, 360 SPORTS LOUNGE ON 4601 WASHINGTON AVE. IS A MIDDLEMAN THAT ISN’T BUDGING.

360 borrows the best from the pomp and circumstance of its neighbors and leaves tired sports bar stereotypes behind, all while maintaining the charm of that favorite old haunt. A visit to Jimmy’s Laundromat&amp;Sports Shack provides you with broken chairs and a standing-room-only attitude. 360? Ample, comfortable seating. Your trusty standby is a dank cube with a few regulars hoarding the good staff and the 1996, bubble-screen Sanyo. Meanwhile, 360 is bright and inviting. Looking at the clean lines, the sharp paint jobs and the bar adorned with giant flatscreens in all the right places, it’s clear to see that 360 spared no expense to provide one of the classiest sports bar experiences in Houston. 360′s kitchen is open late and aims to please, taking your typical bar food for a ride. The house-made pizzas have freshness in every bite, and the quintessential fried fare doesn’t follow that freezer-to-grease-to-plate pattern that it does in your usual sports joint. Onion rings and cheese sticks emerge consistently crispy and delicious.

 While what 360 takes from its more upscale brethren is refreshing, what it’s borrowed from those lore-inspiring dives is just as important. The open design and booming acoustics create a sense of community during big games no matter who you’re rooting for. There’s a great private room for reservation with a pool table and a secluded grouping of couches and barstools, but being on the floor puts you in the middle of the action with grandiose sense of Houston camaraderie. Pick your poison. Either way, just like your old, trusty stomping grounds, the personnel behind the bar and walking the floor will know your name after one visit to your table. A smile, handshake and an earnest attempt to show customer appreciation on Washington Ave.? Yes, it does exist. Sure, the sports dive you’re used to doesn’t offer $5 champagne on Wednesdays like 360, but that concept of hospitality is near and dear to dive-junkies like me. Happy hour every weekday from 3-7 and $25 all-you-can-eat crawfish on the weekends seal the deal on bringing Houston the best of two worlds.

In a world of polarizing opinions, I suppose it’s nice just to have a choice to begin with. It’s even better though, when a place can really thrive in the gray area, becoming a go-between that meets multiple needs. On a foundation of Washington Ave. class and traditional sports bar charisma, 360 Sports Lounge is a perfect example of the middleman standing tall in Houston.

Article from 002houston Magazine– http://002mag.com 

 –YOUR Inner Loop Real Estate Team FEATURED LISTING!!!! 

 
 1020 E 28th St 
 5724 Kiam
 
 1900 Genesee St 308 3 Bedroom 
 New Kitchen with Granite Counters 
 Outside Designer Two Tone Paint 
 Everything is New 3 Bedroom 
 Beautiful brick&amp;cement board exterior! 
 Granite Counter Tops / Stainless Steel Appliances 
 Oversized Garage / Gated entrance! 2 Bedroom / 2 Full Bath 
 Hardwood Floors / Ceramic Tile / Slab Granite Counters / Custom Woodwork 
 Fully furnished for an additional $700 a month For Sale: $225,000 
 MLS# 49179900 For Sale: $264,900 
 MLS# 27592948 
 For Lease: $2,300 
 MLS# 16779125 For Lease: $1,850 
 MLS# 21085011 

 –Real Estate News 

High Credit Score = Low Mortgage Rate

 Credit scoring was developed in the 1960s as a means to determine whether or not consumers were likely to repay their loans. The score ranges from 350 to 850 with a higher score being extremely favorable. Essentially, a high credit score translates into lower interest rates for the borrower.

There are five factors that comprise the credit score. Payment history accounts for 35% of the score; outstanding credit balances have a 30% impact; credit history makes up 15%, type of credit factors at 10%; and inquiries influence the score by 10%. This gives the lender a snapshot of an individual’s sense of financial responsibility and ability to pay back loans.

There are many quick tricks to improve the credit score, and I can provide borrowers with more information on this subject. If necessary, I guide them to a reliable resource for credit remediation. If a borrower has to pay a higher interest rate to close a loan, the tarnished credit rating will begin to improve once mortgage payments are made on time and in full. If that is the case, my team and I will be on the watch to alert the borrower when an opportunity arises to refinance and get a lower interest rate.

 
 Posted in Washington Corridor Newsletter | Tagged corridor , newsletter , washington | Leave a reply 
Post navigation
 ← Older posts 
Follow Us
 
 
 
Categories

 Washington Corridor Newsletter 
 
Archives

 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 July 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 
 
Calendar
 
 July 2012 M T W T F S S «Jun       1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31   
 
 

 As a Seller, NOW is the best time to market and sell your property! Let 

 YOUR Inner Loop Real Estate Team 
 Get YOUR home sold! 

 Call Tiffanie Purvis 713.303.3738 
 YOUR Inner Loop Real Estate Team 

 Texas Real Estate&amp;Co. 
2420 Washington Avenue
Houston, Texas 77007
 www.txreco.com 
 
 
 
 ©2011 Texas Real Estate&amp;Co.
	</body>
</document>
