<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009217" url="http://www.sparkpeople.com/myspark/messageboard.asp?imboard=7&amp;imparent=25954057" time="2012-07-13-02:36" support="2" score="0.002978849548920682" bingtitle="Eating on the Road - Free Diet Plans at SparkPeople" webtitle="Eating on the Road">
			<query id="001223" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001241" bing-rank="250"/>
	<description>If you have to eat at a store or fast food restaurant, study ... I pack my food from now on. I want control over food. ... want to pack, you&apos;re only limited by the containers ...</description>
	<body>
		Search 
 Join Now For Free Help Tell A Friend Log In 
 
 My Trackers 
 Start my Nutrition my Fitness my Weight Other Goals SparkStreaks Reports Planner SparkMail my SparkPoints Web Search 
 Healthy Lifestyle 
 Healthy Lifestyle Home Nutrition Fitness Motivation Wellness SparkDiet Lifestyle Centers 
 Maintaining Your New Weight Men&apos;s Health Backyard Gardening College Living Financial Fitness Green Living SparkMoms Natural Beauty Senior Health Women&apos;s Health Brides-to-Be Limited Mobility 
 Videos SparkRecipes.com dailySpark.com 
 Health Conditions 
 Health Conditions Home Health A-Z Condition Centers 
 Depression Diabetes (Spark*D Program) GERD (Heartburn) Healthy Heart Healthy Skin High Blood Pressure High Cholesterol Insomnia Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS) Menopause Osteoarthritis Seasonal Allergies 
 Health News 
 Community 
 Community Home Message Boards SparkTeams Challenge Central SparkPages Blogs Success Stories Secrets of Success SparkPeople LIVE! Friend Feed SparkAmerica 
 Shop 
 Free Mobile Phone Apps 28 Day Boot Camp DVD The SparkPeople Cookbook The Spark Book SparkPeople LIVE! Online Meetings SparkPeople Merchandise SparkPeople E-Books 
 
 
 
 SparkPeople advertisers help keep the site free! Learn more 
   
 
 

 FORUM:  Diet and Nutrition 

 TOPIC:  
Eating on the Road
 


 Click here to read our frequently asked Diet and Nutrition questions. 

   
   
 
 Search the
Message Boards: 
 
   
 
 SparkPeople advertisers help keep the site free! Learn more 
 
 
 
 

 
 ISMILETOO Posts: 
 263
 12/28/11 11:55 P 

 
 
 Lunch bags filled with portion control items are the best!

8oz reusable plastic containers and refillable water containers - all are must musts!




  current weight: 163.2  

   
 163.2 159.9 156.6 153.3 
 150 
 


 
 LANEYPHOENIX SparkPoints: ( 2,957 )
Fitness Minutes: (758)
 Posts: 15 
 12/28/11 11:28 P 

 
 
 I make sure I have carrots or an apple in the car with me to help me deal with stressful Arizona traffic on Wedneday mornings.

 Edited by: LANEYPHOENIX at: 12/28/2011 (23:29) 


 
 SDMA53 Posts: 6 
 12/14/11 7:52 P 

 
 i;ll give it a try thanks for the idea.

 


 
 LPERKINS75 SparkPoints: ( 12,555 )
Fitness Minutes: (9,522)
 Posts: 1,276 
 12/14/11 9:08 A 

 
 
 Pre-measure out portions of your favorite healthy cereal or pre-measure other healthy portable snacks and then leave them in your car. When I am on top of my game, this is what I do. It&apos;s useful and prevents me from hitting that drive-thru when I go too long without eating or I get a craving for something that I know isn&apos;t healthy for me.

 &quot;Everyday I&apos;m shufflin&apos;...&quot;

 


  July Minutes: 215 

   
 0 300 600 900 
 1200 
 


 
 SDMA53 Posts: 6 
 12/13/11 8:05 P 

 
 Twice a week I need to eat on the road before my doctors appointment because I need to have something in my stomach before taking my medicine.. Usually I don&apos;t have enough time to make something healthy before I leave. Any suggestions? 

 


 
 LULUTYM SparkPoints: ( 4,842 )
Fitness Minutes: (1,484)
 Posts: 36 
 12/2/11 12:07 P 

 
 
 I ruchased a restaurant food calorie guide. If I must eat fast food I can select the restaurant with the most healthy options. If there are only burger joints I choose the most healthy item on the menu. If at McDonald&apos;s I get the hamburger happy meal, diet drink, take one half the bun off the burger, split the other bun in half and eat my burger that way. It satisfies the hunger without all the calories. I also carry fat free cheese with me and well as my own fat free salad dressings. This really helps cut the calories and fat.

 Persistence Pays Off! 


  Pounds lost: 2.2  

   
 0 5 10 15 
 20 
 


 
 MANDALORE Posts: 1,042 
 12/2/11 8:38 A 

 
 
 pack fruits and veggies, plenty to choose from!




  Pounds lost: 15.5  

   
 0 41.25 82.5 123.75 
 165 
 


 
 SAMIP123 SparkPoints: ( 986 )
Fitness Minutes: (1,483)
 Posts: 
 101
 12/2/11 7:51 A 

 
 
 I agree with the snack bags!
Take two of your low cal favorites (I love dried cranberries and reduced fat wheat thins!)
Take little bags and mix ONE SERVING on each (literally measure).
Every time I have class through lunch or I&apos;m driving somewhere I take a snack bag , a string cheese or an apple, and a bottle of water (with crystal light). It&apos;s quick, easy and convenient on the go!




  current weight: 145.0  

   
 158 150 142 134 
 126 
 


 
 STELLA-CO Posts: 73 
 12/1/11 6:37 P 

 
 My own &quot;Snack bags&quot; or pre-weighed pretzels, nuts and even chips. String cheese, apples , dried fruits and protein drinks.

 
Stella in Colorado

I can do ALL things through exercise which strengthens me. 


  July Minutes: 0 

   
 0 90 180 270 
 360 
 


 
 EOINIE Posts: 
 19
 12/1/11 2:45 P 

 
 
 Note to self... Pack fruit for car journeys




  Pounds lost: 3.0  

   
 0 11.5 23 34.5 
 46 
 


 
 GEMINI0614 SparkPoints: ( 303 )
Fitness Minutes: (505)
 Posts: 8 
 12/1/11 1:15 P 

 
 these are really good suggestions to making things easier and not giving into temptations!




  current weight: 198.0  

   
 201 192 183 174 
 165 
 


 
 DEPAULGIRL09 Posts: 2,450 
 12/1/11 1:12 P 

 
 
 I usually carry string cheese or some reduced fat wheat thins with me.

 ~Lisa~



Team Leader: South Suburbs - Fan the Spark 


  current weight: 270.0  

   
 275 243.75 212.5 181.25 
 150 
 


 
 GEMINI0614 SparkPoints: ( 303 )
Fitness Minutes: (505)
 Posts: 8 
 12/1/11 1:10 P 

 
 this is a nice option.. I may look into purchasing this. thanks for sharing.




  current weight: 198.0  

   
 201 192 183 174 
 165 
 


 
 JENDAWL SparkPoints: ( 8,070 )
Fitness Minutes: (5,425)
 Posts: 
 21
 12/1/11 11:43 A 

 
 
 I like to bring FiberOne bar with me. It helps me feel full until i can have an actual meal.

 


 
 ANDBEYOND SparkPoints: ( 25,910 )
Fitness Minutes: (12,933)
 Posts: 1,242 
 11/30/11 6:36 P 

 
 Packing water, fruit and snacks works for me!

 Winston Churchill commanded his troops to &quot;SINK the Bismarck&quot;, and they did, so for Christmas we will sink the bismarck by not over-indulging. Yes I will indulge but with Gods help, &quot;I WILL NOT OVER-INDULGE&quot;! SETASIDE1@YAHOO.COM 


  Pounds lost: 31.0  

   
 0 16.5 33 49.5 
 66 
 


 
 SHERYLG1 Posts: 382 
 11/30/11 9:01 A 

 
 Great ideas. Thanks for sharing

 In 2010 &apos;Paying it forward&quot; 5 Years cancer free !

Vertically challenged 5&apos;2&quot; but fit well in my Mazda Miata !

Be not afraid of going slowly; be afraid only of standing still.

&quot;You cannot dream yourself into a character: you must hammer and forge yourself into one.&quot;
Henry D. Thoreau

&quot;Change your thoughts, and change your world&quot;
--Norman Vincent Peale (1898-1993)
 www.the3day.org/site/TR/2010/Arizona
Event2010?px=4626581&amp;pg;=personal&amp;fr;_id
=1460 


  current weight: 149.6  

   
 151 148.25 145.5 142.75 
 140 
 


 
 TINYC887 SparkPoints: ( 108,031 )
Fitness Minutes: (102,392)
 Posts: 5,059 
 11/30/11 7:47 A 

 
 
 I am on the road all day too so I pack whatever meals ill be on the road for and snacks.




  Pounds lost: 24.0  

   
 0 16.25 32.5 48.75 
 65 
 


 
 GRAYGRANNY SparkPoints: ( 40,189 )
Fitness Minutes: (46,061)
 Posts: 4,767 
 11/30/11 6:41 A 

 
 
 McDonalds smoothies are delicious, healthy, and fulfilling

 People take different roads seeking fulfillment and happiness. Just because they&apos;re not on your road doesn&apos;t mean they&apos;ve gotten lost

&quot;Obstacles are things a person sees when they take their eyes off the goal.. 


  current weight: 147.1  

   
 154 149.25 144.5 139.75 
 135 
 


 
 MRSJOCCO SparkPoints: ( 19,344 )
Fitness Minutes: (9,854)
 Posts: 1,317 
 11/29/11 8:40 P 

 
 
 You could consider a car refrigerator/heater like this one: www.amazon.com/Wagan-EL2577-Personal-Fridg
e-Warmer/dp/B001RKH7FS/ref=pd_sim_sbs_
misc_1 

They&apos;re actually not expensive. 

 You are worth it! 


  July Minutes: 472 

   
 0 250 500 750 
 1000 
 


 
 COGPATTER Posts: 22 
 11/29/11 7:07 P 

 
 
 Dr Phil at one time, called fast food, eating in the car, on the go,,, &quot;poke and go&quot; I try to avoid the &quot;T&quot; strip here in Ponca City that has all the eating joints. Take stuff to work that keeps me away from, &quot;what for lunch today&quot;

 https://colleenpatterson.scentsy.us 


  current weight: 198.0  

   
 198 190.25 182.5 174.75 
 167 
 


 
 HIP-MOM Posts: 
 1,562
 11/29/11 12:35 P 

 
 
 Dairy Queen makes really good grilled chicken salads and so do any grocery store in the deli area. all pre made ready to go. There&apos;s also wraps. Depends on your diet needs to what you buy. Most fast food places are junk and chemical laden products, especially chicken nuggets from McDonalds.




  Pounds lost: 44.0  

   
 0 15.75 31.5 47.25 
 63 
 


 
 HIKER7 Posts: 
 313
 11/29/11 8:01 A 

 
 
 Great topic!
On a recent long drive for a business trip, I noticed that in Ontario&apos;s new &quot;ONroute&quot; rest stops, the variety store stocks &quot;Healthy Snacks&quot;, fresh fruit, and yoghurt along with the usual junk food. The food court restaurants all had salad choices, and of course Tim Horton&apos;s has yoghurt parfaits and some healthy sandwich choices.



 Ruth

&quot;We are here to add what we can to life, not to get what we can from it.&quot;
[Sir William Osler] 


  current weight: 183.0  

   
 183 172.25 161.5 150.75 
 140 
 


 
 COKASTL SparkPoints: ( 229 )
Fitness Minutes: (65)
 Posts: 2 
 11/28/11 11:34 P 

 
 You don&apos;t have to only have filtered water at home - I got a Bobble as a gift and it&apos;s great for travel (it&apos;s a plastic water bottle with a replaceable carbon filter in it). Brita (and probably a bunch of other brands) have similar bottles. And they help you save money!

 Edited by: COKASTL at: 11/28/2011 (23:35) 


 
 SBECKER526 SparkPoints: ( 54,603 )
Fitness Minutes: (61,282)
 Posts: 
 603
 11/28/11 10:30 P 

 
 
 I pack heathy snacks and water. I plan rest stops if it is a long trip with quality foods. I normally check out the menu on the website. At relatives and friends homes I eat sensibly.

 Fitness and proper eating are essential to me! 


  July Minutes: 1,482 

   
 0 625 1250 1875 
 2500 
 


 
 PATRICIAANN46 Posts: 5,749 
 11/28/11 9:51 P 

 
 
 Take along plenty of healthy snacks and water.

 


 
 LULUTYM SparkPoints: ( 4,842 )
Fitness Minutes: (1,484)
 Posts: 36 
 11/28/11 7:29 P 

 
 
 Really great ideas on this thread!

 Persistence Pays Off! 


  Pounds lost: 2.2  

   
 0 5 10 15 
 20 
 


 
 WARMSTRONG2 SparkPoints: ( 35,302 )
Fitness Minutes: (21,042)
 Posts: 1,684 
 11/28/11 4:12 P 

 
 I try to have plenty of fruit in the car to munch on.

 


 
 COROZALOVE SparkPoints: ( 11,344 )
Fitness Minutes: (7,435)
 Posts: 254 
 11/28/11 4:01 P 

 
 pack your food. WATER (no sugary drinks), fruits,and if you take along sandwiches,stick with turkey meat and brown bread.

 They also serve,Who only stand and Wait.
John Milton 


 

   
 0 5 10 15 
 20 
 


 
 PUPPETGIRLKY SparkPoints: ( 44,921 )
Fitness Minutes: (35,486)
 Posts: 2,546 
 11/28/11 2:37 P 

 
 
 CUT UP VEGS IN BAGGIES:O) yogurt CUPS AND CHEESE STICKS

 EACH DAY IS A GIFT FROM GOD--HAVE YOU SAID THANK YOU TODAY??PRACTICE RANDOM ACTS OF PRAISE:O) :O) :O) 


  Pounds lost: 4.2  

   
 0 8.5 17 25.5 
 34 
 


 
 ISAACSJENNY Posts: 4 
 11/28/11 10:33 A 

 
 I get starbucks egg white spinach wrap under 300 calories or Dunkin Donuts veggie wrap or flat bread veggie. For lunch Starbucks has a yogurt and granola parfait which is really filling and around 300 calories. McDonalds and Starbucks offer oatmeal with fruit and/or nuts. Subway, Quikchek, Wawa in Jersey have good veggie italian subs/wraps. Also veggie burritos are less than 600 calories. I pack a lot of fruits but when it&apos;s meal times I often skip them because I crave salt and fat-- if I just get a cheeseburger at mcdonalds it&apos;s really cheap and not totally insane with calories, plus you get your fix-- without the fries and coke you can plan around this with conservative snacks and other meals and still be in your calorie range worst case. If you&apos;re near a microwave I take smart ones-- their Santa Fe beans and rice or veggie lasagna is around 300 calories is super tasty and vegetarian, really filling with protein. Soup cans travel easy and are really low calorie meals. V8 is also a mini meal, but drink an equal amount of water. Nuts are great/filling, salty I think is ok if it means you&apos;ll skip the chips elsewhere. I find it very true as I&apos;ve read on spark that often hunger is a symptom of dehydration-- you don&apos;t feel thirsty but you feel hungry-- your body is seeking the water it needs in food; I think that&apos;s often why eating food just doesn&apos;t fully satisfy. If you think you&apos;re going to stop for food, just try drinking a glass of water first, a lot of the time you&apos;re no longer hungry after or a healthy snack will do the trick-- hey, it&apos;s worth a try.

 


 
 LANEYPHOENIX SparkPoints: ( 2,957 )
Fitness Minutes: (758)
 Posts: 15 
 11/27/11 5:56 P 

 
 
 Thanks for the tip, I will take an extra effort to pack fruits and veggies before leaving for work. This seems to be the hardest time for me because there is so many unhealthy choices in the workpalce. I&apos;m going to also purchase the cook book.

Delaine

 


 
 QUERIDAANA SparkPoints: ( 12,845 )
Fitness Minutes: (12,022)
 Posts: 
 385
 11/27/11 2:57 P 

 
 
 We pack fruits and vegetables. We buy salads on the way.

 It&apos;s the journey. We can do this. 


  Pounds lost: 57.0  

   
 0 18.5 37 55.5 
 74 
 


 
 PATRICIAANN46 Posts: 5,749 
 11/26/11 9:35 P 

 
 
 I usually take a cooler with me and fill it with healthy snacks and lots of water. If I do stop to eat, I look for a Wendy&apos;s which has many healthy offerings.

 


 
 AUNTFANNYJANE Posts: 
 776
 11/26/11 8:56 P 

 
 
 Head to places that offer sub sandwiches and wraps.

 Start Date July 30, 2011
Life is 10% what happens to you and 90% how you react to it 


  current weight: 184.0  

   
 209 200.25 191.5 182.75 
 174 
 


 
 EASTENDCLAM Posts: 
 824
 11/26/11 5:19 P 

 
 
 A small cooler with water and seedless sectioned or small fruit (Clementines, grapes). Stuff the driver can be handed and pop into the mouth, not have to hold (apple) and not be distracted by getting rid of the seeds.




  July Minutes: 1,105 

   
 0 450 900 1350 
 1800 
 


 
 SABLENESS Posts: 1,553 
 11/26/11 10:18 A 

 
 
 There are some really good ideas here. I&apos;ve made myself a rule of no eating in the car as a general practice. When eating on the run is the only option,I stick a small can of low sodium V8 and a protein bar in my purse. For long distance driving, McD&apos;s offers some pretty good healthy choices these days. Keeping grapes , baby carrots, and cut up celery in a small cooler along with no-salt nuts helps when I need a snack. The salty nuts only make me thirsty. I do take along water bottles to ensure that I stop and stretch often.

 &quot;It does not matter how slowly you go as long as you do not stop.&quot; Confucius

&quot;The secret to success is making very small, yet very consistent changes. Or, to make it short, Baby steps, Baby steps in the right direction.&quot; Messies Anon 


  current weight: 175.0  

   
 203 188.5 174 159.5 
 145 
 


 
 SM-ARTGIRL SparkPoints: ( 27,292 )
Fitness Minutes: (25,694)
 Posts: 1,102 
 11/24/11 7:29 P 

 
 
 Wow there are some great suggestions here!
My number one travel neccessity is my steel water bottle.
If away for a few days I use tap water, but at home we filter our water and we have a &quot;water station&quot; where everyone, including the 7yo, fills their bottle or 2 for the day in the morning.
I always pack nuts n fruits for trips, but I am often tempted by my family- my partner always likes to buy a chocolate bar as a treat!

 &quot;Never give up a passion!&quot; me

&quot;To be nobody but yourself--in a world which is doing its best, night and day, to make you everybody else-- means to fight the hardest battle which any human being can fight; and never stop fighting.&quot;
EE Cummings, poet 


  July Minutes: 0 

   
 0 420 840 1260 
 1680 
 


 
 GLITTERMAGIC SparkPoints: ( 1,740 )
Fitness Minutes: (2,120)
 Posts: 
 18
 11/24/11 2:17 P 

 
 
 You got everyone thinking. Great topic and I&apos;ve been reading amazing ideas in dealing with this. Now I know what to do the next time the husband and I have a road trip (which happen a lot!). Thanks to everyone for their great ideas!




  Pounds lost: 9.7  

   
 0 13.25 26.5 39.75 
 53 
 


 
 ANHELIC SparkPoints: ( 25,946 )
Fitness Minutes: (7,292)
 Posts: 1,274 
 11/23/11 11:45 P 

 
 
 Before my friend and I start on the road of delivering Avon, she takes some time and makes us each a bowl of oatmeal with fruit and nuts. She buys fruit like it&apos;s going out of style and takes some with us. I spring for lunch which we find pretty good at McDonalds having the salad with chicken strips entre and diet coke. It&apos;s great and we are getting our fruits and veggies in for the day. 
Joan

 Go Dale Jr. 88 Go, We will both make it to the end of the race. 


  current weight: 233.0  

   
 250 228.75 207.5 186.25 
 165 
 


 
 MTRICE SparkPoints: ( 18,149 )
Fitness Minutes: (1,208)
 Posts: 359 
 11/23/11 1:35 A 

 
 
 DH used to be on the road a lot as well, he had a cooler that hooked into his cigarette lighter hole. I would store my own salads and string cheese, etc in there.

 Mtrice

GOALS:

* Walk and/or Cycle 150+ Miles in June

Miles Walked/Cycled

* Earn 738 SparkPoints in June
*** DONE ***

* Drink 1 gallon of water daily @yuck@ but Dr. recommended

* Try to lose at least 5 pounds this month so I can be in the teens 


  current weight: 255.0  

   
 261 232 203 174 
 145 
 


 
 CHYCHY01 SparkPoints: ( 11,800 )
Fitness Minutes: (3,120)
 Posts: 282 
 11/23/11 12:56 A 

 
 
 interesting tips... i usually take water and fruits..

 &quot;Commit to the LORD whatever you do, and your plans will succeed.&quot; Proverbs 16:3
&quot;It is hard to fail, but it is worse never to have tried to succeed.&quot; Theodore Roosevelt
Rise up; this matter is in your hands. We will support you, so take courage and do it.&quot; Ezra 10:4
&quot;If you don&apos;t like something, change it. If you can&apos;t change it, change your attitude. Don&apos;t complain.&quot; Maya Angelou 


  current weight: 199.0  

   
 199 182.25 165.5 148.75 
 132 
 


 
 CHARLOTTE1947 SparkPoints: ( 27,182 )
Fitness Minutes: (35,326)
 Posts: 1,224 
 11/22/11 10:50 P 

 
 
 I know this sounds crazy, but when I&apos;m on a long road trip with my dh, we split a small bag of peanut M&amp;M;&apos;s. They keep us on the road for those forever miles between breakfast at dawn and lunch at 1:00. I know, I know - it&apos;s not virtuous, but just a few peanuts are filling.




  current weight: 134.2  

   
 158 150.5 143 135.5 
 128 
 


 
 GMAJNET SparkPoints: ( 1,811 )
Fitness Minutes: (95)
 Posts: 10 
 11/22/11 10:43 P 

 
 I also like to GRAZE when I travel. It keeps me from getting into a starvation mode where I just want to eat everything in site at 7 am, noon and 6 pm. I tend to eat more sensibly if I&apos;m not starving.

 


 
 APRECI8 Posts: 
 28
 11/21/11 10:52 P 

 
 
 I only travel 30 min. Per day so I allow myself only water for the road. I find that eating on the road is very mindless eating for me and I am better served if I skip it all together.




  July Minutes: 0 

   
 0 125 250 375 
 500 
 


 
 JENTRY07 SparkPoints: ( 107 )
Fitness Minutes: (0)
 Posts: 14 
 11/21/11 5:11 P 

 
 Fruit is a good option. You could also try topping peanut butter on celery for a quick snack.
Beef jerky is another great high protein option that will help you to feel full longer for less calories.

 


 
 BELLALUCIA Posts: 3,451 
 11/21/11 4:33 P 

 
 Pack some nuts!

 I came, I saw, I conquered.

Veni, Vidi, Vici---Julius Caesar 


  Pounds lost: 0.0  

   
 0 33 66 99 
 132 
 


 
 YSIENKIEW SparkPoints: ( 10,257 )
Fitness Minutes: (6,242)
 Posts: 
 153
 11/21/11 3:22 P 

 
 
 I always have a protein bar in my purse, just in case. I also bring a small cooler for water, snacks, sandwiches. I even bought a soup thermos to take some nice hot soup with me on the road. I pull into a rest stop for 15 minutes or so, use the restroom and enjoy some nice hot soup! I am on the road a lot for work and spend time out in the cold. Sometimes I get chilled all the way to the bone! Sitting for a few minutes to get warmed up and recharged really helps.




  current weight: 161.5  

   
 168 153.5 139 124.5 
 110 
 


 
 JBRAMWELL SparkPoints: ( 1,817 )
Fitness Minutes: (2,250)
 Posts: 4 
 11/21/11 2:11 P 

 
 Like several others have listed, we tend to pack a small ice chest with healthy snacks and a lunch (typically sandwiches and fruit). Not only is it healthier than most choices available off the interstate, it also saves time and money.




  current weight: 194.0  

   
 194 189.25 184.5 179.75 
 175 
 


 
 LJEINVT Posts: 1,399 
 11/20/11 10:36 P 

 
 I always take a cooler of bottled water, some Cabot 50 cal Reduced Fat Cheddar packets, pieces of fruit, protein bars/ and or drinks. sometimes I bring most back home, but I do not get caught unprepared and desperate.

 


 
 PATRICIAANN46 Posts: 5,749 
 11/20/11 8:45 P 

 
 
 I usually take a cooler filled with healthy snacks and lots of water. If not, I try to stop at a Wendy&apos;s or Subway, where I know the choices are usually healthy.

 


 
 CICELY360 Posts: 
 1,231
 11/20/11 3:29 P 

 
 
 have a little ice chest to have healthy snacks like fruits and veggies with you. If you have to eat at a store or fast food restaurant, study what&apos;s on the menu to make informed choices.

 


 
 LAURAB242 Posts: 141 
 11/20/11 10:25 A 

 
 
 I always carry WWW bars, Atkins bars,and Atkins
other snacks like nuts. When traveling I add veggies..

 Laura 


  Pounds lost: 52.6  

   
 0 36.25 72.5 108.75 
 145 
 


 
 SPARKCHRISTY SparkPoints: ( 5,284 )
Fitness Minutes: (4,137)
 Posts: 
 3
 11/20/11 10:08 A 

 
 
 I used to travel for a living (one year I was only home for 26 days - not counting weekends). I always packed my Shake-n-Go Smoothies from Vega and the shaker. I flew so I had to buy the almond milk when I landed, but a quick trip to Whole Foods or Fresh Market was worth it. I could buy the few things I needed and wanted to eat during that segment of my trip. Much cheaper than eating out every meal and healthier. I did find that traveling so much just got to me and I ate out more (and more often than not my travel included luncheons and dinner events so no chance to choose my own meal). The long hours made it hard to exercise too. Lessons Learned: Pack your own food; it&apos;s ok to skip the food at the luncheon (you can be an inspiration to others by bringing your own meal or requesting something healthy- even if you have to pay extra); don&apos;t overload your schedule so that you will have time for exercise...it&apos;s so important to take care of yourself.




  July Minutes: 0 

   
 0 90 180 270 
 360 
 


 
 7WORSHIPS Posts: 1,749 
 11/20/11 7:35 A 

 
 
 When on the road for a long period of time. I pack whatever is in my refrigerator. For example, if I was going to be traveling today I would pack some homemade hummus with separate bags of celery, red bell peppers, cukes and carrots. I also have some butternut squash I cooked yesterday, which I would warm and place in a thermos. I would probably also pack a few nuts ( pistachios and walnuts) and a large bag of salad greens. Now that I have started cooking more healthy dishes at home, it is easy to stay on track while traveling because I simply take whatever is in the house, thus avoiding letting food spoil when I am away.




  current weight: 142.0  

   
 146 139.5 133 126.5 
 120 
 


 
 KOALA_BEAR SparkPoints: ( 11,090 )
Fitness Minutes: (1,097)
 Posts: 488 
 11/20/11 12:23 A 

 
 
 I use Dr Andrew Lessman&apos;s Complete protein that mixes with water - hot or cold. It has the essential nturients in it. You can start your day with it for breakfast or have some as a snack to keep from getting too hungry. Comes in six flavors from vanilla, chocolate&amp;coffee to pina colada, PB&amp;berry.

If you work so many hours, you want what&apos;s easy to prepare like Hormel&apos;s shelf stable boxes of turkey chili&amp;beans. One 14.5 ozpackage is 210 calories and very filling so you could heat it up and place in a wide mouth thermos. A can of sardines in mustard sauce is a good option with some whole grain crackers or maybe a few slices of the cocktail size pumpernickel bread. Hummus&amp;a pita bread cut into 8 sections packs well; throw in a few black olives. Also good is a turkey and cheese whole wheat tortilla wrap. Cold chicken is fine by me - just grab a drumstick&amp;nibble. Excellent with a side salad. I like most salads - 3 bean, carrot, beet, cole slaw and SP recipes has all different ways to make them healthy and low calorie. Other leftovers should also pack well. How about left over meatloaf? You can make your sandwiches lower calorie by wrapping in large lettuce or cabbage leaves rather than bread; it&apos;s a nice change and allows you to still eat your favorite foods.

On weekends, consider making veggie based soups that you can heat up and take in a thermos. GORP and other trail mixes along with veggie stix and fruit snacks should give you plenty of variety and many healthy options. Applesauce and other fruit now come individually packed for lunches but are pricy - you can simply get larger cans and divide yourself once a week. Refridgerate then pack in the AM what kinds you want to take.

I would have two insulated containers - one for cold things; perishable foods, meats, cheeses, and some sandwiches plus drinks - and another perhpas thermos for hot foods; leftovers, and hot drinks like tea, coffe or cocoa. Just like life - you need balance - some savory, some spicey&amp;some sweet. Use your imagination&amp;ENJOY.

 K.bear 


  Pounds lost: 20.0  

   
 0 15 30 45 
 60 
 


 
 MORNINGWALKER Posts: 59 
 11/19/11 3:09 P 

 
 
 I take snack size baggies(when I fly) filled with nuts and dried fruit, sometimes a protein bar in case we are delayed very long.

 


 
 MELINDAM85 Posts: 499 
 11/19/11 12:09 P 

 
 I like the fresco items at Taco Bell. I also go to Subway and order Happy Meals at McDonald&apos;s.

 


 
 JMACLIVES SparkPoints: ( 11,329 )
Fitness Minutes: (2,932)
 Posts: 354 
 11/19/11 10:57 A 

 
 
 I like the &quot;grazing&quot; method when traveling, its easier on my system and I can control bathroom stops easier. Mostly bite sized veggies like celery, carrots, cucumbers and the like and then some nuts like almonds. If you grab a handful of veggies every hour or so you never reach the &quot;hungry so anything and everything sounds good&quot; stage and then when we stop at the end of the day we try to find a healthy restaurant to fill in the rest of the day&apos;s calories.

I also cut my calories back if I&apos;m going to be riding in a car all day, just sitting and staring at the road burns very little calories so I figure that day I don&apos;t need as much fuel.

 ~ June sparking in Mesa


Only You can make Every New Day seems so new. (Reese Roper) www.youtube.com/watch?v=pNmTa8iwLlA 


  Pounds lost: 24.0  

   
 0 16 32 48 
 64 
 


 
 CEDARBARK1 SparkPoints: ( 2,025 )
Fitness Minutes: (50)
 Posts: 831 
 11/19/11 8:31 A 

 
 
 You&apos;ll definitely save money by bringing your own food, since you do this road travel as a living.

You&apos;ll absolutely eat healthier too, because unadorned salads at the fast food places get boring fast and will be as hard to want to continue to eat as pb&amp;j;sandwiches (plus, who needs cardboard tomatoes and brown-edged iceberg lettuce every day?)

Ideas:

Hardboiled eggs, pre-peeled.
Olives, pitted (wipe them off ahead of time)
Seedless grapes
Grape tomatoes
Bananas
Veggie slices: say, cucumber, celery, etc.
Cheeses, say string cheese, or pre-cut chunks
Make your own trail mix (I like a mix of sunflower seeds and Trader Joe&apos;s pistachio meats; you can vary this up to your own tastes -- but make sure most of the ingredients are from unsalted packages)

Beverages: water, unsweetened ice tea, selzter/club soda.

In hot weather, it is handy to have a mini-cooler or cold box with one or two of those freezer packs -- they work amazingly well for keeping any fresh foods cool.

 Edited by: CEDARBARK1 at: 11/19/2011 (08:35) Exploring new and novel whole foods: low carbohydrate, Primal sort of lifestyle.

Just because you steam it, doesn&apos;t mean you can&apos;t add herbs and spices. (A gripe at those insipid restaurant &quot;healthy choice&quot; menu selections.)

 239 

My blog: goatsandgreens.wordpress.com 


  current weight: 188.0  

   
 224 214.25 204.5 194.75 
 185 
 


 
 SALLYANNE0852 Posts: 336 
 11/19/11 12:23 A 

 
 
 i dont eat on the road. but then i never drive more than 5 hours in a day anyway. I do bring water. I usually have something in the truck just in case. I like to bring cheese and crackers or a granola bar or something. I have IBS so eating and long distance driving arent a good thing.




  Pounds lost: 24.6  

   
 0 25 50 75 
 100 
 


 
 CHERYLSBUTT SparkPoints: ( 35,607 )
Fitness Minutes: (20,801)
 Posts: 
 1,318
 11/18/11 7:54 P 

 
 
 It is not as difficult as it once was...
I suggest bottled water, fruit and energy bars in the car.
Stop at restaurants and choose the healthy options

...
I promise, if you lay of the salt and sugar....you will feel much better when you get to your destination.

Take a look online at almost any restaurant and you can preplan choices that keep you on track!




  Pounds lost: 7.0  

   
 0 3.5 7 10.5 
 14 
 


 
 PATRICIAANN46 Posts: 5,749 
 11/18/11 7:51 P 

 
 
 I take a cooler filled with healthy snacks and lots of water.

 


 
 RUTHDEN1 SparkPoints: ( 46,639 )
Fitness Minutes: (31,256)
 Posts: 
 2,000
 11/18/11 1:48 P 

 
 
 Always a small cooler with cut up veggies, crackers and PB, water and breakfast bars.

 Ruth
-----------------------------May you live everyday of your life.
Jonathan Swift 


  Pounds lost: 15.0  

   
 0 6.25 12.5 18.75 
 25 
 


 
 SHOOPETTE SparkPoints: ( 32,553 )
Fitness Minutes: (15,593)
 Posts: 
 2,181
 11/18/11 9:45 A 

 

 
 
 I pack fruits and nuts as well as crackers

 www.youtube.com/watch?v=vY1tyOfna9s&amp;
feature=related 

 


  current weight: 141.0  

   
 183 169.25 155.5 141.75 
 128 
 


 
 SQUEEZE123 Posts: 98 
 11/17/11 9:00 P 

 
 
 I travel with children so I take a cooler bag for waters and a few juices. I also take a bag of fresh fruit, nuts, sandwiches, and eat and sandwich shops and grocery shop when we reach our destination. Eating out is a waste of money!!!!




  Pounds lost: 74.2  

   
 0 37.75 75.5 113.25 
 151 
 


 
 JODIHAFE SparkPoints: ( 912 )
Fitness Minutes: (525)
 Posts: 26 
 11/17/11 7:40 P 

 
 
 I travel every week for work, so here&apos;s some of what I pack:

Hard boiled eggs
String Cheese
Beef Jerky/Turkey Jerky
Thermos filled with chicken broth or WW Zero points soup, etc
If I&apos;m in the airport, I buy pistachios for the &apos;bored eating&apos; times cuz they take longer to eat!
Atkins Shakes that don&apos;t need refrigeration
Atkins Bars
Diet Swiss Miss (great for hotel rooms for a chocolatey treat at night!)
Fuit - it&apos;s Nature&apos;s To-Go Food
If I need to do fast food, I either get a grilled ckn sandwich and ditch the bun, or do the same with burgers, ditch the bun. Or a Cesar Salad with grilled chicken.
Sparkling water keeps me from wanting soda
Cut veggies with the single serving Hidden Valley Ranch to go dips

Hope this helps!





  Pounds lost: 4.0  

   
 0 31.75 63.5 95.25 
 127 
 


 
 JENJENN7 SparkPoints: ( 11,571 )
Fitness Minutes: (11,053)
 Posts: 
 238
 11/17/11 7:11 P 

 
 
 When my husband and I travel we carry a cooler, and pack fresh fruit and vegies and water. For the first day of the trip I try to make sandwiches for lunch. Dried apricots and almonds make a nutritious and no-mess snack. We usually stop for a coffee somewhere. Honey nut cheerios also make a great snack.

 &quot;Youve got to make your own life exciting. Youve got to make your own life real with promise. Youve got to learn how to stand up, walk through each day and believe each day!&quot; Graham Cooke
 


  July Minutes: 430 

   
 0 31 62 93 
 124 
 


 
 ERIN1957 Posts: 3,283 
 11/17/11 4:06 P 

 
 
 We travel a lot in our 5th wheel and the husband hates to stop and eat. So I pack light. No salty, no munchies sweet or salty snacks, no nuts...I can eat a ton, only proteins, veggies and a few low sugar fruits. I do drink my water and green teas and yes he must stop so I can pee. It is also good to move ever few hours and circulate that blood flow that gets pinched off, blood clots can kill.
Doing this every day, is a challenge. I would think in your situation, salads with proteins, yogurts, and berries. Granola and cereal items I would keep at a minimum. I would avoid fast food as much as you can. Processed as well. Clean and fresh, natural and light.
Good Luck and enjoy the journey.

 
Today I am grateful for a special friend like you.

God has poured out his love into our hearts. Romans 5:5 


  Pounds lost: 82.0  

   
 0 27.5 55 82.5 
 110 
 


 
 -DYET- SparkPoints: ( 74,017 )
Fitness Minutes: (51,113)
 Posts: 9,429 
 11/17/11 9:44 A 

 
 
 Great suggestions! Keep them coming




  July Minutes: 315 

   
 0 316.5 633 949.5 
 1266 
 


 
 KELLEY421 SparkPoints: ( 30,113 )
Fitness Minutes: (28,186)
 Posts: 1,319 
 11/17/11 8:06 A 

 
 
 Soups and stews kept hot in a thermos is a great idea!




  current weight: 147.0  

   
 203 184.75 166.5 148.25 
 130 
 


 
 RANNEG Posts: 15 
 11/16/11 10:55 P 

 
 
 Mc Donalds will also sell you a plain grilled chicken breast




  current weight: 240.2  

   
 275 256.25 237.5 218.75 
 200 
 


 
 CATDLK Posts: 678 
 11/16/11 9:28 P 

 
 
 I premake my own frozen meals. I can take them to work or heat them up just before I get in the car for a long commute. My breakfast pancakes are premade, can be heated in the toaster like a poptart and I can easily eat them with my fingers. In less than a couple hours I can make and individually portion out enough breakfasts and lunches to last me a couple of weeks. Totally keeps me on track! I have protein shakes ready to grab as well as preproportioned and measured baggies of my homemade nut mix or favorite veggie for snacking.




  Pounds lost: 5.0  

   
 0 5 10 15 
 20 
 


 
 REACHING4HOME Posts: 
 5,845
 11/16/11 4:59 P 

 
 
 Pack your own food whenever possible.

 &quot;Friends are angels that hold us up when our wings have forgotten how to fly&quot;

Erin
LEADER - IN IT FOR THE LONG HAUL 


  current weight: 227.0  

   
 282 261.5 241 220.5 
 200 
 


 
 SANFORMRN SparkPoints: ( 25,530 )
Fitness Minutes: (22,914)
 Posts: 
 1,069
 11/16/11 1:16 P 

 
 
 I eat a lot of salads and pile on all those different veggies I&apos;m too lazy to cut up at home (at least at one time)

 


 
 HAWKTHREE SparkPoints: ( 11,643 )
Fitness Minutes: (7,948)
 Posts: 445 
 11/16/11 10:00 A 

 
 
 I find myself on the road a lot as well. I heat soup and put it in a thermos.
I like celery for munching, but find it difficult to find it pre-cut. Hate washing it and cutting it myself.

I occasionally will stop at a grocery store and buy a bag of salad greens adn then munch on that for 100 miles.

Hard boiled eggs keep well and are very portable.

I&apos;ve used SparkPeople to find out calories/fat ahead of time of some fast foods. The Panera chicken soup is only 100 calories. Unfortunately my favorite Panera sandwich is 680 calories, so if I have enough calories to splurge, I&apos;ll buy half a sandwich.

Starbucks has pricey small bags of nuts that have about 200 calories.

I will buy a single breast of chicken at KFC and remove the skin.

 Life needs balance 


  current weight: 140.5  

   
 168 159.75 151.5 143.25 
 135 
 


 
 STORMY724 Posts: 4,925 
 11/16/11 9:44 A 

 If you have to stop a a restaurant, a grilled chicken salad with lite dressing on the side (dip the tines of your fork in the dressing for a tiny taste with each bite) is a good option. It will give you lean protein, veggies, fiber, and the dressing will have some fat.

Or stop at a grocery store. If it doesn&apos;t have prepared salads or a salad bar, you can usually buy one whole wheat roll (if it has a bakery) two slices of black forest ham at the deli counter ---or a grilled chicken breast if they have prepared foods, fruit, and skim milk or yogurt.

 &apos;I still have an insane drive to create and express myself and it&apos;ll never stop because I don&apos;t know how to stop it.&apos; ---Graham Nash

(Photo: Parque das Aves, Foz do Iguau, Brazil 8/24/11) 


  Pounds lost: 72.6  

   
 0 22.5 45 67.5 
 90 
 


 
 CORINNEMOMMY SparkPoints: ( 16,354 )
Fitness Minutes: (11,992)
 Posts: 2,839 
 11/16/11 5:12 A 

 
 I pack my food from now on. I want control over food.

 NO MORE EXCUSES WITH TEN MINUTE WORKOUTS!
 www.youtube.com/user/sparkpeople 


  current weight: 159.0  

   
 175 161.25 147.5 133.75 
 120 
 


 
 SPUNKYREDHEAD84 SparkPoints: ( 8,304 )
Fitness Minutes: (10,639)
 Posts: 89 
 11/15/11 9:26 P 

 
 
 Great suggestions!! I agree planning ahead is key, this has helped me soo many times. I also agree that it is really important to not wait to eat until you are starving, that for me always leads to snacking on unhealthy things.

 




  July Minutes: 491 

   
 0 150 300 450 
 600 
 


 
 GWENFITNESS1ST SparkPoints: ( 51,157 )
Fitness Minutes: (46,515)
 Posts: 1,117 
 11/15/11 7:48 P 

 
 
 So many restaurants have calorie reports if you just look for them...this will guide you!




  Pounds lost: 23.0  

   
 0 8.25 16.5 24.75 
 33 
 


 
 MAYBER Posts: 6,672 
 11/15/11 4:21 P 

 
 
 Great take along ideas but stopping along the way at resturants is an option too and just making good choices the same as the food in baggies one day/trip at a time




  current weight: 174.0  

   
 206 197 188 179 
 170 
 


 
 POSSIBLEPEN SparkPoints: ( 5,050 )
Fitness Minutes: (6,371)
 Posts: 
 66
 11/15/11 2:41 P 

 
 
 Your ideas are fantastic! I copied and pasted and sent this to all my friends! Thanks so much for sharing this! :o)


 The outside will finally match the inside! 


  current weight: 222.3  

   
 244 216.75 189.5 162.25 
 135 
 


 
 POSSIBLEPEN SparkPoints: ( 5,050 )
Fitness Minutes: (6,371)
 Posts: 
 66
 11/15/11 2:38 P 

 
 
 This is a fantastic topic. I am headed out of town soon and have been giving this a lot of thought myself. I am definitely cooking ahead and separating snacks (portion controlled) into baggies and bringing tons of water. I am also making sure to keep my gum on hand. When I chew gum and drink water it curbs my appetite.

 The outside will finally match the inside! 


  current weight: 222.3  

   
 244 216.75 189.5 162.25 
 135 
 


 
 GWENFITNESS1ST SparkPoints: ( 51,157 )
Fitness Minutes: (46,515)
 Posts: 1,117 
 11/14/11 11:15 P 

 
 
 Grab baggies filled with fruit or veggies




  Pounds lost: 23.0  

   
 0 8.25 16.5 24.75 
 33 
 


 
 COROZALOVE SparkPoints: ( 11,344 )
Fitness Minutes: (7,435)
 Posts: 254 
 11/14/11 1:21 P 

 
 Pack lots of water and fruit and healthy low-calorie snacks,this will help you to stay off high calorie very expensive doodahs that will undermine your food plan.

 They also serve,Who only stand and Wait.
John Milton 


 

   
 0 8.25 16.5 24.75 
 33 
 


 
 -DYET- SparkPoints: ( 74,017 )
Fitness Minutes: (51,113)
 Posts: 9,429 
 11/14/11 10:53 A 

 
 
 Great topic! I am preparing for a road trip and part of my family is too. These are great ideas!!




  July Minutes: 315 

   
 0 316.5 633 949.5 
 1266 
 


 
 WISDOM73 Posts: 487 
 11/14/11 6:59 A 

 
 
 Planning ahead is what works best for me. I make sure I have my lunch and snacks packed for travels. Eating before I get too hungry is a must.




  current weight: 118.0  

   
 123 121 119 117 
 115 
 


 
 MRS-HARPER SparkPoints: ( 7,303 )
Fitness Minutes: (5,493)
 Posts: 19 
 11/13/11 9:18 P 

 
 
 You and I have similar work situations even though they would appear very different.

I work in a casual dining restaurant. Actually, the most consistently worst ranked casual dining restaurant when it comes to health. Even the meats have trans fats . I don&apos;t know what&apos;s in them and I don&apos;t want to know!

I came armed ever day with a lunch box filled with healthy stuff. Crackers, fruits, vegetables, cheeses, yogurt, sandwiches, anything you want! It&apos;s so great cause I know exactly how many calories I have with me and the nutrient composition of my little bag. Now I don&apos;t know what I would do without it!

Everyone else has made a bunch of really great suggestions about supermarkets and making healthier choices at restaurants. The only thing I would add is that at first I was very tempted to abandon the healthy food I brought for my usual unhealthy fare. I understand how uNappetizing healthy stuff can seem next to French fries and burgers. For me, at least at the beginning, the key was to NOT LET MYSELF GET TOO HUNGRY before I ate. Once I was famished, my willpower was shot. So, as soon as I felt a little hungry I grabbed something to eat. Now that I&apos;m more accustomed to my bag of tricks, I still feel tempted but I have faith that the healthy stuff will satisfy.

Good luck! I understand that it seems really hard right now, but if you really want to find a solution you can work it out. Soon you will be that healthy person with the lunchbox full of real food! We should start a club!

 &quot;Any idiot can face a crisis - it&apos;s the day to day living that wears you out.&quot; --Chekhov 


  current weight: 153.2  

   
 165 160 155 150 
 145 
 


 
 ERINMARIE424 Posts: 2,119 
 11/13/11 7:53 P 

 
 
 There are a lot of awesome ideas - here&apos;s just two more from me:
Bean dip (either homemade or prepared) with veggies and/or multigrain chips (I like Food Should Taste Good multigrain)

Almond Butter (you&apos;re right, peanut butter gets old) - I like it on an Ezekiel tortilla with or without a bit of all fruit spread.

 
Erin - Cincinnati, OH

 


  current weight: 157.0  

   
 189 179 169 159 
 149 
 


 
 MADDUXCR SparkPoints: ( 12,781 )
Fitness Minutes: (14,107)
 Posts: 194 
 11/13/11 7:18 P 

 Keeping the huge cooler in the car packed with healthy goodies is a great idea. It&apos;s good to change things up too because celery sticks and carrots can get old fast. I thought this post was about keeping your diet in order when you have to fly a lot, which is also a real issue for me. I find if I keep my diet pretty much the same when I have to travel, I don&apos;t gain as much. When I eat more than salads at a lot of restaurants, I really have issues. Not only do I gain weight but I feel awful. Travelling a lot is hell on the diet, let&apos;s face it.

 


 
 KAPELAKIN Posts: 908 
 11/13/11 11:57 A 

 
 
 I used to work long days in remote areas where there was no chance of even finding a mini-mart much less fast food, so I&apos;ve got some experience with packing lunches. Get a good-sized cooler, not one of the dinky &quot;lunch&quot; sized ones. I think the one I have is for 12 cans, but I would go bigger if you are frequently packing for 12 hours on the road and want to fit in lots of veggies, which tend to demand space. Get some of the blue ice packs that will keep your food cold all day, and some good containers in a range of sizes that fit in your cooler.

From there, you can do all sorts of things. One of my favorites is making chicken, tuna or egg salad with fat-free Greek yogurt instead of mayo. The egg or chicken salad is great with curry powder and raisins instead of mustard for a change of pace. I like RyeVita crackers with that, but you might have a different favorite bread, or want to try sandwich thins. Bring ready to eat fruit (either things you can eat out of hand, or cut up in a container), cut up veggies with hummus or other healthy dip. Salads are also an option, but you&apos;ll probably want to keep some of the things separate until you&apos;re ready to eat, so that it doesn&apos;t get soggy. The tomatoes and other &quot;dense&quot; veggies like carrots, celery, cabbage, etc. can go in one container, and your greens in another. Salads are only limited by your imagination and what you like to eat, they can incorporate meat, beans, tofu, nuts and seeds, and grains. Quinoa works great in salads with tangy, lemony dressings and is a great carb choice.

Make sure to bring lots of water to drink, and some healthy alternatives if you&apos;re not big on water. When I&apos;m traveling I bring the single serving Crystal Light packets to flavor my water to disguise any funky tap water taste, which saves money on buying bottled water, but keeps me doing a better job of staying hydrated. A good thermos will keep coffee or tea hot most of the day if that is your preferred beverage.

 When you hit a wall - kick it in. ~Patti Smith
SW: 225 ; CW 168
Next Milestone Rewards:
165 -Kettlebell DVDs
160 (GW): New riding breeches, and a new driver&apos;s license with only one chin in the photo! 


 52 Days until: Half Around Payette Lake - 8.6 miler 

   
 100 75 50 25 
 0 
 


 
 JACQUES27 Posts: 8 
 11/13/11 11:23 A 

 
 Everyone has already posted really great ideas. I think that prep the night before is key. As well as investments in a cooler and a thermos. Also, I&apos;m not sure if you&apos;re eating while driving, but if you are, try to schedule in an extra 15 minutes to pull over at a park or somewhere safe - that will allow you to pack or buy healthier things that might require utensils instead of just eating burgers and fries (so a large salad or maybe some vegetable soup packed in a thermos).

I&apos;m not on the road, but have easy access to fast food at work. I also like to sleep until the last possible moment in the morning so if I don&apos;t do easy convenience type foods I won&apos;t pack lunch. My lunch staples:

Ants on a log (celery, peanut butter, and raisins) made the night before
Wheat crackers, string cheese, summer sausage, and grapes
String cheese or Babybel cheese
Granola bars
Trail Mix or other dried fruit and nuts
Pretzels
Tuna salad kits with crackers
Bananas
Apples
Applesauce
Turkey on wheat
Carrots and hummus
100 calorie packs of treats
Yogurt
Peeled hard boiled eggs (can usually find them in packs of two in the deli section)
Soup or chili in a thermos

Honestly, investing in a good thermos would open up a whole bunch of possibilities - soup, stew, chili, curry, oatmeal, pasta, stirfry and rice, leftovers, even hot dogs (bun packed separately).




  Pounds lost: 37.0  

   
 0 10.5 21 31.5 
 42 
 


 
 CARLAWILLDOIT Posts: 
 152
 11/13/11 8:26 A 

 
 
 I think preparation is the theme here. Make yourself aware of the healthy choices for the places you frequent the most and keep a cooler in the car of healthy snacks or a bag of protein bars and fruit to get you over hunger and cravings.

The more time you invest in exercise and in your &quot;car snacks&quot; the more you&apos;ll guard your choices while you&apos;re on the go.




  Pounds lost: 24.0  

   
 0 12.5 25 37.5 
 50 
 


 
 NIRERIN Posts: 9,752 
 11/13/11 8:16 A 

 
 if you like eating at fast food places, head to each place&apos;s website and start making a list of better options to keep in the car. that way all you need to do is pull out the list, pick an item [instead of looking at their menu] and you&apos;ve made a better choice because you planned it that way.

if you want more options, head to the grocery store [or a convenience store] instead of a fast food joint. my local grocery store has
-a deli counter where you can get made to order sandwiches, hot soups, premade sandwiches, hardboiled eggs, rotisserie chicken and sides. they often keep a little cooler with yogurts there too.
- a produce section where you can find premade salads and containers of cut up fruits or veggies.
- a seafood section where you can find sushi that you can grab and go.
- a dairy section where you can get cups of yogurt or yogurt smoothies or cottage cheese cups


and if you want to pack, you&apos;re only limited by the containers you have. they make cooler/heaters that plug into your car to keep things hot or cold. thermos makes a funtainer that has a wide mouth, holds 10oz and keeps foods hot or cold for up to 5 hours. an insulated lunchbox and ice packs are also a great help, as are any sort of portion sized containers. once you have those, the sky is pretty much the limit. i love this site laptoplunches.com because there are tons of recipes that are kid tested [they don&apos;t have access to fridges or microwaves either] and you don&apos;t have to buy the lunchbox to use the recipes. and on that note, head to the kid&apos;s lunchbox aisle at the store. you&apos;ll find things like peanut butter crackers and other individual portions of shelf stable foods [so that you can keep a bag of them in your car, that you just replenish periodically]. granola bars are excellent too [and can be paired with yogurt or fruit or cheese], and most stores carry shelf stable apple or pear sauce that has less than five ingredients. in a pinch cup of soups [check out what&apos;s available from brands like nile, health valley and dr. macdougalls. they have options like chili, lentil curry, black bean soup -25 g fiber in the big cup-, potato leek, that have pretty decent nutritional info and all you have to do is add hot water -which you can get at about any convenience station.]. there are also plain nuts and seeds or fruit, and i want to say there are many options of cheese that qualify too. so just look around and see what you can get, and keep some of it on hand.
if you go the packed route, plan to eat the more perishable items closer to the morning and save the shelf stable stuff for the afternoons [and don&apos;t be afraid to plan to stop by a grocery and pick up something like yogurt or cottage cheese to complement the shelf stable stuff].

and again, once you have containers, leftovers are the easiest lunch ever.

 -google first. ask questions later.

 


 
 SUSANK16 SparkPoints: ( 27,207 )
Fitness Minutes: (37,686)
 Posts: 218 
 11/13/11 8:04 A 

 
 I like the prior suggestion but also I would suggest that you go to the
Spark people eating out guide. There are some better choices at fast
food places. Last week when I forgot my lunch, I found a subway and
had a turkey with vegetables on wheat which is pretty good calorie wise
and followed it up with a yogurt and fruit parfait. I had read on line
that those were good choices prior to ordering.

 


 
 REENIE131 SparkPoints: ( 33,318 )
Fitness Minutes: (18,686)
 Posts: 
 1,220
 11/13/11 8:02 A 

 
 
 I second the idea of keeping a cooler in the car with things like cooked eggs(already peeled) and string cheese in it. How about protien bars? I love Clif bars, they&apos;re filling and come in a lot of varieties. Luna bars are good too. Fruit is easy to keep on hand too.




  Pounds lost: 39.6  

   
 0 12.5 25 37.5 
 50 
 


 
 MPLANE37 SparkPoints: ( 26,777 )
Fitness Minutes: (15,055)
 Posts: 
 1,239
 11/13/11 2:28 A 

 
 
 - You could prepare your next day&apos;s food in the evening, and keep it in a portable cooler in the car...
- Instead of fast food restaurants, you could stop by others (like Whole Foods) where you can get your healthy food to go.


 ``Don&apos;t break the chain.&quot; -Jerry Seinfeld 


  current weight: 187.0  

   
 227 213.25 199.5 185.75 
 172 
 


 
 CHICO227 Posts: 
 1
 11/13/11 1:28 A 

 
 
 Hello All, Wondered if I might get some good advice. I inspect houses for a living, driving all day from one house to the next. Normally I spend 8-12 hours a day in my car. Because of this I have found myself stopping everyday at fast food resturants for lunch. I am looking for tips or ideas of better, healthier lunchs that might also help my wallet some.

I am always on the go, so to stop at an actual resturant is kinda out of the question. And I find I am limited on things I can bring and keep in the car, cause no way to warm anything up and PBJ sandwhichs get old real fast. Please share any ideas, would love to stop eating all this bad food....

 


 
   Page: 1 of (1)   [ 1 ]   
 

 


Thread URL: http://www.sparkpeople.com/myspark/messageboard.asp?imboard=7&amp;imparent;=25954057

 Review our Community Guidelines 



 
Other Diet and Nutrition Topics:

 Anyone on the 21 day detox (holistic nutrition)? 6/18/2012 12:25:52 PM Eating Healthier While Working The Graveyard Shift 7/12/2012 9:51:10 AM Fat Burning Tea 6/1/2012 12:41:35 PM Green Bags--Godsend or Wasted Money? 6/7/2012 12:28:32 AM getting the right amounts for balance 6/14/2012 2:27:18 PM 
   
 
 7 Key Nutrients Vegetarians Need to Watch 
Meat-free doesn&apos;t always mean it&apos;s healthy. If you&apos;re vegetarian, or eat your share of meatless meals, make sure you&apos;re getting enough of these important nutrients.
 Read More 
 Which food do you find you rely on a lot Listening to your body! any CSA members? How do you deal with stress when dieting The BEST Advice I&apos;ve Received from Spark is...? 
 View Demo Single Leg Standing Balance with Isometric Leg Lift 
 Soft-Serve Banana Ice Cream 
Submitted By: SP_STEPF 
Frozen bananas rival soft serve when given a whirl in the food processor. My brother and boyfriend loved this treat! Trust me, it&apos;s AMAZING: no fat, no cholesterol, no added sugar, just creamy and sweet bananas!
 Full Recipe 
 Search Over 200k Healthy Recipes:   Search 
 Calories Burned: 24,965,545,936 Pounds Lost: 20,174,210 Cups Water Drank: 429,570,708 SparkAmerica Minutes: 2,645,599,943 
 Get a personalized diet and fitness plan, great newsletters, post to our message boards, and even your own personal SparkPage!

 Join Now For Free! 

 Home | My Tools | Resources | Community | Blogs | Healthy Recipes | About Us | Announcements | Store | Help Desk 

 Popular calorie searches: twizlers calories | portabella burger | calories in diet cocoa | rice cakes lightly salted calories | grilled chicken cutlet | calories in mcdonald sausage | mcdonalds bacon egg calories | peas | calories in bara | yoplait light orange creme 

Food Versus Food: Bagel Versus Wheat Tortilla   Bagel Versus Pasta   Bagel Versus Flour Tortilla  

 Advertising/Sponsorship 

Copyright SparkPeople, Inc. 2012, All Rights Reserved | Terms and Conditions | Privacy Policy | About Our Ads 

 Free Diet | Calorie Counter | Pregnancy | Weight Loss Forum Archives | The Spark Book 

SparkPeople, SparkPages, SparkPoints, SparkTeams, SparkDiet, SparkAmerica, SparkRecipes, DailySpark,
and other marks are trademarks of SparkPeople, Inc. All Rights Reserved.
SPARKPEOPLE is a registered trademark of SparkPeople, Inc. in the United States, European Union, Canada, and Australia. All rights reserved.

 NOTE: Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy update on February 8, 2012 
 
 close X 
 Sign up for SparkPeople Deals! 
Deep discounts on healthy-living products 
 Featured Today 
 Featured Article: 7 Key Nutrients Vegetarians Need to Watch dailySpark Blog: The Popularity Contest: Why Losers Might Finish First Featured Recipe: Soft-Serve Banana Ice Cream 
 
 
 Like Us On Facebook 
 
 Like Us On Facebook — 
 
 
 
 Login 
 
 Get a Free Diet Plan 
 
 Tell a Friend!
	</body>
</document>
