<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009011" url="http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/100784" time="2012-07-13-02:25" support="1" score="0.00126886451384256" bingtitle="Weber&apos;s Burgers - Ontario (including Toronto) - Chowhound" webtitle="Weber&apos;s Burgers - Ontario (including Toronto) - Chowhound">
			<query id="000692" bing-rank="171"/>
	<description>You park, stand in ... Rail passenger car that they use for their indoor seating. Kind of fun, if a little bit long in the tooth after years of being a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Log in / Sign Up Entire Site 
 Entire Site Chowhound Recipes Stories Video 
 CHOW 
 Follow @CHOW videos 
 All Videos Supertaster CHOW Tips You&apos;re Doing It All Wrong My Go-To Obsessives The Easiest Way 
 recipes 
 All Recipes Quick&amp;Easy Fun DIY Projects Main Dishes Sweets Recipe Slideshows 
 Blogs 
 CHOW Daily Best of Chowhound 
 chowhound discussions 
 All Boards Home Cooking Manhattan San Francisco Bay Area Los Angeles Area Philadelphia Greater Boston Area Southern New England Ontario (including Toronto) B.C. (including Vancouver) 
 
 HOME &gt; Chowhound &gt; Ontario (including Toronto) Save This Board &gt; 
 Email Print 
 
Weber&apos;s Burgers
 
are north of toronto on the way to cottage country i hear?
a lot of hype surrounding their burgers from what im hearing....any thoughts? anyone tried them?
thanks.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Sam I Am on Jul 28, 2004 02:35 PM 
Updated on Aug 20, 2009

 31 Replies 
 
 
Hwy 11 in Orillia, a bridge crosses south and northbound traffic so you can park on either side.

Try their Pearson terminal 3 location if you&apos;re not sure if it&apos;s hype, but if you&apos;re going up north this long weekend be prepared for a long wait in line.

I like Webers myself (not a big meat eater either) and try to visit the Hwy 11 spot once a year at Thanksgiving before they close up for the season.

Link: http://www.webersrestaurants.com/home... 
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Derek on Jul 28, 2004 03:04 PM 
 re: Derek 
I USED to really enjoy Weber&apos;s.....but.....I have been a few times over the last several years, and honestly, I can&apos;t remember why I was ever excited! I find the burgers to be oversalted, thin, and more filler than beef.

JMHO.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Cheech5001 on Jul 28, 2004 03:14 PM 
 re: Cheech5001 
Weber&apos;s is over rated. I think Super Burger, NW corner of Hwy 89 and Hwy 10, is far superior. The best and most deliscious BIG burgers, and they even have a train... or is it a subway car? The atmoshpere and experience is not as unique as weber&apos;s but there&apos;s hardly any line and the food is way better.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Alison on Jul 29, 2004 01:35 PM 
 re: Alison 
Interesting, I am often forced to stop at Super Burger and really am not that impressed with it! Ordinary burger, chicken breasts and souvlaki, fries very light coloured, chunky with no peel so they get soggy quickly. The lineup even when longish does move quickly, I&apos;ll give them that. I thought the Weber&apos;s at the airport was actually a little better, although maybe it was just the novelty, vs. the enforced stop at Super Burger sometimes twice in a weekend...
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By anon on Jul 29, 2004 03:50 PM 
 re: anon 
Super Burger is in Primrose (near Shelburne), and I agree with anon, nothing special but, like Weber&apos;s, is a bit of an institution.

They have encorporated an old TTC streetcar into the restaurant.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Mississauga Matt on Aug 3, 2004 08:36 AM 
 re: Mississauga Matt 
Just stopped at Webers on the way back to TO this weekend...food is average and kinda pricey- two burgers, two drinks and two fries for $18!!! Love the clean lawn they have. Not worth the trip up the highway but a nice pit stop if you happen to be passing by.

I thought I saw a Webers at the airport in one of the terminals.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By LoveToEat on Aug 5, 2004 09:36 AM 
 re: LoveToEat 
As previously stated, it&apos;s not really worth a stop unless your kids and dog are driving you nuts and they need a place to stretch their legs. I&apos;d suggest the double burger. It&apos;s not that bad.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By peter on Aug 16, 2004 10:51 AM 



 
 
 
 re: Derek 
There is a Weber&apos;s in Barrie as well.
It faces the lake.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By erley on Jul 28, 2004 05:50 PM 
 re: erley 
And does anyone know how they compare to the US chain White Castle?
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Maureen on Jul 29, 2004 12:24 PM 

 
 
 
Reasonably good burgers; not better than any other independant burger joint in the city.
Reasonably bad fries (plain old frozen .... yuck!)with a sprinkling of what looks like Lowry&apos;s seasoned salt.

I Never could understand the buzz about this place.
I guess after a weekend in the woods people are hungry enough to eat anything!

Having said that, I still stop there .... a tradition, I suppose ....
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Stewart on Jul 28, 2004 03:17 PM 

 
Check out the previous Weber&apos;s discussion below.

Link: http://www.chowhound.com/topics/show/... 
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Meatloaf Mix on Jul 28, 2004 03:21 PM 

 
As someone said, it&apos;s the tradition. You park, stand in line, slather ketchup or mustard on the perfectly adequate burger (nothing special, in other words) and eat it on the lawn, or even back in the car. It marks the end of the weekend, or the beginning of the weekend, or whatever. Not worth going out of your way for, but better than your average route-to-cottage-country food. Enjoy.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By jhg on Jul 28, 2004 08:26 PM 

 
Weber&apos;s on HWY 11 is not bad at all, I agree.
Line up ehh...?!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By dionysus&amp;maenad on Jul 28, 2004 10:54 PM 

 
The big draw for me (and now my children) has always been the trains. They have maybe half a dozen actual trains that they&apos;ve moved to the site that give the place a certain ambience that just seems to fit. In the&quot;old&quot;days, kids used to be able to climb all over the caboose... no more, thanks, no doubt, to liability concerns. But they do have a 50&apos;s era Via Rail passenger car that they use for their indoor seating. Kind of fun, if a little bit long in the tooth after years of being a fast food restaurant seating area. Also a large yard with lots of picnic tables, clean and nicely sodded.

Also, people stop here to let their dogs stretch their legs. They have an actual, working old-style water pump hooked up to a well where you can bring up H2O for your pooch and get a workout yourself.

The burgers: utilitarian. The ambience serves to make them taste better. And don&apos;t be too deterred by lineups: they have a tried and true system to make &apos;em move quick. As others have said, I stop here often, possibly more out of duty and tradition than anything else.

alan
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Alan on Jul 29, 2004 10:55 AM 
 re: Alan 
New owners at Webbers I believe.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By mernie on Jul 29, 2004 11:53 AM 

 
 
Ya the buzz, I never got that either although it is nothing special there really is NO where else to stop and eat. I am jealous of the hwy 11 people my cottage is up 69 and we have no where to stop unless you go into Parry Sound...just not the same
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Scott on Jul 30, 2004 11:31 AM 

 
It&apos;s a burger place... on a stretch of road where you see nothing but trees and old farms. If it wasn&apos;t for the hype (and the subsequent curious lineup) it could be missed or dismissed altogether. That said, the burger IS okay and you can have the satisfaction of telling your friends that you&apos;ve been there.

Also on the brightside, it looks like a place where you can go during a family road trip and not wonder if you have suddenly stepped into the wrong part of town.

If you are en route, hungry and don&apos;t mind a long line, it&apos;s fine; yet, I wouldn&apos;t bother making it the reason for your trip.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By juniorcruz on Jul 25, 2006 03:19 PM 

 
Weber&apos;s got purchased by a large frozen / processed food conglomerate years ago. There is absolutely no reason to stop there anymore, unless you like lineups, screaming kids, barking dogs and passable food.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Cereal Killer on Jul 25, 2006 03:39 PM 

 
I sit corrected - it wasn&apos;t a large conglomerate (for some reason I thought it was now owned by Versafood Services), but things did change when they got sold a couple of years ago. Keep driving. Unless your kids need to pee.

Webers burgers in new hands
Last updated Mar 11 2004 11:54 AM EST
CBC News

A landmark restaurant popular with cottage-bound vacationers for the past 40 years has been sold to new owners.

Webers, a hamburger stand on Highway 11 near Orillia, has become an institution among the thousands of summer motorists who travel along the cottage-country route.

Paul Weber sold the family-owned restaurant to local businessman Tom Rennie this week.

Weber, who took over the drive-in restaurant from his father Paul Weber Sr. in 1978, said the time seemed right to sell.

The new owner promised he wouldn&apos;t tamper with the formula of home cooking and friendly service that has contributed to the restaurant&apos;s success.

Rennie said many of the staff, including 40-year veteran grill chef Mike McParland, would be back on the job when it re-opens for business Thursday.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Cereal Killer on Jul 25, 2006 04:22 PM 

 
On a fairly recent Vinyl Cafe on CBC radio the host mentioned a mom&amp;pop burger joint in the town near Weber&apos;s. Stuart McLean said they served better burgers in a nicer place for less money. Anybody have a clue where he meant? I&apos;ve been seeking the answer ever since.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Googs on Jul 25, 2006 07:23 PM 
 re: Googs 
I stood in line ONCE for Weber&apos;s out of pure curiousity and I have to say...I don&apos;t get it! Horrible, unsatisfying food. I actually think McDonald&apos;s is better!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By starvin on Jul 26, 2006 01:52 PM 

 re: Googs 
A few years back we’re heading up north and as we pass the crowds at Weber’s I get a hunger for a burger, but I’m damned if I’m going to stop and line up in that mob scene.

But wouldn’t you know it, less than a mile down the road there’s this little shack of a place that has a big sign saying The Toronto Star rated their burgers the best.

So what the heck, we stop and get out at this “mom&amp;pop” place. They have the article from The Star pinned on the wall, and it’s from ... 1972!

But we’re there, so we order, and the burgers are of the same quality as Weber’s, maybe slightly better, but again, nothing to get excited about.

I tip my hat to the owners for the sheer chutzpah of displaying that sign.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Mississauga Matt on Aug 30, 2006 01:52 PM 

 
 
Passed Weber&apos;s on the way to the Lake this weekend. The line-up was horrendous so we didn&apos;t stop. I never understood the hype about this place, other than that about 15 years ago, it was the only place to stop for something to eat north of Barrie. Now there are plenty of other places, including all the fast food chains.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By thenurse on Jul 26, 2006 05:09 PM 

 
The burgers are just very average - thin little patties, averaage buns and the usual condiments. Nothing special really - I think the attraction is that it is part of the&quot;cottage experience&quot;really. That and the fact that it is easy on-easy off from the highway. Don&apos;t go out of your way to go there.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ggirl on Aug 30, 2006 07:09 AM 

 
If you don&apos;t want to take the trek, but are still interested in giving webers burgers a try, they now sell frozen patties at the grocery store. I was a box at Loblaws last week.

Its an alright place, kids probably appreciate it more, and its cool to walk across the highway in the old skywalk they bought from TO. But thats about it. Nice atmosphere, average burger, decent fries. . . .like the seasoning on them.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By pancake on Aug 30, 2006 09:51 PM 

 
Wildly over-rated, IMO. Go to the Lick&apos;s in Barrie.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By francelonian on Aug 31, 2006 11:05 AM 
 re: francelonian 
Ate a great burger at Webers in August of 2009. Double Cheeseburger, with crispy fries, and a malted shake. Can&apos;t beat that!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By dharma on Aug 19, 2009 06:02 PM 
 re: dharma 
I agree with the over rated...never knew what the draw was with this place..been twice years apart and both average or sub par....people draw to it like cattle herding to the lineup thinking something is great and then believing it because why would all the other cattle be there?
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ebay3392 on Aug 20, 2009 05:49 AM 
 re: ebay3392 
I went here once on the way to Muskoka when I was cooking up there. I waited in line for 45 minutes, and it was NOT worth it.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Marumari on Aug 20, 2009 09:05 AM 
 re: Marumari 
For 23 years I have been going to Webers and never have I stood in line for longer than 20 minutes. They have a system that even with a line 100 people deep they can fire you through quickly (especially when they have both grills fired up). Its not the best food, but they do a different variation of salt on the fries, and with a double cheese burger they get the patty to bun ratio correct. I enjoy it due to tradition, munchies from the car ride, the fact my dog can run to his hearts content while I fill up and when meeting people I dont have to be precise with directions...&quot;Drive till you see the orange bridge and lots of people&quot;.

Perfect? No.
Good? Extremely.

that article posted has put a few questions in my head, most notably wondering if the family across the lake from me with the same name has purchased it....
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By craigger on Aug 20, 2009 12:09 PM 
 re: craigger 
It seems the perfect burger may be the most subjective thing we write about on this board. More difficult to define than the finest of haute cuisine. Some day we may have to agree to disagree.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Googs on Aug 20, 2009 07:21 PM 


 
 
 
 
 
 «Back to the Ontario (including Toronto) Board Back to the Top | Reply to original post 
Discussions You Might Also Like...
 The Burger&apos;s Priest - Queen and Coxwell (517 replies) 1 Burger&apos;s Priest vs. Holy Chuck vs. Stockyards (166 replies) 2 Hero Certified Burgers....What the $^%#!!!!! (136 replies) 3 Can&apos;t find what you&apos;re looking for? Start your own discussion now . 
 Most Recent Discussions 
 
Thursday, July 12, 2012 replies 
 
 7 

 Best Sichuan and Hunan in GTA? 

32 minutes ago
 
 5 

 Big-Belly Clams 

32 minutes ago
 
 6 

 Bloor Street Diner 

about 1 hour ago
 
 5 

 Pistachio paste/butter in the... 

about 1 hour ago
 
 2 

 White Brick Kitchen (Bloor and... 

about 1 hour ago
 
 116 

 Cheap and Dirty: Thrifty Dive... 

about 2 hours ago
 
 Videos 
 How to Make an Easy Margarita 
 Recipe Slideshows 

 17 Juicy Burger Recipes See All 19 Recipes» 
 
 »Videos » Supertaster Daily: Vegemite » How to Make an Easy Margarita » Supertaster Daily: Taco Bell&apos;s Cantina Bell Menu » Supertaster Daily: The Seattle-Style Hot Dog » How to Tell How Much Propane Is Left for Your Gas Grill » NY CHOW Report: Bud Light–Battered Fish Po&apos; Boy at Motorboat&amp;the Big Banana 
 
 »Recipes » Road Trip Munchies » French-y Picnic Recipes for Bastille Day » Cold Dishes for Hot Weather » Pine Cone Punch » Homemade Chocolate Graham Cracker S&apos;mores » Campfire Breakfast Toad in the Hole 
 
 »Blogs » Quirky in Queens: Panorama of My Silence-Heart Café » All&apos;Angolo: Tasty Italian Pasta in LA&apos;s Koreatown » Should Lamb Have a Strong Taste? » The Diss, Updated: Calling Asian Food&quot;Hipster&quot; » Anyone in the Bay Area Still Making Mandarin Pressed Duck? » Amazing Espresso in Orange County 
 
 »Discussion » What is your biggest recipe pet peeve? » Chicken broth vs stock Info?? » Vietnamese Pho Soup » Restaurant near Fairfield Inn and Suites » Punjabi Tandoor--what to order » Fast help! Lunch, downtown Chicago tomorrow! 
 
 About/Contact CHOW | Feedback 
 FOLLOW CHOW 
 facebook twitter google plus pinterest youTube rss 
 CBS Cares | CBS Films | CBS Radio | CBS.com | CBSInteractive | CBSNews.com | CBSSports.com | CHOW | Clicker | CNET | College Network | Find Articles | GameSpot | Help.com | Last.fm | MaxPreps | Metacritic.com | Moneywatch | mySimon | Radio.com | Search.com | Shopper.com | Showtime | SmartPlanet | TechRepublic | The Insider | TV.com | UrbanBaby.com | ZDNet 
CBS Entertainment | About CBS Interactive | Jobs | Advertise 

©2012 CBS Interactive Inc. All rights reserved. | Privacy Policy | Ad Choice | Terms of Use 
 X 
Log In
 USERNAME / EMAIL PASSWORD Remember me Join CHOW | Forgot your password? X 
Sign Up
 USERNAME EMAIL PASSWORD CONFIRM PASSWORD 
Choose Newsletters

 CHOW Announcements CHOW Partner Offers Recipe of the Day CHOW Latest Stories Weekly Recipes 
 THE DIGEST - The best of Chowhound 
 San Francisco Bay Area New York City Los Angeles Area Home Cooking Boston 
 Username is public and once confirmed, is unchangeable. By clicking the SIGN UP button, you agree to CHOW&apos;s terms of use and have read and understand our privacy policy . Share with your friends X 
 TO: FROM: MESSAGE: 
 Share &quot;Weber&apos;s Burgers&quot;
	</body>
</document>
