<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009685" url="http://getwrite2it.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-13-03:04" support="1" score="0.0011028175026972693" bingtitle="Write down the line" webtitle="Write down the line">
			<query id="000245" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>SIDEBAR 2: The fast food restaurant chain’s new slogan is &quot;Exciting things are happening at ... you publish theoretical and based on conditions that customers have no shot ...</description>
	<body>
		Write down the line
 
 
 
 Monday, May 28, 2012 
 
 In honor of those who died to protect our freedoms 
 
 

 

 

 

 I fly the Stars and Stripes for you. 

 And I thank you. 

 del.icio.us Tags: United States Memorial Day Holiday 
 Posted by Brian Beasley at 10:55 AM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Inspiration , Leaders 
 Thursday, May 24, 2012 
 
 There’s no such thing as free marketing 
 
I attended a Meetup earlier this week entitled, Marketing Without Dollars . I went into the assemblage loaded for bear because I abhor the idea, belief or notion that marketing can be accomplished without money. 

It quickly became apparent that the presenter wasn’t purporting to possess radical ideas for moving products through various channels and into the buyer’s open arms without spending a dime driving awareness and demand.

No. He stated emphatically (well, for a kind and soft-spoken man, it was meant to be emphatic) that marketing is more a mindset than a skillset…especially for small and emerging businesses. He focused primarily on image and how business people and businesses present and conduct themselves, actively and passively, throughout each and every day.

 Examples: 

 Swept floors and clean restrooms Well manicured lawns Company vehicles neatly aligned in the parking lot Precisely organized product displays Crisp professional company uniforms Courteous and attentive receptionists Visible and sincere participation in civic events 

He categorized all of these as free marketing activities.

The presenter was really talking about image, perception and brand management. Marketing is much broader and comprised of many complex disciplines. Company culture, public perception and brand are aspects of marketing, and quite important ones at that, but few if any businesses of any size and maturity can succeed or survive by putting most of their energy into these“marketing without dollars”activities.

It’s wise to pay attention to them, though.

But are any of them really free? I say no. Do you agree?
 del.icio.us Tags: marketing , perception , image , corporate culture Posted by Brian Beasley at 8:44 PM 1 comment: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Brand Management , Branding 
 Wednesday, May 16, 2012 
 
 You can handle the truth 
 
Do you believe everything you read? Do you trust statistics? Do you casually accept the interpretation of surveys and those that report them as unbiased?

Me either.

Why is that? Could it be because we’ve been mislead too often; burned too many times?

I suspect so. We’ve all come to understand that individuals and groups with a particular agenda choose to dissect data or select certain portions of a study that supports their philosophy and present that information as the complete picture. Generally, what they fail to convey is the numbers are only a slice of the pie. They’ve skewed the truth in their favor.

It’s disingenuous and it fosters mistrust.

Consider the damage it does to your company and your brand when you ask a copywriter to make an unsubstantiated claim to close a gap or secure a competitive advantage. The truth will eventually emerge, and your reputation will be smeared. Customers may walk. Partners too.

So why risk your reputation? Take the high road. Win because your product or service is superior and your customer service puts your competitors to shame. You’ll protect your honor and the dignity of all, including copywriters, who are working vigorously to ensure your product and company succeeds.

 Disclosure: this post was originally published on 10/20/2011 
 del.icio.us Tags: truth , honesty , integrity , trust Posted by Brian Beasley at 8:31 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Copywriting , Power of Words 
 Tuesday, May 15, 2012 
 
 The long and winding road to overnight success 
 
 Knock, knock.
Who’s there?
Success.
Success who?
Overnight success…you started your new venture yesterday, so here I am. 
 
No one is an overnight success.

Businesses are not an overnight success.

Success is preceded by immeasurable blood, sweat and tears over long periods of time. Individuals put their hearts and souls into something they believe in immensely in the hopes others will value their product or service. A viable business may eventually take hold for the lucky and the fortunate. Most efforts take years to achieve market acceptance and modest year-on-year growth.

 Steve Martin said,“ Be so good they can’t ignore you .”

It’s sage advice for businesses as well as individuals. A relentless pursuit of excellence will get you noticed. Your verve, passion and commitment will reap rewards. Success will find you.

Just don’t expect success to find you overnight.
 del.icio.us Tags: overnight success , commitment to excellence , business success Posted by Brian Beasley at 8:53 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Inspiration 
 Monday, May 14, 2012 
 
 I will not be ignored! 
 
 “Be so good they can’t ignore you.”  
 ̶   Steve Martin
 
This quote is making the rounds on Pinterest and blogs lately. It is attributed to the incomparable Mr. Steve Martin, actor, musician and comedian. Mr. Martin spoke these words during an interview he gave to Charlie Rose . It aired nearly four and a half years ago on December 12, 2007.

Talk about sticky, this message definitely has staying power. Perhaps Mr. Martin should have been an ad executive, or a brand manager. I have no doubt he would have been stellar in either capacity.

 Perhaps the quote was Mr. Martin’s credo. He’s lived a brilliant life, excelling at most things he’s chosen to pursue. He first burst onto the scene in the 1970’s as a clever comedian, evolved into an excellent actor and later gained critical acclaim as a banjo player.

Mr. Martin didn’t remake himself. He made a conscious career and life decision to not be a one trick pony. So he committed himself to the things he loved, worked very hard and honed his skills. Mr. Martin’s work ethic paved the path to his success.

He became so good as a comic, actor and musician, that they simply couldn’t ignore him.

We all should be able to do the same with at least one professional pursuit. Agreed?
 del.icio.us Tags: Steve Martin , commitment to excellence , career choice Posted by Brian Beasley at 9:10 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Inspiration , Leadership 
 Friday, May 11, 2012 
 
 Scoreboard!...no wait…word!…wait…forget it 
 
I’ve never been hip to slang, street language, urban speak or other forms of non-standard language. Words from those worlds that were mainstreamed eluded me.

 Example: for the longest time, I didn’t fully grasp the meaning of scoreboard! Friends used it in a vain attempt to end an argument.

“ Scoreboard!” one would shout.

 “Huh? What does a scoreboard have to do with a disagreement over who is the greatest rock-n-roll guitarist,” I thought to myself.

The verbal sparring continued, so my question was never answered for me.

I sort of figured it out in recent years on the softball field when opponents full of attitude would be chirping at us about their superiority while we piled on the runs. My guys didn’t jaw with them, but in the dugout I’d hear scoreboard spoken softly amongst the team.

We had substantially more runs. The team that scores the most runs wins. That’s a fact. Numbers on the scoreboard are cold hard facts. They represent the truth.

 Word! 

I speak the truth.

From Urban Dictionary : 
&quot;Word&quot; is the shortened form of the phrase: &quot;my word is my bond&quot; which was originated by inmates in U.S. prisons. The longer phrase was shortened to &quot;word is bond&quot; before becoming &quot;word,&quot; which is most commonly used. It basically means &quot;truth.&quot; Or &quot;to speak the truth.&quot;
 
And no, I didn’t understand what the heck people meant when the exclaimed “Word!” 
It will be a sign of the apocalypse when I see “Scoreboard!” or “Word!”  in business communications.

 del.icio.us Tags: words , street slang , urban speak , scoreboard Posted by Brian Beasley at 10:16 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Language , Power of Words , Vocabulary , Words 
 Thursday, May 10, 2012 
 
 My word, who needs the aggravation 
 
A favorite online reference of mine is dictionary.com . I use it frequently for this blog and when I come across unfamiliar words during my online reading.

Hey, it happens.

A feature on the site is Word of the Day . For the most part, I’ve ignored it. Why? So many of the words are quite obscure, which means I’ll rarely have occasion to use them. That’s aggravating, and I don’t need more aggravation in my life.

I felt out of character today, so I glanced at the Word of the Day–obtest–and was immediately stumped. I’ve never seen the word in textbooks, articles, editorials, periodicals, novels and others reading materials, nor have I heard it uttered in any context.

Have you?



The definition

 obtest   \ ob-TEST \ , verb; 


 To supplicate earnestly; beseech. To invoke as witness. To protest. To make supplication; beseech. 

Quite frankly, the first definition confuses me. Supplicate means to humbly entreat, petition or request; beseech conveys a sense of urgency. I think the tone of voice when one supplicates would be much more demure and deferential than when one urgently beseeches, which hints at subtle manipulation to bend another’s will in one’s favor.

Today I learned a word that confuses me. A word that confuses me is unusable. So much for avoiding more aggravation in my life.
 del.icio.us Tags: word , word of the day , definition , dictionary Posted by Brian Beasley at 8:54 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Power of Words , Word Choice , Words , Writing Older Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 
Followers
 
 
About Me
 Brian Beasley View my complete profile 
Blog Archive
 
 ▼  2012 (100) 
 ▼  May (14) 
 In honor of those who died to protect our freedoms... There’s no such thing as free marketing You can handle the truth The long and winding road to overnight success I will not be ignored! Scoreboard!...no wait…word!…wait…forget it My word, who needs the aggravation Take my word for it Rain on me Don’t speak ill of the brand Branding at the speed limit The more things change, the more the brand stays t... Am I missing something? Be careful how you speak 
 

 ►  April (21) 
 If you can write, thank a teacher Give your personal brand a purpose Build personal brand cache through actions, not wo... Meet your personal brand manager Your personal brand travels with you What you see online isn’t necessarily what you get... The brand of the people Tennis anyone? Copywriting anyone? Hear ye! Hear ye! Come one, come all There’s a story in there somewhere Have it your way Burger King Stick with what works It’s in their ad, it must be true Advertising, sustainability and the voice of a new... A slow news day? There isn’t an app for that A network of a different social It’s just a fantasy Can I pique your Pinterest? Difficult work beats hard labor every time Colorful content captures customers You take chances, I’ll take opportunities 
 

 ►  March (22) 
 Weekend work I’ll lend you my ear synonym girl Word games people play RISE to the occasion An unexpected vocabulary lesson Give me a break… Let’s Face(book) it, privacy is no longer inherent... You mustn’t be the Etch A Sketch messenger A well scripted day Can you picture this? A little bit of work&amp;a lot of live music Help! I’m drowning in content Of news and nonsense at SXSW Customers can handle the truth Keeping your communications house in order 
 

 ►  February (21) 

 ►  January (22) 
 

 ►  2011 (90) 
 ►  December (22) 

 ►  November (22) 

 ►  October (21) 

 ►  September (22) 

 ►  August (3) 
 
 
Blogs I Admire
 
 A Random Jog We are working on a new product. Can you name it? 9 hours ago RMHC Austin Giant Scissors Needed 11 hours ago First Today, Then Tomorrow Hungry for more Game Of Thrones? Try The Book Of The New Sun 13 hours ago Copywrite, Ink. Teaching Applied: What We Knew In 1895 1 day ago SOME ASSEMBLY REQUIRED Raise the Bar... Then Jump Over It 1 day ago One Hundred Percent and Then Some Opportunity = Responsibility 1 week ago Owners View Crowdfunding Trends 1 week ago Green Man Coffee House 60s Rock 2 weeks ago Exploring New Media Blocking email from countries 3 weeks ago Jaxzen Marketing The ABC’s of Content Strategy (Apple, Batman, and Cat Videos) 1 month ago Texpert Tabloid Honey of a Moon by the Sea 2 months ago 
 
 
 
 Picture Window template. Powered by Blogger .
	</body>
</document>
