<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009399" url="http://community.cookinglight.com/archive/index.php/t-74441.html" time="2012-07-13-02:45" support="2" score="0.003733899925333503" bingtitle="time to find out everybody&apos;s newest cookbooks! [Archive ..." webtitle="time to find out everybody&apos;s newest cookbooks! [Archive]  - CookingLight.com Community">
			<query id="001192" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="001381" bing-rank="204"/>
	<description>... majority is...still deciding if I&apos;m going to keep ... to going through the drive-thru at your local fast-food restaurant. ... the ingredients and am trying to use up all my food ...</description>
	<body>
		CookingLight.com Community &gt; Food &gt; Great Food &gt;time to find out everybody&apos;s newest cookbooks! PDA 
View Full Version : time to find out everybody&apos;s newest cookbooks! 
 angelamaria 05-21-2005, 12:13 PM i always enjoy these types of threads - i figure missindi must have bought something new by now!
since i have a newborn again i have time to browse amazon-unfortunately i have little time to cook from my purchases!
recently i got:
Cupcakes Yearround by Sara Numaier- this is a really cute book; it&apos;s spiral bound at the top and you can stand it up so you can see the recipes. the cupcakes are all seasonal and she has some tasty sounding recipes; the photography is beautiful.

Eat This Book by Tyler Florence- looks good so far; i may have to get his first one too.

the New American Plate cookbook- it was discussed here on a previous thread and was on sale so i got it.

The Petit Appetit Cookbook- really cute baby and toddler food cookbook. this is prob the fourth or fifth one i&apos;ve gotten. have yet to make anything out of any of them. the prospect of cooking for the kids and for us separate items is too daunting although the recipes look great.

i bypassed the new mario batali cookbook.
still looking for CL annual 2005 on sale and F&amp;W Best of the Best from last year on sale- don&apos;t want to pay full price.

anyone else? sneezles 05-21-2005, 12:48 PM Originally posted by angelamaria
still looking for CL annual 2005 on sale and F&amp;W Best of the Best from last year on sale- don&apos;t want to pay full price.

anyone else?

Overstock.com has the 2005 Annual (http://www.overstock.com/cgi-bin/d2.cgi) for just over $22 and the F&amp;W Best of the Best (http://www.overstock.com/cgi-bin/d2.cgi?PAGE=ENDECA&amp;SEC_IID=7812&amp;N=2029&amp;keywords=Best+of+the+Best) for $19.33 with only $2 shipping on the whole order.

My newest:

The Encyclopedia of Cajun and Creole Cooking by John Folse. This puppy weighs 10 pounds!!! Has some wonderful history of the Cajuns, Acadians and such plus amazing pictures. I&apos;ve not made any recipes yet since I&apos;m still reading it...

The Bread Bible by Rose Levy Berenbaum-still in the reading stage, especially about the organic sourdough starter (and hope to start mine soon ;) ).

Small-Batch Baking-rec&apos;d as a gift (just 2 days after I bought it myself :rolleyes: ) haven&apos;t even cracked the cover.

Fine Cooking&apos;sCooking New American-have perused the book a bit but haven&apos;t cooked from it yet. Some of the recipes are from the magazine and some from the special issues. I like having them in one place.

Baking911 by Sarah Phillips-really don&apos;t know why I purchased the book when it&apos;s all on the website or at least the majority is...still deciding if I&apos;m going to keep or gift... NewMrsG 05-21-2005, 02:20 PM My neighborhood library was having a book sale this weekend and I of course wanted to be supportive!

Here&apos;s what I came back with:

American Heart Association&apos;s Low-Fat, Low-Cholesterol Cookbook
Prevention&apos;s Quick and Healthy Low-Fat COoking
Martha Rose Shulman&apos;s Feasts and Fetes
Food Editor&apos;s Favorites: Salads
Canning and Preserving - Ferrari
Sunset - Low Cholesterol Cookbook
Let&apos;s Eat In: Quick and Delicious Weekday Meals - Brooke Dojny and Melanie Barnard
Weight Watchers Meals in Minutes

Hope there&apos;s good stuff in them! zackaboo 05-21-2005, 02:21 PM Nothing new here. I am trying to get some more use out of the oldies. BUT...I am on the verge of purchasing Cook 1.0 based on some good reviews I have read about it. It is a vegetarian cookbook. Does anyone have this cookbook and any opinions about it?
TIA for any insight you can give me. wallycat 05-21-2005, 03:36 PM I am SHOCKED that I have not bought one cookbook in almost a year. My body is in withdrawl :D :p

My next one will be&quot;A year in a vegetarian kitchen&quot;by Jack Bishop
I&apos;m waiting for paperback ...easier to schlep to Washington :rolleyes: susan_foster 05-21-2005, 06:17 PM Originally posted by wallycat
I am SHOCKED that I have not bought one cookbook in almost a year. My body is in withdrawl :D :p

My next one will be&quot;A year in a vegetarian kitchen&quot;by Jack Bishop
I&apos;m waiting for paperback ...easier to schlep to Washington :rolleyes:

Hmm...are you me? I am going to use a gift certificate I got from my boss - for Christmas! - to get this. I also have a long list of cookbooks that I&apos;d love to buy, but am feeling a bit parsimonious recently.

Susan green1 05-21-2005, 09:49 PM Let&apos;s see....

Eat This Book
Weber&apos;s Real Grilling
Instant Cook
The Great American Detox Diet
The New Gas Grill Gourmet
It&apos;s About Time

That is it for now...I really have to stop. Hammster 05-22-2005, 05:09 AM Best of the Best of Oregon.
I like those&quot;best of the best of&quot;cookbooks because they are usually full of recipes from regular folks like us, non profits, fund raising type places, fire fighters, restaurants too. So it has sort of developed into a collection for me. As I visit a state I will find a bookstore and buy the book for that state. greysangel 05-22-2005, 05:46 AM The Professional Pastry Chef: Fundamentals of Baking and Pastry, 4th Edition

Getting ready for my 12 week pastry and baking program this summer :cool: :cool: :D gaja 05-22-2005, 06:56 AM Well I just bought my very first apartment (woo-hoo!) so I have had to be uncharacteristically reasonable in terms of cookbook purchases. However, I figured that baking was essential to making an apartment a home (can I rationalize or what? ;) ) so I just bought The Macrina Bakery&amp;Cafe Cookbook - a lovely, lovely book with appetizing breads, scones, muffins, cookies, etc. annagins 05-22-2005, 06:57 AM For Mother&apos;s Day, I was given Small Batch Baking and The Cupcake Doctor. I&apos;ve had fun reading both of them, but have yet to make anything out of them. Glad there are threads here with reviews from those books. gabbyh 05-22-2005, 07:07 AM A few of my new goodies:

Shape lowfat&amp;easy

FitFood by Ellen Haas

Keys Cuisine by Linda Gassenheimer

The Key Lime Cookbook (guess where we just were???)

Little Cafe Cakes by Julie Le Clerc

the beach house cookbook by scott goodman

Good Day For a Picnic by Jeremy Jackson

Weight Watchers New 365 Day Menu Cookbook

the instant cook by donna hay

Bread for Breakfast by Beth Hensperger

The Best of Sunset Low-Fat Cook Book

Weber&apos;s Real Grilling

Yikes, when you see them in print it really is alot:D

So, do you also want to know what we have in our shopping carts at amazon.com and thegoodcook.com:D :D :D

Hopefully I won&apos;t get too many idease from this thread :)

~Gail sneezles 05-22-2005, 08:18 AM Originally posted by greysangel
The Professional Pastry Chef: Fundamentals of Baking and Pastry, 4th Edition

I&apos;ve had that for about a year and I love reading it and baking from it...very cool that you&apos;re taking a class! Varaile 05-22-2005, 08:28 AM I just recieved in the mail from thegoodcook.com Small Batch Baking.

At first I was regretting my decision, I mean, why bake 2 or 3 or even just 4 of something when it&apos;s just as easy to do a whole pan. Ironically, I made a 9x13 sheet cake the next day and my DH ate the whole thing in two days! :eek: :mad: :rolleyes: I figured then that that was a sign I should switch to smaller batches and I was meant to keep the cookbook. ;) :D capres 05-22-2005, 08:36 AM I realized after I bought Tyler&apos;s new one plus the dozen or so I bought the month before, that I am just about out of cookbook space. DH would kill me if I ask for another bookcase. 1. There is no where to put another bookcase and 2. How many cookbooks can you actually use? (What kind of question is that? :o )

I have so many that I haven&apos;t even looked through yet, plus so many I haven&apos;t even cooked out of, that I am trying to not buy anymore! (For now, that is until I do a major culling of ones I don&apos;t use and will probably never use.)

Of course I got Giada&apos;s new one, plus Ina Garten&apos;s Barefoot in Paris, plus Provence, Glorious French Food, Grilling, plus a cocktail book, Celebrations by Sheila Lukins, Bouchon, The Gift of Southern Cooking and the list goes on and on. I can&apos;t even remember all the titles!

I&apos;m in the same boat as the rest of you! :D


Carol bellringr 05-22-2005, 08:52 AM I love this thread! So many good ideas. :)

I bought two of Rachael Ray&apos;s books for my mom for Mother&apos;s Day. She enjoys her show and has had fun reading them.

I&apos;m sure I don&apos;t have nearly the collection most of you do (yet). ;) I am debating between a couple of indian cookbooks right now as hubby and I both love that kind of food.

Can any of you recommend a book with instructions and ideas for garnishes or plating techniques? kima 05-22-2005, 09:33 AM I just bought The Macarina Bakery Book and have The best of Cooking Light on order.

Gail-I would love to hear what you think of the Shape book. Did you have to order it through the magazine?


Nice purchases everyone! :) Ohioan 05-22-2005, 09:34 AM My most recent buys, both excellent, are:

* Latest edition of The Vegetarian Times Cookbook.

* The Complete Vegan Cookbook by Susann Geiskopf-Hadler and Mindy Toomay.

Cheers,
Phoebe gabbyh 05-22-2005, 09:40 AM Maureen,

I LOVE the Shape Cookbook...I tried to find it on half.com and amazon.com, but it seems the only way to order was from the magazine or their web-site, and I chose the later.

It has 151 recipes and color pictures of each! (I think you need a copy ;-})

~Gail gabbyh 05-22-2005, 09:48 AM Maureen,

I forgot to also add that I love the way the shape book is indexed...really easy to find recipes!

~Gail angelamaria 05-22-2005, 10:37 AM Thanks Sneezles for the tips on overstock. i may spring for the F&amp;W but i am thinking i don&apos;t want the CL annual until it&apos;s under 15$; i have about 6 of them and i don&apos;t use them that much. however last year had better recipes than the year before including some i still mean to try and of course i threw out all the mags so i need to get it at some point.
Hammster i do the same thing- buy a local cookbook as a souvenir. we went to alaska last fall and i got the best of the best Alaska. i am trying hard not to start a collection of these as there are ones from practically each state!
GabbyH i knew you must have gotten something new! i am afraid to even peek at your wishlists. Tell me about Hensperger&apos;s Bread for Breakfast- worth it or not? i have 2 of her cookbooks and i really like her style.
oh missindi...where are you ? i know you must have recently acquired something new!
Bellringr i have one of Madhur Jaffrey&apos;s (sp?) books - i think it&apos;s Indian Cooking made Easy or something like that. the recipes are fairly simple. annagins 05-22-2005, 10:47 AM Originally posted by Varaile
I just recieved in the mail from thegoodcook.com Small Batch Baking.

At first I was regretting my decision, I mean, why bake 2 or 3 or even just 4 of something when it&apos;s just as easy to do a whole pan. Ironically, I made a 9x13 sheet cake the next day and my DH ate the whole thing in two days! :eek: :mad: :rolleyes: I figured then that that was a sign I should switch to smaller batches and I was meant to keep the cookbook. ;) :D

I was thinking along the same lines as you were, but after reading the book and seeing what she has to offer, I&apos;m quite excited about trying a few things -- in particular, one of her adorable little layer cakes baked in a cleaned out soup can. I just haven&apos;t gotten around to cleaning out a soup can.

I&apos;ve also been busy baking out of my Rebecca Rather Pastry Queen book. Her recipes are some of the best&quot;formulated&quot;and most creative I&apos;ve seen in awhile -- plus, they are extremely user-friendly. kima 05-22-2005, 11:18 AM Thanks for the info on the Shape book- it does sound good. Unfortunately the price is too steep for me when you factor in the exchange and shipping. Perhaps it will be on amazon some day. :(

Back to say that I checked out the website and they have TONS of good recipes on it. Perhaps many there are in the book. I have printed out ten recipes already....good lord I am never, ever, going to make all the recipes I want to!

I just noticed I am over 6,000 posts. About the same number of recipes I want to make. :eek: SweetSueDonym 05-22-2005, 06:06 PM Gaja and Kima, I have Macrina .. friend from Seattle bought it for me for Xmas .. haven&apos;t tried much but do like it alot.

DH and DS got me the original Barefoot Contessa for Mothers Day. Also just got Giada&apos;s and just made the balsamic chicken on this BB recommendation. Yum!

I&apos;m thinking about King Arthur Cookies and Stonewall Kitchen Harvest. MISSINDI 05-22-2005, 08:14 PM Originally posted by angelamaria
oh missindi...where are you ? i know you must have recently acquired something new!

LOL - I&apos;m here!! I&apos;m here!!

Oh man, am I gonna get it here!! :eek: This past week is a REALLY bad time to be asking me this. Last weekend, my Mom and I went away to Brimfield, MA (an annual sojourn) and we stopped in the local Marshalls, where I scooped up:

Portable Feasts by Clare Ferguson
Brunch by Jennifer Donovan
Food for Friends by Fran Warde
Family Pleasing Recipes from Pillsbury

This past Friday, at Barnes&amp;Noble, they were having a&quot;buy 2, get the third free&quot;and I bought:

The Lobster Chronicles by Linda Greenlaw (love her stuff, though not a cookbook, but food-related)
Tender at the Bone by Ruth Reichl
Comfort Me with Apples by Ruth Reichl

Garage sale season is here, and my son and I found one with a box of cookbook for TEN CENTS EACH!!! I grabbed 10, he got two. Mostly older ones, but still, what a bargain!

And lastly, went to the Gourmet Food Show today (saw Paula Deen, see my blog for details), and there was a bookseller there who had cookbooks for $3.99 each!! I got 8. Showed great restraint, no? Haven&apos;t lugged them all upstairs (too tired!!), but will list them tomorrow. One of them was 50 Potato Salad Recipes. Bob mentioned this cookbook on last weekend&apos;s Miscellaneous Weekend Reviews thread. He mentioned a potato salad with maple syrup that sounded really interesting, but didn&apos;t give up the recipe, so I was excited to spy this one.

No more cookbooks until I make space for these ... give me a few days!! ;) swquilts 05-22-2005, 08:30 PM This morning I was getting ready to say that I haven&apos;t bought any new ones, but that was before we went to Sam&apos;s Club today! :D

We got Weber&apos;s Real Grilling and Weight Watchers (with the CIA) Great Cooking Everyday.

The Weber one was about $16 and the WW was $10. Great prices! I had seen the Weber at Home Depot for about $22. erinsue 05-23-2005, 08:57 AM I&apos;ve been trying to hold back on cookbook buying, so not too many new ones for me.

Bistro Cooking (Patricia Wells)
Stop and Smell the Rosemary (Jr. League of Houston)
The Olive and the Caper (Susanna Hoffman) jtoepfert100 05-23-2005, 09:24 AM I got The Weekend Baker about a week ago and I LOVE IT! I&apos;ve already made two things out of it and they were big hits. Also winging their way to my house as I type are Vegetables Everyday, Cooking for Two - I think this is by those two guys with the column in Eating Well and King Arthur&apos;s Baking Companion. These were all books I&apos;ve wanted for some time and I finally caved. I can&apos;t wait until they all come in!!!

MISSINDI - you may have a sickness!;) MISSINDI 05-23-2005, 09:31 AM Originally posted by jtoepfert100
MISSINDI - you may have a sickness!;)

Maybe, but I&apos;m pretty frugal about it. Everything I got in the last week totalled less than $80. :D acginkc 05-23-2005, 10:06 AM I had a little breakdown last week and bought quite a few (considering I rarely buy cookbooks).

Cookies by the Dozen- I was so excited to find it since it is out of print

Feeding Baby- actually bought this for a friend, but didn&apos;t give it to her till after I had copied a few neat recipes first :p. It is by 2 professional chefs and has great pictures and ideas. Here (http://www.epicurious.com/features/cookbooks/reviews/2003/feeding) is the link to a review of it.

Small batch baking-can&apos;t wait to give it a try

Young and Hungry- by Dave Lieberman, the new Food TV peronality, and he is a cutie. First skim of the book looks promising.

And not really a cookbook, but Juice Fasting and Detoxification: Use the healing power of fresh juice to feel young and look great by Steve Meyerowitz. From 1st glance, I am not too impressed, but perhaps reading it will help. Any good detox/fasting resources anyone? Sami 05-23-2005, 10:17 AM You all are such a BAD influence. I bought Olive Trees and Honey and am trying to hold off on anymore. I find that when I go to BJ&apos;s and buy reading books, I force myself to avoid the King arthur Cookbooks. As it is, I have no more room unless i move some of my cookbooks from the cabinet. OT&amp;H is sitting on the couch because it doesn&apos;t have a home.

Sami angelamaria 05-23-2005, 11:02 AM jtoepfort i got Weekend Baker for christmas from DH. i really like the way she organized her recipes and gave advice on how to make ahead or freeze them. in fact, i wish all cookbooks had this kind of info.

hmm may have to give small batch baking another look.. i don&apos;t bake bc it&apos;s just dh and me and a 2 yrold. but the idea of soupcan size cakes sounds irresistible! i will have to search for the thread on this.

ha! missindi i knew you would have new ones. you are officially my hero. i want to know how you work full time, run a side business, take care of your boy, and cook dinner plusss! find the time to read your new acquisitions and your mags! i consider myself a fast reader but i haven&apos;t even cracked the spines on several books i have bought in the past 6 months (cookbooks). and i have two bookshelves in my bedroom full of non cooking related books i haven&apos;t read yet either!
eta i am sure i have typos in here but darned if i can find them! angela MISSINDI 05-23-2005, 11:41 AM Originally posted by angelamaria
ha! missindi i knew you would have new ones. you are officially my hero.

LOL - right back at ya on the&quot;hero&quot;thing. I don&apos;t think I could swing a two-year-old AND a new baby, but our thirty-steps-to-our-front-door definitely has something to do with that, so kudos to you!

OK, lugged my Gourmet Food Show stash upstairs. Here&apos;s what I got yesterday, for a grand total of $32!

Fifty Favorite Recipes: Potato Salad by Barbara Lauterbach
The Thrill of the Grill by Chris Schlesinger and John Willoughby
Grilling America by Rick Browne
Diners American Retro (not a cookbook)
One Dish Dinners by Jean Anderson
Let Us Eat Cake by Sharon Boorstin
In the Hands of a Chef by Jody Adams
Father Joseph Orsini&apos;s Italian Family Cooking (my mom met him some 15 years ago and liked his recipes) jtoepfert100 05-23-2005, 12:20 PM Originally posted by acginkc


Cookies by the Dozen- I was so excited to find it since it is out of printhaps reading it will help. Any good detox/fasting resources anyone?

Okay - where did you find this!!!? I haven&apos;t been able to find a copy (under $30) since Bob stole a copy out from under my nose!

MISSINDI - your stash looks awesome! angelamaria 05-23-2005, 01:46 PM this is the trouble i get in when i&apos;m nursing the baby and the 2 yrold is napping-
ahem :o today i ordered used copies of CL annual 2005 and what i hope is the most recent F&amp;W best of the best. i also ordered :o the paperback Small Batch Baking and that Butternut Squash&amp;Pumpkin cookbook there used to be a thread about. (it was only 6.75 and i have been seriously considering it since that thread last fall).
i debated michael chiarello&apos;s book, beth henspergers bread for breakfast (also cheap) but passed.
i got via ups today:
How to Cook Everything Holiday Cooking by Mark Bittman (on sale at amazon)
Summertime Treats by Sara Perry- if i like this i may get other books in the series- they have recipes, crafts to do with kids etc
Feeding the Whole Family -yet another baby/toddler food book i have been eyeing since abby was born -emphasis on whole grains which i like.
and i also forgot i got F&amp;W&apos;s Cocktail Book 2005 - it has recipes for all the latest happenin cocktails from all the latest hippest bars and it&apos;s neat to read about all the newest places.

so i don&apos;t need any more ideas! MISSINDI 05-23-2005, 01:59 PM Originally posted by angelamaria
i also ordered that Butternut Squash&amp;Pumpkin cookbook there used to be a thread about. (it was only 6.75 and i have been seriously considering it since that thread last fall).

Ahhh, good choice. I got it last year too, from Crate&amp;Barrel. Great pictures in it. :D acginkc 05-23-2005, 02:38 PM Originally posted by jtoepfert100


Okay - where did you find this!!!? I haven&apos;t been able to find a copy (under $30) since Bob stole a copy out from under my nose!

I found it on half.com. I have been checking there for it since it was discussed on this board. I believe I ended up paying about $13 for it which I thought was well worth it for an out of print book. If I see it again, i will send you a PM (so that you can have dibs on it ;) ) jtoepfert100 05-23-2005, 03:09 PM Originally posted by acginkc


I found it on half.com. I have been checking there for it since it was discussed on this board. I believe I ended up paying about $13 for it which I thought was well worth it for an out of print book. If I see it again, i will send you a PM (so that you can have dibs on it ;) )

That would be awesome! I&apos;ve been checking there and amazon religiously, as well, but it must have slipped by me. Glad you found a copy - you&apos;ll have to let me know if you make anything good! Molli526 05-23-2005, 04:05 PM Originally posted by angelamaria

Summertime Treats by Sara Perry- if i like this i may get other books in the series- they have recipes, crafts to do with kids etc


Please report back how you like this book. It looks really cute = well, really the whole series does. You are going to get me in trouble with DH ;) :P Gecko 05-23-2005, 04:09 PM Originally posted by MISSINDI
In the Hands of a Chef by Jody Adams

When you&apos;ve had a chance to look through it please let me know if you would recommend this book. I have debated getting this one. MISSINDI 05-23-2005, 07:04 PM Originally posted by Gecko


When you&apos;ve had a chance to look through it please let me know if you would recommend this book. I have debated getting this one.

Absolutely. Like you, I&apos;ve been debating about this one. It&apos;s been on my list for awhile, and I really couldn&apos;t decide yesterday at the show. I just took the plunge figuring I&apos;d never find it again for $4. There&apos;s not a lot of pictures in it (I&apos;m a big&quot;picture&quot;person), and there&apos;s a heavy percentage of high falutin&apos; dishes that I probably wouldn&apos;t make, but that said, think it&apos;s still worth it. I&apos;m going to visit the bookstore where this one came from sometime this week -- if they have another copy, I&apos;ll grab you one, so don&apos;t buy it yet. I still owe you for all those magazines!! :D greek salad 05-23-2005, 08:24 PM I didn&apos;t buy this cookbook but I saw it in the bookstore and it looked interesting. It is&quot;It&apos;s About Time: Great Recipes for Everyday Life&quot;buy Michael Schlow. He&apos;s a very popular chef in the Boston area and is a chef and co-owner of Radius, Via Matta and Great Bat. All VERY higly rated and&quot;in&quot;restaurants in Boston.

Many of the recipes look great (and the pictures are beautiful).

Quite the variety of recipes -- some I couldn&apos;t imagine the average cook making at home since they were pretty upscale, but there were some that seemed easy to replicate at home.

Some of the recipes... chicken with zucchini and snap peas, roast halibut with asparagus and morels, to the basic hamburger with some type of onion strings, raspberry bars.

I would definitely consider this a more upscale ingredient/recipe type cookbook but if you like to cook and enjoy some unusual recipes you might enjoy it. ctr264 05-23-2005, 09:27 PM Newest additions include

Simple Italian Recipes for Cooking At Home - Mario Batali

Taming the Flame - Secrets for Hot and Quick Grilling and Low and Slow BBQ - Elizabeth Karmel

Grilling for Life - Bobby Flay

Cook&apos;s Illustrated - Grilling and Barbeque

Vegetarian Times Complete Cookbook

Vegetarian Suppers - Deborah Madison

Chicken on the Grill - Cheryl Jamison


And when DH wonders why the bookcase looks like there&apos;s more books on it, it&apos;s only cause I&apos;ve rearranged!! imloulou 05-23-2005, 10:30 PM Originally posted by bellringr

I&apos;m sure I don&apos;t have nearly the collection most of you do (yet). ;)

Hah...just you wait...hang out here long enough and you will need to clear a new space for more books!!:D :D :D imloulou 05-23-2005, 10:37 PM Originally posted by bellringr

Can any of you recommend a book with instructions and ideas for garnishes or plating techniques?

Whoops forgot to answer your question:

Here is a search on this forum for Indian Cookbooks:

Indian Cookbooks (http://community.cookinglight.com/search.php?s=&amp;action=showresults&amp;searchid=700617&amp;sortby=lastpost&amp;sortorder=descending)

I love Indian cooking but have never bought an Indian cookbook....there were enough good recipes on this board to keep me busy:

Indian recipes (http://community.cookinglight.com/search.php?s=&amp;action=showresults&amp;searchid=697538&amp;sortby=lastpost&amp;sortorder=descending)

Sorry I could not suggest a cookbook for ya. I look forward to responses...I love Indian food and hope there are some good new books out! Gecko 05-23-2005, 11:12 PM Originally posted by MISSINDI


Absolutely. Like you, I&apos;ve been debating about this one. It&apos;s been on my list for awhile, and I really couldn&apos;t decide yesterday at the show. I just took the plunge figuring I&apos;d never find it again for $4. There&apos;s not a lot of pictures in it (I&apos;m a big&quot;picture&quot;person), and there&apos;s a heavy percentage of high falutin&apos; dishes that I probably wouldn&apos;t make, but that said, think it&apos;s still worth it. I&apos;m going to visit the bookstore where this one came from sometime this week -- if they have another copy, I&apos;ll grab you one, so don&apos;t buy it yet. I still owe you for all those magazines!! :D

I would be happy to reimburse you for the book and the postage. And remember there was nothing owing for the magazines - they were a gift. I was just so happy to find someone who would appreciate them, rather than just giving them to the local library and people not even knowing what they were :) Actually I was going to PM you and tell you that I found another magazine holder with another 9 issues of Delicious 2002-2003 that I will go through and send you, along with whatever misc Aussie ones that I know I am sure to find as I work my way through my older magazines. SDMomChef 05-24-2005, 10:02 AM I have recently gotten into bread baking, and I bought The Baker&apos;s Apprentice. I haven&apos;t tried any recipes yet, but I&apos;m really excited about the book. Does anybody else have this book? cinnabun 05-24-2005, 01:37 PM I have bought about 20 of them in the past couple of months. Too many to really list here but most were either bread machine books and slow cooker books, one of them being not your mothers crockpot cookbook by beth hensperger. cinnabun 05-24-2005, 01:40 PM My cookbok collection has grown since I have been coming here. I used to have only 3, the bhg new cookbook, fannie farmer and betty crocker. Now I have over 100 cookbooks! Not all of them are used on a regular basis in my kitchen but it sure is fun looking through some of them! MISSINDI 05-24-2005, 01:41 PM Originally posted by Gecko
I would be happy to reimburse you for the book and the postage. And remember there was nothing owing for the magazines - they were a gift.

No reimbursement necessary - don&apos;t be silly. :) I&apos;ll pick the book up this week. What other types of cookbooks catch your eye? Gecko 05-24-2005, 02:36 PM Originally posted by MISSINDI


No reimbursement necessary - don&apos;t be silly. :) I&apos;ll pick the book up this week. What other types of cookbooks catch your eye?

You are very sweet! The types of cookbooks that ususally catch my eye are baking books - much to the detriment of my hips :D But I am an equal opportunity cookbook buyer so I am not adverse to others as well. My next purchase will probaly be the new Sara Foster book&quot;Fresh Every Day&quot;which has just been released. Amazon has it for $23.10, and if I add a few Bill Granger books I get free shipping - well tha&apos;s my justification for buying more books - you get free shipping :D irishspy 05-24-2005, 02:57 PM My newest is Anthony Bourdain&apos;s Les Halles Cookbook (http://www.booksamillion.com/ncom/books?id=3169681773365&amp;isbn=158234180X), which I just love -- both for his recipes and his writing style. oceanjasper 05-24-2005, 09:26 PM I just got some books delivered today! I got The Instant Cook by Donna Hay and the Ball Blue Book of Preserving. MISSINDI 05-26-2005, 07:10 AM Forgot to come back and post what I picked up Sunday. Thanks for the reminder, shoezoo! Here&apos;s what I got at the Gourmet Food Show, the whole stash for $32 (also one other non-cookbook on diners). :D

Now to report on the cookbooks I snagged yesterday. I got:
Fifty Favorite Recipes: Potato Salad by Barbara Lauterbach
The Thrill of the Grill by Chris Schlesinger and John Willoughby
Grilling America by Rick Browne
One Dish Dinners by Jean Anderson
Let Us Eat Cake by Sharon Boorstin
In the Hands of a Chef by Jody Adams
Father Joseph Orsini&apos;s Italian Family Cooking (my mom met him some 15 years ago and liked his recipes)

Then yesterday, on a Southern/low-country cookbook binge, I bought:
Miss Mary Bobo&apos;s Boarding House Cookbook
Mama Dip&apos;s Cookbook
Jack Daniels&apos; Spirit of Tennessee Cookbook SueK 05-26-2005, 08:01 AM I got Sara Foster&apos;s new one Fresh Every Day for my bday yesterday. Haven&apos;t looked at it yet, but I loved her first one and everything I&apos;ve tried from it has been a winner. sooty 05-26-2005, 10:52 AM [QUOTE]Originally posted by jtoepfert100
I got [B]The Weekend Baker about a week ago and I LOVE IT! I&apos;ve already made two things out of it and they were big hits. Also winging their way to my house as I type are Vegetables Everyday, Cooking for Two - I think this is by those two guys with the column in Eating Well and King Arthur&apos;s Baking Companion. These were all books I&apos;ve wanted for some time and I finally caved. I can&apos;t wait until they all come in!!!

I LOVE the Weekend Baker, probably have made about half the recipes. If you have not tried the mousse cake, it one of the best I have had and easy to put together, keeps good, too. And the KA Companion&apos;s Cinnamon Roll recipe has become my standard, the rolls come out so light. FYI the KA Cookie Book has a chewy brownie that truely does come out with the crackly (box brownie) top as it states. My son&apos;s favorite (no nuts). jtoepfert100 05-26-2005, 11:40 AM MISSINDI - please do report back on the Jack Daniels cookbook - sounds intriguing!

Sooty - I will try the mousse cake next week. I just can&apos;t get over how much I love that book. As someone else above pointed out, the way she organized it is really great and I LOVE how she gives measurements and weights for all ingredients. Her intro is also a fabulous reference. I just the KA book last night so I can&apos;t wait to try it out. I&apos;ll keep those cinnamon rolls in mind. And not to worry, I&apos;m sure I&apos;ll break down and get the KA Cookie Book soon enough.

I also got Cooking for Two the other day and it looks like it has some great recipes. It was a bargain book, so I wasn&apos;t certain, but there are some interesting recipes in there and I think the authors did try to stay in the healthy range. For you Small Batch fans, it&apos;s got quite a few cookie and cake recipes that look yummy. I haven&apos;t yet had a chance to go through Vegetables Everyday, but I plan on taking it with me out of town this weekend.

I forgot that I also got a few weeks ago Local Flavors by Deborah Madison. It&apos;s a beautiful book and I&apos;ve only made one recipe from it, which was okay. Anyone else have this and have recommendations?

Finally, I got Tante Maria&apos;s Cooking School or something like that in a swap. There is some great advice and a few recipes that caught my eye, but I think most of them seem a bit complicated for the everyday cook. Hopefully, I&apos;ll be able to make something from it soon. Gecko 05-29-2005, 06:33 PM Originally posted by SueK
I got Sara Foster&apos;s new one Fresh Every Day for my bday yesterday. Haven&apos;t looked at it yet, but I loved her first one and everything I&apos;ve tried from it has been a winner.

Are you loving this book? I really like her first book so I am greatly tempted to get this one too. Molli526 05-29-2005, 06:52 PM I can play :)

On the way to me:

The Sourdough Cookbook
Quick Loaves: 150 Breads and Cakes, Meat and Meatless Loaves
Vegetables Every Day: The Definitive Guide to Buying and Cooking Today&apos;s Produce With over 350 Recipes
The Weekend Baker: Irresistible Recipes, Simple Techniques, and Stress Free Strategies for Busy People MISSINDI 05-29-2005, 08:28 PM Last night, I ordered the Dinosaur BBQ book and one other Texas BBQ. Hoping to get to the bookstore tomorrow, just in case I&quot;need&quot;anything. ;) kima 05-29-2005, 09:55 PM The magazine is on its way to you Missindi.

Need anything?????? This is a serious addiction you have! (and one I heartily approve of) ;) MISSINDI 05-29-2005, 10:18 PM Thanks, kima! Going shopping for yours tomorrow. In the meantime, I bought NO cookbooks or magazines today. :D newtricks 05-30-2005, 06:19 AM Originally posted by MISSINDI
In the meantime, I bought NO cookbooks or magazines today. :D

Wow, alert the media!!;)

OK, I looked over Jamie Oliver&apos;s new one at a friend&apos;s house. Not a light cookbook but has this amazing lasagna recipe with a meat sauce AND roasted butternut squash and creme fraiche (instead of bechamel). Looked very very yummy. And the pictures are great. What&apos;s not to like really? chef. recipes. Both delicious.


http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/1401301940/qid=1117455128/sr=8-1/ref=sr_8_xs_ap_i1_xgl14/002-3268515-1441603?v=glance&amp;s=books&amp;n=507846

I also got Rachel Ray&apos;s low carb cookbook.&quot;Get Real&quot;. Haven&apos;t felt compelled to make anything yet. She has a whole chapter on salads topped with mini burgers. Can&apos;t decide if I think that&apos;s stupid or brilliant. Separately the burgers look good and the salads look good. I guess I&apos;ll try it. MISSINDI 05-30-2005, 06:50 AM Originally posted by newtricks
I also got Rachel Ray&apos;s low carb cookbook.&quot;Get Real&quot;. Haven&apos;t felt compelled to make anything yet. She has a whole chapter on salads topped with mini burgers. Can&apos;t decide if I think that&apos;s stupid or brilliant. Separately the burgers look good and the salads look good. I guess I&apos;ll try it.

Last week, she made Paella Burgers with Spanish Fries and Pimiento Mayonnaise (http://www.foodnetwork.com/food/recipes/recipe/0,,FOOD_9936_30814,00.html) and it looked good. The burgers are made with chicken, then separately, she grilled chorizo and shrimp and topped the burgers with that, the flavored mayo and shredded lettuce. Looked delicious. Although it wouldn&apos;t keep with the paella theme, I would have added a slice or two of avocado. Yum. Molli526 06-13-2005, 08:27 PM Originally posted by angelamaria

Summertime Treats by Sara Perry- if i like this i may get other books in the series- they have recipes, crafts to do with kids etc


How do you like this book? I have some GC&apos;s to Amazon, and this series looks cute. honeygirl1971 06-14-2005, 05:14 AM I missed this thread when it was first posted, but you have all gotten some great-sounding books! I&apos;d love to know how that cupcake book is, angelamaria...I love making cupcakes but rarely find really excellent recipes that don&apos;t involve cake mix (which I don&apos;t like).

For my part, nothing too exciting lately since I&apos;m moving and I&apos;ve been trying to avoid accumulating more stuff I&apos;m going to have to move! But, that having been said, I did get the CL Annual from Amazon marketplace and Julia Child&apos;s classic Mastering the Art of French Cooking Books (Vol. 1 revised edition, new, Vol. 2 used off ebay), and the book I&apos;ve bought and used the most recently is Giada&apos;s Everyday Italian. I registered for Barefoot in Paris before my wedding, but no one gave it to me! :( But also my DH asked a friend of his who owns a used book store to pull some good French cookbooks for me, and he gave them to me when I was there a couple of weeks ago--I just had time to flip through them, but they included the Larousse Encyclopedia of Food, which has gorgeous pictures... MISSINDI 06-14-2005, 06:30 AM Yesterday, I got Hogs on 66 (http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/1571781404/qid=1118752167/sr=8-1/ref=pd_ka_1/104-9112020-3388732?v=glance&amp;s=books&amp;n=507846), and one of our neighbors gave me Secrets of Chicago Chefs. Molli526 06-14-2005, 08:09 AM I ordered used (really new) from Amazon:


Family Fun Super Snacks : 125 Quick Snacks That Are Fun to Make
Family Fun Fast Family Dinners : 100 Wholesome Kid-Friendly
Recipes for Your Family Beth H 06-14-2005, 08:38 AM I recently ordered two of Donna Hay&apos;s cookbooks: Off the Shelf and New Food Fast. I love them. The recipes are simple yet fresh and interesting, and the photography is wonderful. I&apos;ll be asking for more of her cookbooks as birthday/Christmas gifts. susan_foster 06-14-2005, 08:47 AM I was in Barnes&amp;Noble on Sunday, and bought:

Wraps: Easy Recipes for Handheld Meals (http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0811818128/qid=1118760113/sr=8-2/ref=pd_csp_2/102-0410180-9717738?v=glance&amp;s=books&amp;n=507846) - Very excited about this one, because it has a breakfast wrap that sounds like fun - if you look at it on Amazon, do the look inside the book thing, it&apos;s 10th page in.


WW Cook it Quick! (http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0743245962/qid=1118760227/sr=2-4/ref=pd_bbs_b_2_4/102-0410180-9717738) - Do another look inside the book thing - the Chicken Salad with Asian Flavors shown looks really different!

The Laurel&apos;s Kitchen Bread Book (http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0812969677/qid=1118760325/sr=1-1/ref=sr_1_1/102-0410180-9717738?v=glance&amp;s=books) - This is one I had thought about buying online, but just couldn&apos;t get into it. But once I held it in my hands, that was it!

I don&apos;t actually have them in my hands right now - I was away for the weekend, and couldn&apos;t fit them in my luggage, so mom will be mailing them (along with some killer shoes). Can&apos;t wait!

Susan erinsue 06-14-2005, 09:23 AM Just put in an order at ecookbooks the other day and got a few things on serious sale... less than $50 total with nothing over 12.98 - hardback even!

Cooking for Comfort - Marion Burros
Jim Fobel&apos;s Big Flavors
Local Flavors - Deborah Madison
Matthew Kenney&apos;s Big City Cooking
Pacific Palate: Cuisines of the Sun - Alaina De Havilland (free choice)

Can&apos;t wait to see the box on my doorstep!
Erin AZJane 06-14-2005, 09:36 AM Just ordered Small Batch Baking last week from overstock.com after reading about it here :) Thanks! MISSINDI 06-14-2005, 10:01 AM Originally posted by erinsue
Matthew Kenney&apos;s Big City Cooking

My sister and I got a copy of this for Christmas last year. I haven&apos;t cooked from it, but she has and really likes it. It&apos;s gotten a lot of good reviews.

Susan - the wraps book sounds great. I can never get wraps to look as nice as restaurants do... just like subs never taste the same as a deli can make &apos;em. kima 06-14-2005, 10:10 AM Did the CL magazine I sent to you arrive Missindi?? gabbyh 06-18-2005, 01:19 PM My latest:

Jamie&apos;s Dinners - Jamie Oliver&apos;s new one...I LOVE this book!

The Weekend Baker

Inspired by Ingredients

The Olive Harvest Cookbook

Bobby Flay&apos;s Grilling for Life

Quick Loaves

Now if only I had time to cook:confused:

~Gail MISSINDI 06-18-2005, 07:47 PM Originally posted by gabbyh
My latest:

Jamie&apos;s Dinners - Jamie Oliver&apos;s new one...I LOVE this book!
~Gail

I love this one too, particularly the impetus behind him writing it. He is determined to show everyone that good, healthy food can be done&quot;fast,&quot;without having to resort to going through the drive-thru at your local fast-food restaurant. He&apos;s also on a mission to rework the school lunch program. Gotta love that!

Got an order from The Good Cook in on Friday, but left them all at the office, so can&apos;t share the titles of those yet.

Today, however, I bought Dungeness Crabs and Blackberry Cobblers: The Northwest Heritage Cookbook (http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0394577450/qid=1119145259/sr=8-3/ref=sr_8_xs_ap_i2_xgl14/002-5428382-4525607?v=glance&amp;s=books&amp;n=507846). Let me tell you, I very rarely buy cookbooks with no pictures, and this cookbook does not have one single picture of any of the recipes. That tells you how good all the recipes look! As I was flipping through the book at the store, I kept seeing recipes I wanted to try. After about the 10th one, I gave in and just bought the book. Some recipes are: Basque Walnut Pudding, Cherries in Amaretto Sour Cream and Hazelnut Sugar, Walla Walla Sweet Onion Jam, Apricot-Nectarine Spoon Marmalade with Cinnamon, McCormick&apos;s Hot Seafood Salad, Creamy Potato Salad with Oregon Blue Cheese and Scallions, Spinach Salad with Honey-Sesame Seed Dressing, and more. CindyWeightWatcher 06-19-2005, 08:58 PM Gail,
Any update on Bobby Flay&apos;s&quot;Grilling for Life&quot;would be
appreciated. Healthy grilling, would love to learn more
about that! oceanjasper 06-19-2005, 09:49 PM I just hit up Save-on-Foods (needed some milk, so I drove way across town because I wanted to check out the clearance pile...) and found a cookbook called The Magic of Asia - Exotic and Aromatic Dishes from the East by Kim Chung Lee. I have never heard of the book before, but it has lots of pictures, including ones showing the technique, and it was a great price! :) jjsooner73 06-19-2005, 10:47 PM I&apos;ve recently purchased American Pie by Peter Reinhart. I have The Breadbaker&apos;s Apprentice and have been itching to make good pizza. I hope to make my first dough recipe this week-I haven&apos;t decided which one yet.

Also, Everyday Italian: 125 Simple and Delicious Recipes by Giada De Laurentiis. I&apos;ve made her version of pesto (it was closer at hand than what I usually use). Not bad, but I will up the garlic next time.

At half-price books, I also bought a book on Syrian cooking that was written by a family team (cousins I think) of recipes their parents brought to the US from Syria. MISSINDI 06-24-2005, 09:39 AM Today in the mail I got Delicious Dips from Diane Morgan. I love dips, and the cover picture looks absolutely gorgeous! You can see it here (http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0811842207/ref=sib_rdr_dp/102-8502907-3828949?%5Fencoding=UTF8&amp;no=283155&amp;me=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;st=books).

Earlier in the week, from The Good Cook, I got:

In a Cuban Kitchen
The Cape Cod Table
The Weekend Chef
BBQ Queens Big Book of Barbecue


Looking forward to delving into them all this weekend. cinnabun 06-25-2005, 02:21 PM I got kitchen companion: The A to Z guide to everyday cooking equipment and ingredients (williams sonoma collection). A reference book but I just don&apos;t have enough reference books. cinnabun 06-25-2005, 02:23 PM Please post a review of BBQ Queens Big Book of Barbecue
when you have time. Been thinking of getting thisone but not sure about it. Sami 06-25-2005, 09:10 PM Someone just gave me Donna Hays&apos; The Instant Cook. I picked 2 recipes from it that I want to try because I have all the ingredients and am trying to use up all my food before I leave for vacation.

Sami MISSINDI 06-26-2005, 10:26 AM Originally posted by cinnabun
Please post a review of BBQ Queens Big Book of Barbecue
when you have time. Been thinking of getting thisone but not sure about it.

I&apos;ve been reading it the past few nights and like it so far. Will make a few recipes out of it this week. Not one stinkin&apos; picture in it though - I hate that. :) pschambers 06-27-2005, 06:48 PM I got Deborah Madison&apos;s Local Flavors at Tuesday Morning for $14.99!
Great Deal!

Patti ctr264 06-27-2005, 08:39 PM Picked up 4 new books, Weber&apos;s Big Book of Grilling, Weber&apos;s The Art of the Grill and Weber&apos;s Real Grilling.

The last one is a book by a mother/daughter team called Recipes From a Very Small Island by Linda and Martha Greenlaw. The live on a tiny island called Isle au Haut, Maine normal population 40 summer population 400! The book is beautful, great pictures, stories and of course recipes. There are a lot of seafood/fish and local Maine ingredient recipes. According to the book jacket, the daughter&quot;Linda is on break from being a swordfish boat captain, a career the earned her a pominent role in The Perfect Storm and a portrayal in the subsequent film&quot;. MISSINDI 06-27-2005, 08:53 PM Originally posted by ctr264
The last one is a book by a mother/daughter team called Recipes From a Very Small Island by Linda and Martha Greenlaw. The live on a tiny island called Isle au Haut, Maine normal population 40 summer population 400! The book is beautful, great pictures, stories and of course recipes. There are a lot of seafood/fish and local Maine ingredient recipes. According to the book jacket, the daughter&quot;Linda is on break from being a swordfish boat captain, a career the earned her a pominent role in The Perfect Storm and a portrayal in the subsequent film&quot;.

I didn&apos;t know she had a cookbook - thanks for the tip! I have her other books; I think there&apos;s 3 or 4, all very good, in case you&apos;re interested. :) ctr264 06-27-2005, 09:02 PM Originally posted by MISSINDI


I didn&apos;t know she had a cookbook - thanks for the tip! I have her other books; I think there&apos;s 3 or 4, all very good, in case you&apos;re interested. :)

Thanks for the tip, they mention her other books on the book jacket, I&apos;m going to see if my library has them. Cookin4Love 06-27-2005, 11:45 PM Oh, boy! Just visited The Good Cook--30% off club prices if you order three or more. No problem. Did you know that they won&apos;t let you order more than ten books at a time? Go figure! annagins 06-28-2005, 06:45 AM Tuesday Morning had Baking In America by Greg Patent on sale for about $11.00. I haven&apos;t made anything from it yet, but every recipe is unique. There is a chapter of interesting American yeast breads, including yeasted corn bread which was the same recipe he published in CL awhile back. The book also has the original recipe for the ever-popular lemon butter crunch bars from CL. I can&apos;t wait to cook from this book!

I also bought Hey There, Cupcake! by Claire Crespo. It has great ideas for cupcake decorating and unlike The Cupcake Doctor, all Claire&apos;s recipes are from scratch. The book is mainly photos of fancy decorated cupcakes -- a picture book to inspire you. However, at the beginning of the book she has about 8 different scratch cupcake recipes, none of which are boring. cinnabun 06-28-2005, 08:38 AM What, no pictures in the BBQ queens book? Oh well, I do recall picking up a few books with no pictures in them. I can&apos;t get them to come out the way they look in the photos anyways. Gecko 06-28-2005, 01:59 PM I think this might just have to become a monthly thread :D I love reading about the books that people have purchased. kima 06-28-2005, 02:17 PM I just bought this lovely looking book. The Wine Lover Cooks Italian . Fabulous pictures, delightful looking recipes and loads of info on Italy and wine.
Check it out! (and it is very reasnably priced)

http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0811841006/qid=1119989613/sr=1-11/ref=sr_1_11/104-4415443-3174368?v=glance&amp;s=books Gecko 06-28-2005, 06:49 PM After telling myself that I am not buying any cookbooks for a while I went in to Costco today and bought a cookbook :rolleyes: Luckily it wasn&apos;t very expensive ($10.49) and most of the recipes sound great. It is called The Spirited Vegetarian by Paulette Mitchell. I am not a vegetarian but I was drawn to this book. Just a word of warning for those who do not like to cook with alcohol - the spirited in the title does mean alcohol in most of the recipes. Here are a sample of a few recipes that caught my eye.

Cranberry Margarita Relish
Curried Lentil Soup
Barley Soup with Miso
Roasted Butternut Squash&amp;Pear Bisque
Potato Salad with Red Zinfandel Dressing
Curried Carrot-Apple Salad
Gingered Squash Risotto with Glazed Pecans
Asparagus-Cashew Stir-Fry
Bow Ties with Marsala Mushroom Sauce
Triple Chocolate-Cassis Brownies
Limoncello Ice Cream MISSINDI 06-28-2005, 06:58 PM Both kima and gecko - I&apos;m going to respectfully ask that you not visit this thread again with your newest purchases, because every time you do, I head over to Amazon!! :D

Not vegetarian either, but these two sound intriguing:
Bow Ties with Marsala Mushroom Sauce
Triple Chocolate-Cassis Brownies

For the poster who bought the Beach House Cookbook (gecko?) -- have you made anything from it yet? Was tempted last night, but restraining myself for now... ;) ctr264 06-28-2005, 08:36 PM Originally posted by Gecko
Here are a sample of a few recipes that caught my eye.

Cranberry Margarita Relish
Asparagus-Cashew Stir-Fry
Bow Ties with Marsala Mushroom Sauce
Triple Chocolate-Cassis Brownies
Limoncello Ice Cream

Theese sound great. Please post a review if you happen to try any of these. The Limoncello Ice Cream sure would hit the spot right about now. Gecko 06-28-2005, 09:34 PM Originally posted by MISSINDI
Not vegetarian either, but these two sound intriguing:
Bow Ties with Marsala Mushroom Sauce
Triple Chocolate-Cassis Brownies

For the poster who bought the Beach House Cookbook (gecko?) -- have you made anything from it yet? Was tempted last night, but restraining myself for now... ;)

Did I buy that one? Ok, it is bad when I can&apos;t remember which ones I have ;) . I don&apos;t think it was me but it sounds good. If you don&apos;t go to visit Amazon I will try and post these 2 recipes tomorrow.

Originally posted by ctr264
Theese sound great. Please post a review if you happen to try any of these. The Limoncello Ice Cream sure would hit the spot right about now.

I will post reviews for any that I make. I will post the limoncello ice cream recipe tomorrow for anyone who wants to try it. Unfortunately I do not have any limoncello at the moment. sooty 06-29-2005, 05:51 AM I bought the Spirited Vegetarian when it first came out. The triple cassis brownies are really good, the cassis flavor adds a nice background flavor. The lasagna rolls, pea soup, curried rice and veggies are repeats for us. I have a couple of her other books and really like the simplicity of her recipes. MISSINDI 06-29-2005, 07:21 AM Ok, Felice, you&apos;re in the clear. Took me awhile to find the guilty party, but turns out gabbyh bought the Beach House Cookbook. So, gabbyh, any reviews yet? green1 06-29-2005, 08:35 AM I picked up the Whole Foods Market Cookbook...I really like this one.
I made the Tofu Chocolate Mousse recipe last week. DH did not even know that it was tofu. He loved it. I think I will keep that little secret to myself.
:D Gecko 06-29-2005, 02:48 PM Bow Ties with Marsala-Mushroom Sauce

Makes 4 servings

8 oz bow-tie pasta
3 tablespoons olive oil, divided
4 cups sliced fresh mushrooms, such as cremini, shiitake, oyster, chanterelle, or a combination (about 12 oz)
cup minced shallots
3 cloves garlic, minced
1 tablespoon all-purpose flour
1 cup milk
cup sweet Marsala wine
2 teaspoons finely chopped fresh tarragon or teaspoon dried tarragon
teaspoon salt, or to taste
teaspoon freshly ground pepper, or to taste

Finely chopped flat-leaf parsley for garnish


Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil over high heat. Cook the pasta according to package directions.

Meanwhile, heat 2 tablespoons of oil in a large saut pan over medium heat. Add mushrooms, shallots, and garlic. Cook, stirring occasionally, until tender, about 5 minutes.

Add remaining 1 tablespoon of oil, then add flour and stir until bubbly. Add the milk all at once and stir until thickened, about 3 minutes. Add the remaining ingredients, except the garnish, and stir until thoroughly warmed. Taste and adjust seasonings.

When the pasta is done, drain well.

To serve, arrange the pasta in shallow pasta bowls, top with sauce, and garnish with parsley. Gecko 06-29-2005, 02:52 PM Triple Chocolate-Cassis Brownies

Makes one 13-inch x 9-inch pan (30 brownies)

Love at first bite. Serve these dense fudgelike brownies in small pieces. You can create variations on the theme by substituting other fruit-flavored liqueurs, such as raspberry. I find that ruby port also adds a nice touch. For a dessert pairing, pour small glasses of raspberry-flavored liqueur, such as Framboise.

6 ounces bittersweet chocolate, coarsely chopped (see Tip)
6 ounces semisweet chocolate, coarsely chopped
2 ounces unsweetened chocolate, coarsely chopped
1 cup butter
cup unsweetened cocoa powder
3 eggs
1 cup sugar
cup packed brown sugar
cup Crme de Cassis liqueur 2 teaspoons pure vanilla extract
1 cups all-purpose flour
teaspoon salt

Preheat the oven to 350F. Lightly coat a 13-inch x 9-inch baking pan with cooking spray.


Combine the chocolates with the butter and cocoa powder in the top pan of a double boiler over barely simmering water. Stir as the chocolates melt until smooth. Remove the top portion of the double boiler; let stand until the mixture is lukewarm, about 10 minutes.


Meanwhile, lightly beat the eggs in a large bowl. Add the sugars; beat with an electric mixer at high speed until thick and light-colored, about 5 minutes. Beat in the Crme de Cassis and vanilla. Add the chocolate mixture and beat until well blended. With the mixer on low speed, gradually add the flour and salt; beat just until combined.


Pour the batter into the prepared pan and smooth the surface with a rubber spatula. Bake for about 30 minutes or until a toothpick inserted 2 inches from the center comes out slightly moist.


Cool the brownies in the pan on a rack. When completely cool, cut the brownies into 30 squares. (Use a sharp knife and dip it in cool water for clean cuts.) Refrigerate the brownies with wax paper between layers in a covered pan. SueK 06-29-2005, 02:57 PM This past weekened I ordered Casual Cooking by Michael Chiarello and The Greens Cookbook by Deborah Madison, both used, off Amazon. I&apos;m looking forward to the mailman hopefully bringing them soon! Gecko 06-29-2005, 02:58 PM I know that I said I would add the limoncello ice cream recipe as well but after looking more closely I see that it really isn&apos;t a recipe for ice cream as such, more a use for using up your home-made limoncello. Vanilla ice cream + limoncello = limoncello ice cream :rolleyes: . I&apos;m going to try and get a bottle of limoncello and experiment with a lemon ice cream recipe, but I will just substitute the limoncello for the lemon juice. pschambers 06-29-2005, 08:31 PM I HAVE to stay away from Tuesday Morning. I went again today and picked up Baking in America (thanks annagins!), The Gardners&apos; Community Cookbook , and Wolfgang Puck&apos;s Pizza, Pasta, and More.

Patti cinnabun 06-30-2005, 11:20 PM &quot;The Foster&apos;s Market Cookbook : Favorite Recipes for Morning, Noon,
and
Night&quot;

&quot;Essentials of Classic Italian Cooking&quot;

&quot;Fresh Every Day: More Great Recipes from Foster&apos;s Market&quot;

&quot;The Bread Lover&apos;s Bread Machine Cookbook&quot;

&quot;A New Way to Cook&quot;

&quot;The Good Housekeeping Step-by-Step Cookbook : More Than 1,000
Recipes *
1,800 Photographs&quot; cinnabun 06-30-2005, 11:21 PM Hope I like the fosters market one
Any suggestions? Will have to wait until I get them to try anything though. MISSINDI 07-01-2005, 07:17 AM I bought a bunch of cookbooks from Amazon this week (all used, and quite a few under $1 each!). Will post the titles once they start coming. In the meantime, looks like I need to head over to Tuesday Morning this weekend! :D gabbyh 07-01-2005, 07:23 AM Think we need to start a new July Cookbook Thread..anyone???

My latest:

Delicious Dips (thanks MISSINDI:D )

Almost Vegetarian

The Savory Way

New World Kitchen

Ready When You Are

The Garden-Fresh Vegetable Cookbook

How To Cook Without A Book (I&apos;ve wanted this one forever!)

~Gail MISSINDI 07-01-2005, 07:35 AM Originally posted by gabbyh
Think we need to start a new July Cookbook Thread..anyone???


Sounds good to me. You start and I&apos;ll meet ya there. :D sooty 07-01-2005, 12:27 PM I am making the chocolate zucchini bread from the Garden Fresh Cookbook tonight, I make a baked good for the hardware store my son works at every Saturday, the owner(a friend) has a coffee area. The Vegetarian Grill and The Roasted Vegetable are also excellent, although there is some similar recipes in both.

Originally posted by gabbyh
Think we need to start a new July Cookbook Thread..anyone???

My latest:

Delicious Dips (thanks MISSINDI:D )

Almost Vegetarian

The Savory Way

New World Kitchen

Ready When You Are

The Garden-Fresh Vegetable Cookbook

How To Cook Without A Book (I&apos;ve wanted this one forever!)

~Gail cniles 07-01-2005, 12:35 PM Just picked up Fresh Every Day - I can&apos;t wait to try some of these recipes!!!;) oceanjasper 07-02-2005, 06:49 PM I just picked up Simply Delectable by Sharon Glass. I skimmed through it at the store and found tons of recipes that I wanted to try, so I bought it (hard to resist at $9.99) It also has really nice pictures and I love it when cookbooks have pictures. Now, if I only had some time to cook out of it! MISSINDI 07-02-2005, 07:44 PM A few more in the mail today (all used from Amazon):

Midnight Munchies from Diane Morgan (love the sparkly cover) - Gabbyh, this is the same author as Delicious Dips, you might want to check it out

Family Fun - Fast Family Dinners

Gordon Ramsay&apos;s In the Heat of the Kitchen

Family Fun - Super Snacks

And our neighbors just came back from a 3-week cruise in Europe and brought me A Little Taste of India. CindySoCal 07-03-2005, 10:18 PM Originally posted by Beth H
I recently ordered two of Donna Hay&apos;s cookbooks: Off the Shelf and New Food Fast. I love them. The recipes are simple yet fresh and interesting, and the photography is wonderful. I&apos;ll be asking for more of her cookbooks as birthday/Christmas gifts.

I just thumbed through her books at the book store, and her books are beautiful! Loved them....
I was browsing Overstock.com for a couple of cookbooks...they have GREAT deals on new books...better then Amazon....but Amazon has more to choose from :) CindySoCal 07-03-2005, 10:34 PM I just went and searched Donna Hay on Overstock and a bunch of her books came up...now I don&apos;t know wich books to buy :) gabbyh 07-04-2005, 05:24 AM Cindy,

I have all of her books, so I guess I&apos;m not much help...but my favorite is probably&quot;Off the Shelf&quot;.

Also, if you like her books, you&apos;ll love her magazine, which you can get at most bookstores...it&apos;s pricey, but filled with wonderful, easy recipes, and more of those beautiful pictures...I&apos;m so lucky to have an Aussie MIL that sends me a subscription for my b&apos;day every year:D

~Gail MISSINDI 07-04-2005, 07:25 PM I agree with Gail - Off the Shelf would be my first choice, if I could only have one. I love her magazine too. If you have a Barnes&amp;Noble near you, you can use their&quot;member&quot;card to get discounts on magazines (unlike Borders), so that helps a bit.

I got Dinosaur BBQ in Saturday&apos;s mail.

Going to Tuesday Morning tomorrow to scope out the cookbook deals. :D CindySoCal 07-04-2005, 11:37 PM I think I&apos;ll get&quot;Off the Shelf&quot;and&quot;Baking for Two&quot;from Overstock.
Thanks for the input. I wish more cookbooks were like Donna Hays.

I have a Borders near me :( so no discount unless they send me one in an e-mail.

Thanks again :) Beth 07-05-2005, 08:50 AM I haven&apos;t read this thread since it was on page one. I knew I shouldn&apos;t open it. I have to run out this morning and am going to have to check Tuesday Morning (of course, anytime I go in that store with an expectation, I come out empty handed, so that may not be too dangerous). susan_foster 07-05-2005, 08:54 AM I went to Borders with Mom over the weekend, and ended up getting:

The New Enchanted Broccoli Forest - I had had this on my list, but after having the potato salad that my SIL made at her barbecue this weekend that came from this book, I knew I wanted to get it right away!

A Year in a Vegetarian Kitchen - AYIAVK was also on my list, and I was going to wait for paperback, but I decided I loved the sturdiness of the hardcover and gave in.

Small Batch Baking - I got, well, just &apos;cause.

Real Vegetarian Thai - It was one I picked up just because it looks interesting. It has a tofu curry that I am looking to try, but AYIAVK also has a curry that looks very similar. I&apos;ll have to try both!

Susan gaja 07-05-2005, 10:12 AM Real Vegetarian Thai - It was one I picked up just because it looks interesting. It has a tofu curry that I am looking to try, but AYIAVK also has a curry that looks very similar. I&apos;ll have to try both!

Susan [/B]

Is that Nancie McDermott&apos;s book? If so, you are in for a treat! I have not made many recipes from this book yet but everything has turned out well. Her recipes for homemade curry pastes are easy and give an&quot;authentic&quot;taste to the dishes. I look forward to your reviews :) Connor&apos;s mom 07-05-2005, 11:13 AM I&apos;m trying to be good and went to the library to see what new cookbooks I could just borrow vs. buying .... Sure enough, I found a good one and ended up picking up a copy used on Amazon for 98 cents. It&apos;s Prevention&apos;s Quick and Healthy Low-Fat Cooking: Featuring Weeknight Meals in Minutes . DS went thru it and found a number of recipes that he&apos;s requested, including some healthy snacks. That justified purchasing it!! cinnabun 07-07-2005, 10:20 PM How do you keep track of all of your cookbooks. I am really getting a good amount of them and don&apos;t want to buy the same book twice. Most of my cookbooks will have to be packed away and put in storage as I do not have the room to keep them all out and that is why I am asking how you keep track and avoid duplicate buys. I still want to collect and buy them I just don&apos;t want any repeats! newcook 07-08-2005, 04:12 AM After making Lentils with Noodles, onions and tomatoes posted by Aubergine, I knew I wanted to pick up the cookbook it came from. I found a used copy on Amazon. Then I went crazy and picked up tons of others. I should be starting to receive them any day now. I don&apos;t know why I buy cookbooks because I never cook out of them. I always seem to take recipes from here.

The Versatile Grain and the Elegant Bean

366 Healthful Ways to Cook Rice, Beans, and Grains by Andrea Chesman

Grains, Rice and Beans

Easy Beans by Trish Ross

More Easy Beans by Trish Ross

Full of Beans: 75 Exciting, Tasty Recipes by Brooke Dojny

Lean Bean Cuisine by Jay Solomon

James McNair&apos;s Beans&amp;Grains

Special Occasion Vegetarian by Valerie Ferguson cinnabun 07-08-2005, 05:39 PM Just ordered these don&apos;t have them yet--

Donna hay books
Modern Classics (Book 1)
Modern Classics Book 2 : Cookies, Biscuits&amp;Slices, Small Cakes, Cakes, Desserts, Hot Puddings, Pies&amp;Tarts (Morrow Cookbooks)
Flavors
Entertaining
New Food Fast
The New Cook
Cool Kids Cook
The Instant Cook
Off The Shelf: Cooking From the Pantry

Zest-Michele Cranston
Ultimate Cook Book : Red Hot Gourmet (Ultimate Cook Book)-Richard Carroll

The last 2 were suggestions after purchasing one of the Donna Hay books and they looked interesting.

This is very addictive!! cher48603 07-08-2005, 06:00 PM Originally posted by cinnabun
How do you keep track of all of your cookbooks. I am really getting a good amount of them and don&apos;t want to buy the same book twice. Most of my cookbooks will have to be packed away and put in storage as I do not have the room to keep them all out and that is why I am asking how you keep track and avoid duplicate buys. I still want to collect and buy them I just don&apos;t want any repeats!
Why not start a list in Excel or Word. You could list your books alphabetically by author or title. It would be easy to refer to on the computer and you could print out a hard copy to refer to. cinnabun 07-08-2005, 08:33 PM Excel would be a good idea but that would mean I would have to have a copy of excel, which I do but want to try and stay away from using it because I have had a few problems with it in the past and lost information that was contained within one and people that I would share the information with would also have to have a copy of the software. Word is a good idea and I have thought of that, but it is not searchable in the way I would want to my searching. But they were good ideas, anymore? cinnabun 07-08-2005, 08:34 PM What about microsofts works or something similar? cinnabun 07-08-2005, 11:20 PM Of her 8, 30-minute meal books which ones do you recommend? Does anyone own the $40-a-day book? Opinions? gabbyh 07-09-2005, 06:19 AM I have the $40 a Day book, and like it...but then I love that show also:D

Have I made anything out of it yet? Of course not:D

~Gail gaja 07-09-2005, 01:08 PM Today I discovered that my local Chapters has a huge bargains section filled with cookbooks... joy!! :D Even though I was tempted to grap everything in sight, I was verrrrry reasonable and I only bought Moosewood Restaurant Cooks at Home for $4.50... Woo-hoo! MISSINDI 07-10-2005, 01:46 PM Just came home from a weekend at the shore, and there were a bunch of books (used) that I ordered from Amazon waiting at home for me.

I got:

Just Add Water - Lauren Chattman
The Savory Way
Cool Kitchen
Icebox Desserts

Last week (not sure if I listed it before): Little Cafe Cakes

Down the shore at TJ Maxx, I got Tarts with Tops on and also went into the Atlantic Book Store and got 4 cookbooks for $20. One if Gourmet&apos;s Best Of from 2000, another is by Mary Ann Esposito&apos;s PBS Italian Cooking show, a third is a Community Farm Cookbook from Smith&amp;Hawken and I forget the 4th. (Haven&apos;t brought back up from car yet - I&apos;ll be back with exact titles).

I got Everything Tastes Better with Bacon a week or so ago and brought it down the shore. We made three recipes so far from it and all were excellent. GREAT cookbook. :D

As far as keeping track, I just rely on my memory, which is a dangerous thing! I have ended up with a double here and there, and I just pass them on. :) oceanjasper 07-10-2005, 03:56 PM Hey gaja, let me know how you like that one! I saw it for $4.99 online at chapters and put it on my wish list. :) cinnabun 07-12-2005, 04:20 PM Here are the one&apos;s I ordered today:

The Visual Food Encyclopedia : The Definitive Practical Guide to Food and Cooking
The New Food Lover&apos;s Tiptionary: More Than 6,000 Food and Drink Tips, Secrets, Shortcuts, and Other Things Cookbooks Never Tell You
The New Food Lover&apos;s Companion: Comprehensive Definitions of Nearly 6000 Food, Drink, and Culinary Terms (Barron&apos;s Cooking Guide)
The Ethnic Food Lover&apos;s Companion: A Sourcebook for Understanding the Cuisines of the World
Brilliant Food Tips and Cooking Tricks : 5,000 Ingenious Kitchen Hints, Secrets, Shortcuts, and Solutions
The Gourmet Slow Cooker: Simple and Sophisticated Meals from Around the World CindySoCal 07-13-2005, 07:58 PM o.k. I just ordered from amazon: (Love the free shipping!)

New Food Fast
By: Donna Hay

Fresh Every Day: More Great Recipes from Foster&apos;s Market
By: Sara Foster, Carolynn Carreno (Contributor)

Off The Shelf: Cooking From the Pantry
By: Donna Hay

Small-Batch Baking
By: Debby Maugans Nakos

I can&apos;t wait to get them...you are all soooooooo bad for my CC, thank goodness they will come while my DH is out of town :D :D :D pschambers 07-14-2005, 08:01 AM From half.com I ordered:


Forever Summer
Everyday Italian
Your Backyard Herbal Garden
Field Guide to Produce

I cannot wait to get them!

Patti pschambers 07-17-2005, 07:49 PM I have been sooo BAD lately. I went to a local used book store and picked up the following:


From Emeril&apos;s Kitchens
The Way to Cook by Julia Child
Feast by Nigella Lawson
30 Minute Get Real Meals by Rachael Ray

Does anyone have any suggestions from these books? I got a great deal on these and only spent approx. $29.00!

I have rec&apos;d all the previous books I ordered from Half.com EXCEPT Everyday Italian It is coming from Tampa so I hope the delay is due to Hurricane Dennis hitting about the time it was shipped.

Patti kima 07-17-2005, 09:34 PM I am really looking forward to hearing more reviews of Fresh Every Day . I can&apos;t find it in any Canadian bookstore and don&apos;t want to order it sight unseen.

LOL about your DH being out of town when your cache arrives Cindy. Good planning! :D gaja 07-18-2005, 07:53 AM The following were just delivered to my door:

The Best New Recipe - Cooks Illustrated

Everyday Greens - Annie Sommerville

The Vineyard Kitchen - Maria Helm Sinskey

This is a cruel temptation on Monday morning: Work on dissertation or read new cookbooks? ;) CindySoCal 07-18-2005, 08:57 AM I vote for browsing through your new cookbooks :) 1MegMeg 07-18-2005, 11:47 AM My dear friend just got me The Wine Lover&apos;s Cookbook (http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0811820718/qid=1121708795/sr=1-1/ref=sr_1_1/103-1143915-8415001?v=glance&amp;s=books) for my birthday. I haven&apos;t made anything yet (just got it yesterday), but everything in it looks fabulous! :) MISSINDI 07-18-2005, 12:47 PM I signed up DH for The Good Cook and&quot;he&quot;got:

Wolfgang Puck&apos;s Make It Easy
Rao&apos;s Recipes from the Neighborhood
Go Fish from Laurent Tourondel
Thomas Keller&apos;s Bouchon

I also got from Amazon&apos;s used section:
Tate&apos;s Bake Shop Cookbook (a bakery in the Hamptons) Gecko 07-18-2005, 12:51 PM Originally posted by MISSINDI
I signed up DH for The Good Cook and&quot;he&quot;got:

Wolfgang Puck&apos;s Make It Easy
Rao&apos;s Recipes from the Neighborhood
Go Fish from Laurent Tourondel
Thomas Keller&apos;s Bouchon

I also got from Amazon&apos;s used section:
Tate&apos;s Bake Shop Cookbook (a bakery in the Hamptons)

I think my DH&quot;needs&quot;to be signed up too. And I know just the books he wants to order ;) Did you refer him as a friend or was he just a regular sign up? jtoepfert100 07-18-2005, 12:57 PM Originally posted by Gecko


I think my DH&quot;needs&quot;to be signed up too. And I know just the books he wants to order ;) Did you refer him as a friend or was he just a regular sign up?

Yes, I&apos;m just certain that my DH would LOVE a Good Cook membership.;) Please tell - did you get extra points for signing up a&quot;friend&quot;? Beth 07-18-2005, 02:02 PM My Summer in Santa Fe came last week and DH and I have already beenthrough it and seen some things we want to make. I have 2 Donna Hay books on hold at the library waiting for mwe to pick them up. The last time I checked out a bunch of cookbooks, I wound up buying a few of those and then some. This could be dangerous! ;) gaja 07-18-2005, 03:31 PM Originally posted by CindySoCal
I vote for browsing through your new cookbooks :)

LOL! :D

I actually went to Starbucks to work on my dissertation (their new Iced Green Tea is quite inspiring indeed) and afterwards found myself wandering to the adjacent Chapters. I found (and bought) a copy of Alfred Portale&apos;s 12 Seasons Cookbook that was on sale for about $10... guess I cannot escape cookbooks after all! :o MISSINDI 07-18-2005, 05:06 PM Originally posted by Gecko


I think my DH&quot;needs&quot;to be signed up too. And I know just the books he wants to order ;) Did you refer him as a friend or was he just a regular sign up?

Just a regular sign-up - didn&apos;t think of the referral angle. I figure the cost of Bouchon alone was worth it. ;) Go on guys, I&apos;m sure your DHs would LOVE a Good Cook membership. ;) Beth 07-18-2005, 05:46 PM I talked to my DH about doing that -- we were wondering if we would have to use his work address to make it go through. I cancelled my membership, so I figure just about the time I&apos;ve bought everything I have to have, they&apos;ll send me a&quot;come back&quot;offer. ;) Gecko 07-18-2005, 07:01 PM Originally posted by MISSINDI


Just a regular sign-up - didn&apos;t think of the referral angle. I figure the cost of Bouchon alone was worth it. ;) Go on guys, I&apos;m sure your DHs would LOVE a Good Cook membership. ;)

Looks like someone is getting Fresh Every Day very soon :D

BTW Let me know when the mags arrive. rubychan 07-19-2005, 08:52 AM I got in the mail yesterday
Nigella&apos;s How to be a Domestic Goddess
Gourmet Cookbook

I bought them off ebay and got both of them for 25.00 shipping and all... pretty good considering the gourmet book is 40.00 cover price and Nigella&apos;s is 35.00 cover price!!

What should I try first??
I am VERY excited about Nigella&apos;s book because of my obsession with baking right now... but I really need to start cooking some decent dinners.... Man cannot live on cheesecake alone..... without gaining 30 pounds..... jtoepfert100 07-19-2005, 09:35 AM Originally posted by rubychan
I got in the mail yesterday
Nigella&apos;s How to be a Domestic Goddess


This is my next&quot;Got to Have&quot;book. Let me know what you make and how it turns out.:) SueK 07-19-2005, 03:57 PM Here are my latest:

Off the Shelf - Donna Hay
I looked through this on Sunday and so far it&apos;s fabulous.

The Food and Life of Oaxaca: Traditional Recipes from Mexico&apos;s Heart - Zarela Martinez
Haven&apos;t even opened this yet, but I will dig into it soon. The reviews and description on Amazon were great.

The Best Recipes from New Mexico&apos;s B&amp;Bs - Steve Larese
Just what I need - another SW cookbook. ;)

A Taste of Enchantment: Treasured Recipes from the Junior League of Albuquerque
Got this one after reading the Jr. League thread earlier this week.

I have a lot of reading ahead of me, I guess! SueK 07-19-2005, 04:36 PM I forgot another one that I have on order:

From the Dining Car : The Recipes and Stories Behind Today&apos;s Greatest Rail Dining Experiences - James Porterfield

I worked with this man at the university and he&apos;s a great guy.I&apos;ve looked through this several times at B&amp;N but the price online was better. Looking forward to getting it and trying out some dishes, plus the commentary looks pretty interesting, too. ctr264 07-19-2005, 06:57 PM My latest is Falling Cloudberries by Tessa Kiros. It&apos;s a family treasury of recipes but a very eclectic (sp?) one. She was raised by a Finnish mother, Greek father, lived in South Africa and has travelled the world, lives somewhere in Europe now (forget where). Its home style cooking from around the world! MISSINDI 07-20-2005, 08:58 AM Originally posted by SueK
I forgot another one that I have on order:

From the Dining Car : The Recipes and Stories Behind Today&apos;s Greatest Rail Dining Experiences - James Porterfield

I worked with this man at the university and he&apos;s a great guy.I&apos;ve looked through this several times at B&amp;N but the price online was better. Looking forward to getting it and trying out some dishes, plus the commentary looks pretty interesting, too.

Oooh, that sounds like an interesting one. kima 07-20-2005, 10:03 AM Originally posted by ctr264
My latest is Falling Cloudberries by Tessa Kiros. It&apos;s a family treasury of recipes but a very eclectic (sp?) one. She was raised by a Finnish mother, Greek father, lived in South Africa and has travelled the world, lives somewhere in Europe now (forget where). Its home style cooking from around the world!

I have been very tempted by this book and would love to hear what you think about it. :) ctr264 07-20-2005, 11:08 AM Hey Kima, so far I&apos;ve only been reading through it but I must say that the recipes look great and there are many that I can see using time and time again. kima 07-20-2005, 07:40 PM I keep hearing how beautiful this book is- but I need to know if I would really use it....
Are the measurements all in weights etc.? I never seem to use books with only the metric measurements. (I know I should but it&apos;s hard to teach this old dog new tricks!)
I&apos;d love any recipes or reviews that you care to share. Thanks for your reply! mbrogier 07-21-2005, 12:52 AM I just bought Everyday Italianby Giada de Larentiis.

I&apos;ve had a lot of fun looking through it. I&apos;ve made a sausage, broccoli rabe, and orichette pasta dish from the book before, and that was good.

I wanted Ina&apos;s new book, but Costco didn&apos;t have any. :( Their price was $10 less than Barnes and Noble. There is another store near here, so I&apos;ll just have to go check their offerings. :D ctr264 07-21-2005, 10:47 AM Originally posted by kima
I keep hearing how beautiful this book is- but I need to know if I would really use it....
Are the measurements all in weights etc.? I never seem to use books with only the metric measurements. (I know I should but it&apos;s hard to teach this old dog new tricks!)
I&apos;d love any recipes or reviews that you care to share. Thanks for your reply!

Kima, your right Falling Cloudberries is a beautiful book, the pictures of the food/places, etc are gorgeous. The measurements are in metric with the equivalent noted in imperial. However, I think for some of the measurements I will still have to wing it slightly, how much is 2 oz of celery leaves, chopped, or 3 1/2 oz sugar, I can never remember how to convert into something easier for measuring.

The book is broken down into section representing the countries she has culled her recipes from, Finland, Greece, Cyprus, South Africa, Italy and then the World. The majority of the recipes call for ingredients that I can probably find in my small town, note that I have 2 small grocery stores and a very small health food store none of which stock anything but the basics. For example, can&apos;t get chipotle chilies here.

I did try 2 dessert recipes from the book last night and both were very good. One was a lemon creme brulee and the other was Baked Amaretti and Vin Santo Plums with Mascarpone Cream. Made both recipes as written except for the vin santo sub a bit of brandy.

Hope this helps and yes I think you need another cookbook :)

Let me know if you want either of those recipes and I&apos;ll type them up. kima 07-21-2005, 12:45 PM Thank you for that great review!

I am going to have resist right now- darn transmission in the car!:( :( :(

I have hear the carrot recipe is really good- would you be able to post that recipe?
Either or both of the other recipes would be great too-only if it&apos;s not too much trouble.
TOT-are you still baking hot in Ontario? Hope it cools down soon! ctr264 07-21-2005, 02:39 PM Kima, yes it is still freaking hot here, supposed to cool down this weekend but I&apos;ll believe it when I feel it.

Which carrot recipe do you want, the carrot cake or the carrot salad with cardamon, ginger and lemon. Let me know.

I will get the other two typed up for you as soon as I can, I may be away for a day or two, if so, I will do when I get back. cinnabun 07-21-2005, 11:12 PM Falling Cloudberries is a beautiful book, the pictures of the food/places, etc are gorgeous.

Why can&apos;t I find it anywhere? It is not at amazon.com and the only one I could find was outside the U.S. brendat4 07-22-2005, 06:26 AM I have been reading this thread a hundred times and am JUST NOW finally adding my latest purchases too. Never mind that some of them are from back in May. But since I haven&apos;t really looked at them they&apos;re still new to me. Here goes:

Everyday Italian
My DD4 loves to watch this show together. She calls it the&quot;smiley lady cooking show&quot;and always says&quot;mom, we need to make that!&quot;So I&apos;m hoping to try something simple with her to start from the book. A little too many&quot;smiley lady&quot;photos in there, but otherwise it looks good.

Cake Doctor&apos;s Cupcakes! (or whatever the real name is).
Ok, this book looks really fun! Lots of neat cupcakes&amp;&quot;theme&quot;recipes. I have the Cake Mix Doctor for Chocolate book too (older purchase). A friend of mine has all the Cake Mix Doctor books and I recently gave her the cupcake one as a hostess gift when we were in town staying at her house. There are tons of recipes that I want to try but other than a modified version of the pudding filled cupcakes I made for a party, I&apos;ve yet to try any others.

Southern Living&apos;s Ultimate Quick&amp;Easy
Just got this one last week at Sam&apos;s Club (gotta stay out of there--the other two were purchased there too!). So many yummy looking recipes. I made the King Ranch Chicken casserole earlier this week (good!) and am planning to make one of the appetizers for our dinner club we&apos;re going to this weekend.

Quick Cooking&amp;Light&amp;Tasty Annual Cookbooks
I bought 3 of these on Ebay for a total steal! I love QC even though many of their recipes are not light, I can modify them. I have been a subscriber since they started and will probably always be one. I&apos;ve rarely made a recipe that me, my family or friends don&apos;t like. So having the annuals are good for me (storage wise vs. the magazines). Too many recipes to list that I&apos;ve tried. Same for the Light&amp;Tasty books--I like their magazine so thought the annuals were a good idea...some of them are&quot;cheater&quot;light recipes IMO (like, use&quot;fat free sour cream&quot;,&quot;reduced fat cheese&quot;, etc.) but many are good.

That&apos;s all--looks like I&apos;ve got some reading/browsing to do! gaja 07-23-2005, 01:36 PM I bought Diane Forley&apos;s The Anatomy of a Dish today. There are many interesting recipes but I was mostly attracted by her&quot;botanical&quot;approach to the study of flavor: She describes the main plant families and discusses how to build dishes and meals around them. Lots of info on seasonal fruits and vegetables as well as fish. I LOVE that she proposes complete menus (including wine suggestions!)for most of the main dish recipes. SueK 07-25-2005, 02:36 PM This heatwave has made me offically ignore summer and dream of the cooler months to come. Due to that, I just picked up:

All About Braising - Molly Stevens

CL Holiday Cookbook

I&apos;m digging into them tonight in the air conditioning! :cool: Lrimerman 07-25-2005, 03:29 PM Well, many of the cookbooks you guys have sound interesting, my list is getting longer and longer.

On the recommendation of Missindi, I recently got Memories of a Cuban Kitchen by Mary Urrutia Randelman. I have been reading it and it is a great read. Very interesting pictures and stories of the author&apos;s time in Cuba and her relatives. The recipes all sound good. We are having supper club here in August and I am going to pick my dish from this book.

I also got&quot;Cool Kids Cook&quot;by Donna Hay. This thread has been dangerous to my book space. I also found a used copy of&quot;The Best of the Best Michigan&quot;. Interesting book, but probably won&apos;t make too much out of it.

I need to start cooking more and experimenting with some of the books I have.

Lisa

P.S. A couple people mentioned that they recently got the book&quot;Gardeners&apos; Community Cookbook&quot;. I have had that book for a long time and I love it. Two recipes off the top of my head are the Wild Rice with Walnuts and Apples on page 284-85, that is my husbands favorite, we add extra celery and apples (3-4 med apples. Also, the Apple Flavored Winter Squash Cake with Apple Cider Glaze, pg 402. It is really good, my sister has me make it for her to take to potlucks, it is her favorite.

Lisa ctr264 07-26-2005, 11:51 AM Kima,

I posted the recipes from Falling Cloudberries on a seperate thread. Leebot 07-26-2005, 10:40 PM I&apos;ve been on a Junior League kick, since as a native-born Denverite, and a transplanted Portlander, (Ore), I&apos;ve loved the various books from those two locations.

So I first decided to go with one of my favorite vacation spots, the Ft. Myers area in Florida, and today in mailbox was Gulfshore Delights and Tropical Settings . I&apos;ve thumbed through them and can&apos;t wait to start trying these out -- there appear to be some nice lowfat and healthy recipes too! (Which isn&apos;t always the case with Jr League cookbooks.)

I also received Simply Simpatico, and won several others on eBay that I&apos;m still anticipating:

Necessities and Temptations

Pearls of the Concho

Above and Beyond Parsley

Bay Leaves

Heart of the Palms

Charlotte Cooks Again

Charleston Receipts

DH is going to think I&apos;ve lost my mind! gabbyh 07-30-2005, 07:42 AM I just received Tropical Settings (thanks Lisa!), and The Best of Gourmet 20th Anniversary Edition both are great additions to the new bookshelf my husband put up in the kitchen :D

~Gail pschambers 07-30-2005, 08:32 AM From half.com I ordered:


Forever Summer
Everyday Italian
Your Backyard Herbal Garden
Field Guide to Produce

I cannot wait to get them!

Patti

I have rec&apos;d all except Everyday Italian :mad:
I e-mailed the seller and have had no response then I was checking the sellers profile on half.com and it said the seller is on vacation :(

That was the book I wanted the most.

I have also recently aquired:
Off the Shelf by Donna Hay
The Minimalist Cooks Dinner by Mark Bittman
Eat This Book by Tyler Florence

Any recipe reccomendations anyone?

Patti Linda in MO 07-30-2005, 09:16 AM I&apos;ve been on a Junior League kick

Necessities and Temptations


My mom got me this one when I got married and I really like it. cinnabun 07-30-2005, 11:49 PM The Penguin Companion to Food
Learning to Cook with Marion Cunningham
The French Chef Cookbook
Breakfast Book
From Julia Child&apos;s Kitchen
The Supper Book
Essentials of Cooking cinnabun 07-30-2005, 11:52 PM The Julia Child books was because I am watching the tribute to her right now. I wish they would put her show back on tv somehwere, I liked those old shows!! cinnabun 07-31-2005, 01:43 AM Betty Crocker&apos;s Cooking Basics : Learning to Cook with Confidence (Betty Crocker)
The New York Times Cook Book
James Beard&apos;s American Cookery
The Best Kitchen Quick Tips: 534 Tricks, Techniques, and Shortcuts for the Curious Cook
The Ultimate Rice Cooker Cookbook : 250 No-Fail Recipes for Pilafs, Risottos, Polenta, Chilis, Soups, Porridges, Puddings and More, from Start to Finish in Your Rice Cooker
The James Beard Cookbook 3 Ed
500 3-Ingredient Recipes: Simple and Sensational Recipes for Everyday Cooking

James Beard&apos;s American Cookery, is one I will be waiting a little longer on, it will come in a seperate shipment. Kayaksoup 07-31-2005, 08:30 AM Finally, I get to join in. Treated myself to Martha Stewart&apos;s Hor D&apos;Oeuvres Handbook! Visions of canapes danced through my head as I slept last night... cinnabun 07-31-2005, 09:13 AM I thought about buying the Martha Stewart Hor D&apos;Oeuvres Handbook, But everytime I make a cake or pasta dish that was on her tv show it never came out all that well. I think I remember only 1 cake coming out right and I think that was the one with the ganache on it and it was a one-layer cake. Let us know how you like the book. KristiB 07-31-2005, 09:38 AM Hot Sour Salty Sweet: A culinary Journey Through Southeast Asia by Jeffrey Alford

I have a brother who works as a chef at a resort in Cambodia. A few years ao I took a trip through Cambodia, Vietnam, Thailand, Laos and Malaysia that expanded my palate (&quot;open your mind or go hungry&quot;was actually the case :D )

This book is a beautiful read even if you don&apos;t make anything from it. I bought it a few months ago and have tried a few things.

Last week I made the Mekong subs with Vietnamese Baked Cinnamon Pate and they were excellent.

Eating Korean: From Barbeque to Kimchi, Recipes from My Home by Cecilia Hae-Jin Lee

I heard about this cookbook on NPR&apos;s Splendid Table. Supposedly Korean cooking is going to be the&quot;next big thing&quot;

I went to Korea and the food was good ( However, I did not try the Big Dog with Noodles we saw in one restaurant :D ) and there&apos;s a Korean restaurant here I want to try.

I haven&apos;t made anything from this book yet. Kayaksoup 07-31-2005, 10:18 AM Hot Sour Salty Sweet: A culinary Journey Through Southeast Asia by Jeffrey Alford


This book is a beautiful read even if you don&apos;t make anything from it. I bought it a few months ago and have tried a few things.

Last week I made the Mekong subs with Vietnamese Baked Cinnamon Pate and they were excellent.


I love this one and want it so much. Its the top of my wishlist...

The Martha came heavily reccomended by one of my instructors. Beth 07-31-2005, 10:22 AM Finally, I get to join in. Treated myself to Martha Stewart&apos;s Hor D&apos;Oeuvres Handbook! Visions of canapes danced through my head as I slept last night...

I have wanted that book, but never broken down to get it. Actually, I did order it from The Good Cook, but it was out of stock and they sent me a replacement. Maybe they&apos;ll ask me to come back and I can get it then. ;) Kayaksoup 07-31-2005, 10:30 AM I have wanted that book, but never broken down to get it. Actually, I did order it from The Good Cook, but it was out of stock and they sent me a replacement. Maybe they&apos;ll ask me to come back and I can get it then. ;)
If there are any good ones, I&apos;ll share them with you. I would think if you do functions or cocktail parties or open houses, it would be very useful. I think I will try my first recipe as part of our anniversary dinner this month (5 years!) Linda in MO 07-31-2005, 11:42 AM I was at Books-a-Million yesterday and decided I just had to have Fresh Everyday by Sara Foster but I wasn&apos;t going to pay $35 for it! I found it used (actually new) on amazon for $12.99! :D Hopefully I won&apos;t get an email back saying that it&apos;s not available now. Mimeea 07-31-2005, 09:18 PM Simply in Season: Recipes that celebrate fresh, local foods

This book does just was the title says. Its emphasis on locally grown foods- whether from a farmer&apos;s market, CSA, or garden- complements Local Flavors by Deborah Madison and supports the uniqueness and variety of fresh foods that are produced with care by the small-scale farmer and artisan. The recipes are not only categorized by season, but also by salads, soups, main dishes, etc. There are great little anecdotes about sustainable agriculture in many different perspectives, and a fruit and vegetable guide, to help take advantages of produce at the peak of their season.

The recipes (over 300 of them) were compiled by cooks from around the U.S. and Canada, I even helped contribute and test some of them. The best part is that there are even recipes in this cookbook that I submitted! :D swquilts 08-02-2005, 10:31 AM I just got Bobby Flay&apos;s Grilling for Life (thanks to someone who shall remain nameless! ;) ) and Fresh from the Farmers Market.

I also drooled onto Flay&apos;s book. I can hardly wait to make that Chinese Chicken salad one! Max Sutton 04-20-2006, 07:01 PM I am brand new to cooking. I just started cooking at home this month. I&apos;ve asked friends what cookbooks they use to get ideas of what cookbooks I should own.

=======================
Max&apos;s cookbook collection:
=======================

&lt;&gt;Better Homes and Gardens New Cookbook 12th edition

&lt;&gt;The Fannie Farmer Cookbook 13th edition

&lt;&gt;Joy of Cooking 1975 ed.

&lt;&gt;Betty Crocker Cookbook New ed.

&lt;&gt;Betty Crocker&apos;s Basics

&lt;&gt;Eat To Beat High Blood Pressure

&lt;&gt;Fix-It and Forget-It Cookbook

&lt;&gt;Fix-It and Forget-It Lightly

&lt;&gt;Now You&apos;re Cooking

&lt;&gt;Healthy Microwave Cooking

&lt;&gt;Best Recipes For Low-Calorie Microwaving

&lt;&gt;Betty Crocker&apos;s New Microwaving For 1 or 2

&lt;&gt;Microwave Cooking: Everyday Dinners in Half an Hour

=========================== IndyKF 04-20-2006, 07:15 PM I am brand new to cooking. I just started cooking at home this month.

That&apos;s an impressive list for someone new to cooking! Welcome to the board, Max :) heavy hedonist 04-21-2006, 10:43 AM The Professional Pastry Chef: Fundamentals of Baking and Pastry, 4th Edition

Getting ready for my 12 week pastry and baking program this summer :cool: :cool: :D

Let us know how good it is-- I have been eyeing this on Amazon, but have decided to wait till I will have some solid time to devote to it.

Small-Batch Baking is a little Wonder Book-- check out the Chocolate Birthday Cake, which by the way, can be made in one mini-loaf pan instead of the pans specifiied; it worked perfectly.

MY newest cookbook (thanks for making a thread so&apos;s I can talk about it!) is Moosewood Desserts. Lots of poundcakes, pies, crisps, plenty of vegan desserts that look luscious instead of just acceptable, many ethnic specialties. I saw it at half-price, and had to have it.

Bargain shopper Alert: tuesday Morning carries lots of cookbooks at slashed prices-- yesterday I saw Family Circles, F&amp;W&amp;CL annuals, Raichlen grilling Books, Emily Luchetti&apos;s dessert book and more at pittance prices, in perfect condition. Not to mention great housewares. It took a mihgty act of will to leave them on the shelf. I was just looking for a can opener. :p heavy hedonist 04-21-2006, 10:47 AM Simply in Season: Recipes that celebrate fresh, local foods

This book does just was the title says. Its emphasis on locally grown foods- whether from a farmer&apos;s market, CSA, or garden- complements Local Flavors by Deborah Madison and supports the uniqueness and variety of fresh foods that are produced with care by the small-scale farmer and artisan. The recipes are not only categorized by season, but also by salads, soups, main dishes, etc. There are great little anecdotes about sustainable agriculture in many different perspectives, and a fruit and vegetable guide, to help take advantages of produce at the peak of their season.

The recipes (over 300 of them) were compiled by cooks from around the U.S. and Canada, I even helped contribute and test some of them. The best part is that there are even recipes in this cookbook that I submitted! :D

Congratulations on your inclusion in what sounds like a wonderful book! Do you have a link to a buyer for it? Max Sutton 04-21-2006, 11:02 AM That&apos;s an impressive list for someone new to cooking! Welcome to the board, Max :)
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Thanks :) Food Fussy 04-21-2006, 11:37 AM I just won a $25 gift card in a raffle at work, so of course on my lunch hour today I went to the bookstore to look at cookbooks I might consider buying. Giada&apos;s new one looks good, and Jamie Oliver&apos;s and Michael Chirarello&apos;s and Ina Gartens and.....

I checked out from my local library Cooks Illustrated&quot;Best Light Recipe&quot;, and I was seriously considering buying it. But then I saw a copy of the&quot;Silver Spoon&quot;, and now I&apos;m torn. I would get more use out of the C.I. book, since I&apos;m trying to cook healthier for me and DH. The&quot;Silver Spoon&quot;would be a pure splurge. Does anyone have this book? cherylopal 04-22-2006, 05:15 AM Simply in Season: Recipes that celebrate fresh, local foods
The best part is that there are even recipes in this cookbook that I submitted! :D

http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0836192966/sr=8-2/qid=1145704230/ref=pd_bbs_2/104-1840539-3732763?%5Fencoding=UTF8


congrats!! is this the book? Leebot 04-22-2006, 10:10 AM I recently purchased (through various online used-book sources) the entire series of Best American Recipes for the years 1999 - present. (The books are published annually). So far I&apos;m really having a blast! Just reading them alone is intriguing, and so far I&apos;ve found several&quot;keeper&quot;recipes.

Other new acquisitions:

Fresh Every Day

The Silver Spoon (Christmas gift)

Boulevard - The Cookbook

Everyday Italian mbrogier 04-22-2006, 01:55 PM I just won a $25 gift card in a raffle at work, so of course on my lunch hour today I went to the bookstore to look at cookbooks I might consider buying. Giada&apos;s new one looks good, and Jamie Oliver&apos;s and Michael Chirarello&apos;s and Ina Gartens and.....

I checked out from my local library Cooks Illustrated&quot;Best Light Recipe&quot;, and I was seriously considering buying it. But then I saw a copy of the&quot;Silver Spoon&quot;, and now I&apos;m torn. I would get more use out of the C.I. book, since I&apos;m trying to cook healthier for me and DH. The&quot;Silver Spoon&quot;would be a pure splurge. Does anyone have this book?

Congrats on winning the gift card! I have drooled over The Silver Spoon, but I haven&apos;t bought it yet. My local Costco has it.

Welcome, Max. You&apos;ve got an impressive collection for a new cook.

I was looking through this old thread to see what cookbooks I had just bought when the thread went around the first time. They were Everyday Italian, and I was on the hunt for Barefoot in Paris.

My latest cookbook purchase was Giada&apos;s Family Dinners. What are the odds? I love this cookbook. It is full of recipes that are my kind of cooking. Max Sutton 04-24-2006, 06:45 AM I just received these cookbooks:

&lt;&gt;FISH: The Complete Guide To Buying And Cooking by Mark Bittman.

&lt;&gt;Learning To Cook With Marion Cunningham

&lt;&gt;How To Cook Everything by Mark Bittman.

&lt;&gt;The New York Times Cookbook revised ed.

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ oceanjasper 05-21-2006, 09:12 PM I just picked up Martha Stewart&apos;s Baking Handbook at Winners for $16.99 CDN. Looking forward to drooling my way though it. :D heavy hedonist 05-22-2006, 10:10 AM I just picked up Martha Stewart&apos;s Baking Handbook at Winners for $16.99 CDN. Looking forward to drooling my way though it. :D

That is so full of wonderful things. ;)

I have gone on a small, but understandable binge-- seeing two books I&apos;ve wanted for a while, Small-Batch Baking (softcover)&amp;Kaffeehaus (hardback), each for less than $10, and then Chez Panisse Desserts, hardback, on closeout for $3! Well that is my find of the year, I think. looking through that, there was a raspeberry mousse recipe with no gelatin, and that sold me. C&apos;mon, it&apos;s $3!! :D Gail K. 05-22-2006, 02:53 PM I just recently got Weight Watchers New Complete Collection and I should be receiving Giada&apos;s Family Dinners from Zooba this week. I also have the following on my Zooba list for the next few shipments:

The Quick Recipe from Cook&apos;s Illustrated
Moosewood Restaurant Simple Suppers
Moosewood Restaurant Celebrates
The Food You Want to Eat by Ted Allen

Unfortunately, I don&apos;t see Fresh Every Day on Zooba&apos;s web site. Maybe one of these days.

Does anyone have the CI book or these Moosewood books? If so, what do you think of them? My next shipment is not due to process until June 18th so I have time to change my cookbook batting order. SheRa 05-22-2006, 03:14 PM my FMIL just bought me RR&apos;s Express Lane Meals : What to Keep on Hand, What to Buy Fresh for the Easiest-Ever 30-Minute Meals. i&apos;m excited because i don&apos;t own many cookbooks, and i like most of her recipes that i&apos;ve tried. vBulletinv3.8.6, Copyright2000-2012, Jelsoft Enterprises Ltd.
	</body>
</document>
