<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009171" url="http://www.stategazette.com/story/1772424.html" time="2012-07-13-02:34" support="1" score="0.0007855419159511576" bingtitle="Dyersburg State Gazette: Local News: Sheriff&apos;s Narcotics Unit ..." webtitle="Dyersburg State Gazette: Local News: Sheriff&apos;s Narcotics Unit arrests four in drug case (10/11/11)">
			<query id="001241" bing-rank="177"/>
	<description>... for a confidential source to trade two boxes of ... location, the exchange took place at a local fast-food restaurant. ... How could you possibly throw someone under the jail ...</description>
	<body>
		Enlarge text Facebook Twitter RSS Subscriber login | Subscribe/register now | Subscription help 
 Mostly Cloudy ~ 79°F   
High: 82°F ~ Low: 68°F 
Thursday, July 12, 2012 Stories since 2002 Photos Events dyersburgfyi 
 
 Home News Sports Obituaries Blogs Entertainment 
 Television listings Movie schedule 
 Agriculture Photos Contests 
 Cutest Pet 
 Recipes Text Alerts Classifieds 
 Submit Online Listing Upload Flyer View All Listings View Flyers My Listings My Wishlist 
 Deals dyersburgfyi 
 
 RSS 
 
 Print Email link Respond to editor Read comments (7) Share: 
Sheriff&apos;s Narcotics Unit arrests four in drug case
 Tuesday, October 11, 2011 
 Dyersburg State Gazette Hooper Hendrix The Dyer County Sheriff&apos;s Department Narcotics Unit made several drug-related arrests over the weekend, including one in which involved a foot chase and the seizure of a 2002 Nissan.
On Saturday evening, Agent Chad Jackson was performing undercover work and had arranged for a confidential source to trade two boxes of Sudafed for methamphetamine from a female suspect. Sudafed, which contains pseudoephedrine, is a common ingredient in the production of meth.
After being moved from another location, the exchange took place at a local fast-food restaurant. Reportedly, Christopher Hendrix, 27, 1705 Browning St. Apt. A, gave the informant a plastic baggy, containing a white powdery substance believed to be meth, in exchange for the Sudafed. Afterward, Hendrix who was driving a Nissan car, pulled onto Highway 51 Bypass and then onto Wade Hampton Drive. Dep. Heath Walker attempted to stop the vehicle after activating his emergency lights. Hendrix stopped the car in a driveway and ran from the vehicle on foot. Cpl. Chris Chism soon captured him on Thorntree Street after he was found hiding in some bushes.
 White Murphy Inside the vehicle were Chasity Murphy, 32, 1705 Browning St. Apt. A; Jennifer White, 37, 5236 Chic; and Michael Hooper, 870 Key Corner Road. All of them, including Hendrix, were charged with manufacturing, delivery, and sale of a controlled substance; and promotion of methamphetamine manufacture. Murphy had an additional charge of conspiracy. Hendrix was also found to have his license revoked for failure to pay child support. He was given additional charges of evading arrest, conspiracy, and driving on a revoked/suspended license. The suspects reported to Jackson they were either unemployed or disabled.
Murphy also reportedly admitted to Jackson they had all used meth two hours prior to their arrest. The sheriff&apos;s department seized the car, which belonged to Hooper.
As of Monday evening, Hendrix, Murphy and White were still in the Dyer County Jail.
Crime Stoppers will make a payment for the information the sheriff&apos;s department received in this case. © Copyright 2011 Dyersburg State Gazette . All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 Comments Note: The nature of the Internet makes it impractical for our staff to review every comment. If you feel that a comment is offensive, please Login or Create an account first, and then you will be able to flag a comment as objectionable. Please also note that those who post comments on stategazette.com may do so using a screen name, which may or may not reflect a website user&apos;s actual name. Readers should be careful not to assign comments to real people who may have names similar to screen names. Refrain from obscenity in your comments, and to keep discussions civil, don&apos;t say anything in a way your grandmother would be ashamed to read. 
WOW, Chasity Murphy sure is a winner. Dang, did the police take her to the hospital first to get the drugs out of her system because she looks totally under the infuence of all kinds of drugs!!! The rest of them should be thrown under the jail. I have stopped asking why the people are doing this. I have come to the conclusion the reason is not only stupidity but total NO common or any other kind of sense, They are stupid from the word go. PLEASE take pity on these idiots and keep them in jail for a long, long time. IF you set them free, let them have 30 days in a rehab house; THE JUDGE OR LAWYER&apos;S HOME FOR 30 DAYS SINCE THEY THINK THE IDIOTS SHOULD BE SET FREE!!!
 -- Posted by TnWanderer on Tue, Oct 11, 2011, at 7:19 PM 
TnWanderer, you are a cruel and heartless individual. Your foul language is uncalled for. You say horrible things about other disadvantaged people so you can fill better about yourself and build up your self-esteem. How could you possibly throw someone under the jail when its on a concrete foundation? It seems like you are the one that&apos;s not smart.
Ben Wilson
 -- Posted by Ben Wilson on Wed, Oct 12, 2011, at 6:08 AM 
Great job by Jackson and department,as stated
if the lawyers and judges are set free the judge and lawyers should pay the county for the cost of catching these idiots.
sidebar,the japs created this junk for thier comacazie pilots in ww2
 -- Posted by tank2 on Wed, Oct 12, 2011, at 8:06 AM 
I would like to apologize to everyone for the comments I made. Ben, you are right. I think you should take these disadvantaged people and let them stay at your home so you can rehabilitate them. You are a much better person. To put them under the jail would indeed kill them. Shame on me. You must take these disadvantaged people and reform them since you are so very worried about them. When you do this, we will then call you ST. Ben Wilson! Praise St. Ben Wilson! Foul language? I did not know the words: stupid and idiots were foul words. You are truly a better scholar than I. YOU go St. Ben!!
 -- Posted by TnWanderer on Wed, Oct 12, 2011, at 12:50 PM 
tank2....you used foul language too! St. Ben will be after you too!!
 -- Posted by TnWanderer on Wed, Oct 12, 2011, at 12:52 PM 
i&apos;d like to know who sold the Sudafed, which contains pseudoephedrine, and what local fast-food restaurant allowed these guys to hang out?
 -- Posted by closerlook on Wed, Oct 12, 2011, at 7:20 PM 
contrary to some of the others comments. it is usually the d a that slaps or slaps at the hand of the serious violaters. not the judges--of course, the defense lawyers defend their clients, that&apos;s what they&apos;re paid to do. it is the d a that need replacing!
 -- Posted by closerlook on Fri, Oct 14, 2011, at 2:22 PM 
 Respond to this story 
 Posting a comment requires free registration . 
If you already have an account on this site, enter your username and password below. Otherwise, click here to register. 
 Username: 
 Password:  ( Forgot your password? )
 Your comments: 
 Please be respectful of others and try to stay on topic. 
 
 
 Home 
 News Sports Obituaries Blogs 
 ©2012 Dyersburg State Gazette
 Contact Us Terms of Service Media Partners Search
	</body>
</document>
