<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009599" url="http://smallbusiness.chron.com/opening-a-restaurant/" time="2012-07-13-03:00" support="5" score="0.01192228174816584" bingtitle="Opening a Restaurant | Small Business - Chron.com" webtitle="Opening a Restaurant | Small Business - Chron.com">
			<query id="000735" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="001191" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="001396" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000311" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000308" bing-rank="27"/>
	<description>A fast food restaurant consists of a business model that serves food usually prepared in a ... There are a number of necessities and steps involved in opening a restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to main content. 
 Subscribe Subscriber Services Make a Payment MyChronRewards 
 Chron.com chron.com Web Search by YAHOO! Businesses 
 Home News Sports Business Entertainment Life Travel Blogs Opinion 

 Jobs Homes Cars Classifieds Coupons 

 Index 
 Close [X] Quick links to the best of chron.com | Still can&apos;t find it? see Site Index 
 Don&apos;t miss: Recent Headlines 
 
 Houston&amp;Texas Houston weather Houston traffic Nation&amp;world Politics Health News bizarre Deaths Hurricanes 9/11 anniversary 
 
 Ultimate Astros Rockets Texans Dynamo Colleges High school Golf Outdoors More sports 
 
 FuelFix.com Markets Houston stocks World markets Your portfolio Currency Small business Tech Homes Commercial real estate Press releases 
 
 29-95 Restaurants Alison Cook Music Movies Bars Arts&amp;Theater 
 
 Mom Houston Houston Belief Health Gardening Pets Gloss Food Books Horoscopes Comics&amp;games Weddings&amp;celebrations 
 
 Texas Travel Travel New Orleans Travel Louisiana Flight tracker 
 
 City Brights Newswatch Celebrity Buzz SciGuy Tubular NFL: John McClain Sports Justice TechBlog Texas on the Potomac Mom Houston 
 
 Nick Anderson cartoons Bill King columns Editorials Op-ed columns Letters to the editor 
 
 Advanced search Browse job categories Career Rescue Houston&apos;s Hiring Work&amp;Career Advice 
 
 New Homes Rentals Farms&amp;Ranches Second Homes Research Mortgages Commercial Real Estate 
 
 Research&amp;Reviews Build a New Car Find Dealers 
 Small Business by Demand Media 
 Starting a Car Business | Vending Machine Businesses | Starting a Food Business | Starting a Recycling Business | Starting a Printing Business | Starting a Grooming Business | Starting a Home Business | Starting a Store | More» 
 
 » Retail Business » Starting a Cleaning Business » Open a Bar » Starting a Sweets Business » Service Businesses » Starting a New Business » Theater&amp;Nightclub Businesses » Starting a Clothing Business » Web Service Businesses » Starting a Home-Based Business » Starting a Photography Business » Design Businesses » Starting a Wedding Business » Fitness Businesses » Starting a Production Company » Starting Your Own Business » Landscape Businesses » Painting Businesses » Starting a Consulting Business » Starting a Catering Business » Craft Businesses » More Types of Businesses to Start » Starting a Nonprofit Organization » Starting a Medical Business » Day Care Centers » Starting an Agency » Starting a Delivery Business » Financial&amp;Secretarial Businesses » Start Up Businesses » Starting a Service Business » Starting a Pet Business 
 
 Small Business » Types of Businesses to Start » Opening a Restaurant 
 
Opening a Restaurant
 

 
 Problems Opening a Restaurant 

Anyone who has ever started a restaurant will tell you it&apos;s a complicated business. Restaurants involve timing, sanitation, teamwork, smart supply buying, great cooking and even better service. ...
 
 Opening&amp;Closing Checklist for a Restaurant 

Running a smooth and productive restaurant requires the balanced coordination of staff, vendors and inventory. In essence, the restaurant’s efficient operation is dependent upon its ...
 
 Starting a BBQ Restaurant 

Barbecue, commonly referred to as“BBQ”, restaurants are popular all across the country. Some BBQ restaurants are old-fashioned, family-style establishments, while others try to break ...
 
 What Equipment Do You Need to Start a Restaurant? 

The equipment you will need for a restaurant will largely be contingent upon the type of restaurant you open: Fast food, mid-scale, casual or fine dining. For example, you will need headsets for ...
 
More Opening a Restaurant Picks
 
 Starting Your Own Restaurant Business 

Opening a restaurant can be challenging and rewarding. You can make a profitable living from a ...
 
 How to Get Started on Opening a Restaurant 

The first step in starting a restaurant is deciding what type of restaurant you will open: fast ...
 
 Pros&amp;Cons of Opening a Restaurant 

Owning a restaurant may seem like a glamorous business, and successful restaurateurs can achieve a ...
 
 How to Start a Breakfast Restaurant 

Breakfast restaurants carry cheery images of pancake stacks, sizzling sausage, homemade biscuits ...
 
 What Does it Cost to Start a Restaurant? 

Restaurant startup costs can vary tremendously from business to business. Costs are affected by the ...
 
 How to Start Up a New Restaurant 

Restaurants provide customers with a variety of food options, providing a valuable service to the ...
 
 The Everything Guide to Starting&amp;Running a Restaurant 

Much thought and effort goes into opening a restaurant. You must first decide what type of ...
 
 How to Get AAA Approved 

AAA is a well-known company that works with everything from cars to business marketing. People ...
 
 What to Know Before You Start a Restaurant Business 

Studying and learning how to enter the restaurant business are crucial in achieving success. By ...
 
 A Guide to Starting a Restaurant Business 

For entrepreneurs considering what kind of business to start, a restaurant seems like a good ...
 
 How Do I Plan an Opening Night for a Restaurant? 

The restaurant business is competitive, and that is why you need to have an effective strategy in ...
 
 A List of Expenses for Starting a Restaurant From Scratch 

It can be easy to underestimate startup expenses for any small business, and new restaurants are no ...
 
 Things to Know Before Opening a Restaurant 

Running a successful restaurant involves much more than serving high-quality food. The restaurant ...
 
 Checklist for a Restaurant Start Up 

Starting your own business is always challenging. Beginning a restaurant requires you to be ...
 
 What Is a Pre-Opening Restaurant Reception? 

New restaurants often have a pre-opening event, sometimes called a&quot;soft&quot;opening, when ...
 
 Information on Starting a Restaurant 

If you can cook and know a little something about running a restaurant, you may have considered ...
 
 Tips on Opening a Restaurant 

Eating delicious food in a pleasant environment makes people happy. Entrepreneurs choose to open ...
 
 Checklist for Opening a Restaurant 

With sales of more than $1.6 billion a day, the restaurant industry has positioned itself as one of ...
 
 Restaurant Start-Up Check List 

Restaurant owners have a lot of work ahead before they can open their restaurants. The first step ...
 
 Basics of Opening a Restaurant 

Opening a new restaurant is a labor of love. The restaurant business can involve long hours, tiny ...
 
 Ideas for a Grand Opening for a Restaurant 

You don&apos;t get a second chance to make a first impression, so your restaurant&apos;s grand ...
 
 The Risk Factors in Opening a Restaurant 

Although any new venture carries an element of risk, an entrepreneur looking to open a restaurant ...
 
 Food Safety When Opening a Restaurant 

New restaurant owners need to be meticulous about food safety, especially right before they open. ...
 
 Procedures to Start a New Pizza Business 

With the odds stacked against them, new pizza business owners can get a leg up on the competition ...
 
 Free Information on Starting a Restaurant 

If you love to cook and people rave about your homemade lasagna, BBQ ribs or seafood jambalaya, ...
 
 How to Start a New Restaurant Business 

There is a lot of truth to the old adage that anything worth having is worth the hard work. Owning ...
 
 How to Plan a Restaurant Grand Opening 

Whether you are launching a new eatery from scratch or taking over the ownership of an existing ...
 
 Business Plans for Opening a Restaurant 

Despite competition from nearly a million other registered food service businesses across the ...
 
 Guide to Starting a Small Restaurant 

Even though nearly a million restaurants serve the needs of American diners every day, ...
 
 Online Guide for Opening a Restaurant 

Movies, books and entire television networks have glamorized the food service business to the point ...
 
 How to Start a Jungle Themed Restaurant 

Jungle-themed restaurants feature colorful décor and themed menu offerings. These ...
 
 The Startup Cost of Opening Restaurants 

Any time is a good time to start a restaurant -- failures rates are the same in recessions and boom ...
 
 How to Open a Barbecue Restaurant 

If you’re tempted by visions of happy customers digging into juicy, slow-cooked barbecue at ...
 
 Tips on Opening a Diner Restaurant 

Diner restaurants are American icons with a history extending back to the 1800s, when a 17-year-old ...
 
 How to Start a Buffet Restaurant 

Buffet restaurants typically serve food in an all-you-can-eat manner. Food is spread out on buffet ...
 
 What Licenses Do I Need to Open a Restaurant? 

Restaurants are highly regulated by various state and local health authorities. Entrepreneurs ...
 
 How to Open a Pizza Restaurant 

Pizza is a favorite food among people of all ages, and you can serve it in a variety of ways. As ...
 
 How to Open a Sonic Restaurant 

Sonic is a drive-in restaurant that offers a menu of burgers, hot dogs, chicken fries and frozen ...
 
 How to Open a Spaghetti Restaurant 

Spaghetti restaurants typically serve a variety of Italian dishes, such as traditional spaghetti ...
 
 How to Open a Restaurant in 30 Days 

Opening any business in 30 days can be challenging, but it is especially challenging for a ...
 
 How to Open a Seafood Restaurant 

Seafood restaurants range from casual and affordable to upscale establishments that cater to ...
 
 How to Open a Popeyes Restaurant 

Popeyes Chicken is a chicken restaurant that provides the opportunity to buy franchises and secure ...
 
 How to Open a Bistro Restaurant 

The bistro restaurant is best known for its gourmet foods and inviting atmospheres. The menus often ...
 
 How to Open a Financially Successful Pizza&amp;Sub Restaurant 

The food service business is very competitive among franchises, family-owned restaurants and ...
 
 The Average Cost of Opening a Restaurant 

Studies by an Ohio State University associate professor indicate about 60 percent of restaurants ...
 
 How to Open a French Restaurant 

The allures of fresh baked bread and dark roasted coffee draw crowds in search of exotic ambiance ...
 
 Can I License a Restaurant Out of Another Restaurant? 

In most cities and states, you can open a restaurant only after receiving one or more licenses from ...
 
 What Is Required to Open a Restaurant? 

About one in four restaurants closes or changes ownership within a year of opening, according to a ...
 
 How to Open an All-You-Can-Eat Restaurant 

Opening an all-you-can-eat restaurant requires attention to detail and working with the local ...
 
 5 Things to Consider When Opening a Pizza Place 

Pizza restaurants are a proven road to entrepreneurship for thousands of business owners. The ...
 
 Things to Consider Before Opening a Fast Food Restaurant 

A fast food restaurant consists of a business model that serves food usually prepared in a specific ...
 
 What Do You Need on the First Day That You Open Your Restaurant? 

A great deal of emphasis is placed on the opening day of a restaurant. Start badly and it&apos;s likely ...
 
 Good Ideas to Build Revenue for a Restaurant 

Being a restaurateur can be rewarding but it can be difficult to make the restaurant profitable. ...
 
 Unique Ideas for a Restaurant Grand Opening 

A grand opening is your restaurant&apos;s first chance to make a splash in the community. It is an ...
 
 What Is a Good Opening Inventory for a New Restaurant? 

If you watch TV reality shows, you know how much work goes into refurbishing an eatery. Starting ...
 
 How to Find a Building to Open Up a Restaurant 

For“brick and mortar”business like restaurants, location is a top priority. Finding ...
 
 Goals&amp;Objectives of Opening a Restaurant 

Opening a restaurant requires you to consider all facets of the business before the actual opening. ...
 
 How to Open a Crepe Restaurant 

Regardless of whether you want to open a small shop that sells dessert crepes or a restaurant that ...
 
 What Are the Top 10 Things to Do to Open a New Restaurant? 

According to the National Restaurant Association, the estimated U.S. restaurant sales for 2011 is ...
 
 How to Open an Effective Fast Food Restaurant 

If you purchase a franchise from a well-known fast food restaurant chain, you&apos;ll be provided with a ...
 
 How to Open Restaurants in California 

Opening and operating a restaurant in California is a challenging task, as restaurants must meet ...
 
 How to Open a Wild Game Restaurant 

A wild game restaurant has all the challenges of a run-of-the-mill restaurant and more because of ...
 
 How to Open a Novelty Sandwich Restaurant 

Major restaurant chains nationwide use novelty sandwiches to attract customers and offer products ...
 
 Grand Opening Promotions for a Restaurant 

Promotions for a new restaurant can be as simple as offering discounted meals or coupons to ...
 
 How to Start a Hawaiian Restaurant 

Starting a restaurant has long been considered a very risky business, but the National Restaurant ...
 
 Fundamentals of Opening a Restaurant 

A restaurant business presents many different fundamental factors to consider during the start-up ...
 
 Restaurant Grand Opening Promotion Ideas 

Make the opening of your new restaurant grand by letting the right people know about it. You can ...
 
 How to Open a Catfish Restaurant in Missouri 

Catfish, the official state fish of Missouri, is a dish served in almost any manner you can think ...
 
 Grand Opening Procedures for a Barbeque Restaurant 

Opening a new restaurant is a challenging task. Prior to opening, the owner must remodel or ...
 
 Necessities to Open a Restaurant 

There are a number of necessities and steps involved in opening a restaurant. These necessities ...
 
 How to Open a Crawfish Restaurant 

Crayfish, crawdads or crawfish are spicy tidbits of crustaceans, packed with flavor. They resemble ...
 
 What Do I Need in Order to Open a Restaurant in Virginia? 

Small businesses are an important part of local economies, with people turning away from ...
 
 What Are the Challenges for Restaurant Owners? 

Opening a restaurant is a dream for many people. Independent restaurant owners get to design their ...
 
 Top Things to Know for Running a Successful Restaurant 

The rate at which new restaurant businesses fail can be enough to strike fear into the heart of any ...
 
 Do You Need a Seller&apos;s Permit to Open a Restaurant? 

A seller&apos;s permit is the legal document that authorizes a business to collect sales tax from ...
 
 How to Open a Restaurant in Alabama 

Opening a restaurant is one of the more challenging business ventures, as the process requires much ...
 
 Accounting Procedures for a Restaurant Opening 

Opening a restaurant involves a range of activities that must be performed before the first ...
 
 How to Celebrate the Grand Opening Day of a Restaurant 

A restaurant has to build buzz to get customers through its doors. Without a regular stream of ...
 
 How to Open a Natural Food Restaurant 

Natural food restaurants generally exist to make a profit as well as to promote a message, whether ...
 
 How to Open a New Restaurant With Bookkeeping 

One of the most important aspects of opening a restaurant is setting up a proper bookkeeping ...
 
 How to Open a Burrito Restaurant 

It is not difficult to open a burrito restaurant. The key consideration is deciding whether you ...
 
 How to Open a Healthy Food Restaurant&amp;Gym 

People are always talking about the latest dieting trends, but the fact is, a healthy meal and ...
 
 How to Be Successful in Opening a Barbeque Restaurant 

Barbeque restaurants stake their reputations on authentic barbeque offerings. If customers think ...
 
 10 Easy Ways to Open a Restaurant Business 

People are busier than ever and even if there&apos;s a lull in the economy, plenty of business ...
 
 How to Open a Soul Food Restaurant in Texas 

Starting a soul food restaurant requires more than a building and food. Opening a successful ...
 
 How to Open&amp;Run a Restaurant 

According to the U. S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, approximately 546,300 privately-owned food ...
 
 The Advantages of Opening a Fast-Food Restaurant in Rural Places 

Fast-food restaurants provide quick meals to people on the go and offer an alternative to ...
 
 What Months Are Good to Open a Seasonal Seafood Restaurant? 

Many seafood restaurants specialize in one or two primary dishes. If this is your situation, you ...
 
 What Is a Concept Description in Terms of a Restaurant Business? 

Starting a restaurant is just like starting any other type of business -- you need a thorough plan. ...
 
 The Best Way to Turn Around a Restaurant 

Restaurants, like many small businesses, face operating issues that can cause significant revenue ...
 
 How to Open a Philly Cheesesteak Restaurant 

A Philly cheesesteak restaurant can draw eager crowds not only in Philadelphia, but all over ...
 
 The Four Permits Needed to Open a Restaurant in Texas 

Texas state law requires certain permits to be obtained by the owners of a restaurant business ...
 
 Restaurant Safety Guidelines 

Despite the large number of restaurants to be found in almost any community, it&apos;s a notoriously ...
 
Related Topics
 
 Day Care Centers 

 SWOT Analysis for a Day Care Center How to Start an Urgent Care Center What is the Cost to Start a Dog Day Care Business? 
 
 Starting an Agency 

 What I Need to Know to Start My Own Ad Agency How to Start a Temporary Placement Business How to Start a Recruitment Business 
 
 Vending Machine Businesses 

 How to Purchase Vending Services How to Get an Establishment to Let You Put Up a Vending Machine How to Protect the Floor Under a Vending Machine 
 Small Business Index Powered by Demand Media 
Chron.com

 Home Houston&amp;Texas Nation&amp;World Business Sports Entertainment Life Corrections Blogs Weather 
 
 City Brights Traffic 

Topics

 Small Business MomHouston.com HoustonBelief.com 29-95.com 
 
Neighborhoods

 Aldine Alief Baytown Bellaire Clear Lake Conroe Cy-Fair East End Fort Bend Heights Katy 
 
 Kingwood Lake Houston Magnolia Memorial Montrose Pasadena Pearland Spring Tomball West U The Woodlands 
 
Marketplace

 Jobs Homes Cars Coupons Classifieds Place a classified ad Place a retail ad 

Other Editions

 Home Delivery iPad iPhone Android Mobile RSS Feeds e-Edition 
 
Local Services

 Air Conditioning Contractors in Houston Car Dealerships in Houston Cleaning Services in Houston Family Doctors in Houston Furniture Stores in Houston Injury Attorneys in Houston New Car Dealer in Houston Real Estate Agents in Houston Real Estate Attorneys in Houston Restaurants in Houston 
 
Services

 Help/Contact us Business directory Legal notices Privacy policy Terms&amp;Conditions Employment opportunities Advertise with us Buy a banner ad 
 
©2012 Hearst Communications Inc.
 Hearst Newspapers RSS My Yahoo!
	</body>
</document>
