<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009167" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Houston/Pizza-Hut_2190" time="2012-07-13-02:33" support="1" score="0.0016273829407349848" bingtitle="Pizza Hut - Fast Food Restaurant Houston, TX 77016" webtitle="Pizza Hut - Fast Food Restaurant  Houston, TX 77016">
			<query id="001027" bing-rank="187"/>
	<description>Pizza Hut a Fast Food restaurant with a location at 9410 Homestead Rd in ... Order Pizza Online. Find nearest Restaurant. Book a Table. View Menu. See Pizza Hut Vouchers and ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Pizza Hut
 
Average User Rating
 
5
 
Average
 
Sponsored Link


 
(713) 633-6418

 http://www.pizzahut.com/ 
 TX &gt; Houston &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Pizza Hut listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Pizza Hut to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Social 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Pizza Hut
 Pizza Hut is a Fast Food restaurant located at 9410 Homestead Rd in Houston, TX 77016. Pizza Hut has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 5 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Pizza Hut
 
 
 
All Reviews for Pizza Hut


 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Pizza Hut:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   0

 
Comments
 
 
Tweets from Pizza Hut
 @DLakesbear We have sent the card to the address you provided. We appreciate your patience. Thank you for being a customer.
 about an hour ago.   Reply 
pizzahut @druidsdude We would love to say yes, but alas we have so many suitors!
 about an hour ago.   Reply 
pizzahut @KeshaWildAnimal We would love to follow you, so we did!
 about an hour ago.   Reply 
pizzahut @acciojanice That&apos;s a wonderful idea! Visit http://t.co/Xfd2ZpP2 and order your dinner!
 about 1 hours ago.   Reply 
pizzahut @jonsteinberg Nice spread!
 about 1 hours ago.   Reply 
pizzahut 
Pizza Hut Tips
 Tell Pizza Hut to stop destroying the rainforest! Read More 
 
Kyle L. 
Pizza Hut News
 Flats to be built above Pizza Hut in Pavement, York (From York Press) SIX new flats are to be built above a pizza restaurant in York. UK Estates Ltd has secured permission from planners at City of York Council to create the properties above the Pizza Hut outlet in Pavement, which is a Grade II-listed building dating back to ... Area Pizza Hut Donates Funds To Charities a nonprofit organization to raise money for Western New York children&apos;s charities. Since 2002, local Pizza Hut restaurants have raised and donated more than $680,000 to Buffalo, Jamestown and Elmira area charities. The grant money will help the Foster ... Yum! Brands Bulls in Charge New York, December 27th ... Brands, Inc (NYSE:YUM), owns and franchises quick-service restaurants worldwide. The Company develops, operates, franchises and licenses a worldwide system of restaurants, like Pizza Hut, KFC, and Taco Bell. Bizz Buzz: Ureno family opens new restaurant has joined his family to open a new restaurant in Tracy called Manny’s Kitchen. Located at 834 W. 11th St., near Dominos and Pizza Hut, the family-operated business ... a chorizo burrito to $9.95 for a New York steak served on a French roll. Spend a week exploring the island cuisine scene Bringing the restaurant week concept to Galveston has been on Jim Cordell’s agenda for a while. “I went to New York City about five years ago and ... the island’s eastern beach front (the Beach Hut) to the bay side of the west end (West End ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Pizza Hut - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia Pizza Hut (corporately known as Pizza Hut, Inc.) is an American restaurant chain and international franchise that offers different styles of pizza along with side ... Pizza Hut - Pizza Delivery, Order Pizza Online, Dinner Deals, Catering Order pizza online for fast pizza delivery or drop by for carryout. You may also contact Pizza Hut and find out about our catering services for your next big event. Pizza Hut - Order Online | Find nearest Restaurant Welcome to Pizza Hut. Feeling hungry? Order Pizza Online. Find nearest Restaurant. Book a Table. View Menu. See Pizza Hut Vouchers and Deals. Pizza Delivery In New York City Italian Restaurants and pizzeria ... pizza delivery in New York city NY pizzeria and pizza restaurants in new york NY. order food and drinks from Italian restaurant in New York order now Nina&apos;s Pizza and Restaurant Northport, New York - Pizza Restaurant ... Nina&apos;s Pizza and Restaurant Northport, New York - This cozy pizzeria is located on Main Street, Northport Village, NY and boasts indoor and outdoor seating. It&apos;s ... 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 79° 
Fri
 
 72° - 88° 
Sat
 
 73° - 88° 
Sun
 
 73° - 91° 
 
Address
 
Pizza Hut

9410 Homestead Rd

Houston, TX 
 
77016
 
Telephone
 (713) 633-6418 
Pizza Hut
 
 Rating :  5 out of 10 based on 5 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Pizza Hut Photos
 
 Fast Food 
 
 Local Places
 
 Wingstop Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food E J&apos;s Mait &apos;n&apos; Burger 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Rudi Lechners Restaurant&amp;Bar 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Wingstop Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Chick-Fil-A 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Lubys Cafeteria 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sonic Drive-In 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Taco Bell 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Arbys Roast Beef Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Papa John&apos;s Pizza 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sonic Drive-In 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Lubys Cafeteria 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Quiznos 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Alley Gallery Antique Prints 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Art Artisans 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries ArtceteraE Foney 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Atelier Jacquinet 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Awards InternationalHouston 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries 
 

See all Houston Art Museums Galleries 
See all Houston ATMs 
See all Houston Bars and Pubs 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Pizza Hut Coupons 

 Pizza Hut Houston 

 Pizza Hut Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Houston Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | X Y | Z 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
