<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009198" url="http://www.insiderpages.com/b/3719881034/king-gyros-greek-restaurant-whitehall" time="2012-07-13-02:35" support="3" score="0.004791926127175496" bingtitle="King Gyros Greek Restaurant - Whitehall - Insider Pages ..." webtitle="King Gyros Greek Resturant - Columbus">
			<query id="000301" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000663" bing-rank="53"/>
	<description>... 400 Hamilton Road looks like any other small fast food restaurant ... I love going into Kind Gyros, and everytime I enter ... great for us because everyone stays in the car and ...</description>
	<body>
		join sign in 
 Find Near Browse Categories 
recommendations that matter most 
 Health&amp;Medical Home&amp;Garden Hair&amp;Beauty Auto
 Services Pets follow us Advertise With Us 
 Columbus, OH &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Restaurants &gt;King Gyros Greek Restaurant 

 

 

 

 
King Gyros Greek Resturant
 ★★★★★ 35 Reviews Write a Review 
614-452-9001
 400 S Hamilton Road Whitehall , OH 43213 www.kinggyros.com 
Restaurant specializes in authentic Greek food combining fresh ingredients with long time family recipes.
 
 Add Photo Email Business 
 
About King Gyros Greek Resturant
 Categories 
 Food Catering Companies Restaurants Fast Food Restaurants Greek Restaurants Mediterranean Restaurants 
 Details 
 Carry Out Local Favorite Outdoor Dining 
 Hours Monday - Thursday 10:30 am to 10:00 pm
Friday 10:30 am to 11:00 pm
Saturday 11:00 to 11:00
Sunday Closed 
Pictures of King Gyros Greek Resturant
 
Message from King Gyros Greek Resturant





Editorial from Citysearch
Restaurant specializes in authentic Greek food combining fresh ingredients with long time family recipes.
Key Points

 Tasty Authentic Greek Food Dine-In or Take-out in Whitehall, OH Greek Catering Signature Meals 
 
 Reviews 
 
Insider Pages Reviews for King Gyros Greek Resturant

Have experience with this business? Write a Review. 
 ★★★★★ Love the Greek! 
 Sofia G. 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 
Since I live in another city I always look forward to going to this Greek Restaurant. The hummus is wonderful for an appetizer, the Mousaka is perfect, best I have tried going to other restaurants in even different cities. I have tried most of their lamb dishes, the lamb is tender, especially their lamb shanks. Baklava! well the biggest piece I have seen, and I have never seen this many choices anywhere. It is worth the drive, go and find out!
 April 19, 2012 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★★☆☆ King of Gyros ! 
 JAMEELAH H. | Top100
| Rank: 46 3 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 
Awesome food and service !
I only have good things to say about this place. When bringing your family and friends remember to come hungry. You&apos;ll love this place.
 December 04, 2007 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 
Latest reviews from Citysearch .
 ★★★★★ If you need an event catered - look no further! 
by lambtina at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 February 26, 2011 
We used King Gyro to feed 60 people for a &quot;Mediterranean Night&quot; at our church. Yianni really delivered. Not only did her arrive early, the food was hot and delicious! Most people came through the serving line with three plates of food and we still had so many left overs many people were back the next day for lunch - all for $8.75 a person!


 ★★★★★ How good is King Gyros? 
by Jorma at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 May 11, 2010 
How good is King Gyros?

King Gyros is so good, If I was on deathrow and could pick my last meal, It would definately be something off the menu at King Gyros, It&apos;s just that good!

I swear it&apos;s the best Greek food I have ever had!

Trust me, I know good food, I&apos;m a fat guy :)

Pros: Great greek food! The best even!

Cons: cons? No cons at King Gyros!


 ★★★★★ AWARD WINING GYROS 
by GLITTERKITTY at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 September 28, 2009 
ME AND MY HUSBAND LOVE THE GYROS WE EAT THERE EVERY CHANCE WE CAN.


 ★★★★★ A True Mom and Pop Greek Restaurant 
by osurubydoo at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 September 25, 2009 
At first glance, the little building at 400 Hamilton Road looks like any other small fast food restaurant, but spend two hours inside sampling the food and anyone will understand why there is a steady stream of customers lining up even in the middle of the afternoon when other restaurants are typically experiencing a lull.

King Gyros, owned and managed by Yanni Chalkias, can seat about 20 people comfortably and has a drive-through. Yanni is a first-generation Greek-American. He and his family opened the restaurant in 1991 using a handful of recipes handed down from his father. Most of the dishes on the menu do not exceed $10, so a family dinner at King Gyros will not break the bank. Parents will be happy to know that there is a kids menu with some less exotic options, such as hamburgers and chicken fingers.

King Gyros is a hidden gem here in Columbus that you must try. The staff is friendly, the portions are huge, and the flavor of the food is unique and superb. Whats more, all the prices are very reasonable. They even have a drive-thru, so you can get your Greek fix on the run at lunchtime. You can visit King Gyros on the web where you can actually order your food for pickup. King Gyros can also be followed on Twitter at @KingGyrosGreek.

Pros: Best Greek Food in Columbus


 ★★★★★ Light my fire... 
by nursingwon at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 August 08, 2009 
I love getting waited on by the owner, with a big, genuine smile. You love what you do and it shows!

Pros: Only place I know to get Greek Fire Feta

Cons: Small dining area


 ★★★★★ Only restaurant my entire family loves! 
by Panu at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 August 05, 2009 
There is something for everyone and it is always fresh, hot and delicious. I just wish I didn&apos;t live over 20 miles away from this restaurant.

Pros: Tasty fries, salads and gyros


 ★★★★★ Great place for authentic greek food 
by RobbLandon at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 August 05, 2009 
The food is simply the best greek food I have had. Read my entire review of King Gyros at

Pros: Out of this world gabbage rolls


 ★★★★★ THE best gyros in town 
by ShawnAnthony at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 August 05, 2009 
The best gyros and salads in town. The gyro salad is amazing!!

Only one suggestion: Move / franchise to the west side!!

Pros: Good prices, great food

Cons: Small building, only one location!!!


 ★★★★★ Best Gyros 
by melvinbetsy at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 August 05, 2009 
I drove past King G\\yros for 12 years and finally decided to stop about a month ago. It was so good that I have been back 5 times already. I recommend them to everyone.


 ★★★★★ Amazing Baklava! 
by lesliekmoran at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 August 05, 2009 
If you like traditional Greek Baklava you will love it at King Gyro&apos;s! It is absolutely delicious!

Pros: Great variety of Greek dishes.


 ★★★★★ best greek food in town! 
by danielleross at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 August 05, 2009 
my mom and i first went to king gyros about two years ago, and we&apos;ve been eating their food ever since! the gyros are outstanding and although we have a lot of special requests with our order, it&apos;s almost always made just how we like it. and the falafel is better than traditionally-made falafel in the middle east - it&apos;s delicious! i&apos;ve been out of the country for months and have been craving king gyros this entire time - i will definitely be eating there as soon as i get back.

Pros: delicious food, low prices, convenient drive-thru

Cons: it&apos;s closed on sundays :-(


 ★★★★★ One of Columbus&apos; little known treasures 
by BuckeyeinTX at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 August 04, 2009 
King Gyros is the type of place that you will want to keep going back to. It is a small, simple establishment with fantastic food! I have taken out-of-town visitors there who will then ask to go back on their next visits. The food is truly authentic and they serve up large portions at very good prices. For Greek food lovers- it is a must! And for those who have never had Greek- you&apos;ll be pleasantly surprised. The dolmades and spanakopita are two of my many favorites :)

Pros: great food, friendly staff, reasonably priced

Cons: None


 ★★★★★ Yanni is the man! 
by LarryDNJR at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 August 04, 2009 
What can&apos;t you say about this place. Nice little restaurant not to far out of the way. The food is delicious with plenty of choices. The service is excellent. Yanni is always a pleasure to meet and talk with while you are there. If you haven&apos;t tried King Gyro&apos;s before I highly recommend it and once you do you will definitely want to come back time and time again.

I have tried a variety of foods from there but usually get the Dolmades Stuffed Grape Leaves and the Big Fat Souvlake (Steak Gyro).

Pros: Food, Service, Quality, Quantity and Prices.

Cons: Closed on Sunday


 ★★★★★ King Gyros an Excellent Experience 
by lowkeyp at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 August 04, 2009 
I really enjoyed the food and atmosphere at King Gyros It has become one of my favorite places to eat. The food there is top notch.

Pros: Best Gyros in Town


 ★★★★★ Great Place for everyone! 
by STELLA1975 at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 August 04, 2009 
King Gyros is one of Whitehall most popular places to eat. It is not only well know but it is also a favorite to many families not only from Whitehall but from Greater Columbus. The food is unique and tasty, carefully prepared and selected. Besides, the service is always outstanding and you are guaranteed to have an overall great customer service and care. Eating at King Gyros feels like eating at home because it is enjoyable and comfortable. A worth experience to try.

Pros: Best Greek Food in Town. High quality customer service.


 ★★★★★ Authentic Greek Eats 
by jrmcmillan at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 August 04, 2009 
My wife and I discovered King Gyros when we moved to Columbus 13 years ago. I was born on a Marine base with a restaurant run by a Greek couple who opened it in 1950. My father befriended the owner, who spoke very little English at the time and they traded English lessons for Greek food. They are still friends today and I ate there often growing up. The owner personally delivered food to my mother in the maternity ward hours before I was born, so I guess you could kind of say it was my first meal.

With due respect to the Greek cuisine of my youth, King Gyros reminds me of home. From the gyros and stuffed grape leaves to the baklava, everything is fresh and fast. Don&apos;t let me forget to plug the cabbage rolls and lamb as well.

Bring an empty stomach you&apos;re going to need it.

Pros: Personal service and friendly staff

Cons: I don&apos;t live next door


 ★★★★★ Best Gyros in Columbus 
by brendasue05 at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 August 04, 2009 
King Gyros has the best Gyros and Greek Food in Columbus. It might be a small restaurant but the food is excellant. Great people working there also!

Pros: Great food and great people

Cons: Restaurant too small


 ★★★★☆ Great Food, Good Service 
by TMcKenna at Citysearch 4 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 August 04, 2009 
I love going into Kind Gyros, and everytime I enter they make me feel like family. I know I get the same great tasting food everytime!

If you are looking for quaility Greek food, then Get it at King Gyros!

Pros: Great Tasting Food!

Cons: None


 ★★★★★ So GOOD my 16 y/o begs to eat there! 
by Tara0111 at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 August 04, 2009 
I usually enjoy eating at King Gyro with only my 16 y/o but recently we decided to bring her 7 y/o sister along. Now I have 2 daughters that love King Gyro!! We just love the dressing...so good you could drink it!

Pros: DRESSING YUMMY!!

Cons: Coke Products


 ★★★★★ King Gyros takes pride in more than just customer service! 
by NickTheGreek at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 April 18, 2009 
Born and raised into a Greek family, coming to King Gyros reminds me of my childhood. I&apos;m always greeted with a smile and the smell of something authentic cooking in the background. Yanni takes pride in sharing his family&apos;s secret receipes with all of us on an everyday basis. You never know what he&apos;s going to do next! I don&apos;t know what I would do without King Gyros being part of my weekly routine!



Pros: Dolmades, Gyro Bowls, list keeps going...

Cons: Can&apos;t think of any!


 ★★★★★ Must, Must Experience King Gyros!!! 
by SarahStruewing at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 April 08, 2009 
I found this place 10 years ago and have been coming back ever since. I definitely recommend this place to anyone and everyone in Columbus. It is worth the drive, believe me, there is no better place for a gyro!

Pros: Best Gyros in Columbus!

Cons: Not open on sundays - the days I crave it the most.!


 ★★★★★ very good place for everyone... 
by mandaharper at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 April 06, 2009 
the orders are always correct...if not they go out of their ways and do everything possible to make it right and make sure you are not wasting your time. the food is good and there is a wide variety. it is good if you want to have dinner alone, as a couple, as a family, as co-workers. all around the place is great and the team there is very close and like family. that is the good thing about king gyros...the team is like a big family and they stick together no matter what.

Pros: good service

Cons: n/a


 ★★★★★ Best Gyro Ever 
by prayerangel614 at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 April 06, 2009 
Gyros are real not frozen imitation. Authentic, tasty and worth every dime. Deserts are great. Reasonable prices.

Pros: Big Gyros Fresh Bread, Lots of Meat

Cons: Can&apos;t think of one


 ★★★★★ Authentic Greek Food Cooked By People Who Care 
by Robin1122 at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 April 06, 2009 
After being disappointed at &quot;Greek&quot; restaurants that really served a mix of Middle-Eastern fare and no real Greek food, I was so happy to find King Gyros. The entire menu is delicious. Before I found this place, it had been about 25 years since I&apos;d had REAL baklava, and King Gyros makes it perfectly. They use the proper honey syrup (instead of heavy, straight honey which would make it too sweet). They add new things to the menu all the time. I go 12 miles out of my way to pick up a meal there. They are usually very busy, and even when I order ahead of time, there is always a wait to get my order, but it is so worth it. Besides, it is good they are busy; it means business is good, and they will stay open! They care about their customers and go out of their way to make sure you get exactly what you want, and they provide the rare treat of authentic Greek food.

Pros: Great prices, Fresh&amp;satisfying food, Family owned&amp;run

Cons: Drive thru&amp;counter wait can be 15min+ at prime time


 ★★★★★ Best gosh darn Greek food in town 
by DonnaPop at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 April 06, 2009 
Yanni keeps a tight ship -- he ensures that food is consistently good and prices are not that high. His food is delicious.

Pros: Always consistent in quality; large quantities served

Cons: Restrooms not in the dining room


 ★★★★★ Fast and fresh Greek food 
by bloodorange at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 September 21, 2008 
On first glance, you might be tempted to drive on by, but don&apos;t be deceived by the modest exterior. This is delicious Greek food! We have tried several dishes there and have never been disappointed. The dolmades, cabbage rolls, moussaka, gyros, and souvlaki pita are some of our favorites. My vegetarian friend enjoys the veggie pita or a dinner of dips! Don&apos;t miss the Greek fries! We&apos;ve also tried most of the pastries and haven&apos;t met one we didn&apos;t enjoy yet. Our favorite is the classic baklava. The staff is helpful and accommodating. They will readily add more dressing or ingredients of your choice, or take items away at your request. You simply walk up to the counter, order your food and then sit and wait for it to be ready. As one reviewer also stated, they do have a drive thru window. This is classic food that is simple and delicious and worth a drive to Whitehall!

Pros: inexpensive, authentic, casual

Cons: note that it is closed on Sundays


 ★★★★★ Delicious Greek Food!! 
by StacyB2 at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 July 27, 2008 
Delicious Greek Food!!
We went there for the first time with my kids and my kids keep on taking us back for more good Greek food.
The Drive-thru works great for us because everyone stays in the car and we can still get something different.
My husband gets the Big Fat Gyro, I get the chicken gyro, and the kids like the Chicken dippers with their dressing that it is out of this world. We are glad our friend told us about this place we drive a couple of miles to get to. The place is worth it. Service is good, always pleasant. A very good change from the ordinary.

Pros: A pleasant change from the ordinary food, portions are quite big

Cons: Should of been next to my house


 ★★★★★ nice choice for fast good food tasty and different. fresh Baklava-soups-salad-gyro (oh my goodness) 
by melodyk at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 March 25, 2008 
we have been there about 36 time in the last year.
eveything is good we have tryed something different each time but the gyro salad is so good we get it every time. best soup Broccoli Cheddar you can buy. the Stuffed Peppers is a nice choice. and it you still have to have a burger anf fries they got that too. lat time i got a Chicken Gyro it was so good tast like slow rosted.
i realy don&apos;t think there is a better fast food place as good as this one. Fresh and fast .

Pros: (order on line)great for party food-Fresh- fast food at it&apos;s best Chicken -lamb-Fish-Burgers-fries- soups-salads gyro&apos;s- Appetizers Greek Specialties

Cons: not open on sunday


 ★★★★★ Best Gyros and Grape Leaves 
by MikeGarber at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 February 03, 2008 
Since I moved form New York, I have tried several Greek places but none Authentic as King Gyros,
their gyros are to die for and the grape leaves with the lemon sauce are the best I have ever had.
Now I know where to go. It is going to be a weekly visit.


 ★★★★★ My Greek Festival, weekly 
by tonytonakis at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 September 02, 2007 
I visited the Greek Festival this weekend and then discovered King Gyros. This is going to be my weekly destination, very well priced and unlike others, this guy is really Greek! The best gyros and 4-5 soups every day. A lot of Greek Dishes too.
I don&apos;t have to wait til next year for this Festival. Happy atmosphere even in the Drive-thru.
You won&apos;t be disapointed.

Pros: Very good and something different from the ordinary

Cons: Nata


 ★★★★★ The best 
by coolcolumbus at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 June 10, 2006 
I love it. The food is excellent and they have a drive thru! It is the perfect take out dinner. The owner is very friendly and the food is authentic. It is a casual place and very relaxed. I can&apos;t stress enough how good the food is and everything is fresh.

Pros: a drive thru!

Cons: none


 ★★★★★ You will NOT be disappointed! 
by scorpionjen at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 May 20, 2006 
I love Greek food but have wandered astray in the past months, mainly due to the quality of the food in surrounding Greek restaurants. I found this gem when I was about to give up all hope. King Gyro&apos;s is the best Greek restaurant in Columbus, period. The staff is friendly and accomodating, the menu is extensive, the prices are fair, the desserts are to die for and the food is outstanding! The baklava is simply the best there is!

Pros: Outstanding food, Tasty desserts, Fair prices

Cons: Parking lot, close quarter dining


 ★★★★★ Best Gyro&apos;s Ever 
by saintrobyn at Citysearch 5 King Gyros Greek Restaurant 
 July 12, 2005 
I have had quite a few gyro&apos;s around town and this is the top on my list. This establishment also knows how to treat their customers. The owner is always warm and friendly and the associates follow suit. If you are looking for a great experience go to King Gyro, you will not be disappointed.

Pros: The owner, The $9.99 King Sack

Cons: Not a darn thing


 Write a Review Get Map&amp;Directions 
Modify or Try Another Search For:
 
Fast Food Restaurants - Columbus, OH
 Find Near Home | About Us | FAQ | Blog | Help/Contact Us | Feedback | Store Finder | Doctor Finder | Sitemap | Privacy Policy (updated) | Terms &amp; Conditions ©2004–2012 Insider Pages. All rights reserved. Partner Sites: MyAutismTeam | Ask Answers | Ask Kids | Life123 | Citysearch | MerchantCircle | Urbanspoon Content by CityGrid; Data by InfoGroup;©2012
	</body>
</document>
