<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009622" url="http://www.tmcasino.com/Slots.aspx" time="2012-07-13-03:01" support="1" score="0.002168131812077304" bingtitle="Table Mountain Casino, located in Friant, CA near Fresno, is one ..." webtitle="Table Mountain Casino, located in Friant, CA near Fresno, is one of the Best Indian Casinos for entertainment and gambling in California.">
			<query id="001299" bing-rank="19"/>
	<description>Visit Table Mountain Casino in Friant ... These random jackpots pay up to $150,000 or add Free Bonus Play anytime you play, just by using The Club Card!</description>
	<body>
		Table Mountain Casino 
 HOME ABOUT US 
 About Us Contact Us Donation Requests Gift Shop Media Room Eagle Springs Golf&amp;Country Club Careers 
 CASINO 
 Casino Slots Table Games Poker Bingo Win Loss Statement Winners 
 PLAYERS CLUB 
 Players Club Club Rewards Sign Up Online 
 ENTERTAINMENT 
 Entertainment Concerts&amp;Events 
 PROMOTIONS 
 Promotions Mega Mountain Jackpots Tournaments 
 DINING 
 Dining Mountain Feast Buffet Eagles Landing Restaurant TM Cafe 
 GETTING HERE 
 Getting Here Bus Schedule 
 
 
 
 
 
Slots

From the Penny Parlor to the High Limit Room, Table Mountain Casino slot players have it all with 2,000 slot machines to choose from. As a bonus, Mega Mountain Jackpots are available on every one of our slot machines! These random jackpots pay up to $150,000 or add Free Bonus Play anytime you play, just by using The Club Card!

Our casino floor is always filled with the newest, most unique, and most popular video, reel, poker, and keno slots with player favorites like Wheel of Fortune, Double Blazing 7’s and Queen of the Nile!

 
 
Michael Jackson


Michael Jackson King of Pop Slots

A Real Thriller. Relive Michael&apos;s greatest performances with surround sound, high-def visuals featuring classic MJ Dance Moves, and Thrilling Progressive Slot Play.


 

 
Reel Edge Slots


We&apos;re one of only 10 casinos in the country to have the new Reel Edge slots! Be one of the first to play these thrilling skill-based games!


 

 
Cashman Fever


 Mr. Cashman is back, and he’s better than ever! Cashman Fever™ brings the excitement to a scorching hot new level. Cashman Fever is a feature-rich, highly entertaining experience with four red-hot, high-frequency Cashman Fever bonus features and an exclusive Cashman Fever Progressive Link feature that offers 20 jackpot pools. 


 

 
More Chili


 Spice it up with a game that delivers more action – and more heat! 


 

 
More Hearts


 With free games and a pulse-pounding bonus feature, what’s not to love about this one? 


 
 
 
 
 &gt; 
 CONTACT US | SPONSORSHIPS | PRIVACY POLICY | MEDIA ROOM | SITE MAP | RESPONSIBLE GAMING | CAREERS Copyright 2012 Table Mountain Casino Inc. All rights reserved. SEARCH: 
 
*There may be slight delays in transitioning the number from the Casino floor to our website. Please contact the Casino for the current amount.
	</body>
</document>
