<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009263" url="http://www.katom.com/487-STCCBSE.html" time="2012-07-13-02:39" support="49" score="0.15657951671541723" bingtitle="Waymar STCCBSE Trash Container, Single, Laminated, 35 Gal, Top w ..." webtitle="Waymar STCCBSE Trash Container, Single, Laminated, 35 Gal, Top w/ Black Plastic Tray Stops">
			<query id="000320" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000317" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000342" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000343" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000329" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000323" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000102" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000885" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000352" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000781" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000228" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="000314" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000214" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000326" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="000507" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000218" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000008" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="001346" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000103" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000009" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000026" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000189" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="001513" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001323" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="001320" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000759" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="001356" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000432" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000775" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000777" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="001482" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="001105" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000030" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="000339" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000764" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000183" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000322" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000337" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000761" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000524" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000120" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000321" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="001325" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000513" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000757" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000197" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000508" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="001332" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000758" bing-rank="24"/>
	<description>Track my Order ... This tray top trash container is ideal for fast food ... face frame, (1) 35 gallon rigid liner, gravity return ...</description>
	<body>
		Need help with your purchase?

Chat with a KaTom specialist
 No, thanks Residential Clearance ( Log In or Register ) Track my Order 
RESTAURANT SUPPLY, INC.
 1-800-541-8683 
 Restaurant Equipment 
 Commercial Refrigeration Commercial Ice Makers Ovens&amp;Ranges Food Warming Equipment Commercial Fryers Grills, Griddles, Char-Broilers, Hot Plates&amp;Accessories Sinks, Faucets&amp;Accessories Shelving&amp;Carts Commercial Dishwashers Slicers Work Tables, Butcher Blocks&amp;Equipment Stands Commercial Mixers Food Bars&amp;Accessories Vegetable and Salad Dryers Hoods&amp;Accessories 
 

 Kitchen Supplies 
 Textiles, Aprons, Towels, Smocks, Pot-holders, Gloves Baking Supplies Storage Containers&amp;Food Bar Crocks Steam Pans&amp;Covers Kitchen Utensils Chafers Trays&amp;Tray Stands Cookware Knives, Turners&amp;Accessories Hot Food Pans, Covers&amp;Accessories Food Pans&amp;Accessories Foodservice Brushes Can&amp;Bottle Openers Time Clocks&amp;Timers Signage 
 

 Tabletop 
 Serving Items Dispensers Silverware&amp;Flatware Table Tents, Card Holders&amp;Decorative Drinkware Baskets Dinnerware Shakers&amp;Mills (Salt, Pepper, Cheese&amp;Other) Presentation Cookware / Serveware Cooling Tubs Menu Covers&amp;Guest Checks Cash&amp;Carry Items Dessert&amp;Pastry Carts Buffet Stands and Risers Table Coverings / Tablecloths 
 

 Countertop 
 Concession Equipment Food Warmers Mixers&amp;Accessories Drink Dispensers Condiment&amp;Food Dispensers Toasters Chop, Core, Dice, Slice, Wedge and Fry Cutters Coffee&amp;Tea Equipment Blenders Hot Dog Equipment Popcorn Machines, Accessories&amp;Supplies Food Processors Meat Processing Equipment Pancake, Waffle,&amp;Crepe Supplies Induction Range 
 

 Bar Supplies 
 Bar Refrigeration Bartending Supplies Bar Drinkware Portable Bars Speed Rails Wait Service Supplies Wine Supplies Bar Matting Glass Racks and Hangers Bar Glass Washers Blenders&amp;Mixers 
 

 Furniture 
 Outdoor Furniture Coca Cola Series Furniture Tables&amp;Bases Portable Bars Youth Seating Crowd Guidance Systems Restaurant Booths Restaurant Seating Chairs Cluster Seating Bar Stools Cashier / Reception Stands Merchandising Carts&amp;Kiosks Kitchen Countertops Rubbermaid Indoor / Outdoor Planters Patio Heaters 
 

 Catering&amp;Buffet 
 Tabletop Serving Items Carts Catering&amp;Buffet Storage Containers Steam Pans&amp;Covers Food Bars&amp;Accessories Chafers Trays&amp;Tray Stands Dinnerware Coffee Percolators&amp;Urns Tea Brewers&amp;Dispensers Commercial Coffee Makers: Thermal / Airpot Brewers Food Pans&amp;Accessories Catering Food Carriers Serving&amp;Buffet Series 
 

 See
More 
 Pizza Equipment Replacement Parts Request a Quote Shop By Brand Buyer&apos;s Guides Learning Center KaTom Kids Jamie Oliver Free Shipping KaTom Coupons Janitorial Go Green 
 
 Order #: Zip Code: Katom  &gt;  Janitorial  &gt;  Trash Cans&amp;Accessories  &gt;  Trash Cans  &gt;  Decorative Trash Cans &gt; Trash Container, Single, Laminated, 35 Gal, Top w/ Black Plastic Tray Stops 
Waymar STCCBSE Trash Container, Single, Laminated, 35 Gal, Top w/ Black Plastic Tray Stops


 
 Product Code: 487-STCCBSE 

Retail Price: $1,014.00 
 
 $456.30 • Each 
 Tweet 
 The warranty will not be honored for residential or non-commercial use of any Commercial Equipment. 
 
Image may not depict product color, inclusions or accessories.
 
Waymar STCCBSE Description
 
This Waymar 35 gallon single compartment laminate trash container is designed to keep your dining area clean and reduce clean up when the day is done! This tray top trash container is ideal for fast food dining rooms, diners, and food courts. The self edged laminate exterior of this tray top trash container provides resistance to smudging and stains. Featuring a single compartment and a 35 gallon capacity, this laminate exterior trash container will easily blend into most waste receptacle areas seamlessly. The hinged trash lid and access floor with magnetic catch prevents waste from falling out and keeps the contents of the trash container discreet. The almond interior liner is easy to remove and will stand up to the demand of even the busiest of venues. The top black plastic tray tops wrangle your trays together and prevent them from sliding.

Trash Container Module, single, self edged laminate exterior&amp;face frame, (1) 35 gallon rigid liner, gravity return trash swing door, access door w/ magnetic catch, almond lined interior, leveling glides, black plastic tray stops, black metal base, closed bottom. Liner included. As with all high quality restaurant furniture, this product is manufactured to meet your specific design requirements at the time you place the order. It is not in stock and typically ships in 4+ weeks. There are dozens of stain colors to choose from for the exposed wood surfaces and hundreds of colors and finishes for the laminate surfaces some of which may be at additional cost. You can also choose from optional wording on the hinged door. Contact customer service to obtain a price and availability quote for your specific needs and samples of laminates if needed to ensure a color match. This product ships direct form the manufacturer. Since all Waymar products are customized to your specifications there are no returns or refunds after we place the order with the manufacturer.

Product Specifications

 Product Spec Sheet Crated Weight: 125 lbs. Category: Trash Cans Type: Decorative Manufacturer: Waymar Manufacturer Part Number (MPN): STCCBSE 
 
Waymar STCCBSE Reviews
 
Waymar STCCBSE Comparable Products
 
 Rubbermaid FGH12IGC Howard Waste Receptacle, 34 Gallon, Post/Wall ... 

 Rubbermaid 

SKU: 007-FGH12IGC
 
 $298.76 
 
 Rubbermaid FG843088BEIG 35 gal Ranger Classic Container, Outdoor, ... 

 Rubbermaid 

SKU: 007-843088BEI
 
 $203.70 
 
 Rubbermaid FG397500 SBLE Landmark Series 50 Gal Classic Dome Top C... 

 Rubbermaid 

SKU: 007-FG397500SBLE
 
 $430.38 
 
 Rubbermaid FGSO1620GLBK European / Metallic Series, Flat Top, 12 g... 

 Rubbermaid 

SKU: 007-SO16GL20B
 
 $119.61 
 
 Rubbermaid FGR2030EPLBK Eclipse Open Top Container, 30 gal Capacit... 

 Rubbermaid 

SKU: 007-R2030EPLBK
 
 $251.75 
 
 Rubbermaid FGCC16EGLBK Steel Open Top Waste Container, 15 gallon, ... 

 Rubbermaid 

SKU: 007-CC16EGLBK
 
 $86.18 
 
 Rubbermaid FGT1424ERBWH 24-Gal Square Indoor Waste Receptacle w/ H... 

 Rubbermaid 

SKU: 007-FGT1424ERBWH
 
 $126.92 
 
 Rubbermaid FGR1536STEPLSM Stepmaster Receptacle, 15 Gal, Silver Me... 

 Rubbermaid 

SKU: 007-R1536STEPLSM
 
 $201.61 
 
Relevant Products
 
 Waymar C320K Classic II Side Chair, Upholstered Tapered Back, 1-1/... 

 Waymar 

SKU: 487-C320K
 
 $126.90 
 
 Waymar C751 Messina Side Chair, Criss-Cross&amp;Upholstered Back... 

 Waymar 

SKU: 487-C751
 
 $181.80 
 
 Waymar B751 Messina Bar Stool, Upholstered Back w/ Double Criss-Cr... 

 Waymar 

SKU: 487-B751
 
 $213.30 
 
 Waymar 0331 Chair Column, Bolt Down, For 30 in Counter Height, Bla... 

 Waymar 

SKU: 487-0331
 
 $57.15 
 
 Waymar 0332 Chair Column, Bolt Down, For 36 in Counter Height, Bla... 

 Waymar 

SKU: 487-0332
 
 $59.85 
 
 Waymar 0333 Chair Column, Bolt Down, For 42 in Counter Height, Bla... 

 Waymar 

SKU: 487-0333
 
 $63.45 
 
 Waymar 0341 Chair Column, Grout In, For 30 in Counter Height, Blac... 

 Waymar 

SKU: 487-0341
 
 $45.90 
 
 Waymar 0342 Chair Column, Grout In, For 36 in Counter Height, Blac... 

 Waymar 

SKU: 487-0342
 
 $48.60 
 
 
Comparable Products
 
 Rubbermaid FGUB1900SSS Metallic Series Executive Wastebasket, 5 gallon, Satin 

 Rubbermaid (FGUB1900SSS) 

SKU: 007-UB1900SSS
 
 $49.72 
 
 
 Rubbermaid FGSC10SSPL Silhouettes Waste Container, Open Top, 6 Gallon, Plast 

 Rubbermaid (FGSC10SSPL) 

SKU: 007-SC10PLSS
 
 $283.09 
 
To see our price, please add the item to your shopping cart. You won&apos;t have to purchase the product (you can easily remove it from your cart if you decide not to buy it) -- your order will not be placed until you click the &quot;Place Order&quot; button.
 Close 
Be in the know and receive exclusive savings
 
KaTom Restaurant Supply

 About KaTom Career Opportunities Product Review 
 
Customer Care

 Contact Us Return Request Order Tracking My Account Financing&amp;Leasing Shipping Information 
 
Shopping With KaTom

 Restaurant Equipment Kitchen Supplies Tabletop Countertop Bar Supplies Furniture Catering&amp;Buffet Shop By Brands 
 
KaTom Policies

 Return Policy Shipping Policy Privacy Policy Terms of Use Secure Shopping 
 
Let&apos;s Get Social

 Facebook Twitter YouTube Google Plus Pinterest 
 
What People Think of KaTom.com
 
Copyright©2001-2012 KaTom Restaurant Supply Inc. All rights reserved.
 
Safe Shopping Guarantee
 
 E-Mail Us With Questions Live Chat 1-800-541-8683 
 Monday - Friday 
 8am - 8pm EST 
 Name 
 E-Mail 
 Phone 

To verify that you are a human user, please answer:
 What is the sum of ? 
 What is the best way to contact you? E-Mail Phone 
 Questions or Comments
	</body>
</document>
