<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009537" url="http://www.dailygames.com/index-202.html" time="2012-07-13-02:55" support="1" score="0.006800692928055464" bingtitle="Page 202 of Free games, online games - Dailygames.com" webtitle="Page 202 of Free games, online games - Dailygames.com">
			<query id="000119" bing-rank="173"/>
	<description>Page 202 of Games, Free Games, Games Free, Erotic Games, Online Games, Flash Games ... Order by:</description>
	<body>
		Free online games , play online games, play free games, online games, daily games - Dailygames.com Daily Games Categories 2 players 
 3D Games 
 Ability 
 Action 
 Adventures 
 Animations 
 Bikes 
 Bloody 
 Board games 
 Cards 
 Cars 
 Classics 
 Fight 
 Soccer 
 Girls 
 Kids 
 Logic 
 Multiplayer 
 Music 
 Platforms 
 Puzzle 
 Shooting 
 Sports 
 Starships 
 Strategy 
 War 
 Download Games Latest online Games Latest online games Best games Best games of the week Best games of the month Order by: A violent game where you have to crash all the possible monsters in a very short period of time. Use the mouse to drive the car. 
 
Pedestrian Killer
 
 2010-11-08 - Bloody Delta Riddle is a puzzle game based in phisics, it has funny visual effects and amazing sounds. There are 25 levels of addictive challenges. Use the mouse to play. 
 
Delta Riddle
 
 2010-11-08 - Puzzle Avoid the cats get near. Point and scary them with your slingshot. Use the mouse to point and choose the potency. 
 
Catgame
 
 2010-11-08 - Shooting 
 Play darts with your friends or against the computer. Get on the aim and score all the possible points. Use the mouse to point and shoot. 
 
Double Diana
 
 2010-11-08 - 2 players Watch closely and look for the hidden Play button in the different levels in order to reach the next level. They will be some occasions that you will have to move things to make them appear. Use the mouse to play. 
 
Click Play 2
 
 2010-11-08 - Puzzle Complete all the possible test quickly. Watch carefully every screen and look for the pieces to complete the challenge. Use the mouse to select and move them. 
 
Speed Scape 4
 
 2010-11-08 - Animations 
 Refill all the horizontal lines with the bricks. Every complete line will disappear and you will win when be no one left. Use the arrow keys to move and the space bar to release the blocks. 
 
Space Brick
 
 2010-11-08 - Puzzle Play this different Sudoko where instead of numbers appear flowers. You can&apos;t repeat flowers neither horizontally or vertically. Use the mouse to select the ones from the sides and locate them in the right place. 
 
Flower Sudoku
 
 2010-11-08 - Puzzle Get into the fantasy and action world of this adventurous young magician apprentice. Explore the castle and tunnels to find the hidden secret. Move with the arrow keys, Z to jump and X to use the magic wand. 
 
Dex Maverick
 
 2010-11-07 - Adventures 
 You are a great ninja warrior, climb up and move it through the walls till you reach the target avoiding the traps on your way. Use W,A,S,D to play. 
 
Visible 3
 
 2010-11-07 - Adventures A dynamic changes game where you have to think on how to achieve the objective which is getting the metallic ball into the basket and grab the little stars using the available elements. Use the mouse to play. 
 
Dynamic Systems 2
 
 2010-11-07 - Puzzle In this game you belong to a cannibal tribe that loves eating the shipwrecked persons. Use the mouse to select the angle and power of the shoot. 
 
Cannibal Casserole
 
 2010-11-07 - Ability 
 Fun game where you will have to get all the balls into the correct spot. Think well which pieces you have to move. Use the mouse. 
 
Alien Roll
 
 2010-11-07 - Puzzle Hoger the pirate have awaken drunk in a lost island now you have to help him to find the treasure and escape from there. Use the mouse to interact with the objects from the screen. 
 
Hoger the pirate
 
 2010-11-07 - Adventures The castle is being attacked by trolls. Throw with your catapult trying to reach your neighbors to ask them for help. Use the mouse to select the power and angle of the throw. 
 
Catapult Madness
 
 2010-11-07 - Adventures 
 Fun car racing game where the tracks are more like a roller coaster. Reach first and get score performing pirouettes. Use the arrow keys or W,A,S,D to play, with N or X the nitro gets triggered and with M or Z for freestyle. 
 
Coaster Racer
 
 2010-11-07 - Cars Your spaceship is crashed in an alien planet. Find the wreckages and survivors. Depends on you to send a signal and escape. Use the keyboard to play. You will see the controls to play. 
 
After years in the dark tunnels
 
 2010-11-07 - Platforms Help the little frog to reach as higher as it can. Wait for the perfect moment to jump and reach other platform. Use the space bar to jump. 
 
Frog Jump
 
 2010-11-07 - Platforms 
 Eliminate the fruits. You must rearrange in groups of three or more according the level. To move the fruit to the place of your choice make click with in the correct fruit and then in the place. 
 
Orchard Harvest
 
 2010-11-06 - Puzzle Help Gallan, the knight armadillo to protect the people from the evil dragon. Use the keyboard to play, move it with the arrow keys, attack with the space bar or with A depending on the weapon. 
 
ArmKnight Armadillo
 
 2010-11-06 - Adventures Second part of the snow trunk where you will have to reach the finish line without crashing. Use the arrow keys or W,A,S,D to drive and balance. 
 
Snow Truck 2
 
 2010-11-06 - Cars 
 This is about to defeat the evil and boring Bill. Throw him bombs with a cannon and destroy him. Use the mouse to choose the angle and maintain pressed to throw it less stronger. 
 
Kill N Bil
 
 2010-11-06 - Ability Test your aim in the North Pole. You have two shots, one for the penguin and other to get on the ice cube. Use the mouse to point and shoot with your gun. 
 
Marksmanship
 
 2010-11-06 - Shooting Spend a fun time being a DJ. Combine your different disco and lights sets. Use the mouse to select the objects and leave it on top to make the discs or lights move by themselves. 
 
Dj Scratch Simulator
 
 2010-11-06 - Music 
 This is a hidden objects game, invaded by animals and filled with garbage. Will you be capable to clean it? Use the mouse to select objectives. 
 
Amazing Fix
 
 2010-11-06 - Ability You are lost in a tropical island and the monkeys are big troublemakers.. you will have to spook them throwing them watermelons. Use the mouse to point and maintain pressed the mouse-left click and release it to throw the coconuts. 
 
Monkey Shooting
 
 2010-11-06 - Ability Will you be able to park big vehicles? Try it without hitting with anything in the parking lot. Use the arrow to drive your vehicle. 
 
Park my big rig 2
 
 2010-11-06 - Cars 
 In this game you belong to a Indian tribe. Practice your skill with the arch and your aim pointing an apple on one of your buddies. Use the mouse to choose the angle and power of the shoot. 
 
Tribal Shooter
 
 2010-11-05 - Shooting Street Fighter styled game but with Kung Fu techniques. Use the arrow keys for the hits and the A and S keys to move. 
 
SuperFighter
 
 2010-11-05 - Fight Make the ball reaches the finish line quickly and with a few movements. Use the mouse to select the angle and power of the shoot. 
 
Go Go Golf
 
 2010-11-05 - Puzzle 

 «« «Prev 197 198 199 200 201 [ 202 ] 203 204 205 206 207 Next» »» Remember! New Games added every day!! 
 
 In order to correctly visualize the games found at DailyGames , the next free plugins must be installed. Search Games in DailyGames.com Game of the week Get rid of the enemy clowns or they will destroy the flowers of the world. Don&apos;t let them get you or you&apos;ll die. Use arrow keys or WASD to move your tank and shoot with the mouse. Just A Random Day 
 
 2012-07-05 - Shooting Most Searched Games Pokemon Pool Naruto 
 Sonic    Chess    Ben 10    Tetris 
 Mario    Ping pong    Barbie 
 Metal slug    Dragon ball    Sudoku 
 Favorite Games loading... DailyGames stats Games count: 14432 Total online users: loading... 
 *** Webmaster - add free games for your site *** 

 Contact        Submit a Game        There is a Game that doesn&apos;t work!        Advertising in DailyGames       

 All rights reserved Copyright©2012 DailyGames.com | Wiju España | Free Online Games
	</body>
</document>
