<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009346" url="http://www.twicethedealpizza.com/Franchise.html" time="2012-07-13-02:43" support="1" score="0.00014281956305520953" bingtitle="Twice The Deal Pizza - Franchise Details" webtitle="Twice The Deal Pizza - Franchise Details">
			<query id="000743" bing-rank="195"/>
	<description>Twice the Deal Pizza is an established take-out and delivery fast food restaurant, and franchising ... Access to our one toll free number 1-866-549-DEAL (3325) Above all ...</description>
	<body>
		You are here : Home &gt;Franchise Details 
 
Franchising
 
Feel like your stuck in your job with nowhere to go? tired of working for someone else?…unexpected layoff or employer going bankrupt ? These are realities of today’s economy…want more control of your situation. Looking for an exciting challenge? Or A strong desire to succeed?
 
Twice the Deal Pizza is an established take-out and delivery fast food restaurant, and franchising company . From our fresh approach to creating superb pizza’s and other great foods we have developed both the management structure and formula for success.
 
What kind of Franchisee are we looking for
 
As a franchise company our goal is not only to ensure total customer satisfaction , but to continue to evolve into a great franchise system. That evolution starts with you“the franchisee.”We are looking for individuals with good &quot;common business sense&quot; . A restaurant or fast food background is not necessary . Your determination and dedication matched with our proven system ensures your chances of success. We believe in a partnering relationship with our owner/ operators. We franchise only to individuals, not to corporations, partnerships, or investors.
 
What We Offer
 

 A chance to run your own business without being alone. You will be supported by the Twice the Deal Pizza network. Support in the areas of operations, training, marketing strategy , construction, store locating /retrofitting , purchasing and equipment . Personal satisfaction both as an owner/operator and as a member of a Twice the Deal Pizza Family Franchise cost varies between $150K and $170K Low weekly flat fee royalty ($200). Access to our one toll free number 1-866-549-DEAL (3325) 

 
Above all ! Continued support and dedication to you the franchisee
	</body>
</document>
