<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009470" url="http://www.cookinggamesclub.com/tag/waitress" time="2012-07-13-02:51" support="2" score="0.003181276310592029" bingtitle="Waitress Games - Cooking Games" webtitle="Waitress Games - Cooking Games">
			<query id="000544" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="001487" bing-rank="195"/>
	<description>... lead the customers to their table ... for you, waitress in a fast-food restaurant. Greet the customers, take their orders and give them ... Collect their order, get it to the ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to: Cooking Games Club 
Cooking Games for girls , played and added daily by our team ! Have fun playing our cooking games for free . 
 Cooking Games Burger Games Cake Games Dress Up Games Food Games Girls Games Ice Cream Pancakes Games Pizza Games Restaurant Serving Games 

 A Universe of its own, BSG online 
 
 Latest cooking games trends: 

 waitress 
 pinky s pancakes 
 sara cooking class 
 omg pizza lol 
 cook 
 cooking new 
 pizza cook 
 real cooking 
 rainbow 
 pizza deco 
 penguin serving 
 job games 
 olives 
 mus 
 lily and tody s bistro 
 
 


 
Waitress Games
 

 Gorgeous Waitress 
 To earn big tips as a waitress the way you look counts a great deal. So today you will create the perfect look for a waitress. Choose the hair style, the makeup, the colors and the clothes. Try different combinations till you’re pleased with the result. ...
 
 Ninas Pizza Restaurant 
 If you want to run a successful restaurant it’s essential to provide excellent customer care. Nina has great expectations from you and she wants you to keep all customers happy. Move fast to serve the food, and the exact order to each customer, or they will get tired of waiting and leave....
 
 Japanese Resto 
 You were hired at the newest Japanese Resto and your goal is to become a five star waitress. So you will have to lead the customers to their table, take their orders and serve them, then don’t forget to clean the table to take the money. Raise enough many to accomplish the target set for the day and you will receive a star. 
...
 
 Fast Food Resto 
 This is a new challenge for you, waitress in a fast-food restaurant. Greet the customers, take their orders and give them to the chef, then place the food to the right customer. Prove in 5 days you are a 5 star waitress. Once the meal is finished collect the money and clean the table so it can be ready for the next customers. Gain enough money to advance to the next level....
 
 Drive In Restaurant 
 You are a waitress at the Drive In restaurant and you have to serve food to hungry clients. Collect their order, get it to the cooker and then bring it back to the client....
 
 Mayhem Restaurant 
 In this game you can choose your character , a waiter or a waitress and you have to serve food for restaurant&apos;s clients. Do it in a short period of time so you can earn big tips....
 
 Dinner Restaurant 
 At our dinner restaurant you will serve one of the most delicious dinner you ever served. We try to make your visit to our restaurant an experience you will never forget. Cooking delicious and tasty food for our clients , we can make them feel in heaven....
 
 
 1 2 Next Last page Barbie cooking Games 
 Dress Up Games 
 Cooking Games Hot 
 Dora Games 

 More Links RSS Feed 
 Privacy Policy 
 Contact Us
	</body>
</document>
