<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009498" url="http://www.armytimes.com/news/2009/07/ap_army_savannah_death_070909/" time="2012-07-13-02:53" support="1" score="0.002346672265618737" bingtitle="Pvt. charged with killing fellow soldier - Army News | News from ..." webtitle="Pvt. charged with killing fellow soldier - Army News | News from Afghanistan&amp;Iraq - Army Times">
			<query id="000175" bing-rank="197"/>
	<description>... old son stranded by a busy highway; and used McCraw’s credit card to buy food at a fast-food restaurant ... Soldier to receive posthumous Medal of Honor; Flynn to head DIA ...</description>
	<body>
		Pvt. charged with killing fellow soldier - Army News | News from Afghanistan&amp;Iraq - Army Times
 Subscribe  |  Subscription Renewal  |  Advertise  |  About  |  Customer Service  |  RSS  |  Digital Edition  |  Newsletters Log in    
 Home News Benefits Money Careers&amp;Education Community Off Duty Entertainment Marketplace Classifieds 
 
 Army News 

 Guard&amp;Reserve This Week&apos;s Issue    Subscribe to RSS 
 
Quick Links

 Hall of Valor Army Discussions Frontline Photos Honor the Fallen 
 
 Webtools 
 Click here for Military Times Webtools Tweet http://www.armytimes.com/news/2009/07/ap_army_savannah_death_070909/ 
Pvt. charged with killing fellow soldier

 By Russ Bynum - The Associated Press
Posted : Thursday Jul 9, 2009 11:58:43 EDT 
SAVANNAH, Ga.—An Army private has been charged with slaying a fellow soldier, his former barracks roommate whose body was found by a dirt road near the Savannah River just before the Fourth of July weekend, police said Thursday.

Police said Pvt. Sylvester Denmark Horton, 21, shot Spc. Necco McCraw, 21;left the slain soldier’s 1-year-old son stranded by a busy highway;and used McCraw’s credit card to buy food at a fast-food restaurant shortly after he was killed.

Savannah-Chatham County Police Chief Michael Berkow would not say what motivated the slaying. He told reporters at a news conference that Horton, of Topeka, Kan., had an outstanding warrant against him for a forgery charge.

“It’s still a continuing investigation,”Berkow said.“We’re following up on a lot of leads. There’s still a lot of evidence to be processed.”

McCraw of Shreveport, La., and Horton served together at Hunter Army Airfield, Ga., for two years with the 110th Quartermaster Company, which handles fuel for the military. An Army commander and Horton’s attorney said the soldiers had previously been roommates, but they couldn’t say when.

Construction workers found McCraw’s body July 2 dumped by a dirt road on Hutchinson Island across the river from downtown Savannah. Nearly three hours later, police in neighboring Garden City found McCraw’s toddler son wandering alone alongside bustling U.S. Route 80.

Berkow said the child was returned unharmed McCraw’s wife.

Berkow said McCraw’s credit card was used at a restaurant in Garden City an hour after his body was discovered. He said investigators soon focused on Horton as a suspect, but he wouldn’t say how.

Military Police found Horton at Hunter Army Airfield the day after the slaying and detained him. Savannah police then searched Horton’s car, parked outside the Army post, and found a handgun inside.

Horton was jailed on a credit-card fraud charge, for using McCraw’s card at the restaurant, while police waited for the Georgia Bureau of Investigation to compare the gun found in Horton’s car with ballistic evidence from the crime scene.

“They have now confirmed that the weapon recovered was in fact the murder weapon,”Berkow said.

Horton was charged with murder and a judge denied him bond at an arraignment Wednesday. He faces a preliminary court hearing July 22.

“My client has denied any involvement in the murder of his former roommate,”said Jennifer Burns, a public defender and one of Horton’s attorneys.“We intend to put up a strong and vigorous defense on his part.”

Brig. Gen. Tom Vandal, the 3rd Infantry Division’s deputy commanding general for support, said both soldiers knew each other from working as petroleum specialists in the same company and from rooming together in the same barracks.

He said both McCraw and Horton joined the Army three years ago and served together at Hunter for the past two years. Neither soldier had deployed overseas, Vandal said.

Vandal described McCraw as a“good soldier”but declined to comment on Horton. He said McCraw had taken his son to a picnic for his unit the day he was killed. He didn’t know if Horton attended.
 Videos You May Be Interested In 
Leave a Comment
 

 

 
Most Viewed Stories

 Rangers to be inducted into hall of fame Family of soldier sues security screening firm Pentagon: Afghanistan exit will cost billions Captain fired over sexy emails he sent Army landing craft arrives in Kodiak Army terminating its NASCAR sponsorship Iraq war veteran faces election fraud charges Family: Pfc. killed in Afghanistan bomb blast Shooting gets Lewis soldier 9-month sentence NATO confirms 6 fallen troops were Americans Faster airport screening for troops hits snag House approves COLA bill for veterans 
 
 Contests and Promotions 
 Win a 60&quot; 3D HD Smart TV! 
Enter to Win TODAY!

 Click Here To Enter . 
 Free Stickers 

 Click here and we&apos;ll send you a FREE AFGHANISTAN, IRAQ, VIETNAM, or DESERT STORM sticker. 
 2012 Service Members Of The Year 


 SMOY 

 Vetting in progress. Winners will be announced July 16.
 
 
 Classifieds 
 
 Announcements Attorneys Automobiles Business Computers Education 
 
 Employment Financial Services Mail Order Market Milestones Real Estate Travel 
 
 Marketplaces 

 Industry 
 
 NEW! The destination for thought leaders in military, government and defense 
 click here→ 
 MIl-MALL 

 Browse and buy some of the awesome products we have at Mil-mall.com
	</body>
</document>
