<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009565" url="http://www.foodproductdesign.com/news/2011/08/kids-pay-high-nutritional-price-for-fast-food.aspx" time="2012-07-13-02:56" support="2" score="0.0040769520791669265" bingtitle="Kids Pay High Nutritional Price for Fast Food" webtitle="Kids Pay High Nutritional Price for Fast Food">
			<query id="000898" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="001118" bing-rank="100"/>
	<description>... and present their receipts from food ... and quality of food, as well as the reasons reported for dining at a fast-food restaurant. ... Have More Fast Food, Obesity; Order Up ...</description>
	<body>
		Food Product Design SupplySide 
Kids Pay High Nutritional Price for Fast Food


 August 3, 2011 Comments Posted in News , Children , Nutrition , Convenience Foods , Science&amp;Research , Sodium , Calorie , Consumer Preference , Foodservice Print 
SAN DIEGO—There’s not doubt that feeding a vanful of hungry kids is a cinch at fast-food restaurants. But researchers in the Department of Pediatrics at the University of California, San Diego ( UCSD ), found that kids who consume convenient, fast-food lunches pay a high nutritional price. Such meals accounted for between 36 and 51 percent of a child’s daily caloric needs.  In addition, 35 to 39 percent of calories came from fat, and the meals provided more than 50 percent of the recommended total daily sodium intake for most children–and as high as 100 percent of sodium levels recommended for pre-schoolers.

“We found that families perceived fast-food restaurants as easy and cheap, and many were using fast food as a reward for their children,&quot; said Kerri N. Boutelle, PhD, Behavioral Director of the Weight and Wellness Clinic at the University of California, San Diego and Rady Children&apos;s Hospital-San Diego, who has studied childhood obesity, its causes and treatment for over 15 years.  “Considering the high prevalence of fast-food consumptions by adults as well as kids, it’s important to recognize the impact of fast food and its impact on the current obesity epidemic in the U.S.&quot;

For the study, UCSD researchers surveyed 544 families with children entering a fast-food chain restaurant located inside Rady Children’s Hospital in San Diego, California, at lunch time over a six-week period.  Families were asked to retain and present their receipts from food purchases and complete a brief survey. Families were provided a $2 incentive to participate.

The purpose of the study was to evaluate the nutritional content and quality of food, as well as the reasons reported for dining at a fast-food restaurant. The top reasons for going to this restaurant were “the children like the food&quot; and it was “convenient.&quot;  Just over half the families reported the choice as “a reward for visiting the hospital&quot; (about the same number as replied “hungry with no other options&quot;).

But adults also overwhelmingly reported that they liked the food.  The toys included with the children’s meals did not appear to be a top reason (49 percent said it didn’t enter into their decision “at all&quot;).

“The number of meals and snacks eaten away from home is believed to contribute to excess calories consumed by children, and this number has increased dramatically in the past 30 years,&quot; said Boutelle. “On a typical day, a remarkable 30 percent of youth report consuming fast food.&quot;
 
 E-Mail Tweet 
 Comments 
 Comments 
 
 Similar Articles 
 
 Rate of Severe Reactions High in Kids With Food Allergies Fast Food Hits the Spot for Diners Fast-Food Morning Sandwiches Ranked Even Health Nuts Eat Fast Food Disney Rewinds Standards for Food Advertising to Kids 
 
 Latest Articles 
 
 House Agriculture Committee Advances Farm Bill ‘Smart’ Use of Low-Calorie Sweeteners Help Weight Loss Whole Almonds Have 20% Fewer Calories Than Previously Thought Low-Fat Diet, Weight Loss May Ease Hot Flashes FDA Launches Genome Project for Food Pathogens 
 
 Other Resources 
 
 The Changing Ingredient Game: A Business Case for High Fructose Corn Syrup Partner Series—Opportunities for Formulating and Manufacturing of Nutritional / Functional Powders Special Report: Top 10 Healthy Food Trends Keeping Food Safety in the Mix: Food Safety in Grain-based Foods and Bakery Products Partner Series—Investigation of HFCS in US Food&amp;Beverage Introductions 
 
Subscribe to
 FPD Subscribe to the magazine 
 Our Digital Edition Our Print Edition See a Sample 
 
 Mobile Media Snaps 
   
Get the latest media snap
 
 Food Product Design Content Library 
 
 
 
Text FOODPRODUCT to 41411 to receive this media snap on your smart phone
 
Image Galleries
 
 IFT—Nutritional Ingredients The Top 10, June 2012 Image Gallery: Clean-Label Ingredients 
 More › 
 Most Popular Articles 
 
 FDA: 40% of Egg Farms Have Food-Safety Violations Image Gallery: IFT—Nutritional Ingredients 1 to 2 Alcoholic Drinks a Day Prevents Bone Loss in Older Women Cutting Food into Smaller Pieces Helps Weight Management FDA Launches Genome Project for Food Pathogens 
 
 Buyer&apos;s Guide 
 Search for 
 
 
 Application Index 
 
 Consultants and Services 
 
 Contract Manufacturing 
 
 Ingredient Index 
 
 Laboratory Equipment and Services 
 
 More Options... 
 

 
 Reports 
 
 Special Report: Top 10 Healthy Food Trends Global Regulations Governing Natural Color Status 
 
 Free Email Updates 
 
 Weekly Newsletter Premium Content (information about FPD Reports, Digital Issues, Webinars, etc) 
 
 featured links 
 

 
 • Search for: 
   
 Home Business Issues   
 Food Safety Market Trends Regulatory Science&amp;Research 
   Applications   
 Bakery / Cereal Beverages Confectionery Dairy Foodservice Frozen / Refrigerated Foods Healthy Foods Meat Products Snack Foods 
   Ingredients   
 Colors Dairy Ingredients Fats/Oils Fiber Flavors Fruits / Vegetables Grains / Pasta / Tuber Gums / Starches Nutraceuticals Nuts Proteins Seasonings and Spices Sweeteners Vitamins and Minerals 
   Content Library OPINION Buyer&apos;s Guide SupplySide Store Resource Center   
 Digital Issues Galleries Immersion Centers Reports Videos Webinars Whitepapers 
   
 HOT TOPICS 
 Low Sodium Market Trends Weight Management Beverages Functional Foods ...MORE TOPICS 
 
 
 Related Sites: 
 SupplySide insidecosmeceuticals Natural Products INSIDER SupplySide Insights R&amp;D 
 
 About Us Advertise Email Newsletters Magazine Subscription Terms&amp;Conditions Privacy Policy Contact Us 

All material on this site Copyright©2012 Virgo Publishing , LLC. All rights reserved.
 
   
 
 Discussion Reports Digital Issues Content Library Galleries
	</body>
</document>
