<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009273" url="http://serviceadvice.cssamerica.com/tag/restaurant/" time="2012-07-13-02:39" support="16" score="0.0298420404488573" bingtitle="restaurant | Customer Service Blog" webtitle="restaurant | Customer Service Blog">
			<query id="000412" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000537" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="001040" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000163" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000288" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000226" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000695" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000225" bing-rank="202"/>
			<query id="001480" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000258" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000788" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="001481" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="000789" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="000946" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001417" bing-rank="155"/>
	<description>The other experience was at a fast food restaurant the next day. I gave my order for the combo; she says ... Enter your email address to subscribe to this blog and receive ...</description>
	<body>
		Customer Service Blog 

Thoughts on the World of Customer Service and Tips on Service for Businesses
 
Main menu
 Skip to content 
 Home about this blog clients contact us who we are&amp;what we do #fanexperience Innovation Center 
 
Tag Archives: restaurant 
 
Post navigation
 Oct 5 2011 
 Groupon Now Rewarding to Retain 
 
If you’ve used Groupon as a consumer, you understand that you get deep discounts (50%+) from local businesses. If you’re a business, you realize that that can drive lots of consumers to your business, but you’re only probably getting half of what the consumer pays Groupon; so you may only be receiving 25% of your normal payment.

So the only way that Groupon really works for a business is for that company to receive repeat business (at a higher per purchase level). So for Groupon to succeed, it’s all about their business clients retaining and growing business with those Groupon customers.

The theory for the business is they take a short-term loss on a consumer purchase to establish and grow a relationship with that consumer. The reality is often different, however. The business could be cannibalizing their own business by selling at discounted rates to existing customers. They could be involved with Groupon only to attract customers who buy purely on price (and a deeply discounted price at that!). So if the discount goes away, so will that customer.

To help its clients with retention, Groupon has created Groupon Rewards. They promote a “Hassle-Free Setup” followed by “Automatic Rewards” followed by “Customer Analytics.”

No, Groupon does not say that it is cutting its fees. It’s apparently proposing to manage a loyalty program for your business, where consumers get discounts once they’ve spent a certain amount. Not exactly leading edge stuff, but it does promote consumers buying before they get the discount.

So let’s focus on the broader lesson here. If you want to grow your business in a smart way, getting customers in your door (such as what Groupon has historically done) is only the start; long-term success is driven by retention and growth.

 Interested in improving your company’s customer retention ? Check out our Fast-Track Retention&amp;Growth Assessment: http://www.cssamerica.com/cssfastrga.htm 

 Read our New Book – “Ask Yourself…Am I GREAT at Customer Service?” http://www.amigreatat.com/ 

 Listen to our latest podcast episode of “Stepping Up Service” on The MESH Network at http://themesh.tv/stepping-up-service/ 
 
Share this:
 
 Digg Email Print 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. By edgagnon  Posted in Business Advice , World of Customer Service  Tagged customer retention , groupon , loyalty , loyalty program , restaurant 1 Mar 3 2011 
 The 3rd Time Better be the Charm 
 
A friend recently relayed this customer service story to me, and food stories are always a special treat! Enjoy!…or at least, Learn…

 Twice this weekend I noticed that servers, in their desire to speed up the delivery process (I can only assume) were actually stepping over my words while I was ordering. I’m not a particularly slow orderer, and I haven’t noticed this much before, but it was odd. 

 Once was at a local sandwich shop. I was ordering the pick two so you have to pick a sandwich, a side, and a soup. I was giving my choices, but before I even got them out of my mouth, the cashier is prompting me for the next thing that I have to decide. I said “and I’d like…” (getting ready to say “a medium drink”), and she interrupted me in mid-sentence to ask if I wanted a drink. I can almost see this occurring if there was a long line behind me, but there was no one else in line. It probably would have even been okay if she was cheery and bubbly or perhaps apologetic, but this young lady was none of those things – not a smile to be found. 

 The other experience was at a fast food restaurant the next day. I gave my order for the combo; she says “what?” in a terse voice, so then I began to restate my order, and before I could finish restating it, she interrupted by saying “Drink?” I was in the process of telling her that; oh, and, again, there was nobody behind me in line. 

These may be perceived as “little things,” but is interrupting others good customer relations? Is being rude good customer service? Is not listening good for repeat business? Is it a good thing to be so task-oriented that you don’t focus on the person for whom you’re doing the task?

Hopefully the 3rd restaurant encounter for my friend will be better, and based on the tone of the story, it probably will be at a different place.

 Read our New Book – “Ask Yourself…Am I GREAT at Customer Service?” http://www.amigreatat.com/ 

 Interested in improving your company’s customer service? See more at our new website! http://www.cssamerica.com/ 
 
Share this:
 
 Digg Email Print 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. By edgagnon  Posted in Business Advice , World of Customer Service  Tagged complaint , customer retention , customer satisfaction , customer service , restaurant , training 0 Feb 24 2011 
 Order a Pizza…Save a Life… 
 
Talk about knowing and caring about your customer! This story about how a Domino’s Pizza delivery person may have saved a life was an amazing read and video. Check out the story , and think about how this could happen in your company…

An 82 year-old woman orders a pizza every day for 3 years. When one of her frequent delivery drivers learns that the customer hasn’t ordered in 3 days, the driver goes to the woman’s house and helps to find out that the woman had been on the floor of her home for 3 days and hadn’t been able to call for help. The woman will be fine, and this delivery driver may have saved her life. There are MANY lessons we can take away from this story.

First, be proactive with customers . Don’t allow their perception of you to be based purely on when they initiate the transaction or the conversation.

Second, monitor the activity of your customers. If something changes, that could be a symptom of a problem (or an opportunity for growth !). Act on those changes in behavior.

Third, care about your customer, and make sure they know you care by reaching out to them in ways that don’t always have a sales pitch attached.

 Enjoy pizza, enjoy your customers, and enjoy life! 

 Read our New Book – “Ask Yourself…Am I GREAT at Customer Service?” http://www.amigreatat.com/ 

 Interested in improving your company’s customer service? See more at our new website! http://www.cssamerica.com/ 
 
Share this:
 
 Digg Email Print 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. By edgagnon  Posted in Business Advice  Tagged customer service , domino’s , pizza , restaurant 0 Feb 16 2011 
 I’ll Drink to Great Customer Service! 
 
In England, Simon Longbottom, managing director at Greene King Pub Partners, has embarked on a series of customer service initiatives for his pubs. The article ( in Eat Out Magazine ) notes how Pub Partners’licensees will get customer service training to make consistent and improve customer service at the affiliated pubs.

The program was spurred on by recent secret shopper reports which have garnered national attention in UK retail circles. Keep in mind that Mr. Longbottom is doing this purely for business reasons. He states that “Research has shown that a high level of customer satisfaction has a direct correlation with customer spend.” He’s doing this for the money – customer service is just good business.

There are 8 key areas of focus for the training: Customer service and the profit chain, Service Excellence , Retail Service Excellence, Driving Up Performance, Service and Standards , Customer Feedback , Engaging People, and Action.

Great customer service works in banks , it works in pro sports , it works in government , education , healthcare , and even…in pubs.

Raise your glass for great customer service!

 Read our New Book – “Ask Yourself…Am I GREAT at Customer Service?” http://www.amigreatat.com/ 

 Interested in improving your company’s customer service? See more at our new website! http://www.cssamerica.com/ 
 
Share this:
 
 Digg Email Print 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. By edgagnon  Posted in Business Advice  Tagged customer retention , customer satisfaction , customer service , custserv , Education , Government , Greene King Pub , Healthcare , hospitals , loyalty , Mary Portas , restaurant , secret shop , service excellence , Sports , student retention , training 0 Jan 20 2011 
 An Ice Cream Cone and a Princess–Lessons from Disney 
 
The little girl was with her family at Disney World for the first time. She had just sat down to have her ice cream cone, and was wearing a princess outfit which was bought just for this special trip.

As she started to eat, the ice cream fell off the top of her cone onto her dress, and then onto the floor. As the tears started to well-up, the mother took her daughter to the restroom to get cleaned up.

When they went back to their table, they noticed two “cast members” standing at the table, and the other family members were there as well. The ice cream had already been cleaned up by the employees, and they asked if she was the girl whose ice cream had fallen. When she replied “yes,” one of the employees said “please come with me,” and the employee took the little girl’s hand, walked with the mother and child to the counter, and greeted the employee making the cone saying “This princess had an ice cream cone, and it fell. Can you please give her whatever she’d like?”

“I would be happy to,” replied the other employee, and the girl was thrilled to get a new cone.

There are LOTS of lessons to be learned here. First, the employees spotted the issue because they were looking for opportunities to engage and help customers . They proactively addressed the other family members. They immediately cleaned up the mess without having to be asked. They were patient in waiting for the child to return. They clarified what had happened . They used respectful phrases in addressing the customer. They quickly provided an alternative product, communicating well with co-workers.

I know…it was just an ice cream cone.

But think about your company. Where are there issues, whether caused by your organization or the customer themselves? How do you deal with these issues?

Are you looking to help customers? Are you proactive in engaging customers? Do you address issues without having to be asked by the customer? Are you patient with them ? Do you clarify the issue instead of making assumptions ? Are you respectful in how you address customers, particularly in these situations? Do you quickly remedy issues, working as a team for the customer?

 Ask yourself these questions, and then learn a little lesson from a Disney Princess .

 Read our New Book – “Ask Yourself…Am I GREAT at Customer Service?” http://www.amigreatat.com/ 

 Interested in improving your company’s customer service? See more at our new website! http://www.cssamerica.com/ 
 
Share this:
 
 Digg Email Print 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. By edgagnon  Posted in Business Advice  Tagged corporate culture , customer service , custserv , Disney , restaurant , service recovery , training 0 Sep 1 2010 
 Take a Measure from Government 
 
When we work with our government clients, whether it’s an economic development division trying to retain local businesses, a property assessment division trying to efficiently serve its customer base, a City/County manager’s office trying to best manage such a large organization, we’ve found a consistent need – measurement.

When government is trying to measure over such a broad organization, they typically create an organization-wide balanced scorecard system. This metrics system will have the typical measures of Revenue, Cost, Quality, and Customer Service. But it will also have some more outcomes-oriented customer measures such as the percentage of residents on welfare and more capacity-oriented customer measures such as the percentage of residents living within “X” miles of a public park.

Let’s translate those last two measures to a typical business. Outcomes. An outcome is some end-benefit from what your service or product provides. It’s not the product itself. For a hospital, it’s the quality of life after discharge, not just how good the care was in the hospital. For a fine restaurant, it’s the enjoyment of the evening, not just the quality of the food. For an automobile dealership, it’s the feeling when driving or knowing you own a particular brand, not just the gas mileage. These outcomes often relate to the feelings your customers have as a result of their engagement with your company. They should be measured to make sure your services had a positive ongoing impact.

The other example metric dealt with Access. How close you live to a park can determine your ease of access and likelihood to use it. Similarly, what percentage of the population lives near a grocery store, what percentage of season ticket holders receive a sports team’s newsletter, and what percentage of long-term customers have online access all help to determine the customer’s access to the company. A greater access leads to a greater chance to develop relationships and retain the customer.

Learn from these atypical measures from government to know how well you impact your customers and to ensure you have adequate access to them.

 Interested in improving your company’s customer service? See more information at: http://www.cssamerica.com/ 

 Check out our new customer service book at http://www.amigreatat.com/ 
 
Share this:
 
 Digg Email Print 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. By edgagnon  Posted in Business Advice , Government  Tagged bre , business retention , business retention and expansion , customer retention , customer satisfaction , customer satisfaction survey , customer service , fans , Government , Healthcare , hospitals , municipal , patient satisfaction , restaurant , season ticket holder , Sports , student retention , survey , ticket sales 0 Jun 18 2010 
 Be an Everybody Business 
 
Pizza…Yum! I was getting a takeout order at Hawthorne’s Pizza in Charlotte, NC, for the first time. As I walked in, the hostesses greeted me with a smile, asked how they could help, and showed me to the counter where I could pick up my order. As I approached the counter, two staff walking by made eye contact, smiled and said hello. I was greeted by an employee at the counter who asked how he could help – he smiled, confirmed my order, noted he’d get my order together and get right back to me. As I stood for a few seconds, I noticed that ALL the employees were moving, working, processing orders, taking food out to the tables…and smiling.

They were having pleasant conversations with each other and operating efficiently at the same time. Another employee walked up to me and asked if I had been helped. When the individual who was getting my order came back, he took the credit card, engaged me in light discussion, and closed the conversation with a smile and appreciation.

As I turned to walk away, another employee walked past me, made eye contact, smiled and said hello, and as I walked out of the restaurant, the hostesses smiled again, thanking me for coming in, and holding the door open for me.

I was in the restaurant less than 5 minutes, but one thing was obvious. This was an “Everybody Business.” Everybody smiled. Everybody worked efficiently. Everybody engaged me. Everybody seemed to be having fun with what they were doing and/or with each other.

When you experience an Everybody Business, you have to realize that this is not by accident. It’s by design. To have everybody operating in the same positive manner – naturally, smiling, engaging customers – that happens only because management wants it to happen. They hire staff with that attitude, train them on how to interact, and model those behaviors themselves.

They don’t leave it to chance that you’ll get good service with Employee “A”, but you could get bad service from Employee “B”. They don’t want that risk. They want to be an Everybody Business so that every customer has the same great experience.

Be an Everybody Business.

 Interested in improving your company’s customer service? See more information at: http://www.cssamerica.com/ 
 
Share this:
 
 Digg Email Print 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. By edgagnon  Posted in Business Advice , Carolinas , World of Customer Service  Tagged corporate culture , customer retention , customer satisfaction , customer service , employee morale , hawthorne’s pizza , north carolina , restaurant , sales , training 0 May 25 2010 
 She’ll Take Your Order 
 
There’s nothing like the feeling of comfort I get from a warm greeting at a business establishment. A feeling of&quot;you are my most important customer&quot;and&quot;I cannot wait to serve you&quot;brings a tear to the eye of a customer service consultant. But that’s not the only thing that can bring a tear to my eye.

Walking into a fast food restaurant, I stood back from the cashiers to determine what I wanted. After deciding, I walked to the counter and the two cashiers, both of which were available. This is how the conversation started:

Cashier #1:&quot;Can I help…oh, she’ll take your order.&quot;

Cashier #2:&quot;No, she’ll take your order.&quot;

Cashier #1:&quot;No, she’ll take your order.&quot;

Cashier #2:&quot;No…well, okay. What would you like?&quot;

This dialogue would have been very flattering had they substituted&quot;I&quot;for&quot;she,&quot;but the conversation made it obvious that, even though neither was doing anything, they’d prefer continuing to do nothing rather than help me buy their product.

Sometimes we complain about how many companies and many employees are more task-focused than customer-focused. But this company was more focused on inaction than action. While we desperately hope this experience is a rarity in your business, there are things to learn from the interaction that can help any business succeed.

First, hire people with not only the attitude of wanting to help others but also the energy to act on those impulses. Next, come up with a mantra that promotes productivity. One restaurant tells its staff to remember during slow times that&quot;if you’re leaning (against the wall) you should be cleaning.&quot;Finally, create a proactive work environment. The more reactive a culture is, the more likely they are to be passive when there’s not a fire to fight. Proactive cultures promote the seeking of action and progress.

Work to create an atmosphere of&quot;I’ll take your order.&quot;

 Interested in improving your company’s customer service? See more information at: http://www.cssamerica.com/ 
 
Share this:
 
 Digg Email Print 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. By edgagnon  Posted in Business Advice , World of Customer Service  Tagged complaint , corporate culture , customer retention , customer satisfaction , customer service , restaurant , training 0 Mar 11 2010 
 Take the HCAHPS Test 
 
Will the government be getting into healthcare with the proposed healthcare reform legislation? That’s probably not the best question to ask, because the government is already in healthcare in many ways. I’m sure we’re all familiar with Medicare and Medicaid, but since this is a customer service and retention-related blog, have you heard of HCAHPS?

The government is already in healthcare in the customer service/satisfaction aspect of the business. The federal government has required that hospitals survey patients using standardized tools to gauge satisfaction with multiple areas of the patient experience including communication, responsiveness, information provided, processes, etc. Then this information is posted on the internet for any current or prospective patient to review to compare one hospital to another.

What if this approach related to other organizations? What if two retail stores had their customer satisfaction ratings posted side-by-side? Or maybe you could compare all restaurants in your region in an evaluation – side-by-side – of key characteristics of the food, the environment, the price, the customer service. How about comparing 3 banks or 4 car dealerships or 5 animal hospitals or 6 grocery stores?

If you were one of those retailers or restaurants or banks or grocery stores being objectively compared for all your current or prospective customers to see, how would you do?

It’s a scary proposition, but if you’re not willing to consider it, believe me, your customers make this evaluation every day.

Think of this as the HCAHPS test. How would you objectively compare on key characteristics of the customer experience with your competitors? If you have no idea, then you might want to consider mystery shopping, having a research firm such as ours to shop your organization…and your competitors.

Make sure you know how you measure up.

 Interested in improving your company’s customer service? See more information at: http://www.cssamerica.com/ 
 
Share this:
 
 Digg Email Print 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. By edgagnon  Posted in Business Advice , Government , Healthcare  Tagged customer retention , customer satisfaction , customer service , Education , employee morale , Government , HCAHPS , Healthcare , hospitals , mystery shop , patient care , patient satisfaction , process improvement , restaurant 0 Sep 3 2009 
 Fast, but Not Fast Food 
 
Customer service is not all about the eye contact, the smile, and the “soft” aspects of the personal interaction. They are very important, but process is also important.

The restaurant world is a tough business from a customer service perspective, because it has many characteristics of a manufacturing environment as you’re processing the food and getting it out, and timeliness is of the essence. One restaurant chain seems to get it when it comes to process. At least the particular location that I frequent of Monterray’s Mexican restaurant is excellent in their service delivery process.

You walk in and you immediately see where to check-in.  You get waited on quickly; typically within 30 seconds, somebody is leading you to your table. As you are being seated, a second employee is walking up behind the host or hostess with chips and salsa, so that the minute the hostess walks away, you are already eating free chips. The drink orders come quickly, the server frequently comes to you in a non-pushy way to check on your readiness to order. No matter what you order, the food comes out fast—all the time it comes out fast. It’s hot, it’s fresh, and it’s very very good. But this blog is about process, not food quality.

When the chip basket looks nearly empty, the next thing you know it’s been refilled. The water is constantly getting refilled. The check comes quickly, and it’s convenient to pay as well.

We never ask about the training, the processes, the systems, or the internal communications that happen over and over and over again between employees during a typical night at the restaurant. But we know they must be standardized, because the service is so consistent. We know they must work, because the service is so quick. We know employees must be confident in understanding their roles, because the flows between encounters with the servers and other employees in the discussions we have are always seamless.

Monterray’s is a great example of how big an impact an effective customer service process can have on the customer’s experience.

Do your processes help or hinder your customer’s satisfaction?

 Interested in improving your company’s customer service?  See more information at: http://www.cssamerica.com/ 
 
Share this:
 
 Digg Email Print 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. By edgagnon  Posted in Business Advice , Carolinas  Tagged Carolinas , customer satisfaction , customer service , process improvement , restaurant 0 
Post navigation
 
Most Recent Posts

 Federally-Driven Health Insurance and the Future of Customer Care In Customer Service, Don’t Mess with the King Be GREAT? Just try Beating Competitors First… Put Your Fans’Names on Your Uniform Linked at the Hip–Business Retention and Long-term Thinking 
 
 Email Subscription 
 
Enter your email address to subscribe to this blog and receive notifications of new posts by email.

Join 568 other followers

 

 
 
Categories

 Business Advice (196) Carolinas (11) Education (23) Government (36) Healthcare (30) Sports (39) World of Customer Service (63) 
 
Service Advice RSS

 
 
 See My Tweets 

 Received request to facilitate planning session between finance #cltbiz and its customers cssamerica.com/cssstratplan.h… 7 hours ago Prepping speech for physician office administrators!! #cltbiz cssamerica.com/csshealth.htm 9 hours ago NEW BLOG: Federally-Driven Health Insurance and the Future of Customer Care goo.gl/fb/AOz2Q #businessadvice 11 hours ago Finished service #excellence training development/design for upcoming call center sessions #cltbiz cssamerica.com/csstrain101.htm 11 hours ago New Blog: Federally-Driven Health Insurance and the Future of Customer Care: Who would want the Federal Governme... bit.ly/NzWarg 12 hours ago 
 
Search This Site!
 Search 
Key CSS Web Pages

 CSS Home Page Free Weekly Customer Service Tips Mystery Shopping Services New eBook! Am I GREAT at Customer Service? Service Excellence Training 
 
High Volume Tags for ServiceAdvice
 bre business retention business retention and expansion Carolinas community college complaint corporate culture culture customer retention customer satisfaction customer satisfaction survey customer service custserv Education employee morale exit interview facebook fan relations fans Government HCAHPS Healthcare higher education hospital hospitals loyalty municipal mystery shop nba nfl north carolina patient care patient satisfaction process improvement restaurant retention sales season ticket holder service recovery Sports sportsbiz student retention survey ticket sales training Blog at WordPress.com . | Theme: iTheme2 by Themify . Follow 
 Follow“Customer Service Blog” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



Join 568 other followers

 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com Send to Email Address Your Name Your Email Address Cancel Post was not sent - check your email addresses! Email check failed, please try again Sorry, your blog cannot share posts by email.
	</body>
</document>
