<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009047" url="http://www.eatingwell.com/food_news_origins/food_news/the_fast_food_ban" time="2012-07-13-02:26" support="4" score="0.02307016002899266" bingtitle="The Fast Food Ban | Eating Well - Healthy Recipes, Healthy Eating ..." webtitle="The Fast Food Ban | Eating Well">
			<query id="000372" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000434" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000310" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="000283" bing-rank="151"/>
	<description>Discover eating well - with healthy recipes, healthy eating, healthy cooking ... in favor of calorie labeling for every item on the menu boards in every fast-food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		First Name: Email: Password: Choose Your FREE Newsletters: EatingWell This Week Weekly healthy recipes, plus cooking tips. EatingWell Diet Bi-weekly low-calorie recipes and diet tips. EatingWell Health Bi-weekly health and wellness information. EatingWell Special Offers Coupons and more from trusted partners. Yes! I’d like to receive news and offers
from your publications via e-mail. Your email address will not be sold or rented to third parties. Read our Privacy Policy . Email: Password: Forgot Password? Mobile Site | Mobile Services Sign In | Join EatingWell Advanced Recipe Search» 
 RECIPES&amp;MENUS HEALTHY COOKING DIET&amp;HEALTH FOOD NEWS&amp;ORIGINS COMMUNITY SHOP 

 
 blogs menu planner meal plans 
 
 Food News Green&amp;Sustainable Organic&amp;Natural Seasonal&amp;Local Food&amp;Travel People&amp;Perspectives EatingWell Magazine How Nick McCrory, 2012 Olympic Hopeful, Eats to Win 
 Advertisement 
 Home » Food News&amp;Origins » Food News » The Fast Food Ban 
 Print Email Tweet 
 
The Fast Food Ban

By Michelle Edelbaum 
 
 login to save print share 
 
We ask 3 experts to weight in.
 READER&apos;S COMMENT:
 &quot;Forty million people are served at McDonalds a day. That means forty million people are putting chemicals, pesticides, and genetically modified meats into their bodies every day. No wonder why we have so many problems with our environment... 
 Article Add/Read Comments (9) 
 
 Related Articles 
 Fixing America&apos;s Food System 
 On the Road: Fast Food Survival Tips 
 Cheap and Easy Quick Dinner Recipes 

 
Last summer, Los Angeles lawmakers banned fast-food chains from opening new outlets in South L.A., which has the city’s highest concentration of fast-food restaurants and a 30 percent higher rate of obesity than the rest of Los Angeles County. The long-term goals of the one-year ban are to reduce obesity, encourage more healthy food choices in existing fast-food restaurants and promote new, healthier food outlets in an area that lacks eateries and grocery stores.

We wondered if a ban on new fast-food restaurants would be effective at accomplishing these goals, so we asked three experts:

Do you support the ban on new fast-food restaurants?

 Michael F. Jacobson, Ph.D. 
Executive Director, Center for Science in the Public Interest

South Los Angeles is already so saturated with fast-food restaurants that a ban on new ones might not have much of an effect. It would be far more productive for the city to provide incentives for supermarkets and farmers’ markets to make healthy food accessible to local residents.

 Aviva Must, Ph.D. 
Professor and Chair of the Department of Public Health and Family Medicine at Tufts University School of Medicine

It represents an important first step in environmental approaches to eating well. The ban alone will not likely have an immediate impact on eating habits in the community because there are plenty of existing quick-serve restaurants, but in my view it is responsive to community calls for such change. Plus, it puts the fast-food restaurants on notice that they need to continue to make healthy options available at an affordable price. It may also empower other communities to advocate for similar changes in their locales.

 Stephen Joseph, J.D. 
Lawyer who fought successfully to eliminate trans fat from Oreo cookies.

I don’t think [the ban is] a good thing. I am in favor of calorie labeling for every item on the menu boards in every fast-food restaurant. It’s very influential. Fast-food companies will change their menus and add on lower calorie items.
 
 more smart savings Advertisement 
 
Free Newsletters 
 EatingWell This Week 
 EatingWell Diet EatingWell for Health 
 Special Offers Yes! I&apos;d like to receive news and offers
from your publications via email. Privacy Policy First Name: Email: 
EatingWell Magazine 
 
 Subscribe» | Give a Gift | Customer Service 
 Advertisement 
 
Today&apos;s Favorites 
 
 Recipes Articles Blogs Searches 
 
 Skillet Gnocchi with Chard&amp;White Beans ( 189 comments ) Chilaquiles Casserole ( 103 comments ) Hamburger Buddy ( 100 comments ) Bev&apos;s Chocolate Chip Cookies ( 87 comments ) Balsamic&amp;Parmesan Roasted Cauliflower ( 74 comments ) Easy Salmon Cakes ( 73 comments ) Broccoli-Cheese Chowder ( 72 comments ) Mini Mushroom-&amp;-Sausage Quiches ( 63 comments ) Sauteed Chicken Breasts with Creamy Chive Sauce ( 58 comments ) Beef&amp;Bean Chile Verde ( 52 comments ) 
 
Poll of the week 
 Do you think the government should tax soda and other sugar-sweetened beverages? 
 Vote Now! | More Polls | Comments 
 Advertisement 
 
 
Magazine

 Give a Gift 

 Subscribe Customer Service Current Issue Recipe Index 
 
Advertising

 Magazine Media Kit Magazine Advertising Contacts Online Media Kit Online Advertising Contacts 
 
About

 About Us Who We Are Contact Us Feedback Jobs&amp;Internships Press Room Content Licensing&amp;Custom Publishing 
 
Multimedia&amp;Tools

 Blogs Mobile Newsletters RSS Video Wallpaper 
 
Resources

 Privacy Policy Terms of Use User Agreement EatingWell KitchenTable Community Guidelines Healthy Living Directory 
 AdChoices 
 ©2012 Eating Well, Inc. 
EatingWell
6221 Shelburne Road
Suite 100
Shelburne, VT 05482, USA
 www.eatingwell.com 

 
 Recipes&amp;Menus 
 Recipe Collections | Browse all recipes | Easy Recipes | Dinner Ideas | Vegetarian Recipes | Kids Recipes | Healthy Desserts | Special Diet&amp;Recipes | Menus&amp;Meal Plans | Holidays&amp;Occasions | Seasonal Recipes | Drink Recipes | Recipe Slideshows | Breakfast Recipes | Recipes for Two 
 
 Healthy Cooking 
 Healthy Cooking 101: Basics&amp;Techniques | Kids Cooking | Healthy Food Guide | Cooking for Two | Quick&amp;Healthy Cooking | Holiday&amp;Entertaining | Wine, Beer&amp;Spirits Guide | Kitchen Product Reviews | About Our Test Kitchen | Recipe Makeovers | Budget Cooking 
 
 Diet&amp;Health 
 Weight Loss&amp;Diet Plans | Blood Pressure | Bone Health | Cholesterol | Diabetes | Digestive Health | Gluten Free Diet | Healthy Aging | Healthy Kids | Healthy Pregnancy | Heart Health | Immunity | Mind, Body&amp;Spirit | Nutrient Library | Nutrition News&amp;Information | About Our Nutrition Experts 
 
 Food News&amp;Origins 
 Food News | Green&amp;Sustainable | Organic&amp;Natural | Seasonal&amp;Local | Food&amp;Travel | People&amp;Perspectives | EatingWell Magazine | How Nick McCrory, 2012 Olympic Hopeful, Eats to Win 
 
 Community 
 See All Blogs | Food Blog | Healthy Cooking Blog | Diet Blog | Health Blog | Food News Blog | 10th Anniversary: Our 100 Best Recipes | Diet Challenge | Eat a Better Breakfast Challenge | Green Up Your Kitchen Challenge | Meatless Challenge | Take Our Summer Slim-Down Challenge 
 
 Shop 
 Cooking, Kitchen&amp;Table | EatingWell Cookbooks&amp;more | Phone Applications | Subscribe | Give a Gift 
 
 FOOD&amp;AMP;RECIPE NETWORK Recipe.com | EatingWell | Better Recipes | Rachael Ray Magazine | Diabetic Living 
 ©Copyright 2012, Meredith Corporation . All Rights Reserved | By using this site, you agree to our Terms of Service .
	</body>
</document>
