<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009233" url="http://surefoodbeverage.com/" time="2012-07-13-02:37" support="4" score="0.02487740809749506" bingtitle="Sure Food and Beverage, LLC | Fire N Ice Indian Fast Food" webtitle="Sure Food and Beverage, LLC | Fire N Ice Indian Fast Food">
			<query id="001185" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="001374" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000462" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000164" bing-rank="195"/>
	<description>Fire N Ice On Easton Ave. Sure Food and Beverage ... world that you&apos;re dining at the first Indian fast food restaurant ... upcoming specials and expansion efforts OR tell us ...</description>
	<body>
		Sure Food and Beverage, LLC 

 Share twitter facebook 
 
 


 
 Slideshow Video Introduction 
 
The First Indian Fast Food Chain

 
 CF CampusFood.com 

 delivery or pick-up full menu college discounts 

 order online 
 
 AM AllMenus.com 

 delivery or take-out full menu weekly specials 

 order online 
 
 
Fire N Ice On Easton Ave
 
 Sure Food and Beverage, LLC is proud to announce the opening of another location of the first Indian fast food chain, Fire N Ice on Easton Ave in New Brunswick, NJ. Stop by today and see what all the hype is about!
 
Connect w/us on Facebook
 
 Like the fanpage to receive special discounts and hear all about our latest offerings. While you&apos;re on our page, feel free to upload pictures of your Fire N Ice experience. We love feedback!
 
Check-In on FourSquare
 
Show the world that you&apos;re dining at the first Indian fast food restaurant in America while you earn points&amp;unlock badges for discovering our menu! The mayor gets a free drink and unlimited sauces!
 
 
 
 “ The Fire N Ice platters are to DIE for! I always get the mixed with Chicken, Lamb, and extra &apos;FIRE&apos; sauce...

Derek Brown Rutgers University 
 
 “ Thankfully, you are Halal certified! Fire N Ice is my new spot for lunch during the week.

Arbab Khan TribeDJs.com 
 
 
 
 “ Been a long time fan of Fire N Ice! Soo excited that they opened a place up in New Brunswick! Bar crawling always works up an appetite and Fire&amp;Ice is the place to go.

Taruj Patel UMDNJ 
 
 “ DELICIOUS samples today guys. I cannot wait to try more!! This might become my new favorite fast food place :)

Autumn Znidarsic SHI International 
 
 
 
 “ The &apos;Chicken Fire N Ice rolls&apos; are awesome bro! I could eat them for breakfast, lunch, and dinner!

Kamil Hage Middlesex CC 
 
 “ I love the &apos;ICE&apos; sauce! No clue what&apos;s in it, but it&apos;s feaking delicious... I can&apos;t complain about half off tuesdays either!

Jamie Cyrus Youngry.com 
 
 

 
 
 
 
 
About Us

We&apos;re on a mission to create the first Indian Fast Food chain in America without compromising on flavor or price.

 With the help of the local community, our friends&amp;family and college campuses, we&apos;ve officially opened another Fire N Ice locationon Easton Ave in New Brunswick, NJ. Shoot us an email if you want to hear about our upcoming specials and expansion efforts OR tell us how much you love the food and be featured on our social networks! 
 
Contact Us

 Full Name: 

 Your Email Address: 

 Your Phone: 

 Your Message: 

 

 
 
 SURE Food and Beverage, LLC. ©2011. All right reserved. Powered by Crimson Lab Corporation 
 Call for delivery! (732) 535 - 7555
	</body>
</document>
