<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009557" url="http://gta.wikia.com/TUBE" time="2012-07-13-02:56" support="1" score="0.0007884753571001983" bingtitle="TUBE - GTA Wiki, the Grand Theft Auto Wiki - GTA IV, San Andreas ..." webtitle="TUBE - GTA Wiki, the Grand Theft Auto Wiki - GTA IV, San Andreas, Vice City, cars, vehicles, cheats and more">
			<query id="000463" bing-rank="100"/>
	<description>Editor&apos;s pick; Most visited; Highest voted; Newly changed ... Tube is a fast food restaurant with two locations in Liberty ... Taking in the Trash</description>
	<body>
		Wikia
 Skip to Content Skip to Wiki Navigation Skip to Site Navigation 
Wikia Navigation

 Start a wiki 
 Video Games 
 What&apos;s Hot 
 Batman: Fire Rises Super Mario Bros. U Halo 4 Anarchy Reigns More... 
 Fall&apos;s Finest 
 Far Cry 3 Borderlands 2 Assassin&apos;s Creed III Resident Evil 6 More... 
 Game Guides 
 Skyrim Mass Effect 3 Infinity Blade 2 Kingdoms of Amalur: Reckoning More... 
 Spec Ops: The Line 
 Walkthrough Martin Walker Delta Force The Exiles More Spec Ops... 
 
 Entertainment 
 What&apos;s Trending 
 Comic-Con Wikia Book Club Summer Animé Guide Fall TV Schedule More... 
 Movies 
 The Amazing Spider-Man Prometheus Brave Savages More... 
 TV 
 Dallas Breaking Bad Falling Skies Weeds More... 
 Music 
 Aerosmith on Tour Summer Albums Guide Carly Rae Jepsen Katy Perry More... 
 
 Lifestyle 
 Body 
 BBQ Recipes Athlepedia Healthy Recipes Nail Color More... 
 Mind 
 Space Travel Human Science How-To Liberapedia More... 
 Soul 
 Art Toys Gardening Travel More... 
 Of Note 
 2012 Olympics Literature Tea Alternative History More... 
 
 
 
 
 Log in Username Password Forgot your password? Stay logged in Or Connect Sign up 
 
 
 
Navigation

 GTA Games  
 GTA V GTA Chinatown Wars GTA IV: The Ballad of Gay Tony GTA IV: The Lost and Damned GTA IV GTA Vice City Stories More games... 
 GTA Information  
 Games Vehicles Locations Missions Characters Weapons Protagonists 
 Community  
 Community portal Community Noticeboard Forum Staff Policy Help 
 Top Content  
 Grand Theft Answers Buy Grand Theft Auto games... 
 
 Random Page Wiki Activity Watchlist Recent Edits 
 0 Talk 

TUBE
 Edit 
 History 
 TUBE, as seen in in the GTA LCS Introduction. Added by Haruhi Suzumiya 
 Tube is a fast food restaurant with two locations in Liberty City : Chinatown, Portland and Torrington , Staunton Island . and only made its appearance in Grand Theft Auto: Liberty City Stories . Tube is a parody of the Subway restaurant . The name was most likely chosen because in London, as the Tube is what Londoners call the subway. Tube&apos;s logo bears a striking resemblance to Subway&apos;s logo. The first two letters (TU) are orange, and the last two (BE) are white opposed to Subway&apos;s yellow and white combination. The sign also has arrows coming off the &apos;T&apos; and &apos;E&apos;.

 See also 

 Substandard - A food business in Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas , also based on Subway. 

 Restaurants 
 Fast Food and Diners 60 Diner • The 69th Street Diner • Beef Bandit • Bolt Burgers • Burger Off • Burger Shot • The Cheesy Crust Pizza Co. • Cluckin&apos; Bell • Crazy CJ&apos;s • Diner Bar Cocktails • Fat Burger Kid • Happy Blimp • Hobos • Jays Diner • Jim&apos;s Sticky Ring • King Knuts • King Ring • Paradiso Diner • Pizza Face • Pizza Pizza • Punk Noodles • Rusty Brown&apos;s Ring Donuts • Secret Valley • Shaft Hot Dogs • Skyway Diner • Substandard • TUBE • Tuff Nut Donuts • The Welcome Pump • The Well Stacked Pizza Co. • Wigwam Burger Traditional Restaurants Al Dente&apos;s • Alazone&apos;s Italian Food • Barzini&apos;s • Belching Buddha • Brother Mings&apos; • The Brown Starfish Bar and Grill • Chinese Restaurant Noodle House • Drusilla&apos;s • Fanny Crab&apos;s • Gelateria Pasta Liquor Pizza • Gozushi! • Gulag Garden • J&amp;J’s Restaurant • Joe&apos;s Pizza • La Cucaracha • Little Gorbachefs • Marco&apos;s Bistro • The Mexican Restaurant • Momma&apos;s Restaurante • Mr. Fuk&apos;s Rice Box • Papa&apos;s 12 Inch • Pastageddon • Pier Pressure Pizzeria • The Pilgrim&apos;s Pantry • Pizza • Pizza This... • Ristorante Ecoli • Roast Peking Duck • Samo&apos;s Wok • The Smokin&apos; Beef Grill • Special Fried Vice • Squid Row • Steakhouse • Sum Yung Gai • Tableau • Ting Fu Garden • Viendemerte • Vinewood Bar&amp;Grill • Wok&amp;Wok • World of Coq Cafés The Bean Machine • Cafe Metropolitan • Café Robina • Café Under the Tree • Front Page Café • Greasy Joe&apos;s • Homebrew Café • Le Singe d&apos;Arbre • Les Beans Café • Mars Cafe • Superstar Café • Tarbrush Café • TW@ Internet Café 
 
Read more

 Burger Shot Chinese Restaurant Noodle House 
The Les Beans Cafe is a cafe located in Downtown, Vice City in 1984, the setting of Grand Theft...
 Les Beans Café 
 Retrieved from &quot; http://gta.wikia.com/TUBE?oldid=336744 &quot; 
Related Categories
 Categories :
 Restaurants All Businesses Food Businesses in GTA Liberty City Stories 
 
Pages on GTA Wiki
 Add a Page 6,806 pages on
this wiki Advertisement | Your ad here 
Latest photos
 Add a Photo 12,588 photos on this wiki 
 by PK LT 
 2012-07-12T21:34:39Z 
 by SolanaBogonPolaris 
 2012-07-12T20:14:39Z 
Posted in Custom Vehicle License Plates by SolanaBogonPolaris 
 2012-07-12T20:13:22Z 
Posted in Custom Vehicle License Plates by Xoox430 
 2012-07-12T15:21:02Z 
Posted in Custom Vehicle License Plates by Superxzibit2012 
 2012-07-12T14:19:57Z 
 by Superxzibit2012 
 2012-07-12T14:19:48Z 
Posted in LSPD in GTA V Era by Xoox430 
 2012-07-12T09:22:51Z 
 by Xoox430 
 2012-07-12T08:46:51Z 
 by Gta inc. 
 2012-07-12T07:59:42Z 
Posted in User:Gta inc. by Gta inc. 
 2012-07-12T07:47:48Z 
 by Gta inc. 
 2012-07-12T07:33:26Z 
 See all photos 
 See more &gt; 
Recent Wiki Activity

 Empire Building edited by Gbarker2000 1 second ago Madd Dogg (mission) edited by S3kshUn8 18 minutes ago Blow Your Cover edited by S3kshUn8 22 minutes ago Beta Releases edited by Cloudkit01 1 hour ago 
 See more &gt; 
Recent Questions
 
 
 Join our Comic-Con trivia chat today at 7pm PDT! 
 
 
Around Wikia&apos;s network
 Random Wiki 
 
 
Wikia Inc Navigation
 [ Video Games ] 
 About Community Central Careers Advertise API Contact Wikia Terms of Use Privacy Policy Content is available under CC-BY-SA .
	</body>
</document>
