<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009614" url="http://www.meetup.com/st-louis-area-climbing/events/10841615/?eventId=10841615&amp;action=detail" time="2012-07-13-03:01" support="2" score="0.0022475535730992506" bingtitle="Outdoor rock climbing at Jackson Falls, IL - St. Louis Area ..." webtitle="Outdoor rock climbing at Jackson Falls, IL -  St. Louis Area Climbing (Saint Louis, MO) - Meetup">
			<query id="000931" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="001151" bing-rank="106"/>
	<description>Keep checking this meetup page as the date draws near. 5. ... You&apos;ll see Ozark General Store on the left along I45. ... For missed connections, late arrivals, etc., leave a ...</description>
	<body>
		St. Louis Area Climbing 
 
 Home Members Sponsors Photos Pages Discussions 
 Message Board Mailing List 
 More 
 Polls Files Promote 
 Join us! 
 Featured Meetup 
August 1, 2009 9:00 AM. 9 attended.

Outdoor rock climbing at Jackson Falls, IL
 
 Meetup Info Meetup Photos 
 
 Jackson Falls ( map ) 
 Selected By: Z 
 13 photos of this Meetup 

Uploaded by: Damon 
 
Ok guys, as promised - here&apos;s the big event! Ta-da!! (gong sound)

 Summary: 

This is a two day climbing adventure on the sandstone at Jackson Falls, IL. Though this meetup is only listed for one day, some of us will be camping there Saturday night and climbing all day Sunday. You can camp and get a second day in if you feel up to it, or just head back in Saturday evening. If you can only do one day, I would much rather you show up Saturday - I am going to organize Sunday&apos;s climbing based on the consensus of what everyone there feels like doing.

This is the ideal first trip if you&apos;ve never climbed outside before! We will be breaking up into groups of 3 to 4 after meeting up in the main parking/camping area. Dez (my climbing partner) and I will be rotating between the groups and setting up top ropes for you. If you have gym climbing experience, you already have all the know-how you need for this trip. If you have never climbed, you won&apos;t be belaying, but will be paired up with those who can.

 Tentative schedule: 

We will meet in the parking lot at 9am Saturday morning, do a quick round of introductions, and break into either 2 or 3 subgroups by ability. Maybe a couple of 5.6-5.7 groups and a 5.8-5.9 one. You can switch groups as the whim strikes. After getting situated and setting up camp, we will head down into the valley. We will have 2 top ropes going, and hopefully 3. All the groups will stay in the same general vicinity at any given time, but we will explore different areas.

After climbing all day Saturday, we will retreat to camp for dinner and beer around the campfire. Then sometime after 9pm those interested can strap on the headlamps and follow me down into the canyon for some night-time bouldering or climbing. Moon will be about three-quarters full that night.

On Sunday we will stay flexible and see what routes everyone feels like doing. I will stay out there until 4pm before heading back to St. Louis. If you&apos;ve had enough climbing, you can always spend the day bouldering.

 What you need to bring 

These items are mandatory: you must beg, borrow, or steal them if you want to come along!

Harness
ATC device
Climbing shoes
Chalk and chalk bag
Helmet (bike helmet is OK)
Gear to carry at least 2L water
Snacks to eat during the day
Headlamp and extra batteries (only if you want to come along at night)

These are recommended, but up to you:

Camping gear - tent, sleeping bag, etc.
Sunblock
Insect repellent
Toilet paper
Cooking utensils (I will bring a 2 burner stove)
Camera

I am assuming everyone reading this has plenty of camping experience, but if not, contact me and I&apos;ll send you a hideously detailed packing list of everything you could possibly need.

 Directions 
Look at the bottom of this post under Additional Resources for a good overview PDF. When you drive in along the gravel road, you will come directly to the main camping area which is right by the creek. Regular cars can make it that far quite easily. If you want to go further up the road to camp, four wheel drive and high clearance are recommended. The parking area is not huge - you will be able to spot us quite easily.

 FAQ 

1. How safe is this?
About as safe as you can be outside the gym. All anchors will be on bolts, redundant, and completely bomber. Both my climbing partner and I are very picky about our gear - you won&apos;t be climbing on anything even remotely questionable.

2. Can I lead/rap/clean the route?
No. Unless your outdoor climbing resume makes me genuflect, you will be on toprope the whole time. The only time you will be tying or untying any type of knot is with both feet on the ground. I am paranoid when it comes to safety - there are going to be zero accidents on this trip.

3. What are the car pooling arrangements?
We will use the discussion thread attached to this meetup to work that out.

4. What are the rain plans?
Unless we have heavy, sustained rain, the meetup will be a go. Keep checking this meetup page as the date draws near.

5. What other equipment can I contribute to the effort?
We need a third rope, and could probably use another bouldering crashpad just in case.

6. Can I bring kids?
Not on this trip. Children have special safety needs (full body harnesses etc), and we are not qualified to evaluate or address those needs. If there is interest, I will try to make it happen on a future meetup.

7. Can I try a 5.10 or something even harder?
Absolutely. But remember that one of us has to lead a nearby route to get a toprope anchor up there, so we might not be able to give you the exact route you want. If there&apos;s a 5.5 right next door that I can lead, you&apos;ll have a 5.10 coming right up!

8. Do you have extra camping gear?
I have limited extra stuff. Ask and I will see what I can rustle up.

9. Most of these terms (toprope, lead, anchor, crashpad) make no sense to me. Am I getting in over my head?
Doesn&apos;t matter one bit. If you&apos;ve never climbed before you&apos;ll be paired with someone who has. A lot of this will make sense once you get out there.

Please post questions and suggestions, and I will edit this post as we go along.

 Additional resources 

 This is the definitive guidebook for the area. If you plan on climbing outside regularly, it&apos;s worth the money.

A free overview booklet of the routes and driving directions are available here .
 
 Z 
Everything&apos;s on track! Weather looks ok with only a slight chance of rain. I&apos;m driving down Friday and camping.

Get to Ozark, IL from I-24. You&apos;ll see Ozark General Store on the left along I45. Immediate right on Ozark Rd. right after store. Go through town and a few more miles. You&apos;ll see a house with a covered well on the right side. Make a right immediately before on the small road (State I think?) and go all the way to creek. Look for a light blue Chevy Aveo with license plates ROK-RAT.
 Posted July 29, 2009 at 12:41 PM Z 
If you&apos;re looking to carpool, just discuss on here. I&apos;m guessing at least some will want to head back after a full day climbing. For those showing up Saturday night - look for my car and we&apos;ll be somewhere near it. For missed connections, late arrivals, etc., leave a note under my windshield wipers. You can use my car as a bulletin board, but use paper instead of writing directly on it... :-)
 Posted July 29, 2009 at 12:45 PM Damon 
I am only going down for the day and I have room for a couple of people in my car if anyone wants to ride along. I will not be camping Saturday night.
Also if anyone wants to meet up to caravan down there that would be cool also.
 Posted July 31, 2009 at 6:18 AM 
You must be a member to post a comment. Join or login .
 
 9 attended 
RSVPs closed
 4.50 3 (3 ratings) 
 Event Host Z +1
 
 
 guest I had a great time with you guys, and thanks again for your patience while I spent an entire hour hang-dogging my way up my first 5.10a route! Z Thomas Z This was an excellent outing! Thanks to (the other) Z! Damon Jackson Falls rocks! (pun intended)
As my first time climbing on actual rock I learned a lot that I can take with me to the gym and was definitely able to put the skills I learned at the gym to use. I can&apos;t wait to go again.
Overall a great time with great group. Jim Lamb Monica +1
 
 
 guest Kristina +1
 
 
 guest 
 St. Louis Area Climbing Saint Louis , MO Founded
Jul 14, 2008
 Read more about us… 
 
Climbers
332 
Group reviews
29 
Upcoming Meetups
1 
Past Meetups
467 
Our calendar
 
 We&apos;re about: Rock Climbing · Bouldering · Rappelling · Tree Climbing · Ice Climbing · Mountaineering · Parkour Organizers: Jay , coolbeans , Dustin , Jon Richard , Sean View The Leadership Team 
 Contact us x 
 St. Louis Area Climbing (SLAC) is a community of boulderers, top, sport, trad, aid, tree, and general climbing enthusiasts of all levels of experience. In addition to trading tips, techniques and sharing outdoor adventures we are also experts at getting drunk around a campfire. Does this sound like your cup of tea? Good!

This is an active group and those caught lurking on the sidelines will be removed. This isn&apos;t some group you&apos;re going to get to eventually; this is some serious climbing and fun times ... damn it.

 See you at the crag!
-SLAC 
 (re-founded circa 2010) 
   
 Our Sponsors 
 
 Vertical Voyages, LLC 

Sign up early for Vertical Voyages classes and get a special SLAC rate!
 
 Membership perks 
 
Offer a perk for our members and get exposure.
 Offer a perk→ People in this
Meetup are also in: 
 St Louis Adventure Group 
1,847 Adventurers

 Next Meetup: 
Friday, Jul 13
 The Missouri Triathlon Meetup Group 
262 Triathletes

 Next Meetup: 
Friday, Jul 13
 The Saint Louis Salsa Meetup Group 
627 Hot Salsaleros

 Next Meetup: 
Saturday, Jul 14
 Dine Out on a Dime St. Louis 
591 Foodies
 The Saint Louis Social Co-op 
350 SLSC Members

 Next Meetup: 
Friday, Jul 13
 Activity Group 
867 Active Members

 Next Meetup: 
Friday, Jul 13
 
 
 What&apos;s new Help Log in Sign up 
 Find a Meetup Group Start a Meetup Group 
 About Meetup We&apos;re hiring! Discuss Meetup Meetup HQ Blog Meetup API 

 Meetup Everywhere Offer a Perk to Meetup Groups Help Privacy Updated 5/23/2010 Terms of service Updated 5/23/2010 

 ©2012 Meetup
 Trademarks belong to their respective owners. Meetup is proudly Made in NYC ! 
 Change language: English Deutsch Español Français Italiano Português 
 
Log in

Not registered with us yet? Sign up 
 Email address: Password: 
 Forgot your password? 
 Remember me on this computer or Log in using Facebook 
Sign up

Meetup members, Log in 
 Your real name Your email 
We hate spam too. We won&apos;t share your address!
 Pick a password or Sign up using Facebook By clicking the &quot;Sign up using Facebook&quot; or &quot;Sign up&quot; buttons above, you agree to Meetup&apos;s Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
