<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009526" url="http://www.rawstory.com/rs/2010/11/22/abc-producer-tsa-patdown-worse-gynecologist/" time="2012-07-13-02:55" support="1" score="0.00012596217200607006" bingtitle="ABC producer says TSA agent felt inside her underwear | The Raw Story" webtitle="ABC producer says TSA agent felt inside her underwear | The Raw Story">
			<query id="001090" bing-rank="231"/>
	<description>Sure, giving these fugitives from a fast food restaurant ... into a restaurant and they give you metal utensils. You ... the Dead’ scrolls found in Australian collection</description>
	<body>
		Featured Video Politics Satire / Parody Activism Whoa! 
 
 Roland Martin accuses Romney of using ‘coded language’ 
 
 Rep. Gowdy on leaks: Reporters aspire to go to jail, so give em what they want 
 
 Steve Martin sells Mitt Romney’s pot in New York City park 
 
 Daily Caller reporter: Democrats reduced women ‘to a sexual being’ 
 
 
 
 VIDEO 2012 420 U.S. News World Science Tech Media Exclusives Raw Meat Pandagon Culture Clutch 
 
ABC producer says TSA agent felt inside her underwear
 By David Edwards
Monday, November 22, 2010 9:09 EDT   Topics: ABC ♦ body ♦ Security 
   
 Pat-down‘worse than the gynecologist,’producer says 

As the busiest travel days of the year approach, more and more passengers are accusing the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of going too far with their screenings.

Earlier this month, the TSA began new security procedures in many airports including scans that produce images of the naked body and pat-downs.

 
One employee of ABC News who opted for the pat-down instead of the full body scan claimed that a TSA agent actually felt inside of her underwear.

“The woman who checked me reached her hands inside my underwear and felt her way around,”said ABC News producer Carolyn Durand.“It was basically worse than going to the gynecologist.”

“It was embarassing. It was demeaning. It was inappropriate,”she said.

Other passengers are also complaining.

A retired teacher from Lansing, Michigan, says he had to walk through an airport and board a plane covered in urine after TSA agents tore open his urostomy bag during a pat-down.

A flight attendant who is a breast cancer survivor says she was horrified when, during an“aggressive”pat-down at the Charlotte, North Carolina, airport, she was ordered to expose her prosthetic breast to two female TSA staffers.

 
Video of TSA agents searching a shirtless 5-year-old boy has become an internet sensation. A Utah man reportedly removed his son’s shirt during the screening process after the boy was too shy to let TSA agents search him.

Luke Tait, the man who filmed the video, said that the TSA agents asked him to delete it but he refused and left for his gate.

ABC’s Robin Roberts asked TSA Administrator John Pistole if some of the more invasive searches were even warranted.

“I don’t want to tell you how upset people are and some people saying that TSA agents are even going into their underwear as part of the screening process,”Roberts told Pistole Monday.“Is there ever any circumstance where that is warranted?”

“No, no, there should never be a situation where that happens,”the TSA chief replied.

“So what happens, what kind of recourse do they have if they do the things that people are saying?”Roberts asked.

“Again, the security officers are there to protect the traveling public,”Pistole explained.“And there are specific operating protocols in which they are to follow. With the advanced imaging technology, the walk-through metal detectors, all of these different layers of security that we have, there are specific standard operating protocols that they follow.”

This video is from ABC’s This Week , broadcast Nov. 21, 2010.

 


 Watch this video on iPhone/iPad 
 Repost this article on your site! David Edwards David Edwards has served as an editor at Raw Story since 2006. His work can also be found at Crooks&amp;Liars, and he&apos;s also been published at The BRAD BLOG. He came to Raw Story after working as a network manager for the state of North Carolina and as as engineer developing enterprise resource planning software. Follow him on Twitter at @DavidEdwards. Share this story&gt;&gt;         By commenting, you agree to our terms of service 
and to abide by our commenting policy .   
 http://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=1046573071 Matt Mosley 
As horrible as this clearly is, maybe now they’ll do some REAL reporting on this issue.
 Anonymous 
Creepy stuff that sounds just like the old Soviet Union.

In San Mateo county just south of San Francisco where SFO is, the local sheriff has said they will arrest any TSA employees that do anything like this. According to some reports he has said deputies will be stationed in the security check areas to watch for such obvious violations of the law.
 Anonymous 
Next time . . . TAKE THE TRAIN.
 Anonymous 
I’ve been saying since the shoe and belt removal began at the airport that we should show up in our bathrobes and get dressed after security. At first it was a joke, but now not so much.
 antiM 
i am seriously surprised that no one has hit a TSA officer yet…not on purpose yet as a reflex due to someone slipping their hands in panties. it’s bed for anyone…yet trauma, rape or incest survivors would have real issues with being forced to let a stranger doing this.
 Anonymous 
I’m beginning to think mass civil disobedience is the only recourse left for us to defend our liberty and our rights. Who in hell has the right to feel you up and grope you on your bare skin? This is obscene…and Obama is fully responsible for this unconstitutional assault on your body and your health. X-ray machines are dangerous and damage your DNA leaving the possibility of future cancer and birth defects with you. Sexual assault is your only other option in this perverse system. The nazis would be proud. MIchael Chertoff, a neofascist dual Israeli/American citizen, is responsible for these deadly Rapiscan devices being installed. We should know better folks. Resist this tyranny at all costs I say.
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_5FG6273Z32MX72SPYHZVJNGGO4 Anonymous 
May karma treat John Pistole as he deserves. The git.
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_5FG6273Z32MX72SPYHZVJNGGO4 Anonymous 
Honey, you tell me when the next train to Sydney, Australia, leaves and I’ll be on it.
 http://real-url.org/twitted.php?id=67267077970 Twitted by redbeard245 
[...] This post was Twitted by redbeard245 [...]
 Anonymous 
It will be interesting to see if airline stocks take a serious hit in the next quarter or 2. They should. I have read messages on many news sites, even the right wing websites, where people are saying they are not flying anymore.
 http://twitter.com/shivabeach Shiva 
this is complete BS. Sniffer machines the smell any type of explosive have been created and developed but they are not being used because Michael Chertoff got these machines in. These machines belong to a huge GOP contributor. We are going through this simply because of politics. There is absolutely no excuse in any American should ever have to go through this. All we are doing is saying that our technology is like the GOP, 2000 years in the past
 Anonymous 
Is it ok for government and former government employees like Michael Chertoff, who in the past have had very close ties to terrorism and foreign intelligence and have very questionable backgrounds to be profiting from these porn scanners?
 Anonymous 
Soon they will be doing the same on trains and buses. This is just to get the people compliant and trained to be scanned anywhere–anytime.
 Anonymous 
This has nothing to do with terrorism.

The terrorism is all staged.
 Ma’at 
It is time to shut TSA down. The rage must overflow. MAKE THEM PAT YOU DOWN. Bog the whole damned thing down. The police state is raging on in America and we must stop it.

And fuck you Obama for, yet again, doing NOTHING.
 Anonymous 
The government is purposely trying to make travel difficult.
 http://claimid.com/shutdowntheairports shutdowntheairports 
Come and join us in our TSA protests.

Nov 24th is National Opt Out Day–more info at http://www.wewontfly.com 

Dec 1st is Shut Down the Airports protest–more info at http://www.shutdowntheairports.com 
 Johnny Warbucks 
Well, maybe next time she flies, she should put a scorpion or a black widow in her pants.
/
/
/
/
/
/
Black widow. Get it? ROFL! Oh, I crack myself up.
 Anonymous 
Any public transportation may get the TSA patdown program
The only travel option that leaves you with your self-respect and personal boundaries intact is private car or may I suggest Craigslist.org -&gt; community -&gt; rideshare.
 Johnny Warbucks 
Rather, the“terrorism”is coming from inside.
 Johnny Warbucks 
That’s not their goal. They’re trying to control people and show them that they do this because they can’t and there ain’t a damn thing people can do about it. Same result, different approach
 Johnny Warbucks 
Interesting that you say that. I thought exactly the same thing and wondered how much air traveled had suffered as a result. As if to answer my question, the corporate media published a“news”article tooting how great the airlines were doing, billions in profits, millions for the CEOs and blah blah blah. Immediately underneath the above-mentioned piece of garbage, there was another one giving the house away with $89 fairs and such. You just can’t make this shit up! They’re trying to say to the sheeple, see? it’s all good. Everybody is doing it. You should go ahead and let them touch you. Yet, they’re going broke and pushing giveaway fairs. ROFL! Gotta love Capitalism!
 Johnny Warbucks 
Ye think?
 Johnny Warbucks 
The only Karma for someone like that would be to get convicted on criminal charges (not the federal kind where you end up going to a country club in PA with swimming poor and tennis court) but a real state prison. Getting a life sentence and having Big Bubba Brown as his roommate. Now, that would be Karma!
 Johnny Warbucks 
Exactly!
 Johnny Warbucks 
What time is the slow train to China?
 Johnny Warbucks 
If he does that, I’ll fly to San Francisco and kiss his feet.
 Anonymous 
Maybe she should wear a kilt. Scot style.
 Anonymous 
This is so far beyond the pale. By it should be abundantly clear these policies are designed to intimidate, to demean, to humiliate, to coerce and control the American people.

Next it will be public strip searches and body cavity probes. Resistance will qualify for you for imprisonment if you are lucky enough to not be shot dead on the spot.

These same policies will apply at the Mall and the local supermarket, at schools, at checkpoints into neighborhoods, my friends. What will it take to awaken the sleeping giant of liberty we are? When will you get beyond the two party theatre designed to keep us all fighting while our liberty has been slowly trampled into dust?

 http://news.antiwar.com/2010/11/21/tsa-chief-us-will-never-ease-screening-policy/ 
 Anonymous 
NO! Do not comply with tyranny!
 Anonymous 
Glad to hear a sheriff is actually doing the job he was elected or appointed to do!
 Anonymous 
Only a small percentage of people fly regularly. The vast majority rarely fly. So all these people claiming they won’t should be taken with a grain of salt.

I favor the more passive / aggressive method of wearing kilts and smearing a small amount of chocolate pudding on your upper, inner thigh. Coughing, sneezing, and flatulence (accidental, of course) may also be effective.
 Anonymous 
Pistole is only the temporary Administrator. The TSA nominee has a hold placed on his vote by Inhofe.
 http://real-url.org/twitted.php?id=67420794472 Twitted by InfoWarJedi 
[...] This post was Twitted by InfoWarJedi [...]
 Anonymous 
Step one in controling the masses: limit travel. Check.
 Anonymous 
Just before the fast OceanTunnel train for Iberia. I think it is around the same time as the ferry to Iceland.
 Hologram5 
It’s only going to get worse unless we do something to stop this devolving of our civil rights. Unless the sheeple take the blinders off and stand up to this blatant attack on our Constitution it’ll never change.
 Johnny Warbucks 
I’ll be waiting.
 Johnny Warbucks 
Throw the other one two in for good measure. Saves money.
 Anonymous 
Maybe ABC should have been doing their job reporting the, you know, the news all these years and maybe we wouldn’t be in this situation now.
 Anonymous 
No, they’re purposely trying to get people to submit to unreasonable, abusive totalitarian control. Would the Nazis have tried this on the German people?
 Johnny Warbucks 
That would only make it easier for the goons to touch her junk.
 Anonymous 
We suffer all these dangers and loss of dignity at the airport, but a worse humiliation is having a War Criminal running around Scot free peddling a book of lies. We as a nation have no dignity and face a life lived in shame.
 Anonymous 
Next up, pat downs at Walmart.
 kiboshki 
 “Again, the security officers are there to protect the traveling public,”Pistole explained. 

This is false. The TSA–along with the rest of“Homeland Security–exists to intimidate and control the American public.

Unbelievably, it has taken about 10 YEARS since Congress passed the PATRIOT Act (ie, the“Let’s Rape Americans’Liberties Act”) for the neocon apologists to finally understand that“It don’t matter, cuz I ain’t doin’nothin’wrong!”is not a valid excuse to surrender our freedoms. The police state actually had to start groping peoples’tits and nuts before they realized what“invasion of privacy”and“illegal search and seizure”means.
 Anonymous 
But it is terrorism. The threat of terrorism used as an excuse for the government to terrorize. To frighten the people into compliant robots.
 Anonymous 
Attention Fliers. If you can drive to your destination in less than three hours more than your flight time you are wasting big money flying.

Send the TSA and the airlines a message and get behind the wheel and experience the FREEDOM of the American road again!

I doubt that Chevron will pat you down before filling your tank!
 Anonymous 
I meant to say that this has nothing to do with“fighting”terrorism.

Don’t forget that the Christmas Day Underwear Bomber didn’t even have proper identification to fly and was alleged to have been assisted on the plane.
 Anonymous 
The terrorists have won!

They’ll be sitting back drinking champagne this holiday season!
 Anonymous 
AMEN!
 Schmice 
In the winter? Yikes. It could result in a man’s meat magnum shrinking down to the size of a peashooter, as it were. Definitely a case of“nothing to see here, folks”.
 Anonymous 
How long are you people going to put up with this gross invasion of privacy? These TSA assholes have never stopped or even found anything in the way of a bomb. It has always been the passengers. In tests to see how effective the TSA is at finding simulated bombs they fail every single time. These guys and women are a bunch of bungling, worthless bums who are destroying our right to privacy in the name of irrational fear.
 Anonymous 
Too late to complain, fuckers. You should have been screaming when the Patriot Act was passed. You should have been rioting in the streets. But you didn’t, because you were scared. You were told that losing your freedom was necessary because The Terrorists wanted to kill you. But you never quite figured out who The Terrorists were.

Well, today I am going to do you a huge favor. I am going to tell you who The Terrorists are. Perhaps it’ll put your mind at ease, perhaps not. The Terrorists are children, babies, innocent people, mostly brown, bombed, shot, stomped, rolled over by tanks, and erased from the Earth with a Tomahawk missile. The Terrorists are the innocent victims of American aggression, American Empire. The Terrorists are all the people you wanted killed so that you–the little pathetic coward that you are–could sleep well in your warm bed at night.

Cowards.

Cowards, all of you. Silly little child cowards cowering under your sheets, afraid of infants and little old ladies. DEAD infants and little old ladies, I might add. Killed with your tax dollars, the ones you were too timid to withhold because you are afraid to defy your government. The same government that tells you to be afraid of your shadow.

Silly children. Fie. Fie unto all of you.

Reap what you sow.

REAP WHAT YOU SOW.
 Anonymous 
I am so glad that I moved out the USA in 1999 and never looked back! I now live in the land of the free and home of the brave—The Russian Federation!
I enjoy so much freedom to travel anywhere (except to the USA–I don’t want to go there), to go and come anywhere, my civil and personal freedoms are fully intact and no one is threatening their removal or threatening me in any way, shape of form!
GO AMERICA!!!!!
 Anonymous 
RIGHT ON BROTHER!
 Anonymous 
Yes, that’s because they all live in Washington, D.C.
 Anonymous 
(quote)”This is so far beyond the pale. By it should be abundantly clear these policies are designed to intimidate, to demean, to humiliate, to coerce and control the American people.”(/quote)

No, no. You must be confused. See, what you typed is the definition of *terrorism*. What the TSA does is protect us *against* terrorism. Totally different. They said so.

And once again I’d like to point out that if your boss say’s“get on a plane to city X”…you really do *not* have a choice any more than someone stuck in a good old-fashioned company town.
 Anonymous 
Just wait for the [insert holiday here] Colon Bomber!

“Sorry about the rectal probe and full cavity search, sir! It’s for your safety, we promise!”
 Anonymous 
Well, you want to be“safe,”don’t you?
 Anonymous 
It’s New Norm! Pity, I quite liked old Norm.
 http://www.facebook.com/people/Matt-Swain/100000193790011 Matt Swain 
BEWARE ANY NEW FALSE FLAG ATTACKS by the Security Industrial Complex to quell the sheeples TSA anger and validate this Gestapo shit.

I can see it now.“Colon bomber stopped by TSA body scanner/pat down”

DONT BELIEVE THE HYPE. Whenever we fight back they bring in a new false flag patsy. REMEMBER THE SCANNERS WOULD NOT HAVE SAW THE UNDERWEAR BOMBERS BOMB!!
 Anonymous 
Actually, I think what will be next is the TSA making photographs or tapes of“security procedures”illegal.
 Anonymous 
Terror works agianst the USA. These draconian measures attest to that fact.
 Anonymous 
The dingleberry search. Dingleberries of mass destruction
 Anonymous 
When will we all just stand up to this tyranny. All I can do for now is not fly, which I’m not
 Anonymous 
Yes! I agree.
The drift towards scrapping our Constitution in the name of fear has got to stop.

Then we have sheriff Joe the fascist in Arizona, he wants to look down everyones pants just for kicks and giggles.
 Anonymous 
Thanks for ruining Thxgiving for so many people
 anony 
Martin Luther King said to‘fill up their jails with our children’if mass arrests were threatened.
 Anonymous 
Get ready to be groped at the airport and then take a flight to SFO because I’ve heard this sheriff is serious.
 Anonymous 
How the Drug War Spawned the TSA:

 http://powerandcontrol.blogspot.com/2010/11/for-children.html 

They are both looking for contraband and you looked the other way when they did it to dopers. Well friends and neighbors. We are all dopers now.

Precedent on how to deal with contraband has been set. It is now going to be applied to everyone.
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_QMPOO3PZFN7XV2XZKCGSXXR3WM Joe Somebody 
Perhaps some creative rebellion.. EVERY man should claim to be gay and demand a female agent be the one to feel him up.. and if they can manage it, have a boner at the time (say you’re looking at some cute guy behind the woman). Maybe if enough Gestapo.. er TSA agents quit in disgust, the problem will solve itself :D

I know if I get forced to fly, that’s what I’m doing :)
 http://www.facebook.com/people/Lon-Warneke/1409625620 Lon Warneke 
I live in San Mateo County and our sheriff is Greg Munks.
I suggest that everyone let him know that his approach to TSA groping is supported by emailing him at: gmunks@co.sanmateo.ca.us .

Some more info here: http://www.co.sanmateo.ca.us/portal/site/sheriffs/menuitem.0d4a172e10cdeb0274452b31d17332a0/?vgnextoid=238e7f3aa7120210VgnVCM1000001d37230aRCRD 
 Anonymous 
Patriot act?

How about the Drug War? Piss in a cup for a job? You kissed your rights away a very long time ago.

 http://powerandcontrol.blogspot.com/2010/11/for-children.html 
 Anonymous 
This is nothing more than selling the Chertoff body scanners. Never mind the exposure that frequent flyers will have to be exposed to, it will certainly be better than having someone messing around in your underwear looking for, what? With the CEO of the scanner traveling with Obama it is clear that we are pushing the rest of the world to get the machines. I have changed travel plans to avoid this and when it becomes necessary to travel by plane I will wear a bathing suit and small t-shirt through the security. I am just lucky that I am not a little boy because everyone klnows that terrorists use little boys traveling with their family to hide devices that will cause explosions. Just how large would a device have to be to cause damage and would that fit taped to alittle boys scrotum or an adult womans labia?
 Anonymous 
Stop the Drug War.
 http://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=751032346 Nathan G. Martin 
All this due to an INSIDE JOB! 911 The road to tyranny begun that day! WAKE UP!
 Anonymous 
It was the Drug War dude.
 http://as-the-beach-turns.blogspot.com/ MissKG 
If“they”hated us for our freedoms,“they”must absolutely love us now.
 Anonymous 
The underwear bomber was escorted around security in Europe
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_QMPOO3PZFN7XV2XZKCGSXXR3WM Joe Somebody 
And that is, of course, the biggest point. The“terrorists”are being given special treatment, they are being led past security stations and put on international flights without passports. No amount of molesting children and grannies and pocketing images of naked bodies will change that. The terrorists aren’t being screened, only us innocent people are.
 Anonymous 
Stinky finger by the TSA, you have got to be kidding me. Sexual assault if ever there was a case. What kind of degenerates do we have in our security services, and I mean all of them from the top on down.
 http://www.tommyjonestheband.com RantingTommy 
none of this is about safety

security theater has one purpose: remind you to be afraid

frightened people vote against their own interests, hence Republicans
 Anonymous 
Who amongst you will protest? It’s all fine and good to post a comment to a news story, but who will go out into the street and raise their voice? Who? Maybe one, two of you, out of hundreds?

Who will be the cowards? Who will be the champions?

Who amongst you?

Speak now or forever hold your silence.
 Anonymous 
Inside every commercial jet, hide sealed packets of bacon grease all over the interior. In pre-flight announcements make sure the presence of bacon fat is announced. I don’t believe any islamist would try to blow up a plane if he knew he’d be covered in pork fat because he’d never get to heaven. It’s cheap, easy and effective.
 Anonymous 
Excellent quote!
 Anonymous 
I’m lucky that when I left the country for good that I went through Boston (Logan Airport) before they got a body scanner. I recommend that everyone get out while you can.
 Anonymous 
Quit trying to find a meaningful reason for this. It is a sales pitch, don’t want your or your childrens genetils gropped in public. Step right into Chertoffs no gropping security check. This is not coming from anything other that corporate greed. We can address the for profit complexes that hold people for any number of reasons when the next GOP take-over of the government is accomplished. Welcome to Rupert’s world. Live Better ~ Shop where we tell you to
 Anonymous 
As long as Dumbya and Cheney can board a flight to Spain tomorrow without and checkpoint circus I’m all for this tyranny, for one day.

Then perhaps at least tow of the chumps responsible for this ridiculous crap might see their day in court for crimes against humanity.
 Anonymous 
At least you can be pretty sure after the fat bitch crosses her arms again, that there aren’t any bombs on the flight. If you asked an observer from a different world I am sure they would say something like,“wow, no wonder they are forced to follow their masters around picking up their shit. These monkeys are stupid (the aliens assume dogs rule the planet for obvious reasons).

If you ask me I would laughingly suggest that if terror was meant to change the way shit gets done terror won and all y’all lost hard.

Score one for Osama, Zero for U.S.A. Fucking toolheads haha. You all make me laugh as you are herded away.

Yeah real American to have you ballsack searched because you’re to chicken shit to get on a plane unless someone holds your hand. ROFL.

Not concerned at all you are all being conditioned.

I mean I could roll with endless war, or body scanners. But when I see both I start playing ideas in my head that end with BIG BROTHER. ROFL.

It’s not like all this shit hasn’t been written down. Not like we’re all in the dark re: The Two Thousand Year Plan of Christs return either.

Go close your eyes and be shocked when“Holy War”comes.

How did Maynard put it? A bunch of dumbfounded idiots. Monkey.
 Anonymous 
Don’t be so sure , I wouldn’t be at all surprised if we aren’t subject to random stops and searches before long . I have already heard this idea bandied about , public safety you know .
 Hologram5 
Although I agree with your statement about the failed drug war I don’t see what that has to do with TSA’s molestation of American citizens wanting to fly domestically.
 Hologram5 
They already do this in CA, they do it for DUI checkpoints and they did it during the whole pig flu scare. Like I posted, it’s only going to get worse until the people stand up to these cretins.
 Hologram5 
Yes he was and by a dude in a 1,000 dollar suit I might add which screams of either CIA or Moussad.
 Hologram5 
Hey, that’s a good link and now I see your point, good post and thanks. We need more info like this but you also know that these goons consider those of us that are informed to be homegrown terrorists right? We are all“Jihadists”in their eyes…And no, I didn’t pee in a cup to work at Microsoft, they’d lose too many good employees if they did that…
 Anonymous 
Only our government thinks that a bomb that is small enough to fit under a little boys underwear would cause a plane to explode.
 Hologram5 
When they came for the corporatists I said nothing as I wasn’t one.
when they came for the mentally handicapped I said nothing as I wasn’t handicapped.
when they came for the Jews I didn’t speak up as I wasn’t a Jew.
When they came for me, there was no one left to speak up.
We’ll all be in FEMA camps real soon and there’ll be no one left to carry the banner. Speak up now or forever hold your silence in the camps.
 Anonymous 
Intrusive searches and the laws supporting them were prototyped in The Drug War. Pee into a cup for a job?
 http://www.darkpolitricks.com/2010/11/abc-producer-says-tsa-agent-felt-inside-her-underwear/ ABC producer says TSA agent felt inside her underwear | Dark Politricks 
[...] Edwards Raw Story Nov 22, [...]
 mick 
The irony is that the“War on Terror”is a fraud !
All this as a consequence of 911 being committed by“Arabs”!
The“fraud of 911″is easy once you have control of the Intelligence Agencies ,the Media and the Justice Department.
 http://revolutionradio.org/?p=8638 ABC producer says TSA agent felt inside her underwear | RevolutionRadio.org 
[...] Edwards Raw Story Nov 22, [...]
 Anonymous 
Pass it around. Get others writing about it.
 Johnny Warbucks 
If he pulls it off, I’ll grope myself and fly there just to thank him. We need more people with balls like him and the Sheriff of Cook County, IL, who refuses to serve people with foreclosure notices.
 http://www.stormfront.org/forum/t751722-22/#post8713623 Backlash grows against full-body airport scanners–Page 22–Stormfront 
[...] Backlash grows against full-body airport scanners ABC producer says TSA agent felt inside her underwear | Raw Story [...]
 http://hotair.com/archives/2010/11/22/tsa-uproar-thats-the-power-of-drudge/ TSA Uproar: That’s The Power of Drudge«Hot Air 
[...] It think that’s the key.  The TSA story, of course, did not end with Drudge.  Do a Google News search for“TSA”and you’ll find all sorts of new information and investigative journalism that has been reported in the last week. (At the time of this writing, doing so yielded me a“Time”story called“Please remove your prosthetic breast,”and a Raw Story titled,“ABC producer says TSA agent felt inside her underwear“). [...]
 http://profiles.yahoo.com/u/4VEBRKTF5E6HAG4DZNIFUB2IZQ Andrew 
Take the train (or bus, or car, or ferry) to Canada or Mexico, and then you can fly unmolested to China or Australia or wherever.

Call the management of the airport you are not flying out of and let them know why you will not be patronizing their establishment.
 http://aussie-pythons.com Fred Winkle 
I was on the fence, but your blog has helped me decide. You made some great points.
 http://www.nebulousness.com Adam 
What the hell are you on about?
 Che_G.IV 
Tell it to some conservative website whose base is absolute fear of all things foreign. The loud voices of the Bush-Cheney regime created and developed the TSA in 2002. They were the silent ones who own the problem.
 Anonymous 
Thanks but I’ll pass on the molestation“protection”plan.
 Anonymous 
Such a hater. What are you on about besides hate?
 http://www.darkpolitricks.com/2010/11/tsa%e2%80%99s-top-transgressions-who-is-doing-the-terrorizing/ TSA’s Top Transgressions: Who Is Doing The Terrorizing? | Dark Politricks 
[...] cases involve an ABC producer who described a TSA agent groping inside of her underwear as“worse than the gynecologist,”a woman being lifted off her heels via her vagina, and several cases of women having their skirts [...]
 Anonymous 
If you watch the videos of the Moussad killing in the middle east you can see that they do not spend that much money on clothing. A thousand dollar suit is a wanna-be somebody. That is the profile of an American with power he does not deserve.
 http://www.facebook.com/people/Daniel-Brown/690547972 Daniel Brown 
These people won’t do anything, they don’t have to. They are your only way into the airplane to fly. The only way to get around the TSA is to find another mode of transpiration. You think there is another company they are competing with that pats you down before a flight? No way! If you want to fly, you have to go through them no matter what. They’ll get your business no matter how bad they treat you.

We’re prisoners on our own planet.
 http://www.facebook.com/people/Gregory-Martin/100000564476826 Gregory Martin 
These patdowns/pornoscanners are directly related to techniques learned at Abu Ghraib, fear and sexual humiliation to break individuals down into compliant prisoners. The next thing in the pipeline for the TSA is a remote controlled taser cuff on every passenger. Eventually, it will evolve into taser cuffs on everyone in the country, as a way of‘controlling terrorism’. Stop this bullshit now, or they’ll keep pushing to see how much they can get away with.
 http://www.facebook.com/people/Gregory-Martin/100000564476826 Gregory Martin 
These patdowns/pornoscanners are directly related to techniques learned at Abu Ghraib, fear and sexual humiliation to break individuals down into compliant prisoners. The next thing in the pipeline for the TSA is a remote controlled taser cuff on every passenger. Eventually, it will evolve into taser cuffs on everyone in the country, as a way of‘controlling terrorism’. Stop this bullshit now, or they’ll keep pushing to see how much they can get away with.
 http://reality-hammer.livejournal.com/ Reality Hammer 
This wouldn’t be happening if private companies were allowed to run airport security stations.
 http://twitter.com/CosConservative CosmicConservative 
Typical leftist logic on display. The nation elects Barack Obama, a Democrat. Obama not only continues, but increases, the draconian“security”procedures in our airports. Tommy concludes from this that the Democrat administration in control of the nation implements policies to keep the public“afraid”so that the ignorant sheeple will then vote for Republicans.

I’m guessing Tommy voted for Obama, you know, the guy who’s administration and hand-picked team has instituted these draconian new policies.
 Anonymous 
and after all these invasive searches, they have found absolutely nothing…
 http://www.facebook.com/people/Press-Watch/100000381641661 Press Watch 
There will be no end to the humiliations and invasions until we (1) admit that we have fallen into fascism and (2) stand up to it en masse.
 http://www.facebook.com/people/Press-Watch/100000381641661 Press Watch 
There will be no end to the humiliations and invasions until we (1) admit that we have fallen into fascism and (2) stand up to it en masse.
 Anonymous 
So, which company do you own?
 Hologram5 
So true there John and I’ll have to agree. You can bet your bottom dollar though that these Al Queada (SP?) worms aren’t spending a grand on a suit when it’s better spent on a printer and cartidges to make bombs…
 http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y_PZPpWTRTU Bamboo_Harvester 
…so that’s why tsa agents are always sniffing their fingers
 Anonymous 
Don’t forget‘economy class syndrome.’I always hated flying, then when they started the‘you’re a terrorist until you can prove otherwise’crap, I really hated it, but we finally stopped after my husband got pulmonary embolisms from being so cramped. He couldn’t get up and walk around, because they were always running those damned drink carts up and down the aisle, so that was the results. We now take Amtrak and are really happy with it.
 Anonymous 
I predict a small riot at one of amerika’s airports VERY soon.

Theater of the absurd………………………..
 Anonymous 
Forgive me for waking you from your wet dream, but Obama is now president, and he’s continuing those same policies.

Your contribution is less than worthless. You are worth less than that. Go fall off a high cliff.
 Anonymous 
Reap what you sow. Stand up and fight now or forever crawl on your hands and knees and beg your masters for life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness.
 Anonymous 
You are so right GM–here is a video showing how strip searches are supposed to be done.

We, though, will be treated as prisoners were in Abu Ghraib, most of them innocent of any crime.

 http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SLZq2iaMpXY&amp;feature=player_embedded# !
 Anonymous 
No, it would probably be much worse.
 http://www.facebook.com/people/Dorothy-Banks/100001470098554 Dorothy Banks 
I am sure these airport workers were not thoroughly vetted before they were hired, given they would have their hands all over passenger’s private parts. Passengers don’t know if the employees are merely performing their jobs with clean minds, or if they are being legally fondled and peeped at by perverts. TSA can call these“necessary”actions whatever they want. In my mind, the so-called pat down is fondling. And behind-the-scene scanners rank right up there with peeping toms.

Given these employees are probably paid minimum wages, maybe a few dollars over, airports can’t afford the luxury of weeding out undesirables, many of whom are clever enough to disguise who and what they are. Fondling a passenger in the form of a“pat down”gives them power over paying passengers who can’t complain about getting touched by a stranger. If a passenger protests, causing a ruckus, it is likely he or she will be secured, whisked off to a room at the airport and viewed with suspicion by security.

I guess the phrase“unlawful search and seizure”in the Constitution does not apply to traveling passengers. I consider the“pat down”unlawful and a passenger’s dignity is certainly seized. I heard a woman on a radio show say that people should just to the airport naked. That should solve the problem. I disagreed slightly because airport security would then resort to cavity searches.

It’s too bad the majority of travelers have to suffer this kind of embarrassment because a few bad apples are stinking up the barrel.
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_QUI2Y5V7JHH2YUSO5C3PNZU44M Crystal 
WHAT ABOUT RAPE VICTIMS, ALSO IF THEY FONT CHANGE GLOVES IN BETWEEN TOUCH PEOPLE’S GENITAL’S WE R GONNA SEEA WHOLE NEW SIDE TO A OUTBREAK OF BODY LICE, CRABS , SPREADING STD’S AND IF THERES CUTS AIDS AND HEP C
 Anonymous 
Hell NO I won’t ever fly again unless it’s a one way trip out. They won’t get my business ever again.
 http://real-url.org/twitted.php?id=68046947562 Twitted by timdomagal 
[...] This post was Twitted by timdomagal [...]
 http://lonelyconservative.com/2010/11/its-all-because-we-dont-profile/ It’s All Because We Don’t Profile | The Lonely Conservative 
[...] to give up on its current course any time soon. So expect to hear more stories of TSA agents shoving their hands down the pants of innocent Americans, while telling us it’s for our own [...]
 http://SALON WHITE DRAGON 
What is the TSA political agenda? Our choices:a) TSA is a big noise to cover massive federal corruption. b) TSA is using fake-security-fear to cover new big spending on unneeded Military toys.c) TSA is a red cape to take our mind off the bombing of Iranian nuke plants by Israel.
d) TSA lets us continue to pretend we are powerful and that China doesn’t run everything (which it does). e) TSA is there to disguise the last gasp of a failed empire. THE MORE THE GOV. CLAIMS TO PROTECT US THE MORE WE SHOULD FEAR.
 Anonymous 
Will this be what starts the mass revolt?
 http://twitter.com/mijadedios mijadedios 
The government of the United States of America has turned on the people it was set to protect. The American people are now the targets, we are the slaves and the enemy of the state. All those who do not submit to the authority and rule will be dealt with. The question is not why TSA is doing this but WHEN will the American Citizens wake from the stupor and exert their freedoms that were established over 200 years ago. As it stand the Tyrannical rule(r) is winning. We have effectively succumbed to a police state and this is what happens when we sell our soul to the devil.
 Anonymous 
The patients are running the insane asylum. If Israel does not have to do this to its air passengers, the U.S. doesn’t.
 Anonymous 
Homeland Security is a boondoggle making assholes like Michael Chertoff millions.

Terrorism is the false boogie man that allows imperialism and a police state level of control.

Cui Bono? That is where to look for the real terrorists.
 Anonymous 
The few bad apples include Michael Chertoff and Janet Napolitano who perpetuate the war on terror ruse. This is a scam to make money and to acclimate the masses to the new police state. The wealthy and powerful know that the masses are restless and angry.

Fuck the TSA and fuck the Department of Homeland Security.

Stop the bullshit.

Stop flying.
 Anonymous 
The moronic screening process is NOT effective except to make us think it is while people are raking in big bucks by gouging government money…And some of the low paid, bored pervs love it they get a quick thrill and then tell all their friends, about the“fun”feel-up stories after work over drinks&amp;laughs….

Th whole concept is so ridiculous, if anyone wants to bring in an explosive device–There’s far more easier ways to do it than by boarding an airplane–Tons&amp;tons of marked&amp;unmarked cargo comes into the US daily 24/7 UNCHECKED–via air freight, ships, trucks&amp;vehicles, mail, UPS, etc. etc….

This TSA airport security is really a joke, a“legal”feel-up program a money making scam for a few, pretending they are really on their job in people’s minds as they are harass, stripe, x-ray&amp;feet-up.

Every other country in the world seem to have much more effective measures to stop‘bombers”as becomes more obvious with each passing day of no incidents and effective intercepting when something does occur–of course the rest of the world sees us as a joke anyway and we never prove them wrong……just another one of the stupid American grandstanding ploys….Conjured up by a few who are making a financial killing ripping-off of our tax dollars!
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_5XLGAVO5KMCDDVXTW5BDTMYQTY Joe 
Oh sure. We could really rely on firms like Blackwater to hire nothing but the best and train them impeccably. And probably for 5 times what it costs now.
 Anonymous 
Your humorous comment indicates that you buy into the Arab terrorists are out to get us BS.

Look a little deeper. Cui bono?
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_Q5GWV36SU42MLR7BEFWQT3NXE4 DWAYNE 
Is that a bomb in your underwear or are you just happy to see me?
 Eyeball_Kid 
I’ll believe that the TSA groping and peeping policies are fairly distributed when I see Mitch McConnell and Karl Rove getting groped by bona-fide members of the rabble. Both, however, would likely go into giggling fits.
 Eyeball_Kid 
Begging won’t help. Money talks. If you have money, you can beg. If you don’t, spread your legs.
 Anonymous 
Yeah, but Israel has never had an airplane hijacking! I don’t believe terror prevention is the goal of Homeland Security, so implementing an effective screening process would be counter-productive. :)
 dk504 
but The man that escorted him is the son of some big banker in the middle east. (how convenient) Undi-bomber’s dad had been calling every law enforcement for the USA to try to stop his own son. But the American authorities refused to heed the FATHER’S repeated attempts and his son was escorted on the plane WITHOUT his PASSPORT.

But we have to be molested because foreign gate agents did the absolute unthinkable and let a guy on with out a passport, looking like a bum. You gotta be f-ing kidding me?
Enough is enough.
 Anonymous 
Sad but true, but still, nothing to laugh about.
 Eyeball_Kid 
Nice thought. It won’t happen. How many millions walked calmly into the gas chambers and ovens in the Nazi era? And you think that fascism has a weakness for mass protests? The only way that your dream can approach reality is if tens of millions turned off their televisions. Without TV, the economy would collapse like the house of cards that it is, within a few weeks. Turn off the TV, and modern capitalism collapses in no time.
 Anonymous 
And please don’t forget the USA Patriot Act was written during Clinton’s time at the helm.
 Anonymous 
Or South Asia intelligence–hmm, ISI perhaps.
 Eyeball_Kid 
Oh, yeah. I forgot. Private companies don’t waste, don’t defraud, don’t abuse. Yeah. That’s what we learned in Iraq, right? Blackwater has an impeccable record using the highest ethical and professional standards. I’m happy that you reminded me. Wasn’t it Blackwater employees who gang-raped one of their colleagues and locked her up in a metal container when they suspected that she wasn’t going to keep her mouth shut? That was efficient and ethically superior treatment, eh? And wasn’t it Halliburton that got paid billions for driving empty trucks all around Iraq? Now that’s efficiency! Oh. And I forgot that it was private contractors in Iraq who seemed to lose 9 billion dollars.“Oops! The money’s not here…Nope, it’s not there, either…”Now that’s what I call the practice of professional standards!
 http://newphosphene.wordpress.com/2010/11/22/4111/ ~«a small room on the top floor 
[...] cases involve an ABC producer who described a TSA agent groping inside of her underwear as “worse than the gynecologist,” a woman being lifted off her heels via her vagina, and several cases of women having their skirts [...]
 Eyeball_Kid 
…days before an election. Just like the OBL fake recording during the’04 election. Again…cui bono?
 Anonymous 
Fuck Pistole and the TSA. And fuck all of the ASSHOLE who voted for the Patriot Act and Homeland Insecurity.
 Anonymous 
What America needs is a method of screening passengers and cargo that doesn’t interfere with basic rights. The focus should be on proactive measures, not reactive measures.
 http://profiles.yahoo.com/u/JTWEQCYVVFC2TXDOR22FHC22QQ Anonymous 
Pistole looks like a Nazi….you have to wonder what he was doing in the 1960′s when the American cultural revolution was going on….he was at some military academy. I wouldn’t let him near my family…
 Anonymous 
How else will one get to Alaska or Hawaii?
 http://profiles.yahoo.com/u/JTWEQCYVVFC2TXDOR22FHC22QQ Anonymous 
America–Land of the Free and Home of the Brave? I don’t see brave, I see people kowtowing to fear, lies, manipulation, extortion, and propaganda. Where’s Freedom and Tyranny Master Glen Beck on this? He LIKES IT…’cause he’s got a private jet.
 Anonymous 
I doubt most so called americans know what the 4th amendment says, or even that there is a 4th amendment. sad.
 Anonymous 
So, take the train, bus, drive or stay home.
 Anonymous 
I doubt most so called americans know what the 4th amendment says. I doubt most know there IS a 4th amendment. SAD.
 Anonymous 
It would also make it easier to claim she was sexually assaulted.
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_KHCOC5OHITOZQPI6PGAPJYSSN4 Andy Greenberg 
It’s not like anyone ever snuck a bomb in their underwear. Oh wait…
 http://www.nypost.com/p/news/national/air_bomber_shorts_fuse_GeBaGmubs9fkAIZnzXY8oJ 
 Anonymous 
These worthless cock suckers have NO INTENTION of letting up on this…they’re going to continue harassing and assaulting people until every American accepts that they no longer have any right to life, liberty, property or protection against unreasonable searches. PERIOD! WAKE UP YOU FUCKING MORONS! If we don’t respond with violence and put a stop to all this bullshit RIGHT NOW, what are we? Why are U.S. soldiers and Marines dying by the thousands in Iraq and Afghanistan? WHY???!!!! TO WHAT END??? If this is the result of going to war to“defend ourselves,”then what is the fucking point?!
 http://bodyscannersexposed.com/tsa-top-transgressions-who-is-doing-the-terrorizing/ TSA’s Top Transgressions: Who Is Doing The Terrorizing? | Body Scanners Exposed–Airport Full Body Scanners 
[...] cases involve an ABC producer who described a TSA agent groping inside of her underwear as “worse than the gynecologist,” a woman being lifted off her heels via her vagina, and several cases of women having their skirts [...]
 Benway for the Nova Police 
“And there are specific operating protocols in which they are to follow.”

This bozo who can’t even speak English is the head of a federal agency?
 Benway for the Nova Police 
See Webster Tarpley on who this retard actually was and who let him loose on the world. I got news for you, Mr. Braindead, it wasn’t Osama bin Laden.
 Benway for the Nova Police 
Eat shit.
 Johnny Warbucks 
Are the sexual molestation charges sticking yet?
 Johnny Warbucks 
Pony Express, of course.
 Anonymous 
Benway your pending trial for felony sexual assault of that 17 year
old girl has gotten you edgy. I suggest you hit the bottle and forget
your problems.
 Anonymous 
add to that : What America needs is a chocolate cake that tastes
great and lets you lose all the weight you want.
 Anonymous 
Israel has few flights each day than Miami.
 Anonymous 
I would take that as an attack on GW Bush and his reps in the congress.
 Anonymous 
If you have a private jet like Limbaugh, Hannity and Beck there is NO SECURITY CHECK.
 Anonymous 
….and your evidence is???????????????
 Anonymous 
The underwear bomber last year about this time came from Holland. The TSA is not at the Amsterdam airport but of
course Obama got the blame.
 http://www.facebook.com/General.L33 Justin Whatchamacallit 
Wake up folks!!! They can’t detect explosives in this manner. Only a dog can sniff out hidden explosives. This is all to train and condition us. If your elected congressman doesn’t even have to do this why should you?
 Anonymous 
What would be the effect on the security of the US if we stopped the occupation of Iraq and Afganistan? Do you think this nation
would sit still while we were occupied by anyone’s military???????
 Benway for the Nova Police 
I managed to figure it out. But then English is my first language.
 Benway for the Nova Police 
He can’t help it. They filled his head up with all that cherry tree nonsense when he was a kiddie and he’s not bright enough to see through it.
 Anonymous 
Hey we have to reach inside underwear to be SAFE FROM THE TERRORIZING TERRORISTS OF TERROR.
 Anonymous 
This is satire, right?
 http://twitter.com/MicheleLucc Michele Angelucci 
way to avoid answering the question about what recourse these passengers and victims of the tsa’s sexual assault have, john pistole. i guess that means there is no recourse for them? the tsa gets to do an unwarranted gynecological exam on passengers just as long as we are all“safe”??? you JERK. your alphabet agency is a joke. you are not keeping anyone safer. you are terrorizing american citizens!!!
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_3WYAWTN4LJ2TAZGFCL3U4H6AWM TheGuru 
Sure, giving these fugitives from a fast food restaurant kitchen the authority to search was bound to result in these abuses. However, don’t tell me that this crap didn’t happen three or four years ago. It just seems that if you complained back then, you would have been called a“terrorist sympathizer.”

There has got to be a better way to make people safer on flights. Does this stuff happen in Europe? I know that they have been very thorough when I have traveled over there. Are there abuses over there too?
 Anonymous 
I’ve posted this before, and I’m sure I’ll post it again:
“Those who would give up essential liberty for personal security deserve neither liberty nor security.”—Ben Franklin
I don’t plan to give up essential liberty. Luckily, I don’t have to fly and therefore don’t plan to take elective flights until I can be sure I’ll neither be exposed to cancer or molested.
 http://twitter.com/shekissesfrogs Kristie Mansfield 
Israel is not a good model and we need to shut this meme down. Nothing Israel does should be imported here. Matt Yglesias was just there, and he’s an Jewish American. He was not impressed. They also treat Arabs like crap, in the airports, never mind everywhere else–because they’re all terrorists, you know.

 http://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2010/01/adopting_the_is.html 

 http://www.examiner.com/populist-in-national/exactly-what-are-israeli-airport-security-measures-and-would-they-work-here 
 http://twitter.com/shekissesfrogs Kristie Mansfield 
ACLU attorneys have questions about abumutallab, from where I got these links.

 http://sacramentofordemocracy.org/?q=node/34726 
 http://antifascist-calling.blogspot.com/2010/01/flight-253-anatomy-of-cover-up.html 
 http://cannonfire.blogspot.com/2010/01/ten-strange-things-about-crotch-bomber.html 
 Anonymous 
This was totally inappropriate and demeaning as well as not necessary. None the less it could have been avoided if this lady would have gone through the scanner.
 Anonymous 
Oh, well does that mean our government should all of US like crap? Israel treats Arabs like crap because Israel is a racist, or whatever you call ethnic prejudice, dishonest, land grabbing, bible literalist theocracy.

But, the reason we don’t employ their intelligent model of screening is that GED holders who could not get other jobs can’t DO that sort of screening. Imagine having to pay screeners up to $100,000 a year for their PROFESSIONAL intelligent screening services.

The intention of the screening methods used on us is not safety but humiliation–let’s not forget that difference between us and Israel.
 http://twitter.com/shekissesfrogs Kristie Mansfield 
No, dogs can’t smell them, but these back scatter machines are about private profit for Chertoff, and he’s also running a Validated BIO ID card scheme too, where you will able to opt out of the scans, or the pat downs and it only costs 179.00
 http://my.firedoglake.com/shekissesfrogs/2010/11/21/dont-like-chertoffs-porno-scans-or-punitive-groping-buy-chertoffs-new-verified-bio-id-for-179-and-skip-the-lines/ 

The Airline Pilots association is telling pilots that back scatter x-rays are dangerous and not to go through with them.
 Anonymous 
Most womens underwear; there ain’t even that much of it anymore to kind of feel inside of nowdays (at least that’s what I’ve noticed when I am doing my own sorta’amatuer TSA inspections with my um, lady friends). What, was she wearing some of those parachute style underwear the ladies used to wear in the 1950′s or something?
 Anonymous 
How about this idea…Fuck the fucking scanner and obama’s travel mate who sells the fucking things too. And hey, the horse the rode in on as well.
 Anonymous 
Bro…Post of the day!!!
 Anonymous 
This guy was escorted past security by some unknown dude who disappeared shortly after. Multiple witnesses have confirmed this story!!!
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_45ZDBHL6CN3277REDTIOLEAFWM JediSifu 
What are you .. a moron?? You should go and work for the TSA…if you don’t already. That’s EXACTLY why they’re doing this with the aggressive pat down and hands in the underwear, because they WANT everyone to go into the scanners instead so that they can radiate you with dangerous X-Rays and to get your BIOMETRIC SCANS in their database in preparation for the greater rollout of TV cameras on every street corner, face recognition technology and total control grid control and tracking systems of everyone in the country and the world.. WAKE UP! Prisonplanet.com
 Anonymous 
Ronald Reagan’s former“Freedom Fighter’s”now relabeled“Terrorist’s”have won. As the U.S. continues to sacrifice liberty for security and receive neither in return.

“Extreme Mental Cruelty”is what Reagan’s first wife accused him of after engaging in pre-martial sex, resulting in his marrying a 3 month pregnant Nancy. That all debt-slave, police-state American citizen’s can now utter.
 Anonymous 
Turn your head and cough.
 Anonymous 
London Mayor Tells Bush To Stay Out of Londontown — Will International Shunning Become Prosecution?

 http://jonathanturley.org/2010/11/19/london-mayor-tells-bush-to-stay-out-of-londontown-will-international-shunning-become-prosecution/ 
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_DFO26ZTHHBKLAS7STLD3JV3USY jjhuyzinga 
New TSA Rule: Fly Naked!
 Anonymous 
OK. Can’t hurt. After all, right now I’m sitting here doing this naked.
 http://dprogram.net/2010/11/22/tsa-news-11-22-10/ TSA News 11-22-10 | Dprogram.net 
[...] (RawStory)–ABC producer says TSA agent felt inside her underwear–Read More Here [...]
 http://twitter.com/MicheleLucc Michele Angelucci 
here is another good quote for you:

“FIND OUT JUST WHAT ANY PEOPLE WILL QUIETLY SUBMIT TO AND YOU HAVE THE EXACT MEASURE OF THE INJUSTICE AND WRONG WHICH WILL BE IMPOSED ON THEM.”~Frederick Douglass
 Anonymous 
You are either extremely naive, or you are a tool.

 http://www.infowars.com/underwear-bomber-false-flag-to-be-exploited-to-renew-draconian-patriot-act/ 
 Anonymous 
You are exactly right Frankzoo!! It was a false flag psyop, just like the shoe bomber, the Times Square bomber and the attacks on 9/11.

Yes, 911 was a terrorist act, but not by 19 Arab guys with box cutters taking orders from some guy in a cave on a dialysis machine.

 http://www.buildingwhat.org 
 Anonymous 
Abu Ghraib at the Airport.
 Anonymous 
Wondering…is this all an effort to convince us that scanning machines are less intrusive than manual pats, and that we need to buy lots of them? Because there is a person with ties to a scanning machine company paling around the administration. This would be excellent prep for that purchase.
 Anonymous 
Fuck flying, fuck Disneyworld, fuck Sea World, fuck Broadway, fuck the Smithsonian, and fuck the entire US Travel Industry. Their silent complicity in this whole“Terrorism”charade while the People’s rights get stripped out from underneath us will result in their utter and complete demise.
 Anonymous 
wear a kilt…….
 Anonymous 
hummmmm………..i wonder what tsa would find if someone decided to load up their DEPENDS for them to go through……?
 Anonymous 
Violence won’t stop anything, it will only bring on more.

If you’re serious about putting a stop to it, pull all your money out of the banks on December 7th.

 http://stopbank.blogspot.com 
 Anonymous 
This is all nonsense. All this effort in order not to”racially profile”. Israel is the best at airport security and they readily admit to racially profiling. Better to go inside some 70 yr. old woman’s underwear than to ask some middle eastern appearing person to step out of line. One big friggin joke.
 http://profiles.yahoo.com/u/5WCODCQ66IC47B7ZSJBDO4A6RM M. S 
Why do these media morons keep defending it then? It’s illegal. Now CHERTOFF THE ISRAELI Scumbag who OWNS the naked body scanners says you can buy an RFID ID instead for $179. He’s making money off this in office? How is this not collusion and completely illegal unconstitutional and CRIMINAL? Obama sux his Nazi minions suck, what is wrong with you acolytes of these monsters?
 http://profiles.yahoo.com/u/5WCODCQ66IC47B7ZSJBDO4A6RM M. S 
Yeah, they are sooooo serious about“security”? Stop letting millions of hostile foreign invaders pour through AZ and TX and other border states from god only knows where.
 Anonymous 
The appropriate action by TSA would be to stop these unwarranted pat down searches and conduct sensitivity training for their employees. What about using simple common sense? Hope that no one becomes angry enough and physically assaults one of these workers.
 http://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100000490818617 Samuel Sikes 
Does any one relieze that the over seas terrorest have won?
the defanition of terrorism is of course to create fear. Over sea terrorest and terrorest within our own government have been sucessful becase they have created the fear within ourselfs and made this country destroyed itself from the inside. we r so falsely affraid of terror that we created it now though that fear. we r terrorizing ourselfs.
 Robert Shaftoe 
Question: what other countries are using the RAPE-SCAN machines and these aggressive pat-downs/feel-ups? Can we see a list please? Do we really want to be on the same list as those countries as taking security a bit too far?

It’s been what, a week since these new feel-ups began and people are already this pissed-off? Funny most didn’t see this coming years ago with the advent of the“Homeland”Security Department.

 The new security measures are now called‘GATE RAPE” 
 Robert Shaftoe 
I just want to know if I can charge the TSA for“baggage handling”?
 Robert Shaftoe 
Or even“Their silent complicity in this whole“Terrorism”charade while the people get stripped will result in their utter and complete demise.
 http://www.zazzle.com/InfinitudeTortoises An Infinitude of Tortoises 
Now, now. This poor, beleaguered TSA agent was merely trying to find the fuse(s) protruding from the producer’s orifice(s)—because short of an X-ray scan, that’s the only way they’ll ever discover a bomb stored internally! The“porno scanners”won’t spot it.

Feel better now?
 http://www.ilovethefirstamendment.com/blog/republicans-and-democrats-agree-on-dislike-of-the-tsa/ Republicans and Democrats agree on dislike of the TSA«I Love The First Amendment 
[...] ABC News producer says experience worse than the gyno. [...]
 David R Velasquez 
Tough decision for the TSA. Either a free feel up or free porn pics (which lasts infinitely longer)
 Che_G.IV 
Timmy, too much Fox News will turn you into a Tea Party zombie. Don’t be too afraid of those people you see outside your window, they’re just trying to live the American dream.
 David R Velasquez 
These pat downs are bs. These scanners are nonsense as well.
I’d rather take my chances with terrorists than let some sweaty TSA agent feel my‘junk’.
 http://sonoranalliance.com/2010/11/22/tips-for-helping-you-survive-your-government-grope/ Sonoran Alliance: Arizona Politics for Conservatives»Tips for Helping you Survive Your Government Grope 
[...] An ABC news employee reported a TSA Screener actually put her hands into her underwear.  The gropin…[...]
 Anonymous 
Terrorists are men, I’m sure you agree it makes more sense to gender profile. I am totally in favor of a separate line at the airport for all men to get invasive scans and strip searches and cavity searches, just to be on the safe side.
 http://www.VimaxReview.com JonnyForever 
It’s sad how many of our civil liberties have been taken away because of this idea that giving them up will make us“safer”…While I think some reasonable amount of security has to be in place, this is well past reasonable.
 Anonymous 
When at the airport…
…MOOO and BAAH like the cattle they treat us like.
 Anonymous 
.

 Q U E S T I O N: 

The lead in that George gives us…
…What does the dome of the German Parliament have to do with American“DOMESTIC”flights?

.
 http://katypundit.com/news/hotair-tsa-uproar-that%e2%80%99s-the-power-of-drudge/ Hotair: TSA Uproar: That’s The Power of Drudge | Katy Pundit 
[...] me a “Time” story called “Please remove your prosthetic breast,” and a Raw Story titled, “ABC producer says TSA agent felt inside her underwear“).Now consider how many of these stories wouldn’t have seen the light of day had it not been [...]
 Anonymous 
The totally stupid part of all this is……….Once you pass through security, you can go into a restaurant and they give you metal utensils. You dropped the ball on that one, ponyboy.
 Anonymous 
The worst part about this is…….after passing through security, you can go into a restaurant and they give you metal utensils. You dropped the ball on this one, ponyboy.
 Anonymous 
How far are we willing to go to support the terrorist state of Israel?
 http://www.lossofprivacy.com/index.php/2010/11/tsa-chief-says-pat-down-went-too-far/ TSA chief says pat down went too far–Loss of Privacy 
[...] Pistole, the head of the TSA said today that a pat down of a woman went too far when a TSA agent felt inside the woman’s underwear. An ABC News employee said she was subject to a“demeaning”[...]
 Anonymous 
Which is why public colonoscopies are the next logical step in airport security procedures. And Americans will simply bend over and take it in the bum for the sake of a false sense of security. Ain’t it grand how the government so lovingly looks over (and now into) us.
 http://warlocketx.wordpress.com/2010/11/23/this-hurts-me-as-much-as-it-does-you/ This Hurts Me As Much As It Does You«Ric&apos;s Rulez 
[...] going to work. In the first place, your bosses are going to run like the rats they are, leaving you swinging in the wind. In the second place,“chust followink orders”hasn’t been a sufficient defense [...]
 http://underthemountainbunker.com/2010/11/23/top-5-most-demeaning-tsa-horror-stories-so-far/ Top 5 most demeaning TSA horror stories (so far) | Under the Mountain Bunker&amp;Coffee Shop 
[...] woman’s underwear: An ABC News producer says that while traveling recently, a TSA agent stuck a hand inside her underwear.“The woman who checked me reached her hands inside my underwear and felt her way [...]
 http://isaskar.wordpress.com/2010/11/23/mer-om-skanningen-och-tsa/ Mer om skanningen och TSA«Isaskar 
[...] ABC Newsproducetn: De kände innanför mina trosor”The woman who checked me reached her hands inside my underwear and felt her way around,”said ABC News producer Carolyn Durand.”It was basically worse than going to the gynecologist.”[...]
 Gerald Perdue 
If the intrusive pat downs are absolutely necessary for airport security, why weren’t they implemented before the scanning machines were introduced?
 Anonymous 
they aren’t overseas
 http://www.facebook.com/people/Gaetano-Giacalone/100000786654768 Gaetano Giacalone 
Pistole is saying the screening are evolving, Well I really dont see how they can evolve to be less invasive. What if Al-Qaeda as a joke or even to physiological terror start publishing that they are considering cavity bombs. Is TSA they going to start doing cavity searches on passengers?
 http://twitter.com/OptimistCapital Alexander Cooke 
this is a collosal load of crap, it doesn’t make flights any safer. Whats next full on rectal exams?
 Anonymous 
wow what gynecologist does she go to? Mine goes inside my body, not inside my pants. She has a right to be outraged but her comparison is way off the mark.
 http://eikonal.wordpress.com/2010/11/16/tsa-folies/ TSA folies«Eikonal Blog 
[...]“ABC producer says TSA agent felt inside her underwear”by David Edwards (RawStory; 2010.11.22)– http://www.rawstory.com/rs/2010/11/abc-producer-tsa-patdown-worse-gynecologist/ [...]
 http://itsumademo.livejournal.com Tri 
I agree with you utterly.
 Anonymous 
David et., al.,

I see your point. Dammed if do, dammed if you don’t.
I guess the only remaining option is don’t fly commercial.
But of course our elected or appointed government officials
are exempt from either being scanned or patted down/felt up,
so their concern level‘May’be less than their constituents
ya think?
 http://profiles.yahoo.com/u/RCBGZNI5LDSLNWBYTTZASC6PE4 morristhewise 
It is very frustrating to be stroked and stimulated for a few seconds by an air safety inspector. If the groping was extended for at least 5 minutes there would be less complaints.
 Che_G.IV 
That is a lie.
 Anonymous 
Here is a question that was posed elsewhere in the blogosphere.

QUESTION: DOES A TSA SCREENER CHANGE HIS OR HER GLOVES AFTER TOUCHING SOMEONE’S SEXUAL ORGANS AND BEFORE TOUCHING THE NEXT VICTIM? ARE THEY SPREADING STD&amp;HIV/AIDS DISEASES? ARE THEY INFECTING THE TRAVELING PUBLIC AND OUR CHILDREN?

This is a very valid question.

 Anonymous 
I hardly think that Michael Chertoff (Bush’s Homeland Security director) is Obama’s traveling mate. The original scanners were ordered by the Bush admin and tested in various airports since 2005. The order was increased and the scanners are now being rolled out on a schedule originally set by Bush.
 Anonymous 
It isn’t Chertoff, he may be a stockholder but doesn’t in fact run the company. I can’t think of the dudes name and I am kind of hungover so I don’t feel like unduly taking my cognition here but trust me, the bastard fuck that owns that company went to India with Obama.
That’s ture though, no matter what Bush did or started, Obama, in spite of his words and even indignance to the contrary, finds a way to follow thorugh with the plan. Or haven’t you yet noticed that pattern.
 http://www.christianforums.com/t7514843-2/#post56161706 A bill to end this TSA madness–Page 2–Christian Forums 
[...] pat-down&quot;could be spreading STDs or pubic lice? if some* of these TSA screeners are putting their fingers under people&apos;s underwear i think that could be a problem. (*i&apos;m sure the vast majority of TSA screeners are non-pervert [...]
 Anonymous 
My fellow Marine, Semper FI! i was once in the 3rd Marine division. When I took the oath we were all shortly after tought that this sort of thing is completely wrong and that we have a DUTY as Marines to stop it if we see it in progress. Now for reasons that seemingly a growing number of people are rightly stating angerly against is suddenly ACCPTABLE!? I hope we re-think this very soon!
 Anonymous 
Question;“What kind of recourse (do people have against violations of their privacy)?”

Answer:“Again, the security officers are there to protect the traveling public…”

A non-answer to a reasonable question. If these people could be held personally responsible for their conduct, things would change in a hurry. But they’re PUBLIC SERVANTS, so they’re basically exempt from laws that apply to everyone else. Sexual molestation is a serious crime, but when there’s no penalty and your boss defends you by saying criticism of the new tactics is“irresponsible,”we can expect it to continue.
 Anonymous 
No recourse. This“enhanced patdown”happened to my hubs–there was NO scanner available. He was frisked, grabbed and groped–in full view of all other passengers, AT THE GATE by a FEMALE AGENT–no private room was offered and no“male assist”.

These agents are nuts–and they are bullies. At no time was he spoken with or told what to expect.
 Anonymous 
Do not kid yourself that they are not planning body cavity searches. As they say, they are not being used“yet”.

We’ll see how the airline revenue drops when they take you in a room with a speculum.
 Anonymous 
They are being done in airports that do not have the new scanning devices. Therefore they are lying. There is NO choice, no privacy is available and you are not given an option of having a same-sex groper.

The TSA is lying through their teeth.
 Anonymous 
They will just trash the airline’s revenues. We generally fly 12-15 times a year. Next year…maybe 1 or 2…no more.
 Anonymous 
I fly a lot. I won’t go through scanner…and if I happen to go to the US again, and am frisked…if anyone squeezes my lemon or strokes my banana? I’ll have an *involuntary* knee-jerk reaction….right under their jaw.

I am VERY ticklish, ya know?
 http://www.theprogressivemind.info/?p=51546 The Progressive Mind»ABC producer says TSA agent felt inside her underwear | Raw Story 
[...] ABC producer says TSA agent felt inside her underwear | Raw Story. November 23rd, 2010 | Category: Uncategorized | Comments are closed | [...]
 http://survivalacres.com/wordpress/?p=2140 Survival Acres Blog»‘Abused’TSA staff vent their anger at patdown searches–TSA Agent Rapes Woman 
[...] b) the alleged’security procedures’that claim to make this all necessary is to ensure passenger safety, ie., nobody is carrying a bomb, etc.  Yet the TSA is now factually and literally“feeling people up”and putting their hands in people groins inside their pants and inside their underwear. [...]
 Anonymous 
There was a story posted a few days ago about men protesting these searches by wearing a kilt. I respectively submit that making it easier for them isn’t the way to go! If you really want to get back at‘em, simply forego taking a bath / shower for a week or so before you fly.
 Anonymous 
Depends on who’s doing the groping… Heck, why don’t they just put massage tables for a complete“around the world”by, Harry, Philis and Fatty, which would of course end with a choice from a menu of very happy endings, gosh, gee whiz, Mrs. C., they could even have a menu of sorts with pics—pick your favorite“massage therapist(s)”and enjoy… while your spouse, children and the general pubic watch via pay-per-view (kinda like one of those xxx peep shows).

Even better, we could just have a hippie-love-fest before every flight…Complete with dancing girls and striptease lap and/or table dances… Wow, the possibilities are endless…

They’ll sell a lot more tickets, and many“travelers”will just spend their“vacations”in the airport going back and forth through“customs/security”. Very efficient… Airports would become kinda like“Roman Bath Houses”were… No more“terrorists”to worry about, they’re all busy getting massages. Another problem solved. Johnny could run a few“episodes”on the Daily Show and O’Really could complain about it on his new“Foxy News Show”and everyone would be so happy…

Must be a lot of pervs signing up for those jobs…

Let’s see… Knock, knock… Who’s there? Security. We think you might be“terrorists”, we need to feel all your family’s members.
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_JK5ANRUXYPQIYFECEEXEK2ETQM Dana 
One has to wonder what kind of sick fuck wants a job with the TSA in which you put your hands all over several hundred strangers every day? These TSA agents must be the most despicable, desperate and deranged people around. Fucking power tripping pervs!
 http://www.facebook.com/people/Berl-Jay-Hubbell/1627730874 Berl Jay Hubbell 
Personally, I think screening and groping is all a scare scam to justify the former head of Homeland Security, Michael Chernoff profiteering from the sale of the dangerous radiation machines.
 Anonymous 
If its the woman in the top picture, I must say that having a license to feel would make me eager to do my job.
 Anonymous 
Harmful concentrated blast of radiation to the skin, or scarring molestation by a mouth-breather?
Can’t wait for these‘precautions’to be implemented at roadway toll-stations after a van is used for the next false-flag.
 http://twitter.com/Thanatos465 Gregory 
Obama and Bush are one in the same.
 Anonymous 
Every year we take a Christmas trip but this year we are staying home. I can just imagine anyone groping my girlfriend when she won’t even let me touch her in those private places without plying her with large amounts of liquor. This whole security thing by TSA is just more B.S. to keep the public scared of their shadow and the Obama administration is just continuing what the shrub started and I pray that the Democrats primary him in 2012.
 http://www.facebook.com/people/Warren-Goldmann/100001526833800 Warren Goldmann 
i volunteer to hold me nose and give all the tsa officials that believe these enhanced pat downs are justified one so they can see how they like it. i am sure none of them have gone through this procedure.
 Anonymous 
how about wearing a cod piece?
 Anonymous 
hope someone beats the shit out of these workers
 Anonymous 
Screw it, put on a Depends™ , fill that fucker and let the TSA guy“knead the dough”.
 http://www.facebook.com/tmayswhite Tami Mays White 
I tell you what a TSA employee would get a knee in the face if they tried that with me (the‘inside the underwear’move). If I go to jail, I go to jail–it would SO be worth it.
 Anonymous 
The same kind of sick fucks that held rifles on Jews as they marched to the gas chambers 80 years ago. These are weak minded conformists who blindly follow authoritarian regimes. If this country continues down this path, and continues to empower thugs like this, America will be a very uncomfortable place to be.
 Anonymous 
It can’t be quoted often enough in these times:

“Those that would give up their liberty in exchange for security, deserve neither.”

Benjamin Franklin
 Anonymous 
Answer: NO other nation does this. Not even Isreal, which truly does have to deal with a credible terrorist threat, and is considered to have the best airport security in the world.
 Anonymous 
Choosing to opt out has nothing to do with trying to create chaos or congestion. The reasons are different for different people and range from health issues concerning the backspatter to an obvious violation of constitutional rights. Not to mention the abuse of the system by overzealous or tyrannical employees. Trying to trivialize our reasons for this action will eventually only backfire. Mr. Pistole never gave a satisfactory answer to most of your questions and should not have been allowed to get away with that. You are not serving the public by allowing him to sidestep on issues. For most of us this is not a one time action and personally I expect not to fly again until these practices are abandoned. I am ashamed of the administration I helped elect believing that having a Constitutional attorney in the highest office of the land would protect me from such flagrant abuse of one of the most important documents in history.
 Anonymous 
Choosing to opt out has nothing to do with trying to create chaos or congestion. The reasons are different for different people and range from health issues concerning the backspatter to an obvious violation of constitutional rights. Not to mention the abuse of the system by overzealous or tyrannical employees. Trying to trivialize our reasons for this action will eventually only backfire. Mr. Pistole never gave a satisfactory answer to most of your questions and should not have been allowed to get away with that. You are not serving the public by allowing him to sidestep on issues. For most of us this is not a one time action and personally I expect not to fly again until these practices are abandoned. I am ashamed of the administration I helped elect believing that having a Constitutional attorney in the highest office of the land would protect me from such flagrant abuse of one of the most important documents in history.
 Anonymous 
Without shadow of doubt this whole affair is the continuation of state sponsored false flag operation to corral American citizens into sheep pens.

Are we going to let them do this?

Personally, I say HELL NO!!
 Anonymous 
For all the good it will do he should still file a complaint. I also offer a couple of options the next time he goes through this procedure. He can request that an actual law enforcement officer be present although I don’t know how long that option will be available. If asked why he wants one he should simply say‘it is for your protection’and continue to insist that one be present. He can also ask for an officer if he feels he has been groped inappropriately, when the officer arrives he should then ask for a specialist from a sex crimes unit to be called. All this takes time and unfortunately most people aren’t willing to miss their flight in order to pursue the issue at the time it happens. Unfortunately not acting immediately and on the spot relegates the incident to not much more than an anecdote or hearsay unless there are witnesses or he has credibility from some other source.
 Anonymous 
The answer is likely not unless you request it. The gloves aren’t there for your protection but for the screener’s. Personally I recommend that everyone ask the screener to change gloves before they touch any of your baggage or your person. I know from experience that there are diseases out there that people fly with that are more than a minor public health issue. According to the TSA site you are well within your rights to expect that this request be honored.
 Anonymous 
As soon as a‘terrorist’tries to get past security with something in a body cavity or after having swallowed it. We have a reactionary system which is always responding to the last attempt. Behavioral profiling and patterning after the system used by El Al would be much more sane and safe.
 Anonymous 
They are also being done in airports that have the backspatter machines. The goal of the TSA at the moment is to make the pat downs so abhorrent that we will willingly submit to the machines.
 Anonymous 
huh?
 http://911newscentral.com/2010/11/24/22-incredibly-revealing-quotes-about-enhanced-pat-downs-and-tsa-groping/ 22 Incredibly Revealing Quotes About Enhanced Pat Downs And TSA Groping«911 News Central.com BETA 
[...] #2 ABC News producer Carolyn Durand: [...]
 http://www.theprogressivemind.info/?p=51601 The Progressive Mind»22 Incredibly Revealing Quotes About Enhanced Pat Downs And TSA Groping « 911 News Central.com BETA 
[...] #2 ABC News producer Carolyn Durand: [...]
 http://blog.deafread.com/sandmanssandbox/2010/11/23/if-youve-got-it-flaunt-it/ Mr. Sandman’s Sandbox»If You’ve Got It, Flaunt It 
[...] cancer survivor forced to remove her prosthetic breast; an ABC producer said the experience was“worse than going to the gynecologist”; and a five-year-old in Salt Lake City who was patted down, with his father finally removing the [...]
 http://www.eternityroad.info/index.php/weblog/4638/ Eternity Road 
[...] and assaulted by the TSA agent. I shook for several hours, and woke up the next day shaking. #2 ABC News producer Carolyn Durand: “The woman who checked me reached her hands inside my underwear and felt her way around.” #3 [...]
 Anonymous 
It’s not like they didn’t see this backlash coming. It’s been planned. If people revolt(which is one possible scenario), they will clamp down even further. However it could also be a case of‘two steps forward, one step back’–that is, they might‘ease’the procedures and people will buy it(people wouldn’t have if those‘eased’procedures were instated in the first place).
 http://lovefreedomtruth.com/2010/11/obamas-tsa-war-crimes/ Obama’s TSA war crimes | LOVE FREEDOM TRUTH 
[...] #2 ABC News producer Carolyn Durand: [...]
 http://tipggita32.wordpress.com/2010/11/24/tsa-worker-allegedly-abducts-assaults-woman/ TSA worker allegedly abducts, assaults woman«THE INTERNET POST 
[...] isn’t going to help the view of those TSA pat-downs, as one ABC producer put it,‘worse than the gynecologist,’at [...]
 Anonymous 
They need to do what the Israelis do by El Al check out, you question the passengers and watch their body language, that is what gives it away whether they are lying or not. They also pull out all Muslims from the line and do a thorough investigation of all contents that are in their belongings. But that would require that we do something original and profile our enemies. Women with children, senior citizens in wheel chairs, etc. are not our adversary. Israel has had no problems in 20 years, they are the safest airline to fly because they do not have a problem with airport discrimination. It is time America wakes and realizes who are real enemies are and who are not!
 http://findinfoworld.com/abc-producer-says-tsa-agent-felt-inside-her-underwear/ ABC producer says TSA agent felt inside her underwear 
[...] Edwards Raw Story Nov 22, [...]
 http://roblosricos.wordpress.com/2010/11/24/are-you-a-bat-shit-crazy-rapist-the-government-might-have-a-job-for-you/ are you a bat-shit crazy rapist? the government might have a job for you…«we are not afraid of ruins 
[...] isn&apos;t going to help the view of those TSA pat-downs, as one ABC producer put it,&apos;worse than the gynecologist,&apos;at all. A Georgia TSA (Transportation Security Administration) behavior detection officer was [...]
 http://www.facebook.com/people/John-House/1011555524 John House 
Shyeah, you just wait until one of them pulls some poor woman’s tampon out…and then there will be Hell to pay.
 http://www.facebook.com/people/John-House/1011555524 John House 
Holy crap…what? Is that English?
 http://panamaexplorer.com/espanol/tiendas/doit-center/ Do-it Center Panama 
Kudos from one brainiac to another. :)
 http://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100000490818617 Samuel Sikes 
Why u gotta take somthing serious and add ur immaturity to it. ( holy crap.. is u 8?) lol
 http://afteramerica.wordpress.com/2010/11/25/happy-thanksgiving-america-thanks-for-raping-us-tsa/ Happy Thanksgiving America. Thanks for Raping US TSA.«AfterAmerica&apos;s Blog 
[...] #2 ABC News producer Carolyn Durand: [...]
 http://www.urbaniulian.ro/2010/11/25/un-producator-al-postului-abc-spune-ca-agentul-tsa-a-pipait-o-prin-lenjeria-intima/ Un producator al postului ABC spune ca agentul TSA a pipait-o prin lenjeria intima | Urban Iulian 
[...] David Edwards 22 Noiembrie 2010 http://www.rawstory.com/rs/2010/11/abc-producer-tsa-patdown-worse-gynecologist/ Pe masura ce zilele cele mai aglomerate de calatorit se apropie, din ce in ce mai multi pasageri [...]
 ateo 
thank god (take your pick)
i’m not american.
Patriot act, Rumsfeld and Co…Land of the free?
Looks like you’re living in your own prison.
Looking back at 9/11 they sure won!!
We were proud to be able to look up to the US of A. Now we wonder what has become of it?
Remember terrorist attacks on London buses Madrid train stations? Still no body scan, TSA..

Be free! Accept to die from a terrorist attack instead of accepting this kind of treatment.
 http://aleapofbadfaith.wordpress.com/2010/11/25/white-people-almost-stand-up-for-someones-rights/ White people (almost) stand up for (someone’s) rights«A Leap of Bad Faith 
[...] from back-of-the-hand techniques to cupping and handling people with their palms and fingers, and reaching inside of their underwear. It’s easy to find lots of horror stories about people who feel embarrassed, humiliated, [...]
 Anonymous 
And the asshole Dems who voted with Bush’s people.
 http://seemytruth.wordpress.com/2010/11/26/the-disgusting-tsa/ The Disgusting TSA«I See 
[...] #2 ABC News producer Carolyn Durand: [...]
 http://www.homefortalent.us Hemorrhoid Cure 
Very helpful site. Thanks, finally a decent website with good information in it.
 http://online-casinotest.com/ online casino 
Den Anblick werd’ich nie vergessen,
 Anonymous 
I hope none of these workers go postal.
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_GOGGUHC3JKELRE3FDCRHHCXCYI Paulette Persons 
Isn’t the disclosure of a medical condition already covered by the Medical Privacy Act? Isn’t it a matter of doctor-patient confidentiality? If so, do we have a requirement to explain to a government employee what our condition is or requires us to wear? In the case of a business traveler who travels twice a week every week, how many government employees would be privy to that confidential medical information by the end of a single year?
 http://tsaholes.wordpress.com/2010/11/30/tsa-agent-felt-inside-a-womans-underwear/ TSA agent felt inside a woman’s underwear | TSA holes 
[...] inside a woman’s underwear Posted on November 30, 2010 by uscitizen1 An ABC employee, Carolyn Durand, chose the pat down instead of the full body screen. Durand said the female TSA agent who performed her body search [...]
 http://www.mp3sites.co.uk MP3 Sites 
Thanks for taking the time to discuss this, I feel strongly about it and love learning more on this topic. If possible, as you gain expertise, would you mind updating your blog with more information? It is extremely helpful for me.
 http://online-casinotest.com/ online Casino 
Why do you have to pick on the Suri? Leave that BABY alone!!!!! She is beautiful. An ANGEL!!! Straight from heaven.
 http://page2rss.com/page?url=photo-video-sexe.magikmobile.com Lose weight 
Good job, i am heading over to check out your entire site now. I have just got interested in blogging and hopefully i am able to do so
 http://online-casinotest.com online casino test 
Issue 1.5 features Dave White, Nneka, Rochelle Sket, DJ Target, Street Style (London), How To Act On A First Date, Neil Danns, DJ Excalibah, Master Shortie, Bluey Robinson, Fuse Green and so many more.
 http://online-casinotest.com Online Casino 
Internet Explorer 8 is more stable than IE 7 that is why i like it. I always experience freezing browser window in IE 7.
 http://www.facebook.com/scorpiojosh Joshua Freeman 
ok, watch the video, at the 5:30 to 5;35 point, they ask if he will change the pat down procedure. As soon as she asks that, mute your speakers and watch him shake his head. This f*cker is lying through his teeth, but his body language is betraying him!
 http://profiles.yahoo.com/u/GCPX7DXZGK2H2CPNYRR5IS5A64 Turnip Mcgee 
Umm. Our real enemies are those that extort us for profit, blow up our buildings, make a myth of retirement, export our means of production, toxify our entire financial system, and kill our children in foreign deserts.
You look at the caricature of evil that has been painted for you. You may do better to look at the artist.
 http://www.earlylearningcenter.co Elmo 
Wow!, this was a real quality post. In theory I’d like to write like this too–taking time and real effort to make a good article…but what can I say…I keep putting it off and never seem to achieve anything
 http://www.gamingjobsonline.com/ Video Game Tester 
Seems like a tweet deserving article for me. Ideas and writeups like this are somewhat helpful to a person like me. Tweeting it up!.
 http://speakerscorneratx.wordpress.com/2010/12/07/come-on-new-yorker-tsasexual-assault-cover/ Come on, New Yorker: TSA/Sexual Assault Cover«Speaker&apos;s Corner 
[...] is just HAHAHAHAHAHAHA so funny that you have to be willing to have your vagina rubbed under your pants in order to get on a fucking flight these [...]
 http://www.fmduxi.com Kosmetika pigiau 
I also use wordpress for my website. The best thing is that comments add additional content. By the way, your chosen design suits perfetcly what is site about.
 http://ezinearticles.com/?How-to-Naturally-Get-Rid-of-Cellulite&amp;id=3514596 Naturally Get Rid of Cellulite 
Hi I found your site by mistake when i was searching Google for this issue, I have to say your site is really helpful I also love the theme, its amazing!. I dont have that much time to read all your post at the moment but I have bookmarked it and also add your RSS feeds. I will be back in a day or two. thanks for a great site.
 http://bestbathroomfurniture.co.uk Kacey Archer 
Hey friend can i publish some paragraph of your article on my little blog of university.I have to publish a good articles out there and i really think your post Fits best into it.I will be grateful to give you an source link as well.I have two blogs one my own and the other which is my college blog.I will publish some part in the university blog.Hope you do not mind.
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_KV3QWHVFXLO7TB56FRGXERRC7Q Lexi 
As a girl who doesn’t trust men and is terrified of being hurt, I would be sobbing if a pat down was done. I would also flip out if they can see me naked through those scanners. I think that this is a horrible invasion of privacy and of self. What about the women and men who were sexually abused? I guess driving is back in for me. I can’t emotionally or mentally handle that.
 http://freedomcrusader.wordpress.com/2010/12/22/had-enough-yet-2/ Had enough yet…«A Journey to True Freedom 
[...] ABC employee, Carolyn Durand, chose the pat down instead of the full body screen. Durand said the female TSA agent who performed her body search [...]
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_I6AMTRIEVLIQ3HOFEV6UWF5PQY S.asimaziz Khan 
hi
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_I6AMTRIEVLIQ3HOFEV6UWF5PQY S.asimaziz Khan 
hi
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_I6AMTRIEVLIQ3HOFEV6UWF5PQY S.asimaziz Khan 
hi
for alllllll
 http://pulse.yahoo.com/_I6AMTRIEVLIQ3HOFEV6UWF5PQY S.asimaziz Khan 
hi
for alllllll
 http://www.darkpolitricks.com/2010/12/abusive-homeland-security-%e2%80%98troll%e2%80%99-attacks-anti-tsa-website-report/ Abusive Homeland Security ‘troll’ attacks anti-TSA website: report | Dark Politricks 
[...] pat-downs have been likened by some travelers to sexual abuse, and several lawsuits have been launched challenging the [...]
 http://mikechamberslive.com/?p=10808 Abusive Homeland Security ‘troll’ attacks anti-TSA website: report 
[...] pat-downs have been likened by some travelers to sexual abuse, and several lawsuits have been launched challenging the [...]
 http://newsrobot.info/2010/12/10-tsa-horror-stories-of-pat-downs-gone-wrong/ 10 TSA Horror Stories Of Pat-Downs Gone Wrong- News Robot 
[...] ABC employee, Carolyn Durand, chose the pat down instead of the full body screen. Durand said the female TSA agent who performed her body search [...]
 http://pracownia4.wordpress.com/2011/01/19/laczenie-punktow-sila-ludu-kontra-bron-masowego-odwracania-uwagi-1/ Łączenie Punktów: Siła ludu kontra broń masowego odwracania uwagi (1)«PRACowniA 
[...] się, że została wybrana do dalszego prześwietlenia piersi. Kolejna, producentka z ABC, stwierdziła, że sprawdzająca ją agentka„wsadziła jej ręce w majtki i dokładnie ją [...]
 http://www.yayinakisi.com Canli Yayin 
 izle canli… 

In searching for websites related to web hosting and specifically comparison hosting linux plan web, your site came up. :)…
 H.P. Loathecraft 
A+ for your avatar
 H.P. Loathecraft 
That fucker will‘knead the dough’because he needs the dough
 H.P. Loathecraft 
Are you prepared to pay extra for the Happy Ending fee?
 H.P. Loathecraft 
Stay tuned. We are only one cavity bomb away from airport gynecology.
 H.P. Loathecraft 
Have you been away? Rubiconski can draw you a diagram if you like.
 http://www.darkpolitricks.com/2011/01/obama%e2%80%99s-tsa-pat-downs-joke-infuriates-aclu/ Obama’s TSA pat-downs joke infuriates ACLU | Dark Politricks 
[...] Administration official. While most travelers did not report being excessively frisked, some other instances of apparently abusive behavior later came to the [...]
 
 
 New on Raw Story 

 U.S. slaps more sanctions on Iran Harry Reid: Burn all the China-made Olympic outfits Maine Gov. LePage: IRS ‘heading in the direction’ of the Gestapo Obama reflects on lack of ‘unity’ in first term Internet media firm Betaworks buys social news site Digg USA Gymnastics adopt new rules to combat abuse after Penn State scandal D.C. officer allegedly threatened to shoot Michelle Obama Rep. Gowdy on leaks: Reporters aspire to go to jail, so give em what they want Democrats push for transparency in political ads with DISCLOSE Act France eyes taxing Internet retailers 
 

 
 New on Pandagon 

 Romney Race-Baits after NAACP Speech It’s Not About Heckling Transparency: It’s What’s For A Bitter, Bitter Dinner The Reality of Abortion Black Lung on the Rise; Excessive Mining and Corporate Malfeasance to Blame 
 Check Out Our New Blogs Raw Exclusives 
 Obama campaign:‘Severe consequences’if Romney committed felony with Bain lies 
 Read More 
 Wisconsin Dem slams passage of House‘Obamacare’repeal bill 
 Read More Featured Video 
 Roland Martin accuses Romney of using ‘coded language’ 
 Read More 
 Rep. Gowdy on leaks: Reporters aspire to go to jail, so give em what they want 
 Read More 
 Steve Martin sells Mitt Romney’s pot in New York City park 
 Read More 
 Daily Caller reporter: Democrats reduced women ‘to a sexual being’ 
 Read More 
Search Raw Story
 
Follow Us!
 
Subscribe to our daily newsletter
 Email Address 
 
Info
 
 Masthead Advertise Jobs and Internships Support Our Work Terms of Service Privacy Policy Contact Blogroll/Media Links Online Shopping 
 
About Raw Story

Raw Story is a progressive news site that focuses on stories often ignored in the mainstream media. While giving coverage to the big stories of the day, we also bring our readers&apos; attention to policy, politics, legal and human rights stories that get ignored in an infotainment culture driven solely by pageviews.

Founded in Cambridge, MA in 2004, Raw Story reaches more than 2.7 million unique readers per month and serves more than 11.4 million pageviews. Recent focal points have included Occupy Wall Street, Wikileaks, wiretapping and judicial abuse.

Copyright © 2004-2012 Raw Story Media, Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
