<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009023" url="http://www.onestore.com.sg/job-interviews/conducting-a-good-interview.php" time="2012-07-13-02:25" support="1" score="0.00034852776612503993" bingtitle="Conducting A Good Interview at Job Interviews" webtitle="Conducting A Good Interview Information">
			<query id="000986" bing-rank="143"/>
	<description>... job interview that need to be considered in order ... level customer service type job, such as at a fast food restaurant ... thousands of interviews from a neutral seat. There ...</description>
	<body>
		MENU Home Common Job Interviews Questions Article Five Common Interview Questions Links Sitemap ARTICLES Conducting work interviews Conducting a personal interview Interviewer questions Frequently asked interview questions Answering interview questions Difficult interview questions Commonly asked interview questions Answering difficult interview questions Funny job interviews Behavioral based interview questions Conduct a good interview Customer service interview questions Dressing for job interviews Illegal interview questions Interviewing skills BOOKS 
 
 Warning : Invalid argument supplied for foreach() in /home/onestore/public_html/job-interviews/includes/amazon.php on line 868 
 
 
 
Resume Essentials


When preparing yourself for a job interview, you must do a number of things to get ready. You need to make sure that you are looking your best, that you are well-rested and fed, and most importantly, that you have a flawless resume to present to your prospective employer. You can go into an interview and say all of the right things, but if your resume has questionable content or is not put together very well, it can be a deal breaker. The following are some ideas on how you can create and present the perfect resume for success at your next job interview.   

While the job of your resume is to tell everything about you to the interviewer, it is your job to put together a resume that can provide all of that information in a short summarization. Your resume should never need to be more than one page in length. If it is, figure out which pieces of information are not essential and cut them from the final product.

Some people feel that they can impress the hiring staff by using speciality papers and fonts with their resume. Do not make this mistake. When human resource managers or shop owners make a decision about who to hire, they do so based on the qualifications of the applicants - not because they took extra effort in preparing their resumes. Your resume needs to be easy to read, it does not need to be pretty.

If you have a short employment history, you may feel compelled to list every single job you have ever had to make your resume appear more impressive. If you are applying for a specialized position, you need only include employment history information that relates to the position you are applying for, which lets the interviewer know that you have previous experience in the field for which you are applying.

The odds are pretty good that you are going to be typing out your resume on a computer, using some sort of word processing software. This software has spelling and grammar checks for a reason. Use it. Make sure that you have used the proper spelling, grammar, and punctuation, and have more than one person double check it after you have, just to be sure.

One popular mistake is to lie in one&apos;s resume. No, not all employers check to make sure that the employment and personal references for an applicant are accurate, but that is not the point. You do not want to start out your employment relationship with falsehoods, so do not pad your resume with things that you never did.

There is no need to attach a list of previous employer and personal references to your resume. Simply note in your resume that references are available upon request, and during your interview, you can offer to deliver copies of those to the interviewer if need be. This shows your willingness to share this information, but cuts down on waste in case the interviewer does not need it.

With a little bit of common sense and these helpful hints, your next job interview should be just around the corner. 
 PRODUCTS 
 SPONSORED LINKS     
 Conducting A Good Interview News 
How to foolproof your hiring decisions

Establishing a rigorous and effective interview process is essential for every small business. Here&apos;s how to do it.
 Read more... 

 
A poll-taker&apos;s technique to get you to respond:&apos;Smile while you dial&apos;

Ed Dubas is one fast talker. He has put this skill to good use over the course of his working life – as a mayor of the small Nebraska town of Fullerton and a used-car dealer.
 Read more... 

 
Scientists trace timeline of Alzheimer&apos;s slow, deadly path

CHICAGO (Reuters) - The first Alzheimer&apos;s-related changes begin to develop some 25 years before memory and thinking problems appear, according to a new study that may offer a valuable guide for companies looking to test new treatments in people at an earlier stage. The study, published on Wednesday in the New England Journal of Medicine, offers a timeline of changes in spinal fluid, brain size ...
 Read more... 

 
Mayor Emanuel: Expand strategy from areas where crime dropped

An initiative targeting gangs and drug markets in two violent Chicago Police districts this year will be expanded to other high-crime districts after a dramatic drop in homicides in the targeted areas, Mayor Rahm Emanuel said Thursday. Former Chicago Police Supt. Jody Weis told the Chicago Sun-Times this week that it might be time to “call an audible” — football jargon for a slight change in ...
 Read more... 

 
7 Signs You Bombed Your Interview

You arrived dressed in your best suit, tackled every question, and think that you made an excellent impression overall . But you still didn&apos;t get the job. Where did you go wrong? You might go crazy trying ...
 Read more... 

   
   Copyright 2012. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
