<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009106" url="http://blog.synqsolutions.com/index.php/category/dine-america/" time="2012-07-13-02:29" support="11" score="0.028384780011488385" bingtitle="Dine America – Synq Solutions&apos; Executing Innovation Blog" webtitle="Dine AmericaArchways Executing Innovation Blog">
			<query id="000838" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000839" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000815" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="000842" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000567" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000913" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000830" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000724" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="000824" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000843" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000832" bing-rank="5"/>
	<description>... franchisors should examine the ... fruits and vegetables if a fast-food restaurant ... A digital menu board solution might be the right answer for you, but before you ...</description>
	<body>
		Home | Contact | Blog | Site Map 
 Subscribe via RSS Subscribe via Email Follow us on Twitter Connect on LinkedIn Become a fan on Facebook 

Dine America
 
 Doug Fergusson Comments on Dine America 2011 
 
By: Glenn Haertel 
October 13, 2011 | No Comments 
 
In this video, Doug Fergusson shares his thoughts on Dine America 2011 and speaks about the emerging themes at the conference.

 


 
 Permalink | Tags: ( Dine America 2011 , Doug Fergusson , interview ) Add Comments | View Comments (0) 
 
 Don MacPherson Discusses Employee Engagement at Dine America 2011 
 
By: Doug Fergusson 
October 13, 2011 | No Comments 
 
In this video interview, Don MacPherson of Modern Survey reveals a surprising and disturbing statistic: 70% of employees in the workforce today are either under-engaged or disengaged. Watch our interview to hear Don describe the four drivers of employee engagement:

 


 
 Permalink | Tags: ( Dine America 2011 , Don MacPherson , employee engagement , interview ) Add Comments | View Comments (0) 
 
 Dave Whitlock Speaks on Unionization at Dine America 
 
By: Doug Fergusson 
October 12, 2011 | No Comments 
 
In today’s economic climate, hospitality employees are particularly vulnerable to unionization. This video features David Whitlock of Elarbee Thompson, who advises franchisees on how they can prepare for labor efforts and promote satisfaction in the workplace.

 


 
 Permalink | Tags: ( David Whitlock , Dine America 2011 , interview , Unionization ) Add Comments | View Comments (0) 
 
 Young Guns Dine America Session Discusses Second Generation Franchisees 
 
By: Glenn Haertel 
October 12, 2011 | No Comments 
 
Dain Pool, Pool&apos;s Restaurant Group
 
One of the breakout sessions I attended was titled “Young Guns”, and it focused on the fact that many baby boomers’ children are coming of age and looking for their own business opportunities. The panel consisted of QSR’s Sam Oches (moderator), Dain Pool of Pool’s Restaurant Group, Jonathan Wagner of Two Trucks, LLC, and Donald Boroian of Francorp, Inc.

All three panelists agreed that while millenials form a complex group of people, they are generally divided into two groups: those who are comfortable operating under franchisee guidelines, and those who are not. Donald Boroian stated that the young guns are not as interested in brands as they are in the latest concepts. They buy from a personal preference point of view—contemporary identity is important to them. It’s as though they’re the “anti-brand” generation, and contemporary movements appeal to them. Franchisors should bear this in mind throughout their efforts to attract this demographic.

The food truck trend emerged several times throughout the panel’s discussion. Jonathan Wagner of Two Trucks, Inc. took his
 
Jonathan Wagner, Two Trucks, LLC
 
father’s brand—Johnsonville Sausage—and featured it in his food truck concept. Wagner’s business model is a perfect representation of how the young guns are developing ideas from what they’ve learned growing up and evolving them. Food trucks appeal to the anti-corporate mindset that so many of the second-generation franchisees embrace.

Other hot concepts discussed included second-generation Mexican food (Chipotle, for instance), healthy, chopped foods and salad venues, and breakfastfoods and sandwiches.

Dain Pool and Donald Bororian both agreed that when seeking quality young gun franchisees, franchisors should examine the candidate’s past level of responsibility, look for strong leadership qualities, and marked passion for the food industry. They cautioned everyone to beware of the disgruntled young gun who is simply trying to get out of his parent’s shadow. Bororian advised,

“Look for kids who live, eat and breathe the business.”

Not surprisingly, the panelists mentioned the importance of targeting second-generation franchisees through social media and search engine optimization.
 
Donald Boroian, Francorp, Inc.
 
I found it interesting that Donald Boroian, who has over 40 year of experience in the food service industry, and the two young gun panelists: Jonathan Wagner and Dain Pool, all agreed on virtually every point discussed during the panel—despite the generational gap. Further, they allmentioned the importance of listening to franchisees, customers, and employees, and adapting your offerings and services based on their input. Adapting quickly to change and adjusting your marketing message to your local customers and their specific preferences is key to succeeding in today’s environment.

Did you attend the Young Guns panel at Dine America? If so, I’d love to hear your thoughts.


 
 Permalink | Tags: ( Dine America 2011 , franchisees , second generation franchisees , young guns ) Add Comments | View Comments (0) 
 
 Kat Cole Video Interview from Dine America 
 
By: Glenn Haertel 
October 12, 2011 | No Comments 
 
This week, Kat Cole, president of Cinnabon was kind enough to give us a video interview at Dine America. In her interview, she speaks about the importance integrating your brand within the local community, and discusses the value of establishing connections and building relationships with your customers.

 


 
 Permalink | Tags: ( Cinnabon , Dine America 2011 , interview , Kat Cole ) Add Comments | View Comments (0) 
 
 Kat Cole Opens Dine America with Inspiring Keynote 
 
By: Glenn Haertel 
October 10, 2011 | 2 Comments 
 
Kat Cole of Cinnabon
 
This year’s Dine America opened with a riveting keynote from Kat Cole, president of Cinnabon . Kat discussed the challenges and opportunity facing businesses in today’s economic environment and reminded us that nearly every business is undergoing some degree of change. While these changes may be daunting, they also present incredible opportunities. As a result, it’s crucial that we maintain a positive mindset and encourage and empower our employees to do the same.

Kat relayed several personal anecdotes as she described her journey from a Hooters hostess to the president of a major foodservice brand. Throughout her career, she seized any and every opportunity with awareness that tumultuous times provide opportunity. Kat was hungry for knowledge and experience, and she learned from a young age how to seek out chances to build trust and prove her inexhaustible work ethic.

The culmination of her experiences contributed to her understanding and adoption of a series of core beliefs:

 Do more than just show up. No borders; no boundaries. Focus on ongoing education. Survive and thrive in times of change by weaving your brand into the fabric of the community. 

Kat’s keynote was full of nuggets of wisdom, including “sometimes you have to get smaller to grow”; and “to move through change, you have to be a changer.” She referenced Harvard professor Francis Frei, sharing her advice encouraging people to “be willing to be bad at something”, and finding out what’s truly important to your customers in the process.

She urged us to find ways to connect business with community, emphasizing the importance of learning what customers are looking for through surveys and interviews. Kat pointed out the benefits of reaching consumers through every channel, from print advertising to social media. Ultimately, the ideal way to discover how to best serve your clients or customers is to simply ask them what they need.

The importance of weaving employees into the fabric of your company and establishing connections with them cannot be overstated. As leaders, it’s our job to provide perspective, coach, educate, and inspire them to think and operate without boundaries. Kat suggested giving employees mentors, providing perspective and renewing their vigor.

Every message of Kat’s keynote was inspirational and motivating—however, one of the most memorable moments was when she briefly described her background and shared that she had “every reason to say no” to success. According to Kat, every part her history lent itself to repeating a history of addiction and failure. Instead, she went the opposite route and reached staggering levels of success.

Now, Kat remains remarkably humble and insisted that great deal of what she knows, she learned in her “orange shorts”.

We’d love to hear from those of you who attended the keynote presentation today at Dine America. What stood out for you?


 
 Permalink | Tags: ( Cinnabon , Dine America , Hooters , Kat Cole ) Add Comments | View Comments (2) 
 
 Dine America 2011: A Conversation with QSR’s Blair Chancey 
 
By: Glenn Haertel 
October 5, 2011 | No Comments 
 
 With Dine America 2011 rapidly approaching, we wanted to get the inside track on what to expect from the conference in terms of hot topics, panels and speakers. Blair Chancey, editor of QSR Magazine , was kind enough to share her insights with us on this year’s Dine America.

According to Blair, the 2011 event will bring some big names and brands—including Google, mobile couponing sites like Scoutmob , and David Davenport, the new CEO of Shoney’s . Interestingly, several of this year’s attendees will be full-service restaurant operators.

We were also excited to hear that this year’s conference will focus on the exploration of  new ideas and technologies within the industry.

To hear more details on Dine America 2011, be sure to listen to Blair’s description here:

 Audio clip: Adobe Flash Player (version 9 or above) is required to play this audio clip. Download the latest version here . You also need to have JavaScript enabled in your browser. 

Are you attending Dine America 2011? If so, what topics are you most looking forward to hearing about? Let us know in the comments.


 
 Permalink | Tags: ( Blair Chancey , Dine America 2011 , QSR magazine , restaurant industry ) Add Comments | View Comments (0) 
 
 Counting Down to Dine America 2011 
 
By: Glenn Haertel 
September 23, 2011 | No Comments 
 
 This year marks our third consecutive year sponsoring Dine America , the boutique conference for restaurant leaders. If you haven’t already perused the lineup , presentations cover topics ranging from unionization to mobile technology, with two of four Keynote speakers representing Cinnabon and Shoney’s.

I encourage you to check back often on our blog for inside looks at presentation themes. We’ll offer insights into what to expect over the next few weeks, as well as video interviews with speakers and written reflections during the conference. Whether or not you are able to attend, we welcome you to join the conversation through the comments section after each post.

For those of you attending, we look forward to seeing you at the Synq Solutions booth Oct. 9-11th.


 
 Permalink | Tags: ( Cinnabon , conference , Dine America , Shoney&apos;s ) Add Comments | View Comments (0) 
 
 Blair Chancey, Editor of QSR Magazine, Wraps Up Dine America 2010 
 
By: Glenn Haertel 
September 15, 2010 | No Comments 
 
We’d like to thank Blair Chancey, Editor of QSR Magazine , and her team for coordinating this year’s conference. We enjoyed making new connections with people in the industry and hearing from accomplished, inspirational speakers. What are your concluding thoughts on Dine America 2010?

 


 
 Permalink | Tags: ( Blair Chancey , conference , Dine America , Dine America conference , QSR ) Add Comments | View Comments (0) 
 
 Highlights from Dine America’s Legislating Foodservice Panel 
 
By: Doug Fergusson 
September 15, 2010 | No Comments 
 
Today, restaurants are subject to various forms of foodservice legislation on a daily basis. This has a tremendous impact on businesses—for this reason, it’s of vital importance to understand and acknowledge these legislative issues as an industry.

Ken Cutshaw, EVP, chief legal officer, secretary, and chief compliance officer of the Cajun Operating Company for Churches Chicken moderated the Legislating Foodservice session and introduced the following three panelists:

 Charles Hoff : general counsel, Georgia Restaurant Association

 Keisha Carter : Carter Political Group&amp;RaZors Consulting

 Mike Vaquer : lobbyist, Georgia Restaurant Association; Founder; The Vaquer Firm

Cutshaw opened the session by discussing some vital issues that are currently being addressed not only by the federal government, but by the state government as well. He pointed out that many restaurant owners feel that they have very little impact on legislation and public policy; however, when we come together as restaurant associations or within group conferences, we can make significant changes. Case in point: we’ve seen recent success on the credit card interchange swipe fees.

 Interchange Swipe Fees 

Charles Hoff commented on this topic by pointing out that the interchange fee has been “the bane of restaurateurs’ existence for three years”. Between 2001 and 2008, costs catapulted from 16 billion to 48 billion—in terms of overall costs, it’s been #3 behind food and labor. Thankfully, the NRA and other organizations joined forces and lobbied against this legislation, which provided some welcome relief. Now, improved legislation stipulates that debit card charges must be “reasonable and proportional to the cost of processing.” Additionally, merchants will have set costs for credit card usage, allowing them to set a $10 minimum purchase amount.

Hoff pointed out that while we’re not quite where we’d like to be with the legislation, it’s a great start.

 Card Check Legislation 

Cutshaw shifted the conversation to card check legislation, and Keisha Carter explained that this was one of the unions’ biggest pushes in 2008. The legislation would allow employees to go into businesses (mainly retail establishments) with a card, fill it out, check a box, and employers would suddenly find themselves subject to the unionization process. In the next few weeks, we could see a majority shift in Congress, which would delay and possibly deter this proposed legislation. That said, card check legislation isn’t going away, and businesses should educate themselves on how they could be affected by this bill. As it stands, it’s likely that we won’t see this legislation addressed in 2010, or even in 2011.

 Menu Labeling with Nutritional Values 

Cutshaw introduced the much-discussed topic of menu labeling, and Charles Hoff responded by raising an interesting point: many restaurant chains actually support this legislation. However, issues arise when an uneven patchwork of nutritional policies are put in place. These challenges would be preempted if we could adhere to one uniform regulation, which would allow us some protection from lawsuits and ambiguity. Although the federal government will eventually preempt state regulations, many jurisdictions are taking steps to initiate policies for their own protection.

Mike Vaquer commented on this topic as well, and warned restaurateurs not to rest on their laurels and assume that the issues are being resolved with the federal government’s intervention. He cautioned us to be wary of overzealous food inspectors and regulatory “creeps” who attempt to implement ridiculous stipulations, such as disclosing the origin of species of fish for items on a menu, or indicating the temperature of cooked meat, e.g. medium, well-done, rare, etc. Vaquer encouraged the audience stay vigilant, and to inform and question governmental regulatory figures about imposed regulations that seem questionable.

Keisha Carter urged us to stay involved from a regulatory perspective, and pointed out that currently, the FDA is in a “comment period”, where restaurateurs and other interested parties can go online to fda.gov and communicate their questions and concerns regarding legislation. This sort of proactive involvement applies to our communications with federal legislators and congresspeople as well.

 Healthcare Reform 

Keisha Carter also contributed valuable advice on the topic of Healthcare Reform, and mentioned the upcoming statewide elections—which serve as a huge opportunity to take advantage of relationships with our insurance commissioners. Carter pointed out that when it comes to regulatory healthcare issues, the restaurant industry is an area that is often ignored. For this reason, it’s important to stay in touch with legislators and stay informed of regulations that may or may not apply to your state.

 First Lady Michelle Obama / The Childhood Obesity Pledge 

Cutshaw segued from the subject of Healthcare into Michelle Obama’s pledge to make childhood obesity her personal cause. Keisha Carter took on this topic, and explained that the First Lady’s plan to lower the rate of childhood obesity by 5% by the year 2030 is a considerable goal. The logic behind the movement is that healthy children will grow up to be healthy adults, and make healthier food choices.

Keisha mentioned that certain aspects and repercussions of this pledge are reminiscent of the menu labeling issue.  For example, the government is essentially asking the industry to self-regulate by stopping the use of certain marketing tools, such as kid-friendly characters to entice children to eat at a particular restaurant. One study revealed that children would be more likely to eat more fruits and vegetables if a fast-food restaurant such as McDonald’s told them to do so. Therefore, many jump to the assumption that the QSR/fast-food industry is responsible for kids’ food choices. Carter mentioned two plan recommendations under discussion:

1)  food and beverage industry and the media and entertainment industry jointly adopt meaningful, uniform nutrition standards for marketing food and beverages to children, and establish a uniform standard for what constitutes marketing to children

and…

2)  restaurant industry should provide technology to help consumers distinguish between advertising for healthy and unhealthy food and limit their children’s exposure to unhealthy food advertisements

These recommendations are going as far as suggesting that parents will have the ability to set parental guidelines on their televisions and block certain restaurant advertisements. Television food rating systems will come into play, causing parents and children to make healthier choices. Another possible future development is additional taxes on foods considered unhealthy.

Carter made an excellent point: if school systems would stop removing physical education and sports from school programs, children would be far less likely to be at home watching television and eating junk food. As businesses, we need to encourage kids to go out and play by supporting local softball teams, etc.

One of the major takeaways of this session was how crucial it is to maintain constant contact with our legislators. Restaurateurs have the ability to open their doors to fundraising events and thus establish deeper relationships with our legislators. If we join forces by leveraging the power of our associations and organizations, our voices will be heard.


 
 Permalink | Tags: ( card check legislation , childhood obesity , menu labeling , menu legislation ) Add Comments | View Comments (0) 
 
 One Foot on a Block of Ice and the Other in a Fire: A Review of Economics with Gene Stanaland 
 
By: Randy Naegele 
September 15, 2010 | 1 Comment 
 
 Yesterday we had an enjoyable morning eating Krispy Kreme doughnuts and exploring economics with the second Keynote speaker at Dine America 2010, Gene Stanaland. After warming up with some jokes about the Alabama-Auburn rivalry, he launched into a thorough explanation of Washington’s connection to our economy. He compared the president’s relationship with the economy to a bull rider’s relationship with the bull; while the president may influence some economic policy, ultimately, the economy is another beast. After stressing that politics always come first in Washington, Stanaland explained the source of the housing decline as well as its impact on the recession, and offered details regarding baseline budgeting and sub-prime loans.

Although it’s never pleasant to discuss a recession, Stanaland approached the topic with humor, never dwelling too long on the dismal facts without some comedic relief. (Before listing some averages of unemployment rates, for example, he explained: “Now these are averages; if you have one foot on a block of ice and the other in a fire, on average, you’re comfortable.”) In addition to injecting humor into his presentation, Stanaland left us with some good news—the overall forecast for 2011 is positive, with the economy rising from the depths of this recession by the start of next year. Unemployment will be slow to follow suit, but we should expect improvement from 2010’s 9% unemployment rate by 2013.

To those of you who attended Stanaland’s Keynote presentation, what did you learn and enjoy?


 
 Permalink | Tags: ( Alabama , Auburn , conference , Dine America , economics , Gene Stanaland ) Add Comments | View Comments (1) 
 
 Cheryl Bachelder, President of Popeyes Louisiana Kitchen Presents at Dine America 
 
By: Glenn Haertel 
September 15, 2010 | No Comments 
 
 Cheryl Bachelder’s presentation was one of the Dine America events that I was eagerly anticipating—I’m sure many conference attendees felt the same. After all, Popeyes is the 2 nd largest chicken QSR in the country, and has made great strides since 2008. I was very interested in hearing Bachelder’s formula for success.

Bachelder opened by stating that 2009 was a game-changing year for Popeyes. In a matter of months, the brand achieved the following goals:

-       increased guest traffic

-       beat competitors

-       built and enhanced brand

-       provided a significantly better customer experience

-       married passion to fact based decision-making process

-       moved owner operators to put more money in the bank

-       opened new successful restaurants

Popeyes’success was based on a combination of focus, collaboration, and fact-based decision-making, rendering 2009 a foundational year in their long-term plan.  Their menu consists of Cajun Creole packed flavors from regions of America—which differentiates them as a QSR brand that offers only the highest quality, best tasting food.

Popeyes is headquartered in Atlanta, and now has over 1900 restaurants with 26 international locations, including Asia, Canada, Latin America, and the Middle East.

Bachelder stated that Popeyes is feeling very confident as they look towards the future, and by all accounts, they have good reason to be optimistic, as their results distinguish them from the rest of the industry. Through the 2 nd quarter of this year, Popeyes outpaced the overall results of the QSR category in sales, and they outpaced the cQSR for the ninth consecutive quarter. Their domestic same store sales in 2009 were positive as compared to overall QSR same store sales figures, which were negative. These positive figures and percentages have continued into 2010. Additionally, Popeyes’ guest traffic has been extremely strong, and resulted in a dramatic increase in their market share.

So—what’s the reason for this considerable momentum? The answer to this is related to Popeyes finding themselves at a major crossroads in November of 2008—a time period that coincided with the realization that the brand was failing miserably in several areas. Bachelder referred to this time frame as “The Brutal Reality”, and pinpointed the major issues as negative sales and traffic, poor service, margin pressure, and no metrics or measurement system to track success.

Popeyes was forced to take a hard, cold look at the facts, and compelled to make a major decision: should they view the recession as a sign of danger, or as one of opportunity? Clearly, the brand chose the latter and embarked on a plan titled “Road Map For Results”. Rather than shying away from the risks and fears of the economic downturn, they accelerated their plan, believed in it, and never looked back.

Bacheleder went on to describe the four major pillars of their plan:

1) Build a distinct, real brand : a brand must resonate with its customers. Popeyes’tagline: “Food so good, you can’t wait to eat.” The food is intended to summon a Cajun, culinary, authentic, superior experience. Popeyes immersed themselves in understanding their guests through traveling around the country and interviewing customers. “Grow market share” became the mantra; they placed emphasis on streamlining design and adjusted their fractured messaging. Last, they pinpointed “Annie” as the Popeyes brand ambassador, and featured her in commercials and marketing collateral.

2) Run great restaurants : “Service so good, you want to come back.” The brand established a GEM, or Guest Experience Monitor, and guests would use their phones to call in and take a survey while their experience was fresh in their minds. Service with speed: Popeyes tracked drive-thru times, and began running quarterly business reviews with restaurant owners.

3) Strengthen unit economics : profits so good that franchisees love the business as much as the food. Constantly be building a strong business case to build more restaurants, both domestically and internationally. Measure, track, and collect information—no more guessing

4) Ramp up unit growth : Popeyes embraced an international, strategic plan.

95 units opened globally; locations include Malaysia, Egypt, Turkey, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam, and the Cayman Islands. Countries have embraced the colorful culture, flavorful food and authenticity of the brand.

According to Bacheleder, the foundational tenet behind the four pillars of Popeyes’plan is to align people and resources across the company. The brand developed a new culture of partnership focused on honest dialogue and mutual trust, increased the frequency and quality of their daily communications, and has taken steps to accurately measure franchisee satisfaction. Without a doubt, Popeyes is reaping the rewards of their efforts; recently, QSR magazine named them as “One of Ten Great Franchise Deals”, and their name recognition has increased along with their overall momentum.

As far as 2010 is concerned, Bacheleder shared the good with the bad. The bad: the economy is proving to be slow to rebound, and unemployment rates continue to be high. The good: we’re seeing vitality in various segments, and franchisees are ready to grow. Throughout all of this, Popeyes will continue to move forward, innovate, grow market share, develop strong unit economics and growth, and hire capable operators.

It was virtually impossible not to be inspired by the story of Popeyes and their journey to success. Their story is a testament to the fact that brands and organizations can overcome any challenge by establishing a solid brand, practicing stellar customer service, and viewing obstacles as opportunities.

For those of you who attended Bachelder’s presentation, I’d like to hear hear your thoughts. Were you equally inspired by the Popeyes story?


 
 Permalink | Tags: ( Cheryl Bachelder , conference , Dine America , Popeyes ) Add Comments | View Comments (0) 
 
 Cheryl Bachelder, President of Popeyes Louisiana Kitchen, Shares Insight on Women Leadership and Social Media 
 
By: Glenn Haertel 
September 14, 2010 | No Comments 
 
We’re thankful to Cheryl for taking time with us after her informative presentation to share a few more insights. Our next post will feature highlights from her presentation.

 


 
 Permalink | Tags: ( Cheryl Bachelder , conference , Dine America , Popeyes , social media , Women Leadership ) Add Comments | View Comments (0) 
 
 Quiznos Franchise Owner Idris Talib’s Experience at Dine America 
 
By: Randy Naegele 
September 14, 2010 | No Comments 
 
 

What did you enjoy most at Dine America?


 
 Permalink | Tags: ( conference , Dine America , Idris Talib , Quiznos ) Add Comments | View Comments (0) 
 
 The Digital Panacea: Our Takeaway from the Price Is Right Session at Dine America 
 
By: Mike Snyder 
September 14, 2010 | No Comments 
 
Yesterday I attended “The Price is Right” breakout session at Dine America. I expected the conversation to focus on discounting and the impact it is having on the industry, umbrella pricing strategies, pricing anchors and other relevant and tangible issues operators are facing today. Instead of discussing these topics, the session evolved into a conversation about the benefits of digital menu boards.

Digital menu boards were presented as the solution for everything from enabling regional or market specific pricing and product mix to product testing through limited tests, to solving for the complexity of caloric disclosure legislation implementation. Rather than throwing a digital menu board at any and every business problem or challenge, we recommend that a business start with the question: “What business issue are we looking to solve?”

Implementing and installing digital menu boards can be expensive for the average franchisee, and it may not be the most cost-effective means of accomplishing your goal. All of the scenarios I mentioned above can be effectively managed through fairly basic location and item attribute profiling, the core of our own Intelligent Profiling solutions. We conduct Intelligent Profiling today for a number of our existing clients and it can be done quickly, cost effectively and with a high degree of agility and adaptability to the changing business environment.

A digital menu board solution might be the right answer for you, but before you make any investment, make sure you’re solving the right problem.


 
 Permalink | Tags: ( conference , Dine America , Dine America conference ) Add Comments | View Comments (0) 
 «Older Entries 
 
featured
 

 Local Marketing Series 
 What is “Local Marketing”? Segmentation Profiling Setting Goals Messaging Media Execution 
 
recent posts

 The State of Marketing Fulfillment Restaurant Leadership Conference Wrap Up What’s Trending at the Restaurant Leadership Conference 2012 2012 Restaurant Leadership Conference Archway and Synq Solutions Join Forces 
 
 Twitter 

 Could not connect to Twitter 
 
categories
 Announcements Dine America marketing materials Menu Labeling Requirements Quick Serve&amp;Fast Casual International Printers&apos;Network Industry News store profiling CFA Local Marketing Local Marketing Series Restaurant Leadership 2011 data collection franchisees PURLs synergy of services Training Intelligent Profiling profiling Client Project Profile QSR Restaurant Leadership Conference 2012 POP Fulfillment Industry Trends consumer spending Client News webinar national marketing NRF Expo Retail NRA Show 
sites

 Chain Store Age Marketing Today Nation&apos;s Restaurant News QSR Buzz QSR Magazine Restaurants&amp;Institutions www.thecfainc.com 
 
archives

 April 2012 March 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 
 
 
©2012 Archway, Inc. | tel: 866.779.9855 |  info@archway.com
	</body>
</document>
