<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009809" url="http://www.aolnews.com/2010/04/27/california-county-bans-toys-with-meals/" time="2012-07-13-03:12" support="1" score="0.0004929612065254481" bingtitle="Santa Clara County Bans Toys With Fattening Meals" webtitle="Santa Clara County Bans Toys With Fattening Meals">
			<query id="001440" bing-rank="167"/>
	<description>(April 27) -- For county officials in the Silicon ... House Bill Limits Federal Restrictions on Hunting ... Big Change at Group That Pushed &apos;Stand Your Ground&apos;</description>
	<body>
		AOL News has a new home! The Huffington Post .
 Click here to visit the new home of AOL News! 
Hot on HuffPost:

 WATCH: Romney Booed Over Obamacare House GOP&apos;s Obamacare Repeal Efforts Reportedly Cost Nearly $50… 
 See More Stories 
 MAIL 
 You might also like:  News ,  Politics  and  More 
 

 
 Sphere 
 News Web 
 
 Main Nation World Business Entertainment Sports Politics Health Weird Good More 
 Crime Tech Science Meet Our Team About Us 
 Help&amp;Feedback 
 
 ACLU Victory: Charges Dropped Against Denver Man Who Gave Cops The Finger EXCLUSIVE VIDEO: The Amazing Kreskin On UFOs, Doomsday And His Own Mysterious Future Chinese Prisoners Forced To Play Video Games In Bizarre Scheme Skull Of St. Vitalis, Patron Saint Of Genital Disease, To Be Sold At Auction Exclusive Video: 74-Year-Old Grandma Struts Her Stuff In Lycra Outfits At Muscle Shows Cicada Chirping Could Cause Hearing Damage What Makes Croatia&apos;s &apos;Magnet Boy&apos; So Sticky? Colorado&apos;s UFO Watchtower A Hotspot For Saucer Sightings 
 Nation 
California County Bans Toys With Fast-Food Meals
 Apr 27, 2010–6:16 PM Text Size Email This 
 Richard C. Paddock San Francisco Correspondent 
 (April 27) -- For county officials in the Silicon Valley, it turns out that Happy Meals are not so happy after all.

The Santa Clara County Board of Supervisors, tackling the problem of childhood obesity, voted today to ban restaurants from offering toys with children&apos;s meals unless the food meets specific nutritional standards.

The measure is the first in the nation to restrict fast-food restaurants&apos; marketing strategy of using toys to entice children to buy high-fat, high-sugar and high-calorie meals.

&quot;This ordinance breaks the link between unhealthy food and prizes,&quot; said board President Ken Yeager, who sponsored the measure. &quot;It imposes commonsense nutrition on meals linked to toys. We hope that other municipalities, counties and states will follow suit.&quot;

The ordinance applies only in the unincorporated parts of Santa Clara County, a largely suburban region south of San Francisco. County officials say there are just 50 restaurants that would be affected by the law, and only a few are fast-food restaurants that might offer toys as incentives.

Nevertheless, the measure was strongly opposed by fast-food franchise operators and other restaurant owners who fear the idea might spread to other jurisdictions. Santa Clara County was one of the first to require that restaurants provide calorie information on their menus, a requirement incorporated in the federal health care law signed by President Barack Obama.

Dozens of opponents of the ordinance attended the meeting and at times applauded loudly when their representatives spoke.

&quot;We do agree that there is a childhood obesity problem,&quot; Amalia Chamorro, local government director of the California Restaurant Association, told the board. &quot;Getting rid of the toys is going to do nothing to solve this problem.&quot;

The board, granting a small concession, agreed to give opponents 90 days to come up with an alternative plan before the ordinance takes effect.

Supporters of the measure say toys offered with high-calorie meals entice children to choose high-fat, high-sugar items that can be addictive and lead to obesity.

County Public Health Director Dan Peddycord told the board that childhood obesity has become an epidemic and that nearly 25 percent of the children in the county are overweight or obese. One in every three children born today will grow up to be a diabetic, he said. The odds are even worse for Hispanic children: One in two will become diabetic.

&quot;Childhood obesity is the public health issue of our era,&quot; he told the board. &quot;We have a collective responsibility to right-size the environment we live in.&quot;

Children who become obese at a young age are likely to be obese as adults and have a significantly higher risk of heart attack, stroke, diabetes and cancer, said acting county public health officer Sara Cody. A 2006 study found that obesity costs the county $420 million annually in health care expenses and $496 million in lost productivity.

The ordinance sets limits of 120 calories for a beverage, 200 calories for a single food item and 485 calories for a meal for any item sold with a toy.

Restaurants will be fined $250 for the first violation and $500 for the second.

Peddycord said a check of restaurants in the county found few children&apos;s meals under 650 calories.

Offering toys with the lower-calorie items could create an incentive for children to make healthier choices.

The issue brought out emotional, if not always well-informed, opposition. Some critics accused the board of banning all toys with meals.

Stephen Hazel, who brought one of his own favorite toys to show the board, says he collects them and sends them to children in the Philippines. He called Supervisor Yeager &quot;head Grinch Ken Yeager&quot; and angrily asked, &quot;Do you want to be the one who bans toys?&quot;

Kevin Kettila was equally heated. &quot;I take this personally that you are trying to take away our freedom of choice,&quot; he said. &quot;Parents have enough good information without you having to legislate this. You are going to deprive the little kids of a toy.&quot;

But Joanne Seavey-Hultquist, the mother of a 3-year-old and coordinator of a nonprofit for children called FIRST 5 Santa Clara County, said parents need help in countering the fast-food restaurants&apos; marketing strategy.

&quot;Research shows that parents are at a disadvantage when children are offered a reward for selecting a high-fat, high-calorie meal,&quot; she said. &quot;I appreciate a policy that helps me as a parent to do my job.&quot;

And Nicole Kohleriter, communications director for the Health Trust, another Silicon Valley nonprofit, said fast-food marketers know that parents can be worn down when their children plead for a toy.

&quot;The toys are in the food because the toys sell the food,&quot; she said. &quot;I think this ordinance is not about taking away parental choice but about leveling the playing field.&quot; Filed under: Nation , Health Tagged: happy meal , happy meal toys , Happy Meals , HappyMeal , HappyMeals , HappyMealToys , obese children , ObeseChildren , santa clara county , SantaClaraCounty , toys with kids meals , ToysWithKidsMeals Follow AOL News on Facebook and Twitter. 

2011 AOL Inc. All Rights Reserved. Follow us on Facebook and Twitter. 

2011 AOL Inc. All Rights Reserved. Email This 
 be the first to comment 
 
Hot Leads
 AP 15 Amazing Things You Didn&apos;t Know About Sharks 
-- TruTV
 
 12 Craziest Swimsuits -- Oddee 10 Spooky Ghostly Recordings -- Oddee 10 Dumb Lies Women Tell Men -- Dumb As A Blog 10 Paranormal Mysteries Easily Explained by Science -- Cracked Nazi Raiders of the Lost Holy Grail -- Fortean Times 7 Unusual Ways to Combat Impotence -- Oddee 
 

 More Stories» 
 Some Good News? Are Americans Cutting Back on Sugar Intake? I Ditched Dieting -- And So Should You Kate Bosworth&apos;s Fit Routine Should We Fear Our Genetics? What Nutritionists Order When Eating Out 
 More Stories » Sports News 
 Dwight Howard update: D12 rejected new GM&apos;s plea to stay, according to report Freeh Report: Joe Paterno exposed as Penn State&apos;s Cowardly Lion Team USA basketball: Blake Griffin hurt, Anthony Davis reports Penn State report: Freeh says Paterno, administrators engaged in Sandusky cover-up Report: Houston Rockets to use amnesty provision on Luis Scola 
 View All Sports News» Business News 
 The 5 Biggest Obamacare Myths Explored, Explained and Debunked Target and Neiman Marcus, an Odd Fashion Pairing? Not At All 3 Super Ways You Can Profit From the New Comic Book Media Boom Low Risk, No Gain: It&apos;s Time to Dump Your Money Market Mutual Fund Beyond Hotels: 4 Ways to Save Tons on One-of-a-Kind Vacations 
 View All Business News» 
ON FACEBOOK
   
News From Our Partners
 
 Tyler Calls it Quits as &apos;American Idol&apos; Judge Low Lobster Prices Putting The Pinch on Fishermen Trustees: Paterno&apos;s Legacy &apos;Marred&apos; by Abuse Scandal Airport Laser to Scan For Explosives ... and Lunch? Mitt Wants Apology for &apos;Felony&apos; Remark 
 More Stories» 
 President Obama&apos;s Calculated &apos;Evolution&apos; on Gay Marriage Israel&apos;s New Coalition: Why Netanyahu Has Moved to the Center How Small-Size Satellites Could Find Earthlike Exoplanets Big Tech: America&apos;s New Corporate Villain? Five Lessons About Work You Won&apos;t Learn in School 
 More Stories» 
 Serene Jones: Why Attend Seminary? Dennis House: Romney&apos;s Veep Pick? Waldo Mellon: Which Would You Smack With a Shovel? Timothy Stoltzfus Jost: Siding With the 1%? 
 More Stories» 
 Lawmakers: Burn &apos;Made in China&apos; Olympic Uniforms Penn St. Board Unsure of Paterno&apos;s Legacy Israel Accused of Killing Arafat 1 Chimp Dead After Vegas Escape One Ton of Illegal Ivory Seized in NY 
 More Stories» 
 Our First Book Club Live Chat If Felons Could Vote Endangered Species: Fossil-Fuel Dems &apos;The Scream&apos;, in 1921 Kim Dotcom&apos;s Legal Circus 
 More Stories» 
 stories ipad covers blogs amazon 
 More Stories» 
 Good day, bad day: July 12, 2012 Did Mitt Romney lie about his tenure at Bain Capital? The Taliban&apos;s execution of an accused adulteress: The fallout Jesse Jackson Jr.&apos;s mysterious disappearance: A guide Can Mitt Romney win without winning over minority voters? 
 More Stories» 
 FCD signs homegrown player Acosta Harry Kewell named Australia&apos;s greatest footballer Paraguay to face Guatemala in Washington Ibra, Silva sold to Paris St Germain Family of Border Patrol victim demands justice 
 More Stories» 
 Obama: My Biggest Mistake Was Failure to &apos;Tell a Story&apos; American Samoans Sue for US Citizenship Cruise Threatens Lawsuit Over Enquirer Story Opposition: New Syria Massacre Kills 200 Google&apos;s Nexus 7 &apos;Obliterates&apos; Kindle Fire 
 More Stories» 
 Everybody Bashes Bain, Including Romney &apos;A Tech-Savvy Robber Has Broken Into Your House&apos; Steven Tyler Flies the Coop More Than Half of Obama&apos;s TV Spending Since April Has Been on Negative Ads Iran&apos;s Navy Is Absolutely &apos;Dazzling&apos; 
 More Stories» 
 Investigator to FBI: Zimmerman not racist Man accidentally kills huge lawn Some Olympians are broke Syrian opposition report &apos;massacre&apos; Dad held in deaths of 3 young daughters 
 More Stories» 
Also on AOL&gt;&gt;&gt;
 
 Latest News 
 
 Mother&apos;s Day Crafts TV Listings Movie News Printable Coupons GMC Trade Secrets Summer Olympics 
 
 Depp&apos;s Dames 
   
 Photos: Johnny&apos;s Girlfriends 
 
 Alicia&apos;s Evolution 
   
 From Braids to Baby Bump 
 
 Lip-Sync Fun 
   
 Celebs in Music Videos 
 
 They Hooked You 
   
 Top Viral Marketing Movies 
 
 Search Footer Tab 1 
 Search Feedback 
 Top News 
 2012 Elections Business News Good News National News Tech News Techcrunch Weird News World News 
 More News 
 Movies Small Business Fantasy Football NBA NFL Stock Quotes Stock Market News Golden Globes 2012 
 More on Aol 
 Apple News Comedy Green News Music News Sports News Style News TV Listings Video Game News 
 More on Aol 
 Education News Food News Parenting News Real Estate News Science News Teen News Travel News 
 Local News 
 Chicago News Los Angeles News New York News Wasington, DC News Mapquest Patch Weather 
 More From AOL 
 Radio Horoscopes Autos Latino News Heidi Klum Online Games 
 
 
Latest news, weather, health, business, sports, science, money, entertainment, world news, elections, weird news and more.
 
 Terms of Use | Privacy Policy | Trademarks | AOL A-Z | HELP | Advertise With Us 
 
 ©2012 All Rights Reserved AOL News . Back to Top
	</body>
</document>
