<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009487" url="http://workoutprogramstogetripped.com/" time="2012-07-13-02:52" support="1" score="0.0007720872709321318" bingtitle="workoutprogramstogetripped" webtitle="workoutprogramstogetripped">
			<query id="001500" bing-rank="190"/>
	<description>You DON’T need to waste your money on expensive ... ever in a situation where you must eat at a fast food restaurant ... In order to be effective, a home fitness program ...</description>
	<body>
		Sitemap Contact Video Privacy About Home 
 
workoutprogramstogetripped.com
 
Workout Programs to Get Ripped
 More 
Make An

Impression
 
When I watched this video I just started to cry.From right now I&apos;m going to change my self, and help the planet not destroy it.
 More 
 The Get Ripped Workout Program for Starters! 
 On October 4, 2011, 
 in Uncategorized , 
 by admin 0 Being in a fitness business mean you are always dealing with a lot of interested asking what workout programs to get ripped are all about and can they deal with it if they get enrolled into one.  My answer to all those peeps is simply this, Read Full Article » 
 5 Facts You MUST Understand if You Are Ever Going to Lose Your Belly Fat and Get Six Pack Abs 
 On August 13, 2011, 
 in Uncategorized , 
 by admin 0 
 1. Many so-called“health foods”are actually cleverly disguised junk foods that can actually stimulate you to gain more belly fat…yet the diet food marketing industry continues to lie to you so they can maximize their profits.

 

 2. Ab exercises such as crunches, sit-ups, and ab machines are actually the LEAST effective method of getting flat six pack abs. We’ll explore what types of exercises REALLY work in a minute.

 3. Boring repetitive cardio exercise routines are NOT the best way to lose body fat and uncover those six pack abs. I’ll tell you the exact types of unique workouts that produce 10x better results below.

 4. You DON’T need to waste your money on expensive“extreme fat burner”pills or other bogus supplements. I’ll show you how to use the power of natural foods in more detail below.
 Read Full Article » 
 Workout Programs To Get Ripped 
 On August 3, 2011, 
 in Uncategorized , 
 by admin 0 In order to be effective, a home fitness program needs to combine a nutritious diet, cardiovascular exercises, strength building exercise, and also stretching. You will not get a full body fitness package unless you make time for each and every one of these areas.

First off: nutrition. It is important before you do anything else to rid your daily diet of sugar, fat and fried foods. A healthy diet should contain a combination of fruits, vegetables, low calorie grains, and can also contain low calorie dairy and low calorie meats if you choose.

 

It is very important to banish all fast food products from your daily food intake, as these kinds of foods do nothing for your health. If you are ever in a situation where you must eat at a fast food restaurant, try to stick to having a grilled chicken salad with a low fat dressing and a bottle of mineral water . You may even find that they have healthy substitutes for fries in the form of apple slices.

Don’t fall into the common trap of thinking that you can skip the stretching. Stretching will help prevent your body from getting injured, so it’s important to develop a routine. When you wake up in the morning, get your body ready for the day by doing a few stretches. You’ll also want to do some pre-workout stretches to loosen your target muscles. You will also need to do cool-down stretches after your workout, as this will be when your muscles are at their most warmed-up and you will be able to stretch them the most.
 Read Full Article »   
 


 
   
 
 
In order to be effective, a home fitness program needs to combine a nutritious diet, cardiovascular exercises, strength building exercise, and also stretching. You will not get a full body fitness package unless you ... Read More 
 
 
 
copyright 2011 WORKOUTPROGRAMSTOGETRIPPED.COM
	</body>
</document>
