<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009400" url="http://classifieds.nj.com/?temp_type=browse&amp;category=results&amp;tp=ME_nj&amp;property=nj.com&amp;classification=Garage-Yard%20and%20Estate%20Sales&amp;page=2&amp;citysort=asc" time="2012-07-13-02:46" support="1" score="0.0012236136161323128" bingtitle="Garage-Yard and Estate-Sales classifieds Online - NJ.com" webtitle="Garage-Yard and Estate-Sales classifieds Online - NJ.com">
			<query id="001468" bing-rank="229"/>
	<description>Search our easy to use free online Garage-Yard and Estate Sales classifieds to find all ... MERCERVILLE NEAR 5 POINTS More Info ... Everything must go end of Endicott Rd ...</description>
	<body>
		Site Search Search Local Business Listings 
 
 Home News Weather Sports Entertainment Living Interact Jobs Autos Real Estate Rentals Classifieds Find n Save 

 Classifieds Obits Rentals Pets For Sale Garage Sales Fraud Prevention Manage Your Ad Place An Ad More 
 
 
Garage-Yard and Estate Sales Classifieds Local NJ Classified Ads 
 
 Sort Listings By: Newest Ads First Oldest Ads First    Listings Per Page: 10 20 174 listings match, 11-20 shown &lt;Previous  Page 1 2 3 4 5 6 ... 18    Next&gt; 
Can&apos;t find what you&apos;re looking for? Try our
 Advanced Search 
 
Narrow Search By
 
Keyword/Web Id/City
 
 Full Listing Details
 Switch to brief listing details Print This Page 
 Address City Date/Time Send Save Map 
19 DIANE DRIVE
   8a-2p 7/14 Send Save   W.Trenton 19 Diane Dr Sat 8a-2p. Textile sample Sale. tbl clothes, runners doylies, decor pillows More Info Published in The Times of Trenton 7/12. Updated 7/12.   
6 BOXWOOD COURT
 Add to Driving Tour   SATURDAY JULY 14 8-2 Send Save Map EWING 6 Boxwood Court Sat 7/14 8-2 Multi family. Tools, bikes, golf clubs, sports, CDs, DVDs, video games,clothes, etc More Info Published in The Times of Trenton 7/12. Updated 7/12.   
42 Maple Ave
 Add to Driving Tour     Send Save Map Caldwalder Park 6 Unit.42 Maple ave.RR 43k. new ktchns, boiler. owned for 10 yrs. Drvwy, grge. $258k 732-779 0256. More Info Published in The Times of Trenton 7/10. Updated 7/12.   
365 Oakland Street
 Add to Driving Tour   9a-2p 7/7 Send Save Map Trenton -SIDEWALK SALE 365 Oakland St Near Parkside Ave. Sat 7/7 9am-2pm. More Info Published in The Times of Trenton 7/5. Updated 7/7.   
4 Tall Tree Ct.
 Add to Driving Tour   7/7 8-1 Send Save Map Ewing - 4 Tall Tree Ct. Sat. 7/7, 8-1. baby clothes&amp;shoes, children&apos;s clothes, Adult clothes, HH items. More Info Published in The Times of Trenton 7/5. Updated 7/7.   
169 Dutch Neck Rd.
 Add to Driving Tour   9-3 7/6-7/7 Send Save Map East Windsor , 169 Dutch Neck Rd, 7/6&amp;7/7, 9-3. So many household items&amp;K-5 books for teachers. More Info Published in The Times of Trenton 7/5. Updated 7/7.   
130 Andrew St.
 Add to Driving Tour   9 Send Save Map Hamilton - 130 Andrew St. Fri&amp;Sat, 7/6-7/7, 9:30a-4p. Estate Sale. All wood furniture, antiques, vintage collectibles, lots of tools, HH&amp;Kit. items, rummage boxes, more! EliteAuctionsNJ.com 732-751-1112 More Info Published in The Times of Trenton 7/5. Updated 7/7.   
3 Kerr Dr
 Add to Driving Tour   8a-1p 7/7 Send Save Map Hamilton- Indoor Estate Sale 3 Kerr Dr. Sat 7/7 8am-1p. BR, LR, Fm rm, Kit&amp;DR furn, 62 years of other stuff! More Info Published in The Times of Trenton 7/5. Updated 7/7.   
930 Rt 537
 Add to Driving Tour   6pm 7/10 Send Save Map AUCTION 930 Rt 537 Cream Ridge, NJ July 10th Tuesday @ 6pm 100&apos;s of items, gen&apos;l merch, dealers welcome, to benefit The Christian Fellowship Church of New Egypt More Info Published in The Times of Trenton 7/7. Updated 7/9.   
29 Erica Drive
 Add to Driving Tour   8am-2pm 7/7 Send Save Map Langhorne PA 29 Erica Drive Sat 7/7 8am-2pm 12pc DR, 65pc SS Flatware, 12pc crystal stemware sets: 14pc outdoor furn, 5pc LR set, 8&amp;10 person Poker tables&amp;custom poker chip w/case; portable camping grilling sets; toys: collectables; luggage, DVD&apos;s, area rugs&amp;More! 267-227-2234 More Info Published in The Times of Trenton 7/7. Updated 7/7.   
 174 listings match, 11-20 shown &lt;Previous  Page 1 2 3 4 5 6 ... 18    Next&gt; 
 
 
Learn how to protect yourself from Internet scams. Read our online fraud prevention tips 
 • Place Your Ad Now 
 • Search Classifieds 
 • 
 New Jersey Free Classified Ads 
 Find A Local Business 
 Local Business Listings in New Jersey 
 Send this listing to a friend Recipient&apos;s E-mail Address: Please enter a valid e-mail address 
 Your Name: Please enter your name Your E-mail Address: Please enter a valid e-mail address 
 Message: (optional) CC Yourself:   Yes No 
 Please enter the code in the box below: 
 
Can&apos;t read the code? Get Another .
 There was an error. Please try entering the code again. 
 
NJ.com is not responsible for the privacy practices of the person or company you are contacting with this form. Please review our Privacy Policy .
 
 
Thanks!

Your message has been sent.
 
 
 Best Local Classifieds: Place An Ad | Manage Your Ad | Fraud Prevention Tips | Start New Search | Site Map 
 Site Search Search Local Business Listings 
 Site Map | Advertise | Contact Make us your home page Home | News | Weather | Sports | Entertainment | Living | Interact | Jobs | Autos | Real Estate | Rentals | Classified Ads | Shopping | Place an Ad 
 Your Photos Your Videos Blogs Forums NJ Shore NJ Weddings 
 
 Post a Job Post a Free Classified Ad Sell Your Car Sell/Rent Your Home Apartments&amp;Rentals Claim Your Business
   Listing for Free 
 
 Business High School Sports NJ Lottery NJ Politics Obituaries Pets 
 
 Subscribe to our content (RSS) Sign up for news alerts NJ.com Twitter feed Ledger Live vodcast NJ.com mobile site View mobile product offerings 
 Special home delivery offers! The Star-Ledger | The Times, Trenton | The Jersey Journal | Gloucester Co. Times 
 The News of Cumberland County | Today&apos;s Sunbeam Registration on or use of this site constitutes acceptance of our User Agreement and Privacy Policy (Revised November 1, 2011)

©2012 New Jersey On-Line LLC. All rights reserved ( About Us ).
The material on this site may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, cached or otherwise used, except with the prior written permission of New Jersey On-Line LLC.

 Community Rules apply to all content you upload or otherwise submit to this site. Contact interactivity management .

 Ad Choices
	</body>
</document>
