<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009547" url="http://www.olx.ca/restaurant-jobs-food-service-jobs-cat-385" time="2012-07-13-02:56" support="2" score="0.0030060547008076994" bingtitle="Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs Canada" webtitle="Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs Canada">
			<query id="000288" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000312" bing-rank="241"/>
	<description>Enter a City ... Full time short order cook in fast food restaurant. Must be willing to work weekends ...</description>
	<body>
		Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada 
 
 Search 
 Post a Free Ad  | English 
 Français 
 
Category: Home &gt; Jobs &gt; Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs 
 
Selected Location
 
 Canada 
 
Refine your search

 Enter a City Accept 
 
 Category: 
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs   unselect 
 Ads: 
 With Photos 
 Type: 
 All Offering Wanted 
 Position Type: 
 All Full-time Part-time 
 Location: 
 Calgary Edmonton Toronto Montreal Vancouver Kamloops Mississauga Brampton Kelowna Ottawa Burlington Lethbridge Chilliwack Saskatoon Cambridge London Red Deer Winnipeg Cold Lake Hamilton Merritt Niagara Falls Prince George St. Albert Burnaby Cornwall Victoria Courtenay Grande Prairie 
 
 Results for Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs in Canada 1 - 50 of 709 List | Picture Gallery How do I feature my ad? How do I buy a sponsored link? 

 
 Cook ( Mexican Food ) ( NOC: 6242 ) 
 
Rinconcito Salvadoreno Restaurante located at 2062 Commercial Drive, Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada is looking to hire a Cook ( Mexican Food ) ( NOC: 6242 ...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Vancouver 
July 10   
 Experienced Line Cook 
 
Culinaria Restaurant is looking for an experienced line cook to join our team. We are looking for a passionate, dedicated cook with at least 4 years experience ...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
July 8   
 FOOD SERVICE SUPERVISOR 
 
Title: Food service supervisor ( NOC: 6212 ) Terms of Employment: Permanent, Full Time, Shift, Weekend, Day, Night, Evening Salary: $13.50 Hourly, for 40.00 Hou...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Calgary 
July 7   
 Food photographers required! Get paid for food photos 
 
O&apos;Munch is an exciting new Vancouver based startup company that is looking for candidates to help us discover new dishes from great restaurants. Your role is to...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Vancouver 
July 4   
 Cook (Full time / Permanent) 
 
Employer: POPS PUB&amp;GRILL LTD Location: 1475 St. Edward Boulevard North, Lethbridge, Alberta T1H 2P9 Anticipated Start Date: As soon as possible Job Duties -Pr...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lethbridge 
July 3   
 Sushi Cook 
 
St.Vital Sobeys Sushi Shop in Winnipeg, MB Seeks a Sushi Cook. Completion of Secondary school. 3 yrs or more experience in japanese cooking required. Duties: 1....
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Winnipeg 
July 3   
 Catering Truck operator/driver 
 
Position Information: Serving schedule route 8:00-3:00 Catering truck operator/driver position requires to service our customers on schedule basis with food, sn...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Toronto 
July 3   
 Inside Sales / Customer Service Representative, STEEL-CRAFT DOOR PRODUCTS LTD. 
 
A private, family owned business that manufactures overhead residential&amp;commercial doors, Steel-Craft has been in business for nearly 50 years and has almost ...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
July 3   
 Industrial Mechanic 
 
2012-06-31-1671 - Grasslands Recruitment Specialists has represented a successful client-base with career opportunities for Executives, Professionals, and Skill...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
July 3   
 Quality Manager/ Customer Liaison - Oshawa 
 
Stratosphere Quality Quality Manager/ Customer Liaison - Oshawa Qualifications: Must have direct experience supporting Automotive, Quality and Tier 1 Activities...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
July 2   
 Senior Office Manager - Construction 
 
2012-06-31-1693 - Opportunity: Our client presents an opportunity for an experienced administrative professional with sound operational management skills to adv...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
July 2   
 Automotive Tire Technician - Fountain Tire (Whyte Ave) 
 
Fountain Tire Automotive Tire Technician - Fountain Tire (Whyte Ave) Career wheels spinning but getting nowhere? Put yourself in the drivers seat and get some t...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
July 2   
 Automotive Tire Technician - Fountain Tire (Calgary) 
 
Fountain Tire Automotive Tire Technician - Fountain Tire (Calgary) Career wheels spinning but getting nowhere? Put yourself in the drivers seat and get some tra...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
July 2   
 Tax Manager- Human Capital 
 
TorontoJobs.ca Tax Manager- Human Capital Our client, C.A Firm, in Kitchener is currently looking for candidates for a Tax Manager- Human Capital position. The ...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
July 2   
 Mortgage Underwriter&amp;Sales Support 
 
2012-06-31-1658 - A growing mortgage brokerage will be hiring a Licensed Mortgage Agent for a full time, in-house Underwriting/Sales Assistant.The position is a...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
July 2   
 Owner Operator 
 
2012-06-31-1572 - We are hiring! - Owner Operator Trimac understands that you&apos;re looking for independence and flexibility on the road.. We offer Owner Operators...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
July 2   
 Service Manager 
 
Assist in ownership of client issues that are out of scope with existing Terremark process and work with internal business owners to develop processes to meet t...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
July 2   
 Senior Accountant 
 
Modern Technical Staffing Senior Accountant Senior Accountant Our Client, an alternative dispute resolution firm that specializes in providing conflict resoluti...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
July 2   
 experienced Painter foreman 
 
Experienced painters wanted, must be a self starter. Have own tools and transport. A good sprayer and work well with others. Quality work and royalty are promot...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Burnaby 
June 28   
 Project Manager - Pega, RANDSTAD TECHNOLOGIES 
 
Specializing in delivering tailored IT recruitment solutions to specific business areas, Randstad Technologies provides short-term contractors with specific ski...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
June 26   
 Travel Consultant - Thomas Cook Kelowna 
 
Thomas Cook Canada Travel Consultant - Thomas Cook Kelowna Thomas Cook has an immediate part time opening for an Experienced Travel Consultant at our Kelowna Lo...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
June 25   
 Thomas Cook in Victoria is Hiring a Travel Consultant 
 
Thomas Cook Canada Thomas Cook in Victoria is Hiring a Travel Consultant Thomas Cook has an immediate full time opening for an Experienced Travel Consultant at ...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
June 25   
 Customer Service Representative 
 
The Lady Bug Studio Customer Service Representative The Customer Service Representative is responsible to input and edit orders accurately, provide product info...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
June 25   
 Manager, Legal Assistants 
 
RSG Recruiting Manager, Legal Assistants Manager, Legal Assistants Description We have an opportunity for a full-time Manager of Legal Assistants. The ideal can...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
June 25   
 Account Manager, VERBATIM AMERICAS, LLC 
 
Verbatim America seeks an experienced Key Account Manager ( Canada ) to develop new prospects and interact with existing customers to increase Data Storage Prod...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
June 25   
 Service Technician 
 
People Placement Group Ltd. Service Technician This outstanding opportunity will be responsible for installing, repairing, maintaining and trouble shooting of C...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
June 24   
 jobs 
 
I like jobs to canada jobs I am indian
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Chilliwack 
June 20   
 Cook 
 
Company: #819740 Alberta Ltd. / The Keg Steakhouse and Bar Location: 6365- 50th Ave. Red Deer, Alberta T4N 4C7 Type of Employment: Full time – Permanent Anticip...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Red Deer 
June 19   
 Restaurant Manager 
 
Full time positionCompetitive Salary to be negotiatedFull benefits packageGood bonus potentialRRSPLocation: Winnipeg, MB (Positions also available in Portage La...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
June 16   
 Restaurant Manager 
 
Restaurant Manager BENEFITS: Full time position Competitive Salary to be negotiated Full benefits package Good bonus potential RRSP Location: Winnipeg, MB (Posi...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Winnipeg 
June 15   
 Pasta Chef (St. Clair/Yonge) 
 
Busy fine restaurant looking for a pasta chef. The right candidate will be able to work fast, be efficient, CLEAN, and reliable. Must have the ability to make i...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
June 13   
 cruiseship, crew, wanted 
 
QUEENS CRUISE 101 Holloway Rd , London , WC1D 3QB We want to use this medium to inform you that vacancies are now on for the under-listed job. Do let us know if...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - London - job 
June 11   
 FOOD SERVICE SUPERVISOR 
 
:1135405 Alberta Ltd. o/a Subway in Cochrane Alberta has an opening for 3 Full Time Food Service Supervisor. ASAP. Applicant must be flexible and willing to wor...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Calgary - land for sale in alberta 
June 8   
 FOOD SERVICE SUPERVISOR 
 
1135405 ALABERTA LTD. o/a Subway located in Cochrane Alberta has an opening for 3 full time Food Service Supervisor. Willing to work shift work and must be flex...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Calgary - resume for a labourer 
June 8   
 Restaurant manager (Full time - Permanent) 
 
Company: Pop&apos;s Pub South Ltd. Location: 1516 9 Avenue South Lethbridge, Alberta T1J 1V8 Type of Employment: Full time – Permanent Anticipated Start Date: As soo...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lethbridge - jobs in food services 
June 5   
 FOOD COUNTER ATTENDANT (PIZZA MAKER) 
 
FOOD COUNTER ATTENDANT (PIZZA MAKER) LOOKING FOR A JOB? If you are flexible and energetic, CANADIAN PIZZA MASTER FANCHISE CORPORATION is looking for competent a...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Calgary 
June 5   
 Prep Cooks 
 
NOW HIRING full time and part time: servers, bartenders, bussers, host/esses, line cooks (wok experience preferred but not mandatory), pantry cooks, prep cooks,...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
June 5   
 Cooks 
 
NOW HIRING full time and part time: servers, bartenders, bussers, host/esses, line cooks (wok experience preferred but not mandatory), pantry cooks, prep cooks,...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
June 4   
 FOOD COUNTER ATTENDANT 
 
1135405 Alberta Ltd. o/a Subway located at Cochrane Alberta is hiring 8 Full Time Food Counter. attendants ASAP. Salary $11.40 /hr. 40 hrs./wk/ This position is...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Calgary - duties of counter attendant 
June 4   
 Cook 
 
Company: Mojos Pub&amp;Grill Ltd. Location: 32-550 University Drive West, Lethbridge , Alberta T1J 4T3 Type of Employment: Full time – Permanent Estimated Start D...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lethbridge - cooking alberta jobs 
June 4   
 Hotel Cook 
 
New boutique hotel in the heart of the downtown core seeks energetic, talented cooks. Candidates must be professional, well spoken and willing to work in an ope...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Toronto 
June 4   
 EXPERIENCED BARTENDER AND COOK WANTED 
 
Hiring full-time experienced bartender (female preferred) with basic salary plus bonus from the break even above level by percentage; Also hiring cook join with...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Calgary 
May 31   
 Cook 
 
Company: Pop&apos;s Pub West Location: 132 Columbia Boulevard West, Lethbridge, Alberta T1K 4J4 Type of Employment: Full time – Permanent Estimated Start Date: As so...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lethbridge - FOOD 
May 28   
 Restaurant Manager for Hamilton branch 
 
Position Restaurant Manager for Hamilton branchWe are looking for Excellent customer service Diploma or Degree in related services (preferred) Experience in the...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
May 25   
 ola busco trabajo en canada de lo que sea 
 
ola me llamo antonio ablo muy poco ingles pero puedo aprender busco alguen que me pueda contratar para trabajar en canada de lo que sea tengo experiencia de cho...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Nelson 
May 21   
 Saturday - Sunday Server 
 
The View at Lethbridge Are YOU: Able to work BOTH Saturday AND Sunday? Dependable? Looking for fulfilling employment that will look GREAT on a resume? Comfortab...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lethbridge 
May 20   
 MANOS GRILL&amp;BREWHOUSE RESTAURANT MANAGER 
 
If you have passion for excellence, exuberant energy, and ambition for a rewarding career...We are looking for a restaurant manager to join our team! Responsibi...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Saskatoon 
May 19   
 General Manager 
 
Our client is a casual concept in Ontario, growing at a high rate with an average of 5 locations/year and looking for top shelf General Managers in London, Onta...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
May 18   
 cleaning staff or cooking staff 
 
Hi all!My name is Deepti, and i am looking for a part time job on Fridays and weekends in a restaurant or factory or in any bakery!At present, i am doing Comput...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
May 18   
 Chef/Kitchen Manager-x2 
 
Our client is a premium casual dining industry leader in Ontario and looking for top shelf senior assistant managers to go through the GM/Chef training program....
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Canada
May 18   

 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Next 
 Create Alert. Get emails for Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs in Canada 
 
 Can&apos;t find what you are looking for? Ask for it! 
 
Popular Searches: Culinary arts jobs 

Popular Searches
 
 Sous chef 

 Restaurant work 
 
Location: Canada 

 Free classifieds in Canada &gt; Jobs in Canada 

 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs in Canada 
 close 
Useful Information

 Help About OLX Terms Of Use Contact OLX 
 
OLX Features

 Sponsored Links Featured Ads How to Partner with OLX Tools&amp;Widgets Post a Free Classified Ad 
 
OLX Close to you

 Browse Cities Sitemap 
 
Stay Connected

 OLX Mobile Facebook Twitter 
 Canada Free classifieds  -  Copyright © 2006-2012 OLX, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
