<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009628" url="http://www.tripadvisor.com/ShowUserReviews-g34227-d851682-r120405425-Fort_Lauderdale-Fort_Lauderdale_Florida.html" time="2012-07-13-03:02" support="18" score="0.02185687942165858" bingtitle="Sixt Car Rental Fort Lauderdale - Review of Fort Lauderdale, Fort ..." webtitle="Sixt Car Rental Fort Lauderdale - Review of Fort Lauderdale, Fort Lauderdale, FL - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="001400" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000458" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="000708" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000677" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000240" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="001399" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="000866" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000709" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="001525" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000364" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000457" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000051" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="001395" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="001054" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000718" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="001409" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="001117" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="001022" bing-rank="33"/>
	<description>Couldn&apos;t type my email in the box - sent email to customer service complaining I need my receipt - no tolls posted yet. - still waiting. Oh, and don&apos;t try to ...</description>
	<body>
		Fort Lauderdale reviews
 
 Home Fort Lauderdale 
 Fort Lauderdale Tourism Fort Lauderdale Hotels Fort Lauderdale Vacation Rentals Flights to Fort Lauderdale Fort Lauderdale Restaurants Things to Do in Fort Lauderdale Fort Lauderdale Travel Forum Fort Lauderdale Photos Fort Lauderdale Travel Guide 
 Hotels Flights Vacation Rentals Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
 Home 
 &gt; United States &gt; Florida (FL) &gt; Fort Lauderdale &gt; Fort Lauderdale Restaurants &gt; Fort Lauderdale 
 
 Back to Fort Lauderdale 
Fort Lauderdale: Restaurant Reviews
 3200 North Federal Highway , Fort Lauderdale , FL 33306 (954) 390-7992 Website Got a photo? 
 Add it. Ranked #333 of 689 restaurants in Fort Lauderdale 11 Reviews Cuisines: Fast Food Restaurant details Update restaurant details Write a Review 
11 reviews from our community
 54% Recommend 
 Excellent 5 Very good 1 Average 1 Poor 1 Terrible 3 
 Rating summary 
 Food Service Value Atmosphere 
 11 reviews sorted by Date Rating Donna247 Chicago Reviewer 3 reviews Reviews in 3 cities 10 helpful votes “Sixt Car Rental Fort Lauderdale” Reviewed November 10, 2011 8 people found this review helpful 
I rented a car from Sixt Nov 2011. The shuttle was fine - well marked and I didn&apos;t wait too long for the shuttle. Received a brand new Toyota Camry - great rate. Only problem was..I was asked have you heard of the SunPass? Sure it&apos;s been around for 20 years. Do you want to prepay the SunPass? No thanks. Well I wasn&apos;t told - since Feb 2011 you can no longer pay cash for the tolls down to the Keys. When I get back I&apos;m told I need to pay $5.00 Service fee from Sixt per toll plus $1.00 for the toll. That&apos;s $48.00 or I could have prepaid the tolls for $7.00 per day - If your gone a week that&apos;s $49.00. Good thing my rental was cheap to make up for these extra costs. Use to pay the toll person $1.00 per toll sure didn&apos;t expect this plus the counter person didn&apos;t explain this at all. I was told I would have a receipt on line in 24 hours - it&apos;s been 48hrs went on line to print out receipt. Couldn&apos;t type my email in the box - sent email to customer service complaining I need my receipt - no tolls posted yet. - still waiting. Oh, and don&apos;t try to call the counter they won&apos;t pick up the phone.
 Visited November 2011 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Ask Donna247 about Fort Lauderdale This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. 22faith Chillicothe, Ohio Reviewer 5 reviews Reviews in 2 cities 1 helpful vote “Great Place” Reviewed August 28, 2011 
Food was great as well as the service. I like dining where others around me are having a good time. This restaurant has it all.
 Visited May 2011 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Ask 22faith about Fort Lauderdale This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. jvdr Fort Lauderdale, Florida 1 review “GREAT FOOD&amp;SERVICE, FUN STAFF” Reviewed November 18, 2010 
We were seated at Table #12 next to the aviary-wonderful!! What a nice touch!
Tom and Marin gave us excellent service and spent time with us explaining more about the cuisine and the birds.

We had outstanding lobster bisque with yummy complimentary potato pancakes w/ sour cream and applesauce.

We ordered Jagerschnitzle - superb and
Veal goulash - also spuerb. The sides of spinach and red cabbage tasty.
Big portions , no room for what sounded like great desserts (apple strudle etc)
All in all a nice experience.

Maybe a new owner? Definitely will return
Janet, Marie (+ Jim&amp;Jerry)
 
 
 Value Atmosphere 

 Service Food 
 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Ask jvdr about Fort Lauderdale This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. Dordie Barbourville Contributor 14 reviews Reviews in 8 cities 4 helpful votes “Casablanca” Reviewed July 1, 2009 1 person found this review helpful 
Dined on balcony late June 2009. Ocean view lovely except for cars on busy street below. Restaurant has great atmosphere-very romantic. Our party ordered three different fish dishes. All were excellent. A bit pricey. Worth it.
Desserts only average- skip them. Service was confusing due to a mixup. Got meal before drinks and bread???? Parking tickets (25.00) issued on street ALL night long. Be careful!
 
 
 Value Atmosphere 

 Service Food 
 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Ask Dordie about Fort Lauderdale This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. Love2travel18 Cleveland Senior Reviewer 8 reviews Reviews in 8 cities 27 helpful votes “Tourist Trap Restaurant” Reviewed April 10, 2009 1 person found this review helpful 
Waited 30 minutes outside then sat in dining room for 50 more minutes without being served any food. The server comment that they had a full restaurant as we watched the entire room arrive and get fed before we were served anything. Their service attitude is poor. The smug response from our server basically told us that they didn&apos;t care. More unsuspecting tourists will arrive to fill our shoes. The manager tried to smooth things over with us but by that time we needed to leave the restaurant to get to our parking meters. We just wanted to get away from that place. Save your money.
 
 
 Value Atmosphere 

 Service Food 
 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Ask Love2travel18 about Fort Lauderdale This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. 5-9 of 11 reviews « 1 2 3 » 
Travelers who viewed Fort Lauderdale also viewed
	</body>
</document>
