<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009793" url="http://m3rni3.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-13-03:11" support="1" score="0.0005199785404356639" bingtitle="M3rNi3" webtitle="M3rNi3">
			<query id="000523" bing-rank="220"/>
	<description>Thank god, there are only two papers to clear this ... Cool on a wire tray. Cut into squares and serve. ... Komala&apos;s Fast Food Restaurant; unkl347 ► November (4)</description>
	<body>
		Monday, May 28, 2012 
 
 Pandan Muffins 
 
If you have not already known, I love muffins. I love baking them too. They are really quick to make. Two bowls are what you need - one for wet and and one for dry ingredients. Mix them together, spoon them in muffin liners or tin and you&apos;re good to send them into the oven.

Do you love the aroma of pandan leaves? I love walking at the garden near my office because I enjoy getting hit with the wafting aroma of pandan leaves. Pandan leaves are hugely used in Southeast Asia cuisine as a flavouring. And that&apos;s what i used this time to make my Pandan Muffins . For this recipe I did not blend the real pandan leaves to get the extract but instead I used the store bought pandan paste.

 
 Ingredients 

2 1/2 cups self raising flour
1/2 cup caster sugar
a pinch of salt
200gm coconut milk
1/2 cup canola oil
2 eggs, lightly beaten
3 tbsp pandan paste

 Method 

Preheat oven to 175C.
Lay 12 paper liners in muffin tin.
A - In a large bowl, mix together, flour, sugar and salt.
B - In another bowl, combine coconut milk, oil, eggs and pandan paste.
Incorporate B into A and using a spatula, fold in the flour till just moistened.
Spoon mixture into the muffin tins and then bake for about 25 - 30 mins or until a pick/skewer inserted comes out clean.
Stand muffins for about 5 mins before turning out to cool on a wire tray.

Note - You may if you wish to blend 5 - 7 pandan leaves together with the coconut milk to get that fresh green pandan extract. Be sure to strain the mixture before using it. Posted by m3rni3 at 10:00 AM Links to this post Labels: Breads No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Wednesday, May 23, 2012 
 
 Kiwi Muffins 
 I have some kiwi fruit sitting in my fridge for almost a week! Gotta consume them before it gets too soft and squashy. Kiwi fruit is highly nutritious and a good source of vitamin C, potassium and fibre. Kiwi (if you have yet to try) are both tangy and sweet. Oh, did you know that kiwi fruit skin is edible? Ermm, but with the hairy outer skin, I don&apos;t think I&apos;d dare try!

So back to the kiwi in the fridge, I still have a few more after consuming a couple and thought why not use them to make some muffins.  Using the Buttermilk Blueberry with White Chocolate Muffins as the base recipe, I substituted the blueberry for kiwi fruit, omitted the chocolate and made Kiwi Muffins . These muffins were moist with a slight tangy taste.

 
 Ingredients 

2 cups self raising flour
1/2 cup caster sugar
a pinch of salt
2 kiwi, chopped
1 cup buttermilk
1/4 cup canola oil
1 egg, lightly beaten

 Method 

Preheat oven to 175C.
Lay 12 paper liners in muffin tin.
A - In a large bowl, mix together, flour, salt, sugar and kiwi.
B - In another bowl, combine buttermilk, oil and egg.
Incorporate B into A and using a spatula, fold in the flour till just moistened.
Spoon mixture into the muffin tins and then bake for about 25 - 30 mins or until a pick/skewer inserted comes out clean.
Stand muffins for about 5 mins before turning out to cool on a wire tray. Posted by m3rni3 at 10:00 AM Links to this post Labels: Breads No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Tuesday, February 21, 2012 
 
 Cranberry Upside Down Muffins 
 I wanted to make Pandan Marble Cake so bad. Nevermind that my hand mixer is with mum. I&apos;ll make do with a wooden spoon or hand whisk, or so I thought. But with just two eggs left in the fridge, I had to forget about making pandan marble cake. I checked my pantry and there&apos;s just slightly less than half a cup of sugar left. What else can I make? Then I saw a can of cranberry sauce that I had bought a couple of months back. I remembered some time ago, I had wanted to try  this recipe from Joyofbaking.com. I checked the recipe again and was elated that I have all the ingredients required. An egg was all that the recipe called for and nevermind that I only have slightly less than half a cup of sugar left in my kitchen. I was sure the cranberry sauce would make up for the lack of sugar.

So I made this Cranberry Upside Down Muffins  and was glad it turned out just fine. Just a note of caution, do be patient when handling these babies. They need to cool for a while before you invert them out else the cranberry will not stick to the cake. I am speaking from experience! I took the pan out of the oven and started inverting one and was disappointed when the sauce did not stick to the cake. It left me wondering for a moment where had I gone wrong.

Feeling a little disappointed, I left the muffins alone and attended to my little girl who was busy with her schoolwork, then returned to the muffins once I was done with her. I inverted each one, and to my delight, the sauce sits nicely on top of the fluffy cake. So the moral of the story - Be patient and let the cakes cool before inverting them :)

 
 Ingredients 

2 cups self raising flour
1/2 cup caster sugar
1/2 tsp salt
1 cup milk
4 tbsp canola oil
1 egg, lightly beaten
1 tsp vanilla extract
3/4 cup cranberry sauce

 Method 

Preheat oven to 175C.
A - In a large bowl, whisk together, flour, sugar and salt
B - In another bowl, whisk together milk, egg, oil and vanilla extract.
Using a spatula, fold B into A together till just moistened.
Evenly divide the cranberry sauce among the 24 mini muffin cups of a mini muffin pan.
Evenly spoon muffin batter over the cranberry sauce.
Place the mini muffin pan in the oven.
Bake for about 15 - 20 mins or until a pick/skewer inserted comes out clean.
Stand muffins for about 5 mins before inverting them on a cooling rack so the cranberry topping is faced up. Posted by m3rni3 at 12:30 PM Links to this post Labels: Breads , Cakes , Desserts No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Monday, February 13, 2012 
 
 Rainbow Cupcakes 
 I have seen way too many people putting up pictures of rainbow cakes that they make or sell online. The cakes look so pretty and how not to love the bold colours!

 
One of those nights when I couldn&apos;t sleep, I actually watched videos after videos on how to make this cake. It looks rather tedious to make but somehow I kept hearing these Rainbow Cupcakes calling out my name. I had to do it! I just had to do it!

 
 While bold colours make the cakes look fun and vibrant, pastel makes the cupcakes look cute and pretty! Now, won&apos;t you agree? 
 
 Ingredients 
1 box White cake mix
1 1/4 cup water
3 egg whites
1/3 cup vegetable oil
liquid food colorings

 Method 

Preheat oven to 175C.
Lay 12 paper liners in muffin tin.
In a large bowl, whisk together cake mix, egg whites and vegetable oil till well combined (or as directed on box).
Divide batter into 6 small bowls.
Add about a drop or two food coloring to each bowl to make red, green, purple, pink, yellow and blue. Ensure that you stir well.
Starting with the red batter, add a level tablespoon to each of the 12 paper liners.
Repeat with all the remaining colours - green, purple, pink, yellow and blue.
Do not spread the layers of colour as it will cause the colours to combine.
Just let it spread out on their own.
Bake the cake for about 20 minutes or until a toothpick inserted comes out clean.
Cool cupcakes on a wire rack. Posted by m3rni3 at 5:30 AM Links to this post Labels: Cakes , Desserts No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Thursday, February 09, 2012 
 
 Video: Tiramisu 
 
 Watch my video for pictorial instructions to make Tiramisu! 
 
 Posted by m3rni3 at 9:00 AM Links to this post Labels: Desserts No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Monday, February 06, 2012 
 
 Carrot Muffins 
 A few weeks ago, I had late night coffee with my sister and her friends at The House of Robert Timms. We ordered a few desserts to go along with our coffee and one of them was Carrot Cake.

 
A four-layer cake with thick cream cheese icing in between. The carrot cake was heavenly and sinful. Besides the specks of carrot and walnuts, I spotted bits of pineapples in the cake!

I knew I had to bake some myself after having the carrot cake at the House of Robert Timms. I think by now, you ought to know my love for easy-no-mixer-required recipes. I was glad I found this recipe from Joyofbaking.com.   The recipe calls for grated apple and coconut which I omitted. Instead, I added crushed pineapples. Carrots and crushed pineapples helped in keeping the muffins moist.

These Carrot Muffins tasted so good on its own. It would be perfect when topped with some cream cheese frosting! Next time I make these, I will definitely smear some cream cheese frosting. But first, let me find a good and simple cream cheese frosting recipe.

 
 Ingredients 

1/2 cup walnut, roasted and chopped
2 cups grated raw carrots
2 cups self raising flour
1 cup caster sugar
1/2 tsp salt
1 1/2 tsp cinnamon powder
3/4 cup canola oil
3 eggs
3/4 cup crushed pineapples
1 tsp vanilla extract

 Method 

Preheat oven to 175C.
Lay 15 paper cups in a baking tray.
A - In a large bowl, whisk together, flour, sugar, salt, cinnamon powder and walnut.
B - In another bowl, whisk together oil, eggs, crushed pineapples and vanilla extract.
Using a spatula, fold B into A together with grated raw carrots till just moistened.
Spoon mixture into the paper cups and then bake for about 25 - 30 mins or until a pick/skewer inserted comes out clean.
Stand muffins for about 5 mins before turning out to cool on a wire tray. Posted by m3rni3 at 11:30 AM Links to this post Labels: Breads , Desserts 1 comment: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Thursday, February 02, 2012 
 
 Tiramisu 
 The last I made Tiramisu was in 2006 and had not tried making them ever since.
Remember my  first post of 2012  when I said I wanted to try making David Rocco&apos;s Tiramisu   and that I had bought the ingredients? It was over the Chinese New Year holidays last week, that I decided to make them. I really wanted to try David Rocco&apos;s recipe but the thought of using raw eggs sort of puts me off.

So I browsed my blog for the Easy Peasy Tiramisu recipe that I used in 2006 and made slight adjustments to it. These are the ingredients that you need.

 
I was happy with the results of the  Tiramisu that I made with the adjustments! Note that you definitely need to chill the dessert for at least 4 hours or overnight. I couldn&apos;t wait and took it out after 2 hours and the slice (pictured below) looks rather sloppy but still tasted good. I had another slice the next day and boy did the tiramisu come together in perfect harmony. The flavours just meld together and the texture was oh so right!
 
 
 Here&apos;s the new adjusted recipe for my  Tiramisu  - the twisted version minus the eggs and a virgin one because it does not contain alcohol.

 Ingredients 

18 - 20 pcs savoiardi (ladyfingers)
2 tbsp nescafe coffee powder
1 cup boiling water
2 tbsp sugar
250g mascarpone cheese
170g cream
3 tbsp thickened cream
1/4 cup caster sugar
cocoa powder

 Method 

Dissolve coffee powder and 2 tbsp sugar in boiling water.
Let it cool to room temperature.
Meanwhile beat cream and sugar till soft peaks form with a hand whisk.
Then add in the mascarpone cheese and beat for a further half a minute.
Lightly dip ladyfingers in cooled coffee and lay them on a dish.
Spread evenly half of the mascarpone cream mixture over the ladyfingers.
Repeat the step with a second layer of ladyfingers and then the rest of the cream mixture
Cover dish with foil and refrigerate for about 4 hours or overnight.
Dust tiramisu with cocoa powder when set.
Cut and serve cold. Posted by m3rni3 at 9:00 AM Links to this post Labels: Desserts 1 comment: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Monday, January 30, 2012 
 
 Beef and Broccoli Stir Fry 
 Have you ever found yourself strapped for time and need to prepare dinner in a hurry? 
I made this Beef and Broccoli Stir Fry a few nights ago and I thought this is perfect for those nights when you need to feed yourself or even your family in a jiffy.
This recipe is great because you have both your meat and vegetable proteins in one dish.
You may of course add red capsicums for added colour and nutrients and thicken the sauce with cornstarch, but I didn&apos;t.
 
 
 Serve it with plain steamed rice. 
 
 
 Ingredients 
 250gm store bought pre-cut stir fry beef 2 tbsp soy sauce, divided 2 tbsp fish sauce, divided 2 tbsp worcestershire sauce, divided 2 tbsp oyster sauce, divided 4 cups fresh broccoli florets 1 big onion, sliced 2 pips garlic, finely chopped 1 cm ginger, finely sliced oil  water 
 Method 
 Marinate beef with a tablespoon each of soy , fish, worcestershire and oyster sauce. Heat some oil in a wok and over medium heat, stir fry beef till it is cooked and no longer pink. Remove and keep warm. Heat some oil again and saute the onion, garlic and ginger. Add in the broccoli and stir fry briefly. Then add some water and the remaining sauces to the broccoli and cook till broccoli is tender but crisp. Lastly add the beef to the broccoli, remove from heat and serve with warm steamed rice. 

 
 Posted by m3rni3 at 9:00 AM Links to this post Labels: Main Course No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Older Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 
 
About Me
 m3rni3 m3rni3[at]hotmail[dot]com View my complete profile 
Total Pageviews
 
My Picture Blog
 
 http://m3rni3.posterous.com/ 
 
Blog Archive
 
 ▼  2012 (13) 
 ▼  May (2) 
 Pandan Muffins Kiwi Muffins 
 

 ►  February (5) 
 Cranberry Upside Down Muffins Rainbow Cupcakes Video: Tiramisu Carrot Muffins Tiramisu 
 

 ►  January (6) 
 Beef and Broccoli Stir Fry Macaroni Soup Ham and Cheese French Toast Buttermilk Blueberry with White Chocolate Muffins Sausage and Cheese Muffins Banana Nutella Croissant Pudding 
 
 

 ►  2011 (8) 
 ►  April (3) 
 Vegetable Shell Pasta in Tomato Cream Sauce Beef Pastrami and Brie Panini Corn Pudding 
 

 ►  March (1) 
 Kuih Bakar Pandan 
 

 ►  February (4) 
 Applesauce Squares Baked Corn Pudding 7-Layer Dip Cheese Platter 
 
 

 ►  2010 (11) 
 ►  October (3) 
 Instant Creme Caramel Minced Meat Baked Pasta Longan Grass Jelly 
 

 ►  September (1) 
 Lychee Konnyaku Jelly 
 

 ►  August (1) 
 Chicken Quesadilla 
 

 ►  May (1) 
 Sofra Turkish Cafe&amp;Restaurant 
 

 ►  April (5) 
 Chocolate Banana Cake J&apos;s Wok&amp;Grill Blic Ice Cream Cafe Zac&apos;s Middle Eastern and Mediterranean Cuisine M3rNi3 is Still Aliv3 
 
 

 ►  2008 (10) 
 ►  June (3) 
 Mr Prata ... yet again Spize @ Simpang Bedok Charco&apos;s @ Ang Mo Kio 
 

 ►  March (2) 
 BBM - Little Things Mr Prata @ 26, Evans Road 
 

 ►  February (3) 
 Breakfast @ Swensen&apos;s U.D.D.E.R.S Ice Cream Ya Kun Kaya Toast 
 

 ►  January (2) 
 Kids and the Kissy Kiss Robin&apos;s Portuguese Egg Tarts 
 
 

 ►  2007 (98) 
 ►  December (11) 
 One Chilly Afternoon Eatzi Steakhouse and Bistro Nando&apos;s Donut Factory Siam Kitchen Banquet @ Lion City Hotel Ramen Ten E-Donuts 
 

 ►  November (4) 

 ►  October (4) 

 ►  September (9) 

 ►  August (12) 

 ►  July (14) 

 ►  June (9) 

 ►  May (3) 

 ►  April (7) 

 ►  March (6) 

 ►  February (6) 

 ►  January (13) 
 

 ►  2006 (89) 
 ►  December (15) 

 ►  November (7) 

 ►  October (9) 

 ►  September (11) 

 ►  August (5) 

 ►  July (7) 

 ►  May (2) 

 ►  April (7) 

 ►  March (14) 

 ►  February (9) 

 ►  January (3) 
 
 
Labels
 
 Appetisers (6) Award (1) Blog Events (18) Breads (18) Breakfast (11) Cakes (32) Cookies (12) Desserts (28) Food Review (32) Ice Cream (5) Main Course (17) Music Video (1) Side Dishes (1) TV (1) 
 
FEEDJIT Live Traffic Feed
 Feedjit Live Blog Stats 
Shoutouts!
 
 
Food Blogs I Read
 
 80breakfasts bakingbites cupcake bakeshop dispensing happiness domesticgoddess hanieliza mamafami mamazieza mykitchen peabody rozzan tartelette 
 
Recipe Sites
 
 All Recipes Jamie Oliver Martha Stewart Nigella Lawson Williams-Sonoma 
 
Don&apos;t miss a new recipe! Subscribe to M3rNi3 via Email :)
 
 
 
 
Popular Posts
 
 Kuih Bakar Pandan Kuih Bakar Pandan is one of my favourite traditional Malay kuih. I love this sweet, soft and rich kuih which is laced with pandan flavour.... Black Pepper Seafood Pasta I was talking to a friend over the pasta I made the other day and he mentioned that I should try making black pepper pasta. Suddenly I star... Minced Meat Baked Pasta I love weekends because that&apos;s like the only time I can prepare food for the family. Today I decided to have pasta! I have already bought ... White Chocolate Biscuits My angel, Tihani has Phonics on Wednesdays. And since last week, Wednesday, she has been requesting me to whip her something. She requested... Rainbow Cupcakes I have seen way too many people putting up pictures of rainbow cakes that they make or sell online. The cakes look so pretty and how not to... 
 
Recent Posts
 
 Watermark template. Powered by Blogger .
	</body>
</document>
