<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009340" url="http://www.mytravelguide.com/hotels/reviews-14852901-Royal_Garden_at_Waikiki_reviews.html" time="2012-07-13-02:42" support="2" score="0.001833366760777251" bingtitle="User Reviews for Royal Garden At Waikiki, Oahu | MyTravelGuide.com" webtitle="User Reviews for Royal Garden At Waikiki, Oahu | MyTravelGuide.com">
			<query id="000519" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="001295" bing-rank="202"/>
	<description>Not clean. Messy, poor management, rayed was not ... tray was not the proper size for it so the tray ... The same quality could be found in a fast food restaurant for a ...</description>
	<body>
		Hotels Flights Rental Cars Vacation Packages Cruises Attractions Restaurants Travel Guides Last Minute Deals 
 
 
 Home &gt; Hotels &gt; United States &gt; Hawaii &gt; Oahu Hotels &gt; Honolulu &gt; Royal Garden At Waikiki &gt; User Reviews for Royal Garden At Waikiki Search MY Travel Guide: 
 
User Reviews for Royal Garden At Waikiki 

Research 71 user reviews for Royal Garden At Waikiki.

 «Go back to Royal Garden At Waikiki 
440 Olohana Street, 
 Honolulu, HI
 
Research User Reviews for Royal Garden At Waikiki (1-20 of 71) 
 
 Add Your Own Review» 
 
 Average User Rating: 5.5 
 
Cleanliness:[6.0] •Staff:[7.0] •Location:[6.5]
 Based on 122 user ratings 
 Add Your Own Rating
 
 
 Sort by: Most Recent • Positive • Negative • Most Helpful 
 May 2, 2010   by Jonathon from Frisco,TX
Overall Rating: 3 


 Great entry way and bell boy. Not clean. Messy, poor management, rayed was not right and just not up to standards. 

“Poor management. Short showers. Dirty rooms. Bad beds and not safe feeling. They spent all the
night on the entry way.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Mar 21, 2010   by Lloyd from Fargo,ND
Overall Rating: 3 


 Lobby was nice, room was large. Our room was worn out, ratty. 

“Lobby and common areas were nice but our room was pathetic, ratty, worn out. Maybe they gave us a bad room and some others are decent.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Sep 11, 2008   by Leerich from Las Vegas, NV
Overall Rating: 1 
 Cleanliness: [ 1 ]• Staff: [ 2 ]• Location: [ 1 ]

 Absolutely nothing! Everything! 

“If you don&apos;t mind staying at a hotel which charges you more for parking than the rental car company charges for daily fees, then stay here. If you don&apos;t mind waking up at 5:45 am, every morning to the sound of construction workers hammering steel and pouring concrete fifty feet away from your window, then stay here. If you don&apos;t want any privacy while using the toilet then stay here. If you don&apos;t mind paying $1.50 for every packet of coffee you use then stay here.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Sep 1, 2008   by Richard from Lafayette, IN
Overall Rating: 6 
 Cleanliness: [ 5 ]• Staff: [ 5 ]• Location: [ 7 ]

 No internet, not enough outlets in the room. 

“For the price, the Royal Garden hotel is a fair value in this part of Waikiki, however, the hotel shows it&apos;s age and greatly needs to be renovated. Don&apos;t stay here unless you would be satisfied with a 2.5 star (or less) quality level. This hotel is good for the budget traveler who only needs a place to stay that&apos;s conveniently located near downtown Waikiki.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Aug 29, 2008   by Victor F. from Silver Spring, MD
Overall Rating: 3 
 Cleanliness: [ 4 ]• Staff: [ 8 ]• Location: [ 3 ]

 Inexpensive. Old, dirty, and not a desirable location. 

“We have stayed in this hotel before (in 2005) with much disappointment. We were not impressed this time and saw very little improvement. We hope to never stay here again. The hotel is old and in much need of an overhaul. Our room on the 10th floor was facing the rear and constant construction noise from a building they are erecting immediately to the rear. That started daily at 7 Am M-F. The hotel was not busy at all. As a matter of fact you rarely crossed paths with anyone. My girlfriend and I asked ourselves why did not they put us in a room facing the front and away from the construction. To further complicate matters there was ongoing exterior construction on the hotel itself. You did not want to stay in the room because of constant noise from various types of heavy equipment. Our room was in poor condition. The carpet appeared to be very old and had warn patterns in it. The room was spacious but I refused to sit or lay on the floor. The room was equipped with a microwave, however, the turntable tray was not the proper size for it so the tray would not rotate. The hairdryer attached to the wall in the bathroom did not work. The bathtub/shower did not drain properly and backed up. The bed spread on the bed appeared to be something from the 1960&apos;s and had a very rough texture. The bed itself was hard and the bed did not have a bed skirt showing the raw box spring underneath. The box spring was old, stained, and worn with tears on the corners. Way over due for replacement. Parking was $18 and valet only. I learned to park along the Alai Wai and did not have to pay this unreasonable price to park on site. I hope to never stay here again.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Aug 29, 2008   by Daniel from Flums, CA
Overall Rating: 8 
 Cleanliness: [ 8 ]• Staff: [ 7 ]• Location: [ 8 ]

 Good location. Rooms looked a little old. 

“Nice place in a central location.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Aug 20, 2008   by Sarah from Saint Louis, MO
Overall Rating: 6 
 Cleanliness: [ 9 ]• Staff: [ 8 ]• Location: [ 7 ]

 Nicely placed in Waikiki. Charged you for everything. 

“Big charge for parking and internet. Price might seem good at first, but they haven&apos;t charged you for any extras yet.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Aug 17, 2008   by Maureen from Houston, TX
Overall Rating: 7 
 Cleanliness: [ 8 ]• Staff: [ 9 ]• Location: [ 7 ]

 Location, lobby, staff friendliness, large room. Bed hard. 

“Overall, I was pleased with the hotel for the price. I would stay here again.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Aug 10, 2008   by Bubba from Carson, WA
Overall Rating: 6 
 Cleanliness: [ 6 ]• Staff: [ 9 ]• Location: [ 7 ]

 Friendly staff. Dirty carpet. 

“Decent for price, need to seriously clean carpets and keep room walls clean. Bathroom was fine enough. Best thing was the friendly attitude of the staff.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Aug 6, 2008   by Jo from Nauvoo, IL
Overall Rating: 2 
 Cleanliness: [ 2 ]• Staff: [ 9 ]• Location: [ 7 ]

 The lobby was beautiful and the staff friendly. The rooms reminded me of a motel 6 very plain and a bit run down the halls were in need of much repair. 

“I would not recommend this hotel as it is very out dated and run down.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Jul 31, 2008   by Eve from Brisbane, CA
Overall Rating: 5 
 Cleanliness: [ 6 ]• Staff: [ 6 ]• Location: [ 5 ]

 Allowed late check-out. Pool nice, but hot metal chair frames. No WiFi. 

“The bed was super stiff/hard. The rug was dirty - cream carpeting was a very odd choice. The staff was nice and very helpful. The air conditioner needed a tune-up. Charged for coffee packages which is uncalled for.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Jul 24, 2008   by Stacey from Mountain View, HI
Overall Rating: 0 
 Cleanliness: [ 10 ]• Staff: [ 7 ]• Location: [ 8 ]

 Rooms are very spacious and clean. Parking is expensive. 

“Hotel is in a very convenient location for Downtown shopping. Rooms are spacious. Staff was friendly.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Jul 23, 2008   by George from West Covina, CA
Overall Rating: 2 
 Cleanliness: [ 5 ]• Staff: [ 8 ]• Location: [ 8 ]

 Good location, good price. Poor AC, shoddy rooms, poor mattress. 

“The basics in lodging.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Jul 22, 2008   by Denise from Honolulu, HI
Overall Rating: 9 
 Cleanliness: [ 8 ]• Staff: [ 10 ]• Location: [ 7 ]

 It was close to Waikiki, but not in the crowded part of Waikiki. The parking fee. 

“The hotel staff was friendly and very helpful. The location is in walking distance of most of Waikiki.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Jul 21, 2008   by George from West Covina, CA
Overall Rating: 2 
 Cleanliness: [ 8 ]• Staff: [ 9 ]• Location: [ 8 ]

 Nice lobby. Poor cooling, stiff mattress. 

“Cheap hotel in good location but shabby, dated room with poor air conditioning, stiff mattress.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Jul 17, 2008   by Holly from Calgary, AB CA
Overall Rating: 6 
 Cleanliness: [ 4 ]• Staff: [ 9 ]• Location: [ 4 ]

 The staff was amazing. Room was not very clean, no internet available, quite far away from beach. 

“The staff was friendly, but the resort left lots to be desired. There were very few amenities (internet, concierge), and the hotel was quite a hike from the action of the Waikiki area. I really can&apos;t say enough good things about the staff. They were very accommodating, and really seemed to care.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Jul 8, 2008   by Nicole from De Forest, WI
Overall Rating: 4 
 Cleanliness: [ 4 ]• Staff: [ 6 ]• Location: [ 6 ]

 The location of the hotel was convenient if you want to be near Downtown and not the beach. The hotel did not have a functioning restaurant for dinner services. 

“The hotel was overrated. The hallway to the room had huge stains and was disgusting. They advertised a restaurant but did not actually have a functioning one when we there. They had breakfast service which offered a decent variety but wasn&apos;t very good for the price. The same quality could be found in a fast food restaurant for a lower price. The room was not fancy but sufficient and it was a lot cleaner than the hallway. You are required to pay to use the valet parking because there is no other option. But the valets were good. The hotel is alright if your only there for an overnight stay and don&apos;t want to spend much, but I would not stay there again. I would opt to spend a little more money for a hotel with a decent restaurant and a few more amenities that was cleaner.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Jun 15, 2008   by Ed from Morton, IL
Overall Rating: 10 
 Cleanliness: [ 10 ]• Staff: [ 10 ]• Location: [ 8 ]

 Easy walk to all Waikiki Activities. There is construction of a new building 100 ft behind it. They start working at 7:00am. 

“Very nice location. Clean room with microwave and small fridge. Everything clean and bright except the carpet.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Jun 12, 2008   by zane 
Overall Rating: 1 




“Lobby looks nice, but rooms were very dirty. Carpets and bathroom were dirty.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Jun 4, 2008   by A. from Hudson, NY
Overall Rating: 4 
 Cleanliness: [ 1 ]• Staff: [ 8 ]• Location: [ 5 ]

 Staff is very nice and friendly. Old and dirty. 

“The room is big. Everything is very old and dirty. Most of the items in the room have stains on them. I wouldn&apos;t want to walk around the room without slippers. Mattress was very uncomfortable. No bed skirt and the side of the box spring shows all kind of stains. Not enough electrical outlets in the room.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 May 31, 2008   by Fernando from Austin, TX
Overall Rating: 5 
 Cleanliness: [ 3 ]• Staff: [ 5 ]• Location: [ 5 ]

 The lobby architecture. Cockroaches in bathroom. 

“I got the internet access but no instructions were provided for the connection. Asked for information but was not helped.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 May 30, 2008   by Mark from Bozeman, MT
Overall Rating: 8 
 Cleanliness: [ 8 ]• Staff: [ 9 ]• Location: [ 4 ]

 Reasonably priced, easy walking distance to central Waikiki. Only minimal food service available, and no room service. 

“This property is in the process of being converted into residential condominiums, so amenities are gradually disappearing. Still a well-maintained and mostly-pleasant experience, though.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 May 29, 2008   by Collin from Fort Worth, TX
Overall Rating: 7 
 Cleanliness: [ 6 ]• Staff: [ 9 ]• Location: [ 6 ]

 All staff was helpful and nice. Air Conditioner was barely adequate, TV remote did not work, shower not hot enough. 

“This hotel met expectations, but did not exceed expectations. It was a little further from Waikiki beach and area nightlife than desired, but I know the Royal Garden Waikiki is not classified as Waikiki Beach area. The staff was very friendly and helpful at providing advice, arranging transportation, etc. Room was ok, hallways on all floors have seen better days, but most common areas were quite nice. There are many hotels in the area, and I expect that most are similar to this one.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 May 26, 2008   by Brad from Kailua Kona, HI
Overall Rating: 8 
 Cleanliness: [ 4 ]• Staff: [ 10 ]• Location: [ 8 ]

 Friendly staff, beautiful lobby, convenient location, close to restaurants/shopping. Overpriced parking, run-down room, and stained carpet. 

“We did not feel this hotel deserved a 2 1/2 star rating. Although the lobby and elevators were recently remodeled, the room was run down and depressing. The room did have a small safe, and the staff was very friendly and helpful. For the price, the room was okay.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 May 23, 2008   by Dionne from Salisbury, MD
Overall Rating: 8 
 Cleanliness: [ 9 ]• Staff: [ 10 ]• Location: [ 8 ]

 Spacious lobby, quiet comfortable sitting area wit plush furniture. Slow elevators. 

“The rooms were huge. Worth the price. older decor, but I didn&apos;t care. Bell boys were extremely helpful and kind. Would stay here again.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 May 20, 2008   by Anthony from Los Angeles, CA
Overall Rating: 1 
 Cleanliness: [ 1 ]• Staff: [ 5 ]• Location: [ 8 ]

 Worn. 

“The rooms and public areas, elevators, carpets are worn, damaged.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 May 13, 2008   by Ronnie from Canton, MI
Overall Rating: 8 
 Cleanliness: [ 8 ]• Staff: [ 9 ]• Location: [ 8 ]

 Good place and nice. Not much information for attraction in the area. 

“Good place to lay the head and enjoy the place of Hawaii.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Apr 29, 2008   by Ian 
Overall Rating: 9 


 Changed my room after I complained about noise from construction next door. Terrible hard mattress. 

“It was okay. A little far away from the beach. Complained about the noisy room because of construction next door. They moved my room to a quieter area of the hotel”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Apr 3, 2008   by Bill from Waterloo, IA
Overall Rating: 5 
 Cleanliness: [ 1 ]• Staff: [ 9 ]• Location: [ 9 ]

 Blocks from the beach. Bad housekeeping. 

“We stayed here from March 14th to March 22nd. A nice location (just 6 blocks from the beach walk, 4 blocks from post office, ABC Convenience store just 1 block away). The room was ok (was on 12th floor with city/ocean view from balcony). The lobby was excellent. When we got off elevator on 12th floor, water stains on carpet. in the room, some stains on carpet. Beds were alright. Housekeeping needs some work. There were two of us staying in the room but only left us one towel each morning. Also, only vacuumed the carpet once while there 9 days. The pool was on the small side but it was clean. There is also a sauna for men and one for women. The staff (besides housekeeping) was always courteous and polite. It might have been better back in the day but it needs to be remodeled quite a bit. Only stay here if you&apos;re trying to save money and want to stay in &quot;ok&quot; conditions.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Mar 19, 2008   by Allison 
Overall Rating: 1 


 It had a king size bed. Mandatory valet parking $18, port-a-crib $25, no room service, unsafe area, 20 minutes walk from the shops, restaurants, and beach. 

“This hotel needs a makeover. I felt like I was staying in a bad hotel in a developing country. There were stains on the carpet, peeling paint and water dripping from the balcony, hair in the shower.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Mar 6, 2008   by Vikram 
Overall Rating: 8 


 The location ! 

“The location of hotel is excellent. We had a good view from our balcony.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Mar 3, 2008   by Tracy 
Overall Rating: 1 


 Nothing. Horrible service, were denied use of our room, lied about distance to Waikiki beach. 

“Manager
said there was a 5 minute walk to the beach, it was more like 20-30. Their pool closed at 7pm. Dirty rooms, horrible beds, do not stay here.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Mar 2, 2008   by Tracy 
Overall Rating: 8 


 Pretty in the lobby and central areas. The hotel room was clean but needed new carpet - old stains present. 

“Clean and tidy. Quite and easy good location - expensive car parking - $18 daily - valet only, no other parking near by.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Feb 25, 2008   by Daniel 
Overall Rating: 1 


 Nothing. Not clean, dirty rooms, extremely small single beds. 

“I checked out of this hotel after 45 minutes. Room was extremely dirty, bathroom was not clean, sliding door glass was broken, twin size bed was smaller than a twin, not attractive.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Feb 20, 2008   by Allen 
Overall Rating: 5 


 Central location. Twin beds. 

“Maid service was lousy
I don&apos;t think
I would recommend this hotel to anyone.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Feb 10, 2008   by Sheila from Spruce Grove
Overall Rating: 3 
 Cleanliness: [ 2 ]• Staff: [ 3 ]• Location: [ 4 ]

 Lobby was nice. Very dirty hotel. 

“This hotel was very disappointing. It was a dump. The lobby was nice. The rooms were dirty; the carpets were very stained and dirty. The bathtub would not drain. Their was dried dead bugs on the wall pictures. It almost ruined our whole trip. My husband said we would not be in our room very much which was true but the hotel was a real dump. The staff was not very friendly.”
 Report This 1 of 1 people found this review helpful.
 Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Jan 31, 2008   by Ed 
Overall Rating: 8 


 Spacious room. Uncomfortable bed, and old towels, not enough pillows. 

“I was very satisfied, the bed was not the most comfortable. It is an older hotel, but still clean and bright!”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Jan 30, 2008   by Thomas 
Overall Rating: 7 


 The kitchenette and the view. The stained carpets. 

“It was much better than I thought it was going to be. The location was in walking distance from everything you needed. If the carpeting wasn&apos;t stained
it would be
much better .”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Jan 18, 2008   by DeMarcus 
Overall Rating: 6 


 The view from the room. I have no respect for a place that charges you extra for internet. 

“The room was nice, but I am morally opposed to paying $10 per day to use the internet and $20 per day parking. Any Inn will give you free internet and parking.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Nov 7, 2007   by Chieko 
Overall Rating: 8 


 Clean looks overall. No bathtub. 

“Hotel looks nice. Room was okay.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Jun 4, 2007   by Jang 
Overall Rating: 3 


 Unclean. 

“The hotel staff was so friendly but I saw cockroaches in that hotel. Cleanliness was aslo horrible.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 May 1, 2007   by 
Overall Rating: 8 


 Room. Pool. 

“Pretty good location good for you and your lady.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Mar 16, 2007   by Laura 
Overall Rating: 1 


 The lobby. The room. 

“The lobby was beautiful. We expected the same for our room. The room was dirty, the carpet severely stained. The single bed was directly in front of the bathroom so we had to walk sideways to get into the bathroom. The bathroom door was slatted, not solid and gave no privacy.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Aug 3, 2006   by Carol 
Overall Rating: 5 


 Bellman and valet was very friendly and nice. 

“Our balcony was always wet from air conditioners.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Nov 13, 2005   by Lee from San Francisco
Overall Rating: 10 
 Cleanliness: [ 10 ]• Staff: [ 10 ]• Location: [ 10 ]

 Cheap drinks, and even cheaper customers. Seedy, disgusting place. 

“All I can say is that this place is a trashy dump.”
 Report This 1 of 1 people found this review helpful.
 Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Nov 11, 2005   by Ralph from Chunchula, AL
Overall Rating: 8 
 Cleanliness: [ 9 ]• Staff: [ 9 ]• Location: [ 8 ]

 The location was in walking distance of all the things to see and shop. The hotel does not give extra anything. We had to ask daily for clean towels, coffee is extra. 

“The location and stay was nice. The parking was $9.00 daily. The staff was helpful and nice. The cleaning staff needs attention to details, such as: soaps removed after the first day, towels had to be used the whole stay. The view was okay depending on the side of the building you were on.”
 Report This 1 of 1 people found this review helpful.
 Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Nov 9, 2005   by Randy from Barefoot Bay, FL
Overall Rating: 9 
 Cleanliness: [ 9 ]• Staff: [ 9 ]• Location: [ 8 ]

 Beautiful art paintings on the ceilings and throughout the hotel. Late check in time of 3pm. 

“A great place to stay for the overnighter. It&apos;s not located right in the middle of Downtown but a three block walk gets you there.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Nov 8, 2005   by Sela from West Valley, UT
Overall Rating: 10 
 Cleanliness: [ 10 ]• Staff: [ 10 ]• Location: [ 10 ]

 It is very beautiful and close to places to shop. I do not think of anything that I do not like about this hotel. 

“This hotel is very beautiful and clean. I love the decorations and the decor. It is close to everything that I wanted to do in walking distance. The staff is friendly and I like the atmosphere.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Oct 8, 2005   by Joel from Valley Village, CA
Overall Rating: 5 
 Cleanliness: [ 8 ]• Staff: [ 6 ]• Location: [ 8 ]

 The room was nice. Only a few rooms with internet. No air conditioning in the lobby. 

“The hotel is nice, clean, locally situated, but no room service, no air except in the room; the main pool was not open.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 
 Sep 9, 2005   by Gary 
Overall Rating: 3 


 Room was dirty and air conditioner did not work. 

“The floor and chairs in the room were very dirty. The air conditioner did not work and they did not fix it after we reported it.”
 Report This Was this review helpful to you?→ YES / NO 
Thanks for the valuable feedback you provided to other MYTravelGuide members. Your vote will be counted and will soon appear on the review page.
 1-20 of 71 
• NEXT → 
 
  Find and Compare Travel Deals
 
 Royal Garden At Waikiki 
 
 Change My Search Check-In: 
 Check-Out: 
 Rooms: 
 1 room 2 rooms 3 rooms 4 rooms 5 rooms 6 rooms 7 rooms 8 rooms 9 rooms 10 rooms Adults: 
 1 adult 2 adults 3 adults 4 adults Check Web Sites (Most Shoppers Check 3 or More)      
         
 Each web site you select will open a new window in your browser. 

 
 
 Close 
 
Find Great Hotel Deals
 
City:
 
Check-In:
 
Check-Out:
 
Rooms:
 
Adults:
 1 room 2 rooms 3 rooms 4 rooms 5 rooms 6 rooms 7 rooms 8 rooms 9 rooms 10 rooms 1 adult 2 adults 3 adults 4 adults 
 
Compare prices and availability with partners:
 
 
 
   
Opens one window for each offer. Please
 disable pop-up blockers.
 
 
 See more great deals for Oahu &gt;&gt; 
More great deals for Royal Garden At Waikiki 

 Kayak.com –Compare hotel prices from 100+ travel sites in one search! SideStep.com –SideStep.com 
 Hotel Representatives: 

 Reach millions of travelers. Advertise with us for Royal Garden At Waikiki . Improve the Royal Garden At Waikiki listing by providing a photo, description or suggesting a correction. 
 Bookmark this Page  •  Return to Top↑ 
 Overview User Reviews Nearby Hotels Nearby Attractions Nearby Restaurants 
 
Browse Oahu

 Oahu Travel Guide Oahu Hotels Oahu Group Hotel Deals Oahu Attractions Oahu Restaurants Oahu Neighborhoods Nearby Cities&amp;Towns Oahu Deals Oahu Flights Oahu Rental Cars 
 MY Recently Viewed Places 
 You do not have any recently viewed hotels, attractions, restaurants or destinations. 
 
Copyright©2012 MyTravelGuide.com, Inc. All Rights Reserved.
MYTravelGuide is a service mark of priceline.com Incorporated

 About Us  •  Privacy policy  •  Terms and Conditions  •  Help  •  Partner Links  • 

 Site Map  •  Hotels by City  •  City Travel Guides  •  Attractions  •  Restaurants  •  Cheap Hotels  •  Hotels in Asia  •  Pet Friendly Hotels  •  Hotel Room  •  Airport Car Rental 

MyTravelGuide.com is not a booking agent and does not charge any service fees to users of our site.
MyTravelGuide.com is not responsible for content on external web sites.
	</body>
</document>
