<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009311" url="http://deals.woot.com/deals/details/679aae81-e9a9-4a5e-879b-bd71730e475b/nesco-american-harvest-fd-1020-gardenmaster-digital-food-dehydrator" time="2012-07-13-02:41" support="1" score="0.0015084972044827531" bingtitle="Nesco American Harvest FD-1020 Gardenmaster Digital Food ..." webtitle="Nesco American Harvest FD-1020 Gardenmaster Digital Food Dehydrator for $113.99 + free shipping">
			<query id="001514" bing-rank="223"/>
	<description>Gardenmaster, Digital, 1000W Dehydrator, 4 Tray Expandable To 20 Trays, Digital ... What is the worst American remake of a foreign film? 6 answers. What is the best fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		Woot 
 The original deal pioneer keeps on pinching pennies and cracking wise. No, that price isn&apos;t a typo.
 Go to Woot. 
 Today&apos;s Woot Dyson DC35 Multi Floor Vacuum $199.99 Refurbished Woot Plus 
 Knife Fight! Camping Essentials SOLD OUT Gunnar Optiks Advanced Computer/Gaming Glasses 
 Home.Woot 
 High living at low prices with name-brand deals for your pad, crib, nest, or castle - inside and out.
 Go to Home.Woot. 
 Today&apos;s Woot Water Tech Robotic Pool Cleaner $499.99 $1,299.99 62% off List Price Woot Plus 
 Willow Decor Accessories Smart Planet Kitchen Novelties SOLD OUT WoodWick Candles 
 Sport.Woot 
 Sports, fitness, and outdoors deals, because saving money is only one of your passions.
 Go to Sport.Woot. 
 Today&apos;s Woot Callaway RAZR X Black Driver (460cc) $169.99 $249.00 32% off List Price Woot Plus 
 Golf Gear Must Haves Shape Up Teva Footwear 
 Kids.Woot 
 Deals for moms and dads and anybody else who needs kids&apos; stuff, from toys to baby gear to furniture to clothing.
 Go to Kids.Woot. 
 Today&apos;s Woot Boppy Nursing Pillow and Slipcover $22.99 $49.99 54% off List Price Woot Plus 
 Momeni Decorative Kids Rugs Dr. Seuss Bodysuits Melissa and Doug Kids Activities 
 Shirt.Woot 
 Our exclusive graphic tees will make you laugh, will make you cry, will make you look totally hot.
 Go to Shirt.Woot. 
 Today&apos;s Woot FURBALL! $12.00 Woot Plus 
 Caffiends 
 Wine.Woot 
 Direct from the winery to your thirsty lips: wine deals worth doing a spit-take over.
 Go to Wine.Woot. 
 Today&apos;s Woot Triacipedis the White III (5) $59.99 Woot Plus 
 Schug Carneros Estate Winery Lucas&amp;Lewellen Vineyards 
 Sellout.Woot 
 Last chance deals for hardcore cheapskates. Catch &apos;em before they - you guessed it - sell out.
 Go to Sellout.Woot. 
 Today&apos;s Woot Turtle Beach Gaming Headset $39.99 Refurbished Woot Plus 
 Deals that keep you Hydrated ABO Pet Gear 
 Community Sourced Deals.Woot 
 289,352 deals (and counting) from around the web, shared and ranked by a community of deal fiends like you.
 Go to Deals.Woot. 
 Top Community Deals 
 137 Steam Summer Sale Day 1! for $0.00 + free shipping @ store.steampowered.com 20 Comments 22 Silky peach babydoll nightie for $17.99 + free shipping @ ohcheri.com 1 Comment 122 $99 - Drive a Lamborghini, Ferrari, or Aston Martin on a Racetrack, Reg. $259 for $99.00 @ travelzoo.com 41 Comments 
 
 New to Woot? Start here or Sign in Stuff You Bought | Your Account beta feedback 
 Deals.Woot 

 community deals ask the community leaderboard what is deals.woot? 
 
 deals → nesco american harvest fd-1020 gardenmaster… 
 vote-for -2 vote-against 
 Nesco American Harvest FD-1020 Gardenmaster Digital Food Dehydrator for $ 113.99 + free shipping 
 
Gardenmaster, Digital, 1000W Dehydrator, 4 Tray Expandable To 20 Trays, Digital Timer Control, Top Down Technology, Includes: Clean A Screen, Fruit Roll Sheet&amp;Original Jerky Spice, Patented Converge Flow Technology, Adjustable Temperature Range From 90. Nesco American Harvest FD-1020 Gardenmaster Digital Food Dehydrator METALWARE/NESCO
 @ buy.com 
by wootbot 
added a year ago

 
 0 Comments add a comment 
 
Stats
 Added a year ago Added By wootbot Clicked 77 times Commented On 0 times Viewed 279 times Voted Against 2 times Voted For 0 times 
Similar Deals
 
 
 NESCO Food Dehydrator Snackmaster Pro 700 Watt Pr-75 for $84.95 + free shipping @ meatgrindersnow.com 
 
 Gardenmaster Pro 8-Tray for $169.99 @ urbanhomemaker.com 
 
 Gardenmaster Fruit Roll Sheets for $14.99 @ urbanhomemaker.com 
 
 
Related Questions
 
 
 Burgers or Hot Dogs? 

 35 answers 
 
 Do you enjoy American Television or British Television more? 

 23 answers 
 
 Is digital audio out worth it? 

 6 answers 
 
 Advertisement 
 Woot Home.Woot Sport.Woot Kids.Woot Shirt.Woot Wine.Woot Sellout.Woot Deals.Woot Local.Woot 
 Deals.Woot 
 Community Deals Ask the Community Leaderboard What is Deals.Woot? 
 Community Deals 
 Popular Deals Fresh Deals Add a Deal 
 Ask the Community 
 Popular Questions Fresh Questions Ask a Question 
 What is Deals.Woot? 
 Woot This Deal Button Terms and Conditions Privacy Policy 
 Mumbo Jumbo 
Woot.com is operated by Woot Services LLC.
 Products on Woot.com are sold by Woot, Inc.
 Product narratives are for entertainment purposes and frequently employ literary point of view ; the narratives do not express Woot&apos;s editorial opinion.
 Aside from literary abuse, your use of this site also subjects you to Woot&apos;s terms of use and privacy policy .
 Woot may designate a user comment as a Quality Post, but that doesn&apos;t mean we agree with or guarantee anything said or linked to in that post.
 Woot logos, site design,&amp;content©Woot, Inc. 2004-2012. All Rights Reserved. 
Sorry
 
This is only for people who have bought woots

We restrict voting to users who have purchased something from one of the other Woot stores. It&apos;s not just because we want your money (which we do) - it&apos;s the best way to be sure all the votes are coming from real people and not spam-bots or phony accounts. The best way we can think of, anyway. For now.

You can always get voting rights by buying something from one of Woot&apos;s other sites:

 woot.com wine.woot.com shirt.woot.com sellout.woot.com kids.woot.com home.woot.com sport.woot.com 

Purchases through Deals.Woot don&apos;t count, because in that case you&apos;re not buying anything from us. And we don&apos;t have your account information for those purchases.

If you think you&apos;ve bought something from Woot before and still can&apos;t vote, make sure you&apos;re logged in with the same account you used to buy from us.
 
Geez, why so negative?
 
You have to vote up more before you can vote down.

Don&apos;t get us wrong. Negativity has its place. And downvotes are just as essential as upvotes when it comes to making Deals.Woot a useful place to find deals.

But when your votes lean so heavily toward the dark side, we have to wonder. Go vote up a few things. Accentuate the positive for a little while. It&apos;ll do you some good, and it&apos;ll do the site some good, too. Then you can get back to dealing out the smackdowns, OK?
 
Too late, we all heard you!
 
Hmm... you&apos;re wanting to take your vote back?

Well, that&apos;s a bit tricky. See, we do a lot of stuff with your vote, using it to work out the popularity of what you voted for, compare that to all the other things voted on, tally up our leaderboard , work out your reputation. Someday we&apos;ll do a little cartoon showing just how hard your vote is working.

Anyway, taking votes back messes all that up, so we give you five minutes, in case you just mis-clicked. After that we&apos;ve got to say no take-backs. Luckily, votes are free, so feel free to throw them around left and right wherever you see fit.
	</body>
</document>
