<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009670" url="http://in.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20091119185902AATdHmD" time="2012-07-13-03:03" support="5" score="0.009082698201937415" bingtitle="Decision based on Productivity? - Yahoo! Answers India" webtitle="Decision based on Productivity? - Yahoo! Answers India">
			<query id="000225" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="000036" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="001165" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="001480" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="001353" bing-rank="224"/>
	<description>Food &amp; Drink; Games &amp; Recreation; Health; Home ... A fast food restaurant has a drive –through window and ... assemble them, and the third will act as cashier.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! India Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Business&amp;Finance &gt; Other - Business&amp;Finance &gt; Resolved Question 
 ? Member since: 08 October 2009 Total points: 88 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Decision based on Productivity?
 A fast food restaurant has a drive –through window and during peak lunch times can handle a
maximum of 80 cars per hour with one person taking orders, assembling them, and acting as a
cashier. The average sale as per order is of the order of Rs.100. A proposal has been made to add
two additional workers and divide the tasks among them. One will take orders, the second will
assemble them, and the third will act as cashier. With this system it is estimated that 120 cars per
hour can be serviced. All workers earn the minimum wage. According to productivity arguments
recommend whether or not to change the current system. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Hande Member since: 24 May 2009 Total points: 252,447 (Level 7) Badge Image: 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 Looks it should work. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 100% 1 Vote 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (0)
 
No other answers.
 
Discover Questions in Other - Business&amp;Finance 

 How much does he make per year? Briefly explain the performance appraisal process of a current/former employer. Which method is used? If you? Accounting Problems! Need help!? Need help with financial accounting class!? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Business&amp;Finance 
 Advertising&amp;Marketing Careers&amp;Employment Corporations Credit Insurance Investing Other - Business&amp;Finance Personal Finance Renting&amp;Real Estate Small Business Taxes 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any user content on Yahoo! Answers. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2009 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines
	</body>
</document>
