<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009057" url="http://businessinsuranceusa.com/fast-food-restaurant-business-insurance" time="2012-07-13-02:27" support="8" score="0.0064147704090403174" bingtitle="Fast Food Restaurant Commercial Insurance, Liability Insurance For ..." webtitle="Fast Food Restaurant Commercial Insurance, Liability Insurance For Restaurants, General Liability Insurance Quote">
			<query id="000620" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000541" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000623" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000981" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000550" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000995" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000997" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000990" bing-rank="12"/>
	<description>As the owner of a fast food restaurant, you have made a solid ... suits are filed against your restaurant for products ... Glass Tinting: Group Health: Business Auto Coverage</description>
	<body>
		USA BUSINESS INSURANCE CONTACT need help?
 888 900 0205 
 GENERAL LIABILITY BUSINESS AUTO WORKERS COMP PROFESSIONAL LIABILITY (E&amp;O) 
 OTHER LINES 
 Business Owners D&amp;O EPLI Surety Bond Group Health 
 
 
 BUSINESS INSURANCE FOR
 Fast Food Restaurants
QUOTE AND SAVE NOW!
 OUR PRE PACKAGED PROTECTION GIVES YOU ADDED VALUE AND SECURITY 
Fast Food Restaurants

As the owner of a fast food restaurant, you have made a solid commitment to providing local goods and services for many years to come. Starting a restaurant is a large investment of both time and money. Protect your restaurant from unexpected perils and events by covering it with the right types of business insurance .

General Liability

General liability is commercial insurance coverage that provides your fast food restaurant with a broad, overall level of protection. It is tremendously important for making sure you’re covered when unexpected events arise. General liability insurance protects you from problems that you don’t expect to arise. For example, if a customer hurts themselves while they’re in your fast food restaurant, general liability provides you with bodily injury coverage to pay for the customer’s required care. This coverage pays for repairs if a customer’s property is damaged while on your premises as well. General liability can pay for your legal and defense expenses if liability suits are filed against your restaurant for products that you’ve sold and it can protect you from mistakes or claims against your advertising materials as well.
 
General Liability Insurance Includes:

 Premises Liability - If a customer is accidentally injured while dining at your restaurant, premises liability pays for the injuries and damages. Additionally, this portion of your coverage also pays for damages or losses caused by restaurant operations. 

 Products Liability - Any company that sells, manufactures, handles or distributes products is at risk of potential litigation and problems. If your fast food is blamed for making a customer sick for example, your restaurant will  have to defend itself against those claims. Products liability helps protect you from the expenses involved with litigation defense, judgments and settlements. 

 Completed Operations - If property is damaged or someone is injured due to work your company has completed, this portion of your general liability insurance can cover those damages. 

Business Owners Policy

General liability insurance can be purchased as a stand-alone policy for your restaurant, or as an inclusion with a more advanced commercial insurance policy known as a BOP, or Business Owners Policy . A BOP is particularly useful for small businesses because it provides you with protection of both your physical and intangible assets.

 Buildings and Contents Business Income and Extra Expense Electronic Data Newly Acquired or Constructed Buildings Employee Dishonesty Coverage 

Business Auto

As the owner of a fast food restaurant you may find yourself driving for business purposes occasionally. If you or one of your employees is involved in an auto accident while driving for business, you can protect your company from the financial burden and loss by carrying a business auto insurance policy.

Workers Comp

Fast food restaurants rely on a number of employees in order to effectively serve customers. Workers comp coverage is mandated by law for all companies who employ one or more persons. Workers compensation pays for an employee&apos;s hospital care or related medical expenses if that employee is injured while on the job.

Commercial Umbrella

Commercial umbrella insurance is designed to protect you from accidents and unexpected events that exceed the cost of coverage that your general liability policy provides. When the maximum benefit amounts are paid from your general liability policy , that policy will be unable to continue making payments towards medical bills, litigation costs and other damage expenses. A commercial umbrella insurance policy will provide you with protection above and beyond the limits of your liability coverage. Commercial umbrella business insurance can provide extra protection for your general liability, commercial auto or workers comp policies.

 Insurance Quote For Fast Food Restaurants
 
 BUSINESS INFO   Business Type CHANGE BUSINESS TYPE Business Name 
Required. Owners / Partners Select 1 2 3 4 5-10 10+ 
Please select. Legal Entity Select Sole Proprietorship Partnership LLC S Corporation C Corporation Other 
Please select. Full Time Employees Select None 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10-25 
Please select. Years In Business Select 0 - New Business 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25+ 
Please select. Part Time Employees Select None 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10-25 
Please select. Annual Revenue Select Under $25,000 $25,000 - $50,000 $50,000 - $75,000 $75,000 - $100,000 $100,000 - $125,000 $125,000 - $150,000 $150,000 - $175,000 $175,000 - $200,000 $200,000 - $225,000 $225,000 - $250,000 $250,000 - $275,000 $275,000 - $300,000 $300,000 - $350,000 $350,000 - $400,000 $400,000 - $450,000 $450,000 - $500,000 $500,000 - $600,000 $600,000 - $700,000 $700,000 - $800,000 $800,000 - $900,000 $900,000 - $1,000,000 $1,000,000 And Up 
Please select. Sub Contractors Select None 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10+ 
Please select. Property SqFt (Occupied) 
Required. Full Payroll (Annual) 
Required. W2s Liability Limits Select $100,000/$300,000 $500,000/$500,000 $500,000/$1,000,000 $1,000,000/$1,000,000 $1,000,000/$2,000,000 $2,000,000/$2,000,000 $2,000,000/$4,000,000 Umbrella Coverage 
Please select. Need Insurance To Start Select ASAP In A Week In A Month Later This Year Not Sure Brief Description of Operations         
 
 COVERAGE OPTIONS   General Liability Commercial Auto Business Owners Policy (BOP) Workers Comp Professional Liability (E&amp;O) Bond Group Health       
 
 CONTACT INFO   First Name 
Required. Last Name 
Required.     Business Address 
Required. City 
Required. State AL AK AZ AR CA CO CT DE DC FL GA HI ID IL IN IA KS KY LA ME MD MA MI MN MS MO MT NE NV NH NJ NM NY NC ND OH OK OR PA RI SC SD TN TX UT VT VA WA WV WI WY 
Required. Zip Code 
Required. 
Invalid Zip. Phone 
Required. 
Invalid Phone.     Alt. Phone 
 Email 
Required. 
Invalid Email.     Comments         Any information you give will be used only
 to help you find insurance products.
We will not sell your personal information. 
 
Insurance Lines
 general liability workers comp professional liability business owners commercial auto Employment Practices Liability Directors&amp;Officers (D&amp;O) group health surety bonds 
Insurance Solutions
 Architects&amp;Engineers Acupancturists Beauty Salons Bars&amp;Taverns Flooring Contractors Fitness Centers Fast Food Restaurants Garage Door Installers Land Surveyors Manufacturers Pool Cleaners 
Affiliations


 
 
 
 
 NAVIGATION COMMERCIAL AUTO WORKERS COMPENSATION POPULAR SOLUTIONS Homepage Liability Coverage Medical Care General Contractors General Liability Bodily Injury First Aid Treatment Beauty Salons Commercial General Liability Property Damage Temporary Disability Carpet Cleaners Business Owners Policy Medical Payments Permanent Disability Flower Shops&amp;Florists Workers Compensation Physical Damage Vocational Rehabilitation Jewelry Stores Professional Liability (E&amp;O) Collision Coverage Supplemental Job Displacement Janitorial Services Commercial Auto Comprehensive Coverage Death Benefits Kiosks (Mall) Surety Bond Uninsured Motorist Workers Comp Quote Glass Tinting Group Health Business Auto Coverage   Law Offices&amp;Attornies Employment Practices Liability (EPLI) Commercial Auto Solutions   Organic Food Stores Directors&amp;Officers (D&amp;O) Retail Stores Services     Web Developers&amp;Designers Articles&amp;Blog     Woodworkers Contact Us       We Insure in: Arizona, California, Colorado, Illinois, Marriland, Pennsylvania, Florida, Georgia, Missouri, New Jersey, New York, North Carolina, Ohio, Oregon, South Carolina, Tennessee, Texas, Virginia and Washington. More states coming soon... © 2012 businessinsuranceusa.com website Terms&amp;Conditions All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
