<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009710" url="http://www.wikilaw3k.org/forum/Insurance-Registration/What-do-you-do-when-someone-backs-into-your-car-and-then-won-39-t-give-the-insurance-agent-a-statement-343204.htm" time="2012-07-13-03:05" support="2" score="0.0011362210780008217" bingtitle="What do you do when someone backs into your car and then won&apos;t ..." webtitle="What do you do when someone backs into your car and then wont give the insurance agent a statement?">
			<query id="001399" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="001053" bing-rank="200"/>
	<description>Two weeks ago, a young man backed into my car at a fast food restaurant ... rims and tv and extra things i put on the car? My car got stolen and USAA asked me to get receipts ...</description>
	<body>
		Home     Links     Contact 
 Us     Bookmark   
 
   
 
 

   Homepage     News     Legal 
 Forum     Dictionary   

 Home : Legal 
 Forum : Insurance&amp;Registration What do you do when someone backs into your car and then won&apos;t give the insurance agent a statement? 
Find answers to your legal question. 

 


 What do you do when someone backs into your car and then won&apos;t give the insurance agent a statement? 


 Two weeks ago, a young man backed into my car at a fast food restaurant while I was waiting in the drive-thru. He gave me his insurance information and I called that day and spoke with a claims adjuster. She has tried to contact him by phone and by mail and he refuses to return her calls to give a statement. She will not authorize payment for my car until she gets in touch with him. Short of notifying my insurance to make a claim what can I do to get him to call his agent and give a statement? 
 


       Reason for Reporting
 No Spam 
 Adult 
 Gambling 
 Unfinished 
 Deception 
 Plagiarism 
 Not English 
 Other 



 
 bundysmom 
 All insurance companies have a COOPERATION clause in the policy. NO insurance will pay out on a claim until they have spoken with their insured. If the guy fails to cooperate coverage can be denied. You would be off going thru your insurance at this point and they will pursue the other carrier on your behalf. 
 
 CowboyBill 
 Go through your own company (providing the loss exceeds your deductible amount). The bozo will likely listen when your company&apos;s legal staff contact him for subrogation. 
 
 oklatom 
 Nothing, and you shouldn&apos;t be talking to his insurance anyway. Contact your insurance and let them collect for you, as you should have done in the first place. 
 
 babysister32 
 call the police you should alway report even when you know or not who hit your car every time your 1st thing after the ins company is the police 
 
 alex l 
 call the police .also call the place the accident happen and ask for the manager . ask him if he still has the video tapes from the day the accident happen and if so does he have ones that show the parking lot . ask him to set them aside . and not re record over them do that asap like tonight 
 
 viisionary 
 A lesson to be learned: if ever you are involved in an accident that is someone else&apos;s fault, always get the police involved. That way, everything will be on record and you will be able to receive compensation for damages through insurance. Since the police was not involved in your accident, the young man may unfortunately get away with it. You may opt to try to take the man through the legal system, but it is a time consuming and expensive process to do so. 
 
 wantajeannie 
 He is scared that it will raise his premiums or that his parents will find out. You will have to call your insurance company which is in the future the first thing that you should do. 
 
 S17V 
 Unfortunately there is nothing you can do to force the person to give his carrier a statement. The BEST and most sucessful recourse for you - is to file a claim with your carrier (if you are NOT at fault, they WILL NOT surcharge you for this accident or any accident you are NOT at fault for) and they will pay for your damages and then subrogate the other carrier. At that point the other carrier has to respond - with or without their insured&apos;s statement. 
 
 Stefanie B 
 Call the police. 
 


 
 
   Enter Your Message or Comment 


 User Name:    
 User Email:    
 Post a comment: 
 

 
 

 
 Legal Discussion Forum Marriage&amp;Divorce Insurance&amp;Registration Law&amp;Ethics Immigration Law&amp;Legal Jobs Law Enforcement&amp;Police Cars&amp;Transportation Safety Child Adoption Embassies&amp;Consulates Military 


 
   If you have your permitt for driving with a licensed adult could you drive by yourself with their permission? I&apos;m confused?... 
 



 
   Sueing over accident-is it wrong? My boyfriend and I were in a bad accident and my head hit the windsheiled, causing me to be in a short coma and have a subarracnoid hemorrage. He was drinking, and had to suffer a lot of consequences ... 
 



 
   If someone steals your carwill the insurance cover for the rims and tv and extra things i put on the car? My car got stolen and USAA asked me to get receipts for my rims and my tv . But someone i met said she had her car stolen and they will NOT cover any of the extra stuff unless i called and put my ... 
 



 
   Does auto insurance automatically go up with a speeding ticket? Got the first one in 5 years and wondered if this will affect my rates.... 
 



 
   Any advice on my insurance claim? I was driving home today and i stopped at the red traffic lights at a padestrian crossing. About 10 seconds later a car drove (not skidded) into the back of me, sending my car fully over the ... 
 



 
   Can i drive with out a license for a lil bit? I want to get used to driving by myself and i have driven With my parents. I&apos;m already 18 and in a couple of months i&apos;m going to take driving exam. But i wanted to take the car out for a ... 
 



 
   Why is UK car insurance so much more expensive than most of Europe? My brother lives in Sweden and pays so much less then he did (And I do) in the UK. More than that over there it&apos;s the car that is insured rather than the driver (or at least with his policy) so ... 
 



 
   What type of license for a trike? In the UK I have been told that you can drive a Reliant Rialto (3 wheeler - classed as a tricycle) on a motorcycle and a car license but I was wondering if this is true?
 Additional Details &lt;... 
 



 
   I need some advice my husband brought a car through a friend? I need some advice
my husband brought a car through a friend of a friend for cash but prior to doing this he had his friend a machanic look over the car we also did an check on car at www.... 
 



 
   I recently got two penalty points will this affect my insurance policy much? 
 Additional Details 
i got this for using a mobile and am interested in answers in uk and ireland.... 
 



 
   A car is written off by the other insurer. the car + cash is offered. am i it still insured to drive on my ins ... 
 



 
   Auto insurance plz help!? i have a 2005 ford mustang and im 17yrs old. i have had a couple of speeding tickets and etc. is there any place in arkansas were i can find cheap insurance thanks.... 
 



 
   Question about no-claims bonus (UK)? Soon, I will be coming up to the 1 year anniversary of passing my driving test. After that date, I want to buy a car and get it insured in my name (I have not had any insurance before). Do I ... 
 



 
   Can a co-signer sign for a car if they don&apos;t have a license?? I&apos;m 17 and I want my mom to co-sign on a car for me. I have a license but her license was suspended several years ago. Can she sign for a car for me??
 Additional Details 
I AM IN FLOR... 
 



 
   Is car insurance active on expiration date? Hey there, I have to renew my car insurance on or before December 8th. I did not realize it was on a Monday so it&apos;s impossible for me to reach my agent during the weekend.

I was ... 
 



 
   Can I claim back unused insurance if my car is written off? My car was invovled in an accident and I claim my insurance and the insurance co decided to write it off. I just renewed my insurance one month before the accident. I can claim back the 11 month ... 
 



 
   My car got stolen - If you work for a car insurance co please help .? Please only answer this question if you are 99 to 100% sure of your answer. Thanks

Will the insurance still pay for my car if it was stolen out of my garage with the keys in the car? I ... 
 



 
   How Insurance companies determine quotes for car insurance? ... 
 



 
   No Insurance car accident.? I don&apos;t have car insurance, but I hit someone car. Now, that Insurance Co. Ask me to pay 8k? Do I have to ?... 
 



 
   Driving to school with learners license? what happens if you get pulled over with learners permit or nothing in florida?... 
 


 


 
Copyright (c) 2009-2011 Wiki Law 3k Thursday, July 12, 2012 - Trusted legal information for you.
Archive: Forum  |  Forum  |  Forum  |  Links 
0.004
	</body>
</document>
