<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009623" url="http://www.bcre.com/dana-point-coastline-view-homes.php" time="2012-07-13-03:01" support="1" score="0.001556183168123954" bingtitle="Dana Point Coastline View Homes - Coastline View Homes for Sale" webtitle="Dana Point Coastline View Homes - Coastline View Homes for Sale">
			<query id="001457" bing-rank="94"/>
	<description>Enjoy the gourmet kitchen with high end appliances ... back of home makes the back patio/yard a perfect place to sit ... Near 5 star Saint Regis, Ritz Carlton and Montage ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Content Skip to Navigation 
 Home Beach Cities Real Estate 
 Beach Cities Listings List Your Home 
 Selling Approach Marketing Plan Online Magazine Property Evaluation Testimonials Sold Gallery 
 Beach Rentals 
 
Orange County
 Newport Coast Rentals Newport Beach Rentals Corona Del Mar Rentals Laguna Beach Rentals San Clemente Rentals Dana Point Rentals Huntington Beach Rentals Irvine Rentals 

 
San Diego County
 La Jolla Rentals Del Mar Rentals Encinitas Rentals Cardiff By The Sea Rentals Carlsbad Rentals Oceanside Rentals Coronado Rentals Rancho Santa Fe Rentals 
 Home Search 
 Orange County Home search San Diego County Search 
 Beach Homes Sold Search About Us Blog 
 
 San Clemente Real Estate Dana Point Real Estate Monarch Beach Real Estate Laguna Beach Real Estate Newport Beach Real Estate Newport Coast Real Estate Huntington Beach Real Estate 
 
Dana Point Coastline View Homes
 
 

 
 
Dana Point Coastline View Homes for Sale in Dana Point, California
 Looking for an Dana Point Coastline View home for sale in Dana Point.  We have narrowed down the search here for you to show you only Coastline View homes and Coastline View condos for sale in Dana Point.  Searching for Dana Point Coastline View homes and Dana Point Coastline View homes for sale in Dana Point, California.   This page has only Coastline View properties, whether your looking for an small Coastline View condo or a luxury Coastline View Dana Point home, we have it all right here for you.  We are your Dana Point Real Estate Realtor specialists and can assist you in finding your perfect Dana Point Coastline View home! 
 




Dana Point Coastline View Homes for Sale In Dana Point, California


 All Listings $100,000 - $200,000 $200,000 - $300,000 $300,000 - $400,000 $400,000 - $500,000 $500,000 - $600,000 $600,000 - $700,000 $700,000 - $800,000 $800,000 - $900,000 $900,000 - $1,000,000 Over $1,000,000 


 
MLS# U11001176
 
Dana Point 53 Strand Beach Dr
 Few private oceanfront communities in Southern California overlook as scenic a beach as The Strand. This recently completed Strand oceanfront residence of approx. 9,000 sq. ft. offers the uncommon chance to live on the beach without sacrificing the amenities or security of a proper home. Occupying the most enviably sited parcel on this beach, this villa enjoys numerous vistas of the Pacific, islands, and sunsets. Interior spaces open seamlessly to loggias, terraces, and Mediterranean gardens overlooking the ocean. The defining features of Italianate architecture have been artfully blended with an informal plan to create a home that is grand and substantial, as well as warm and inviting. The impressive 3-story residence is built around a courtyard awash in sunlight optimizing privacy, light, and ventilation. An ever-present relationship to the ocean is experienced in every significant room, and expertly arranged and appointed interior and exterior spaces make living here a delight. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $23,500,000 5 Beds 7 Baths 8,838 SqFt 
MLS# L38034
 
Dana Point 6 Monarch Cv
 Gracious Old World splendor is defined in this oceanfront estate. Next to the 5-star Ritz Carlton Resort, this home offers 12,000sf of seclusion&amp;luxury at the end of a priv.gated street of 6 homes in prestigious Ritz Cove. Residents enjoy 24hr guarded entry, cameras&amp;security. The premier double lot stands alone with oceanfront fairways to the south, open space to the north&amp;whitewater vistas. Main Level has an elegant Great Room&amp;gourmet kitchen opening to an expansive lounging/dining terrace, formal dining,&amp;sublime Master Suite fronting the crashing sea&amp;lush golf course green. Mid-level hosts 5 ensuite bdrms, family area&amp;study. Lower level has theater, wine cellar&amp;tasting room, full bar and game&amp;fitness rooms. An elevator services all levels. Built w/finest materials&amp;craftsmanship; furniture-quality cabinetry&amp;hand-hewn beams, staircase with artisan wrought iron&amp;wall of stacked limestone spanning all 3 levels, Travertine slab floors, and Mahogany doors and windows View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $22,995,000 6 Beds 10 Baths 12,000 SqFt 
MLS# S694367
 
Dana Point 45 Strand Beach Dr
 Awe inspiring design meets with pristine white sands and breathtaking ocean views for the ultimate in modern luxury living. This sleek, sophisticated estate commands attention with its dramatic entrance over a glass bridge above a beautiful mosaic tiled fountain. Enter through the large stainless steel door to be greeted by a one of a kind visually stunning glass elevator and glass staircase. Attention to detail in its finest form addresses each room with top of the line finishes including Rift Oak flooring, 8 Alderwood doors, Limestone smooth textured walls, Marble and Quartz slab counter tops, radiant floor heating, top of the line appliances and fixtures. The floor plan with 5 bedrooms, 8 baths, library, office, wine room, gym and theatre is designed to accentuate the ocean front lifestyle and Pacific Ocean views. Infinity edge Saline Pool and spa in black Zimbabwe Granite. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $22,500,000 5 Beds 8 Baths 9,500 SqFt 
MLS# L35871
 
Dana Point 71 Ritz Cove Dr
 Located on a 19,664 Sq. Ft. Private Bluff in the Prestigious Oceanfront Guard Gated Community of Ritz Cove in Monarch Beach, this Custom 9,000 Sq. Ft. Luxurious Architectural Masterpiece is Positioned at the Premiere Elevation to Capture Breathtaking 180 Degree White Water, Catalina&amp;Coastline Views of the Pacific Ocean. Every Detail in this Spectacular Home has been Artfully Planned with Extraordinary Craftsmanship&amp;the Living Space is Oriented to Capture Sweeping Ocean Views Through Expansive Windows. The Elegant&amp;Open Interior of this Magnificent Ocean View Estate is Exquisitely Appointed with a Dramatic Grand Foyer, an Expansive Family Room, a State of the Art Professional Kitchen, a Sprawling Formal Dining Room&amp;Living Room, a Private Executive Study, an Enormous Master Retreat, an Opulent Master Bathroom with Sauna, a Lavish Master Walk-in Closet, a Spacious Wood Paneled Library, Four Additional En Suite Bedrooms&amp;much much more...&apos;Villa Pacifica&apos;is Truly a Work of Art! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $14,500,000 5 Beds 7 Baths 9,000 SqFt 
MLS# L38667
 
Dana Point 5 Monarch Cv
 Distinctively set on the 3rd green of one of the few oceanfront golf courses in California, this custom villa offers breathtaking white water views&amp;over 7,200sf of luxury. The home boasts a dramatic 2 story entry, formal living&amp;dining rms, gourmet kitchen w/professional grade appliances,&amp;family room filled w/natural light opening to outdoor entertaining area w/rock waterfalls, pool, spa&amp;forever views. There are 5 bedroom suites including a lavish master retreat w/sitting area, private veranda, dual walk-in closets, his/her baths&amp;a separate office with coastline vistas. Other highlights include 9 fireplaces, exotic stone&amp;mosaic tile, artisan iron work, rich woodwork&amp;cabinetry, custom lighting&amp;elevator.Ritz Cove is nestled between the Ritz-Carlton&amp;St. Regis hotels.Residents enjoy 24 hr gated&amp;monitored security. This home is on a private cul-de-sac of 6 homes granted membership&amp;private access to Monarch Bay Club until 2020. This is truly resort living at its finest! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $11,500,000 5 Beds 8 Baths 7,200 SqFt 
MLS# L37826
 
Dana Point 34545 SCENIC
 Majestically set above the crashing waves of the Pacific Ocean, this oceanfront estate is one of 3 properties home to the Headlands Preserve. Cook&apos;s Pointe is a unique gated compound comprised of 2 seaside homes plus carriage house. Vistas of the ocean, Harbor and Catalina are framed by every window. Inspired by the sea, the historic lower A Frame residence boasts superb contemporary upgrades while retaining its original nautical attributes including sculptures, murals and authentic maritime hardware. The upper home, with original art glass windows and copper roof, has been meticulously remodeled using exotic finishes including Koa floors, jade and quartz counters, etched glass art, and exquisite custom cabinetry&amp;lighting. Each residence offers oceanfront terraces and patios for lounging&amp;dining while taking in the breezes, sights&amp;sounds of the ocean. There are 5 garages plus ample parking. This is a rare opportunity to own an impeccable, noteworthy estate in an idyllic location View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $9,995,000 8 Beds 7 Baths 7,350 SqFt 
MLS# L38996
 
Dana Point 39 Monarch Bay Dr
 OCEANFRONT ESTATE LOCATED IN THE 24 HOUR GATE GUARDED COMMUNITY OF MONARCH BAY. COMPLETELY PRIVATE GATED ENTRANCE WITH MOTOR COURT.4 BEDROOMS, 4.5 BATH RESIDENCE FEATURES OCEAN VIEWS FROM ALL ITS EXPANSIVE LIVING AREAS AND SPACIOUS REAR GROUNDS WHICH INCLUDE A LARGE BLUFF TOP LAWN, COVERED DINING TERRACE, AN ELEVATED VIEW DECK AND NUMEROUS SUN TERRACES. MAIN FLOOR INCLUDES EXPANSIVE FAMILY ROOM WITH FIREPLACE, A BEAUTIFUL KITCHEN OPEN TO GREAT ROOM AND SUN FILLED BEDROOM. UPSTAIRS MASTER SUITE INCLUDES GENEROUS SITTING ROOM WITH FIREPLACE, STONE CLAD BATH WITH DEEP SOAKING TUB AND PRIVATE OCEANFRONT TERRACE AND DRAMATIC OCEAN VIEWS. FRONT ROW LOT WITH WHITE WATER AND COASTLINE VIEWS AND DIRECT BEACH ACCESS. hOMEOWNERS IN MONARCH BAY ENJOY A PRIVATE BEACH CLUB AND BEACHFRONT RESTAURANT. CLUB MEMBERSHIP IS $30 PAID QUARTERLY. DUES QUOTED FOR ASSOCIATION ARE YEARLY. OWNERSHIP IS LEASEHOLD WITH A NEGOTIATED BUYOUT PROVISION. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $7,500,000 4 Beds 5 Baths 3,701 SqFt 
MLS# S689826
 
Dana Point 35851 Beach Rd
 Rare Opportunity Luxury Beach Front Home Located on 2 lots - A quintessential Cape Cod, this architecturally-significant oceanfront estate is uniquely set on two lots in the private community of Capistrano Bay which is resident-owned guarded beachfront community. Designed by renowned residential designer and builder James Glover, the 4,000-square-foot turn-key home features top-of-the-line amenities and finishes throughout. From the large decks, gorgeous seafront courtyard with stone fireplace, lush landscaping, sandy fire pit lounge area with built-in BBQ and glass enclosure outside to the main floor with movie theatre, wine cellar, chef s gourmet kitchen and family room complete with separate full wet bar and extending Nana Wall design doors inside, the beachfront truly is your playground. Located on a great surf spot right in front of the home. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $7,495,000 4 Beds 5 Baths 4,032 SqFt 
MLS# S642897
 
Dana Point 35301 Beach Rd
 A True Piece of Art...Newer Construction, Ocean, Beach Front Home located in Exclusive Private Community on Beach Road. Artistic Warm Contemporary design with only the highest of quality materials. Home features 3 bedrooms plus Large Bonus, Media or Game room with Bar, Office loft, 4.5 bathrooms, Spacious Living room with walls of glass sliders which open to the Beach and Ocean front, Amazing Gourmet Kitchen overlooking Living room out to Ocean, Formal Dining room, 2 car attached garage, Large, Private Roof Deck with space built for Spa, All Floors serviced by Elevator!! This was not a Spec home Build. Owner spared no expense here...Great location on widest portion of beach and close to Entry Gate... Never lived in full time!! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $6,950,000 3 Beds 5 Baths 3,900 SqFt 
MLS# L38006
 
Dana Point 4 Monarch CV
 Truly Unique in All Orange County, California. Fronting on the Monarch Links Golf Course. Majestic Ocean, White Water, and Ocean Front Green Views. This Executive Mansion is Irreplaceable in All Aspects. Private Gated Access to Monarch Bay Beach Including Special Membership in the Monarch Beach Club Until 2020. This Exclusive Double Gated Community of Six Estates is Second to None in Privacy. Views of the Pool and Spa and the White Waters of Monarch Beach. Stroll the Fabulous Beach from Three Arch Bay Point to the Dana Headlands. The Surf at Salt Creek is at the Top of Southland Breaks. The Ritz Carlton and St. Regis are Both Within Walking Distance. These Amenities Even Eclipse the Dana Strand Development at Far More Expensive Prices. Disability access to all major rooms, Elevator. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $6,485,000 4 Beds 7 Baths 6,532 SqFt 
MLS# S697918
 
Dana Point 45 Beach View Ave
 EXQUISITE CUSTOM HOME TO BE CONSTRUCTED IN EXCLUSIVE GUARD GATED, OCEAN FRONT, COMMUNITY! SANTA BARBARA STYLE WITH 5 BEDROOMS, OFFICE, GAME ROOM&amp;6.5 BATHS! FANTASTIC PANORAMIC OCEAN VIEWS! MAIN FLOOR OFFICE WITH FULL BATH! MASTER SUITE WITH FIREPLACE&amp;LARGE VIEWING DECK! KITCHEN SHALL INCLUDE HAND CRAFTED CUSTOM CABINETY WITH DESIGNER FINISHES, VIKING APPLIANCES, SUB-ZERO&amp;BREAKFAST NOOK WHICH OPENS TO THE FAMILY ROOM! QUALITY WORKMANSHIP AND FEATURES THROUGHOUT INCLUDING SLABSTONE COUNTERTOPS, DESIGNER STONE&amp;DISTRESSED HARDWOOD FLOORING, QUALITY KOHLER PLUMBING FIXTURES THROUGHOUT&amp;DRAMATIC CURVED WOOD&amp;WROUGHT IRON CUSTOM CRAFTED STAIRWAY! EXTENSIVE EXTERIOR DETAILING WITH CUSTOM CRAFTED FRONT/GARAGE DOORS! STUNNING SALT WATER POOL&amp;SPA LOCATED OFF COVERED LOGGIA WITH STONE FLOORING! SOPHISTICATED LANDSCAPING&amp;WATER FEATURE WITH STONE WALKWAYS&amp;DRIVEWAYS! 3 CAR ATTACHED GARAGE! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $6,395,000 5 Beds 7 Baths 6,300 SqFt 
MLS# L36278
 
Dana Point 33881 Cabrillo ISLE
 Stunning architecture, spectacular sunsets, sandy beaches and panoramic white water views characterize this private estate. Behind the gates of Niguel Shores and only 200 yards from a private oceanfront beach park, this completely remodeled home offers a resort-like living experience. The private courtyard entry leads to a grand marble foyer. The impressive living room and adjacent family room have soaring ceilings and 20 ft. walls of glass to take in ocean vistas and the crashing surf. Other spaces include a grand formal dining room, gourmet kitchen equipped with professional appliances, and a refined office with fireplace, built-ins and leaded glass doors. The five en suite bedrooms include two master suites with fireplaces and luxury baths. The terraces off the main living area and master bedroom offer a perfect place to relax and enjoy the coastal lifestyle. Guard gated Niguel Shores features 5 Star resort amenities with tennis, spa and a Jr. Olympic pool View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $5,750,000 5 Beds 6 Baths 7,500 SqFt 
MLS# L33932
 
Dana Point 329 Monarch Bay
 Newly remodeled turn key&apos;Beach Home&apos;. Unobstructed panoramic views of whitewater.beach.golf.surfing.sailing.SUP&amp;Ritz Carlton with Catalina&amp;San Clemente islands.Unpack&amp;hit the beach. Bamboo flooring, Lift&amp;Glide doors, electronic solar shades, fireplace, central air. Single level with Elevator to garage. Home sits out farthest on street for awesome views.Dual masters, steam shower, Huge deck with power awning, oversized two car garage with lots of built-in storage&amp;epoxy floor&amp;large store room. 24 hour guard gated&amp;tennis. Bay Club Membership is only $10 per month and includes private restaurant&amp;cocktail lounge on the sand, surf butlers, bbq, special events&amp;more as well as beach parking. Bay Club is operated by the St. Regis Hotel&amp;Spa. This home has incredible views day&amp;night View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $5,450,000 2 Beds 3 Baths 
MLS# L39280
 
Dana Point 33891 Nauticus Isle
 Spectacular Ocean View As You Approach The Entrance To This Contemporary Beauty! This Home Has Been Totally Renovated On The Inside And The Outside. A Must&apos;SEA&apos;Property! 180 Degree Panoramic Ocean&amp;Catalina Island Sit Down Views. Designer Firepit Spanning Almost The Entire Rear Patio. Features On The Interior Include Designer Granite In Kitchen. Steam Showers, Jacuzzi Tubs, Porcelein Tile Flooring In Downstairs&amp;Polished Stainles Steel Railings Leading To Upstairs Bedroom. Two Bedrooms Downstairs and One Upstairs With Great Ocean Views Or Overlooking Quite&amp;Serene Front Entry Patio With Olive Trees, Fountains And Sitting Area. Unique&apos;WAVE&apos;Sculpture In Dining Room Overlooks The Great Room With Sliding Walls Of Glass Panels Which Open To Large Patio Overlooking The Ocean With Floor To Ceiling Fireplace. Audio/Video System Built-In. Dramatic Courtyard Entry With Electronic Video Front Entry System For Your Added Security. Truly A Showplace At The Beach. See Virtual Tour View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $4,500,000 3 Beds 4 Baths 2,600 SqFt 
MLS# S700282
 
Dana Point 50 Monarch Bay Dr
 Streamlined glass and modern accents showcase the vast coastal views throughout 5,200 sq. ft. of living space designed by Brion Jeannette. Panoramic ocean, white water, beach, and Ritz Carlton views. This svelte estate built in 2009 features a SmartHome system, imported stone, Ann Sacks and Walker Zanger bathrooms, Dornbracht fixtures, temperature controlled wine cellar, and Fleetwood doors and windows. 5 bedrooms, 5 full and 2 half baths. Lower level features a bonus room with kitchenette, guest suite with private access, laundry, and powder. Infinity edge pool&amp;spa with stunning water feature plus a swim tunnel under the front walkway. Brazilian marble imported from Indonesia adorns the spacious center island in the gourmet kitchen. Guard gated Monarch Bay on the ocean side of PCH offers a private clubhouse, beach, tennis courts and community events. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $4,349,000 5 Beds 7 Baths 5,200 SqFt 
MLS# L35037
 
Dana Point 325 Monarch Bay Dr
 A contemporary front row masterpiece with unobstructed panoramic views encompassing Catalina&amp;San Clemente Islands, Salt Creek Beach, Links Golf the Ritz Carlton Hotel and beyond. Artistically designed for a modern lifestyle. The massive great room completly opens to an extra large lanai with firepit and the unmatched view over the Pacific. Gourmet kitchen with huge center island, professional grade appliances. Master suite retreat with panoramic ocean/beach views, fireplace, steam shower, zen tub and large walk-in closet. Home has professional lighting, surround sound, electronic solar shades. Three car garage with incredible storage(room&amp;lockers) plus a large bath with custom shower. An incredible opportunity to own one of only 12 homes on the front row in Monarch Bay. Enjoy watching surfers, dolphins, whales, sailing regatta&apos;s and romantic sunsets while listening to the surf lull you to sleep every night.Financing available to qualified buyers. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $4,275,000 3 Beds 4 Baths 
MLS# S644195
 
Dana Point 35295 Beach Rd
 Private Beach front home located in the Exclusive guard gated community of the Capistrano Bay District. One of only 200 homes this sits directly on the sand. You own all the beach in front of you, all the way to the water, your very own private beach. Stunning interior completely redone in classical fun style. Beautiful wood floors, massive fireplace, goreous tile, beautiful glass solarium. Very open floor plan that lens itself to all ocean views. Large wrap around deck off master bedroom. Brick patio and walkways. New vinyl windows throughout. Large laundry room and out door shower. This is a must see with 5 bedrooms and 3 full beautiful baths. Gourmet kitchen. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $3,999,900 5 Beds 3 Baths 2,268 SqFt 
MLS# U12001940
 
Dana Point 35795 BEACH ROAD
 New listing. Seller will entertain offers between $3,695,000-$4,194,876. Beautiful beach front residence constructed in 2002. Located on an exclusive, individually owned beach, this home features a modern, open design which embraces its prime location. True to the modern spirit, the kitchen, dining, living areas, and master bedroom were carefully designed to take full advantage of the spectacular view 24 hours a day, 7 days a week, 365 days a year. Boasting 5 bedrooms, a loft, and a bonus room, the home is both functional and versatile. The exclusive community provides utmost security including a 24 hour guard gated entrance, in addition to a 24/7 continuous patrol of the neighborhood. The availability of this home is an excellent and rare opportunity. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $3,995,000 5 Beds 5 Baths 3,150 SqFt 
MLS# L36617
 
Dana Point 35341 CAMINO CAPISTRANO
 PRICE REDUCED 3M!!! DOUBLE LOT,10+ FRONT ROW OCEAN BLUFF CUSTOM ESTATE! 180 DEGREE FOREVER OCEAN VIEWS OF WHITEWATER SURF&amp;SAND,CATALINA ISLAND, SUNSETS&amp;SAILBOATS FROM DANA PT HARBOR TO SAN CLEMENTE PIER&amp;BEYOND. THE VERY BEST HOUSE, LOCATION, QUALITY AT A HUGELY DISCOUNTED PRICE!!!$950,000+ in remodeling improvements. Security-Gated Courtyard entry w/ lush gardens&amp;intimate seating areas. Impressive front porch welcomes you into spacious foyer with immediate Blue Ocean views. Elegant double split staircase. Library w/ spiral staircase to upper bookcased walkway. Remodeled Gourmet Kitchen w/ fireplace&amp;exquisite granite counters. Each Remodeled Bath a Masterpiece. TRIPLE MASTER SUITES&amp;maid&apos;s quarters total 6 Bedrooms + Office + Library&amp;6 Baths. ALL living areas have access to enormous patio overlooking Panoramic Ocean Views. Wine Rm&amp;Butler Pantries.Open floorplan designed for entertaining&amp;comfortable everyday family living. THIS IS CA. RIVIERRA LIFESTYLE AT ITS FINEST! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $3,925,000 6 Beds 6 Baths 8,100 SqFt 
MLS# S698335
 
Dana Point 35283 Beach Rd
 Seller will entertain offers between $3,245,000 and $3,795,000. Tremendous value for one of the original&apos;Doheny Family&apos;Adobe bungalows. This lovely historic home sits right on the sand in the gated Beach Road community of Capistrano Beach. Remodeled to include beautiful features such as granite counters&amp;stainless steel appliances in the kitchen, gorgeous stone&amp;tile work in the updated bathrooms and travertine flooring throughout. Sitting this close to the beach you will enjoy beautiful ocean and sunset views from 2 of the 4 bedrooms, living area, sunroom and the spacious patio that is a great spot for outside dining and entertaining. This charming home also features large windows on the first floor to maximize your views, fireplaces in the living room and master suite, a quaint courtyard style entry and all the wonderful amenities&amp;experiences Dana Point has to offer. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $3,795,000 3 Beds 3 Baths 2,279 SqFt 
MLS# S649506
 
Dana Point 35321 Camino Capistrano
 OCEAN FRONT BLUFF!!!BETTER THAN ON THE SAND!!!. HURRY, THIS IS THE BEST HOUSE, BEST LOCATION AND BEST PRICE FOR AN OCEAN FRONT/BLUFF FRONT HOME FROM NEWPORT TO SAN CLEMENTE!!! This magnificent home was built with the highest construction and safety standards in mind, using only the best materials and finishes. Since being constructed and finished....it has rarely been used which makes it feel and live like a Brand New Custom Beach Home! Combine this with its pure, panoramic, Ocean, coastline, white water, Islands, Pier and Harbor Views and you have a True 10 out of 10!!! This home is a Tuscan masterpiece estate. Now is your opportunity to own one of the finest homes in Southern California. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $3,750,000 5 Beds 6 Baths 4,701 SqFt 
MLS# L38456
 
Dana Point 139 Monarch Bay Dr
 Luxuriate in the art of fine living in this stylish Monarch Bay home. Masterfully designed by Architect Chris Light, the residence was recently completed&amp;offers panoramic oceanviews&amp;exquisite finishes. Sliding walls of glass in Great Room optimize the sea view, seamlessly merging the saltwater pool and front courtyard w/the expansive rear patio for gracious entertaining. The flowing single-level floorplan has 3bds and oceanview study.Gourmet kitchen features Viking range, SubZero refrig, wine chiller, Casa Esmeralda granite w/Walker-Zanger backsplash,Venetian blown glass pendant lights&amp;ample walk-in pantry. Other highlights incl dramatic outdoor fire features, gleaming oak plank floors, Carrera marble master bath, Lutron elect. shades, comprehensive sound system/smart house technology.Homeowners in the oceanfront comm.of Monarch Bay enjoy 24hr gate guard,tennis,&amp;membership in the private Bay Club-operated by the St. Regis. This is casual elegance and resort living at its best! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $3,750,000 3 Beds 3 Baths 2,780 SqFt 
MLS# S684148
 
Dana Point 35221 Beach Rd
 Highly desireable location with fantastic beach, lots of sand, plenty of parking and two wonderful decks to enjoy all of the sites and sounds of the ocean. Wide open floor plan with new tile flooring and two bedrooms on both the 1st and 2nd floor. Beautifully remodeled downstairs bathroom, new sliders/windows and window coverings on the first floor beach side. Pride of ownership throughout and ready to move in and enjoy. Maybe you&apos;ll catch a glimpse of the Killer Whales recently seen on the news, but for sure dolphins are regular visitors. Very unique Beach Front community with 24 hour gate guard and security patrol plus private beach to enjoy your favorite cocktail. After a hard day of swimming, surfing, biking, jet skiing, fishing or just a long walk, relax in your private hot tub located on the privacy deck View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $3,495,000 4 Beds 2 Baths 2,221 SqFt 
MLS# S698559
 
Dana Point 24662 El Camino Capistrano
 WOW!! Rare opportunity to own the only estate with guest house on Dana Point Bluff. 4 bedroom, 3.5 bath and dens. Stunning contemporary gated estate on the Dana Point Bluff designed on 3 levels with an elevator and remarkable unobstructed views of ocean and Dana Point Harbor. This elegant home has a great flow for entertaining which includes 4 decks, outdoor jacuzzi, wine room, numerous carved glass inserts in walls and stairways. Gourmet kitchen with Gagganau and Miele appliences, fabulous living room with glass/metal fireplace, 18 foot ceiling heights and travertine floors. Master bedroom retreat spans entire 3rd level and has sitting room, fireplace and office. Separate guest house includes 2 bedrooms, 2 baths with same quality features as main home with deck and ocean views. Inspired by Richard Meier Michigan home. No HOA or mello roos! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $3,495,000 4 Beds 4 Baths 4,500 SqFt 
MLS# S690791
 
Dana Point 34282 Shore Lantern
 Unbelievable custom home with panoramic ocean and sunset views in this 24 hour guard-gated community. Absolute dream kitchen for the chef with beautiful granite and state of the art appliances looking out to the ocean. Thoughtfully designed for entertaining, the open floorplan, soaring ceilings and skylights are breathtaking. No detail was spared in this amazing home including the master suite with separate bonus area and beautiful resort like bath. The extra wide lot enhances the views and open feeling of the home. Easy walking distance to beaches, restaurants, shopping&amp;Marina and just minutes from world class resorts. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $3,475,000 5 Beds 5 Baths 5,687 SqFt 
MLS# S686583
 
Dana Point 35401 Beach RD
 Perfect Beach Cottage. Don&apos;t let the size fool you, the home has the best use of space. One of the best lots on Beach Road with plenty of beach front and parking. Tearing down is an option, if you want bigger, but not necessary since home was completely remodeled 6 years ago. District fees yearly $1765.35 Additional parking exclusive to this homeowner $50.00 per year View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $3,295,000 3 Beds 2 Baths 1,300 SqFt 
MLS# S693151
 
Dana Point 35165 Beach Rd
 Very unique side-by-side duplex on the sand with upgrades, plenty of parking, two bedrooms on the water and two beautiful ocean front decks. Use as a single family home with adjoining door, rent one side and use the other, rent both sides or build close to a 5000 sq ft home on a huge lot. The possibilities are endless. Located in the exclusive Capistrano Bay gate guarded community with 7x24 Security Patrol. Many recent upgrades including new roof, exterior paint, interior remodeling which makes this turnkey and ready to enjoy. Each side has 3 bedrooms, 2 bathrooms and a full kitchen. Private Beach that you own to the mean high tide line! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $2,995,000 6 Beds 4 Baths 2,002 SqFt 
MLS# S691464
 
Dana Point 35577 Beach Rd
 Hughly Desirable Ocean Front Property!!! Direct beach access from the private back balcony!! Enjoy the amazing 180 degree, unobstructed ocean front views from this amazing home! Located in one of the highest sought streets in south Orange County with one of the widest lots (47.69 feet) in the tract. 24 guard gated community, recently remodeled interior with tons of upgrades. Seperate 1 bed 1 bath room off the garage (not counted for in listing). This amazing beach front property is absolutely turnkey and a STANDARD SALE!! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $2,990,000 2 Beds 2 Baths 1,200 SqFt 
MLS# L38255
 
Dana Point 34332 COVE LANTERN
 It&apos;s amazing how the Southern California Coast gets into your blood. Another sun-drenched morning overlooking the Dana Point Harbor. You breathe deeply and think, It&apos;s a slice of PARADISE and It&apos;s HOME. This beautiful modern constructed(built in 2000) Mediterranean Styled Lantern Bay Estate is situated a stones throw from the harbor and features a fantastic wide open floorplan and: approx. 5,285 sq. ft. of living space with 5 Beds 3.5 Baths, 3 car garage with rare long driveway, spectacular Ocean/Coastline/Harbor&amp;City Lights Views, lush mature landscape with tropical palm trees throughout yard, awesome private pool and spa, 28 ft. high cathedral-vaulted ceilings in living room, modern ergonomic fixtures and convenient electronics which include: security system, intercom, automatic timers and is situated on one of the largest corner lots(over 12,000 feet) in the Estates. Don&apos;t miss this rare chance to own a beautiful Lantern Bay Estate.&apos;COME EXPERIENCE THE LANTERN BAY LIFE-STYLE!!!&apos; View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $2,969,000 5 Beds 4 Baths 5,285 SqFt 
MLS# S697907
 
Dana Point 32571 Caribbean Dr
 HUGO SORIA OF LAGUNA BEACH DESIGNED THIS HOME....Stunning! Enter double doors into the atrium oasis with interconnecting koi ponds to reach the foyer. This awe inspiring contemporary home features floor to ceiling windows which display the panoramic ocean and hillside views in the open-living design. Note the sand blasted marble floors in the foyer and great room. The four bedrooms are situated in a way that each feels as if it rests in its own wing. A private courtyard featuring an outdoor fountain connects two bedrooms and a spacious family room. Three level deck with spa, sunning and eating decks and never ending views make this home an entertainer&apos;s gem. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $2,950,000 4 Beds 3 Baths 3,100 SqFt 
MLS# L39231
 
Dana Point 18 POINTE MONARCH Dr
 Pointe Monarch - This impeccably detailed, five bedroom, five and one-half bath family home is ideally located within the private gated community of Pointe Monarch on a premiere lot with phenomenal views of the St. Regis Resort and golf course. A gourmet chef s kitchen features top-of-the-line stainless steel appliances, granite countertops, center island along with a breakfast nook. The kitchen opens up to a spacious family room with built-in media niche with French doors that open to an utterly amazing rear yard. The rear yard with exquisitely sculpted hardscape and landscape features a swimming pool, separate and oversized Jacuzzi spa, sunken outdoor covered loggia with fireplace and built-in flat panel television niche, built-in barbeque, and an enclosed private outdoor shower. The master suite features a fireplace, retreat, spacious balcony with golf course and ocean views. There are numerous upgrades of finishes and detail to this must-see, fabulous home. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $2,850,000 5 Beds 6 Baths 5,314 SqFt 
MLS# S703163
 
Dana Point 432 Monarch Bay Dr
 Step into Panoramic Ocean and Catalina views in the prestigious gate guarded ocean front community of Monarch Bay. This single story home offers the essence of casual elegance and beach living at its finest with 3 bedrooms and 3 baths. Quality features include gourmet kitchen with double oven and refrigerator, spacious family room with fireplace and seperate casita with stunning ocean views! Other amenities include wood beam ceilings, crown moulding, neutral paint and carpet, window coverings, recessed lighting and fireplace in master bedroom. Situated on a quiet 7,600 sq ft lot with private quarters and lush surroundings, including mature palm trees and tropical flowers. Experience magnificent ocean and white water views. Monarch Bay homeowners enjoy private beach access, 24 hour gate guarded security, tennis and membership to the distinguished Monarch Bay Beach Club! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $2,799,000 3 Beds 3 Baths 2,300 SqFt 
MLS# S694049
 
Dana Point 34605 Camino Capistrano
 Spectacular ocean views! One of the best locations on the bluff in Capo Beach. Panoramic views from the Southern Coastline to San Clemente Island to Catalina Island and all of the Dana Point Harbor. Fantastic night light views as well. This custom property is turnkey and loaded with amenities. Only the best quality and materials utilized throughout including Subzero refrigerator, gas Viking range and oven, electric Viking convection oven, wet bar with Uline refrigerator and ice maker, dual pane Pella windows, security and fire alarms, Cat 5 wiring, built-in speakers, 2 extra large storage areas, Lynx stainless steel BBQ with built-in granite top, gas fire pit, 4 fireplaces, 3 outdoor water fountains , 5 ton air conditioning system and 100 gallon water heater. Four bedrooms all with their own baths and walk in closets. A grand master suite with beautiful master bath, a private balcony and spa. You won&apos;t want to miss this absolutely stunning home, must see to appreciate! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $2,749,000 4 Beds 5 Baths 4,016 SqFt 
MLS# L38769
 
Dana Point 127 Monarch Bay Dr
 Enhanced by ocean and Catalina views, 127 Monarch Bay Dr. presents a rare 1-level design of approx. 3,400 s.f. Blending a hint of mid-century flair with contemporary style, the home reveals a courtyard with fountain; large-scale living areas; 4 bedrooms (2 with courtyard access) and 4 baths; and chef&apos;s kitchen with ocean views, Dacor appliances, and Sub-Zero refrigerator. Glass doors in dining and den open to the patio; 2 fireplaces with granite and/or limestone hearths; sound system throughout living room and den; motorized opaque blinds; ambient ceiling lighting; 9&apos;ceilings; garage parking for 2; and 18&apos;Coliseum Stone floors throughout are also featured. A fireplace-warmed master suite offers patio access to spa and fire pit; oversized garden shower; and dual vanities. A 10,000 s.f. corner homesite enhances a Pebble Tech pool and spa surrounded by a stone patio, outdoor fireplace, and BBQ station with oversized 9&apos;double counter bar and seating for over 10. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $2,695,000 4 Beds 4 Baths 3,434 SqFt 
MLS# S703975
 
Dana Point 34342 Port Lantern
 Located within the guard gated community of Lantern Bay Estates, this Mediterranean inspired home delivers riveting Dana Point Harbor views as well as sweeping coastline and city light views. Extensively remodeled with quality craftsmanship in mind, this 4br home with 1br&amp;bath on the main level features extensive use of solid slab travertine, marble, granite, rich wood floors as well as artisan wrought iron details. Adding to this home&apos;s current features is a handsome library as well as an elegant wine room (libray could convert to a 5th bedroom). Featuring ocean&amp;harbor views the chef&apos;s kitchen which opens to the family room and wine bar is fully equipped with top-of-the-line appliances, custom cabinetry, granite counter tops and a spacious center island. A grand master suite includes a beverage and entertainment center, cozy fireplace, view deck and a travertine&amp;marble finished master bath featuring heated floors, spa tub and walk in shower. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $2,695,000 5 Beds 5 Baths 4,300 SqFt 
MLS# S683468
 
Dana Point 32451 Seven Seas DR
 Rustic Italian elegance of over 4,300 sq. ft.. This one of a kind villa features 5 bed,office and 5 baths of luxurious amenities. Two master suites, one on the main floor, and the second master on split level with Catalina Island views. This manor is enhanced with all the fine qualities a custom home deserves. Rich wood covers the walls and arched openings, solid Mahogany doors, distressed walnut flooring, and the Italian travertine flows from the entrance throughout the home. Kitchen designed for the person with an appreciation for the culinary arts. Thermador chefs range and oven, Fisher&amp;Paykel dishwasher drawers, sub zero refrigerator and slide out refrigerator/freezer drawers, center island and lava flow granite counters. Separate office with ocean views. Laudry and Hobbie room. Window walls open to a gigantic lot with playground, pool, spa, waterfalls and seating for 20 around the fire pit. Directions Crown Valley or PCH to Seven Seas View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $2,499,000 5 Beds 5 Baths 4,391 SqFt 
MLS# S702692
 
Dana Point 34302 Shore Lantern
 Designed by architect John McInnes and built in 1991 this Mediterranean classic delights in architectural splendor and graceful elegance. Intended to capture this exceptional view the home features walls of glass and skylights producing an abundance of natural light and amazing views of Dana Point Harbor and coast towards San Diego. This exclusive 3 bedroom, 4.5 bath estate is situated in the gate guarded community of Lantern Bay Estates within close proximity to the Harbor. Approximately 5200 sq. ft. with numerous architectural elements created reflecting quality craftsmanship at every turn built using the hightest quality materials. Be in awe as you approach through an impressive grand entry and generous open floor plan. This custom designed home features a lower level with it&apos;s own Chart Room and an elevator for ease of entry. Relax and experience this Lantern Bay lifestyle with easy walking distance to beaches, shops, restaurants and Marina. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $2,495,000 3 Beds 5 Baths 5,215 SqFt 
MLS# S662729
 
Dana Point 32703 Caspian Sea Dr
 Art Collectors spacious, single level home. Magnificent Monarch Bay Terrace home is perched on a spacious 16,032SF lot. Spectacular SIT-DOWN Whitewater views from Salt Creek Beach to Catalina, Views include COASTLINE, Ritz Carlton, Monarch Beach Golf Links, and Saint Regis. The extraordinary courtyard allows for a tranquil walk to the front door where views of the Pacific are beckoning. Hickory hardwood floors, Anderson double paned wood windows, doors, custom moldings and high quality designer hardware, allowing for a seamless panoramic ocean view from most rooms. Italian glass tile has been used on the front of the fireplace in the living room and hall bath room. The stunning sun-filled and inviting kitchen features the finest in modern architectural appeal featuring cherry cabinets, leathered granite counter tops. The gourmet chef will enjoy the Bertazzoni Gas 6 burner cook top and oven. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $2,295,000 4 Beds 3 Baths 2,901 SqFt 
MLS# L39083
 
Dana Point 32491 ADRIATIC Dr
 Located in Monarch Bay Terrace with panoramic ocean views, this completely remodeled and absolutely stunning single story home has it all. Enter through the front gated courtyard with soothing fountain to a wonderful floor plan. This 3 or 4 bedroom home has a separate living room, family room and dining room. The gourmet kitchen with custom cabinetry and high end appliances also has an informal dining area with French doors that lead to the outside custom Lynx grilling island. Formal dining and living room has large picture windows that take in the big ocean and coastline view. All the interior and exterior details are of the finest quality. Hardwood doors and windows throughout. The master bedroom with large lavish bath is just off the patio where a soothing salt spa and rock fountain awaits. All of this in wonderful Monarch Bay Terrace, close to great shopping, beaches and 5 star resorts. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $2,295,000 4 Beds 4 Baths 2,810 SqFt 
MLS# S695093
 
Dana Point 32462 Crete Rd
 Offering solace and escape within its borders this luxurious Monarch Bay Terrace pool home provides breathtaking ocean, Monarch Beach Links golf course and city light views. Inside the home is graced with many artisan finishes articulating the home&apos;s natural grace and attention to detail. Spanning almost 3400Sqft, this two story design invites the outdoors in to reveal elegant limestone flooring, tongue&amp;grove wood paneled ceilings, faux finished wall, numerous picture windows in prime locations, art niches, contemporary lighting and stone finished bathrooms. In addition to 3 spacious bedrooms, the upstairs loft/bonus room can also serve as the 4th bedroom which includes a three quarter slate bathroom, custom built-in and dual work spaces. Outside, one can enjoy several private patios with ocean, gold course and city light views. The oversized garage provides ample space for up to four vehicles. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $2,200,000 4 Beds 4 Baths 3,392 SqFt 
MLS# S669159
 
Dana Point 34887 Doheny Pl
 Views beyond your wildest expectations. From the San Clemente pier to the Dana Point Harbor. This bluff front house has the best view in Orange County. Located on a secluded street, next to charming Pines Park. A dramatic two story entry leads to this amazing home. The first floor has large family room, 2 guest bedrooms, office, and a wet bar with paned windows looking into the inner couryard. The upper floor has the kitchen, dining room, massive living room, master bedroom suite, powder room, and laundry room. The whole house looks at the Pacific Ocean, If your pleasure is watching dolphins, whales, pelicans in flight, sunsets, fireworks, or just checking out the waves this is your house. Your search for the good life ends here.The long gated driveway has room to park 8 cars or an RV or Boat. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $2,196,000 3 Beds 4 Baths 3,890 SqFt 
MLS# S701985
 
Dana Point 48 Monarch Bay Dr
 Single story with beautiful ocean views in guard gated Monarch Bay. 3,243 sq. ft. estate with 3 bedrooms + office/library and 3 baths. Gated courtyard off the formal dining room. Great room with fireplace, numerous French doors and panoramic ocean views. Situated on a small, quiet cul-de-sac on the ocean side of PCH. Spacious&amp;private backyard with a pool and spa. One of the largest lots in the community. Monarch Bay offers a private beach club, beach, clubhouse, and tennis courts. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $2,000,000 3 Beds 3 Baths 3,246 SqFt 
MLS# L37900
 
Dana Point 17 Monarch Bay Dr
 This elegant Fred Briggs design contemporay home has spectacular white water views of Salt Creek Beach overlooking the Ritz Carlton Hotel. This prime corner lot offers privacey and is next to the communtiy tennis court.A single level floorplan that has a huge living room that perfect for entertaining.This living room has marvelous white water views,as well as vistas of the beach and cliffs. There is a thrid bedroon that is brand new with a new 3/4 bath and private entrance. It leads to a patio area off the house. Inside this warm home are two suites and a large den/family room.Tiled two car garage with lots of storage as well as an additional Sub-Zero refrigerator/freezer. Extra parking space to side of garage perfect for your golf cart to go to the beach.Enjoy security and privacy in this guard-gated comm.This property includes membership in the spectacular private oceanfront Monarch Bay Beach Club. Never again will a special place be bulit like this in Southern California View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,995,000 3 Beds 4 Baths 3,500 SqFt 
MLS# S704538
 
Dana Point 20 Monarch Bay Dr
 ENDLESS VIEWS! This gorgeous single-level, four bedroom, four bathroom custom home is a part of one of Southern California&apos;s most desirable communities. Live in paradise with ocean and sunset views from almost every room. The chef&apos;s dream kitchen offers a big island with premuim stainless steel applicances and granite counter tops. Both the executive dining room and formal living room areas have dramatic fireplaces. Wake up every morning in the master bedroom, to a ocean view oasis, with an over-sized walk-in closet and a terrific updated bathroom. The large laundry room has an extra storage area. A quaint Jack&amp;Jill bathroom joins two spacious bedrooms together. The 4th bedroom has its very own full bathroom. Enjoy your morning coffee in the beautifully landscaped atrium and look forward to spending your evenings watching the sunset from your private back yard. Monarch Bay offers a beautiful beach with a private beach club. Live in a resort! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,995,000 4 Beds 3 Baths 3,450 SqFt 
MLS# L37942
 
Dana Point 24 Monarch Bay Dr
 A beautiful traditional styled view home on just over one quarter acre in the gated oceanfront community of Monarch Bay. Spacious floor plan with large open rooms&amp;walls of glass. Appx 1 1/2 blocks to the beach with some whitewater, beach&amp;ocean views(potential for more). Kitchen opens to a large family room&amp;fireplace with oversized hearth. Spacious patio with electric awnings&amp;spa for entertaining. Gracious master suite with beautiful wood work. Separate laundry room. Two car garage. Home is situated well on the lot for abundance of light and privacy. 24 hour guard gated community. Association tennis. Private beach club on the sand offering continental dining, cocktail lounge, surf butlers&amp;beach parking is only $10 per month for residents. Only 214 homes in the community which is adjacent to the St. Regis&amp;Ritz Carlton Hotels.Financing is available to qualified buyers. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,895,000 3 Beds 3 Baths 3,066 SqFt 
MLS# L39142
 
Dana Point 415 Monarch Bay
 Breathtaking ocean and beach views from this four bedroom home located in the exclusive oceanfront community of Monarch Bay. First time on the market, this mid-century residence presents a very short walk to the beach and Monarch Bay Beach Club while also offering its own unique park-like grounds and expansive lawn. All major rooms offer views of the ocean including the large covered lanai. The Cul de Sac location provides an abundance of outdoor spaces. The gated community of Monarch Bay provides a rare opportunity to have direct access to one of the most picturesque beaches on the South Orange County Coast. Golf, tennis, surfing, restaurants, shopping and the amentities of two five star resorts are within walking distance. This particular home is located in the desirable&apos;mall&apos;location of the community. Great opportunity in an oceanfront community. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,895,000 4 Beds 3 Baths 
MLS# S704580
 
Dana Point 33912 Granada Dr
 Lantern Village Home with panoramic white water, coastline and city light views on a street-to-street wide lot. An entertainer&apos;s dream home with ocean views from every level. Entertain in the main level kitchen, living room with custom library, deck or lower level family room that leads to an endless pool and another view deck. The kitchen is a Chef&apos;s dream with custom cabinets, glass doors, recessed lighting, two sinks, upgraded stainless steel appliances, and ocean Views! The master bedroom has two separate bathrooms, custom granite and cork fireplace, and view deck. This 3500 square foot, 5 Bedroom/5 Bath home on a 9000 square foot lot has vaulted ceilings, brazilian cherry flooring, recessed and custom lighting throughout, central vacuum, and laundry chute. Enjoy cozy nights with the three fireplaces made of Custom Cork and granite. Private gated entrance, large deck and patios. This home is walking distance to town and to the famous Strands Beach surrounded by $15M+ Homes. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,695,000 5 Beds 5 Baths 3,500 SqFt 
MLS# S703091
 
Dana Point 16 Terraza Del Mar
 Modeled-Perfect panoramic ocean and hills view on the most sought after largest lot in Terraza del Mar with unobstructed views. The main house has 3 bedrooms plus a detached casita acting as a 4th bedroom or office, with full bath. Award winning architecture with privacy abounding. Enjoy indoor-outdoor entertaining year round. Pool, spa, grassy area, BBQ, fire pit and total luxury! The home and pool have been recently upgraded. Terraza Del Mar is a small gated enclave of 36 Mediterranean homes located approx. 3 miles from the beach and Dana Point Harbor. Located close to beaches, harbor, shopping and entertainment... View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,650,000 4 Beds 4 Baths 3,000 SqFt 
MLS# L38720
 
Dana Point 42 Monarch Bay Dr
 Enjoy beautiful coastline views from this single level custom home located across the street from the oceanfront in Monarch Bay. This corner lot allows abundance of light and privacy. Open beam ceilings in living room with spectacular views and woodburning fireplace. Open floor plan. Library/den could easily be 4th bedroom. Banquet sized formal dining room with adjacent wet bar. Large master suite. Ocean view kitchen with breakfast nook&amp;BI work area. Entry opens to large enclosed courtyard. Large laundry room off kitchen. Monarch Bay is a gatede oceanfront community of 214 homes with association tennis and a private beach club currently operated by the St. Regis Hotel&amp;Spa. Bay Club membership is $30 paid quarterly. There is beach parking, gourmet dining, surf butlers beach activities and more. Ownership is leasehold with a negotiated buyout provision. Please call for clarification. Dues quoted for association are yearly. Financing is available to qualified buyers. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,535,000 3 Beds 3 Baths 2,863 SqFt 
MLS# S679188
 
Dana Point 34081 Blue Lantern St
 JUST REDUCED $150K!! 180 degree PANORAMIC white water ocean view in a highly upgraded home with numerous designer touches. The gorgeous Brazilian wood floors and open floor plan are a welcoming committee for this breathtaking panoramic ocean/coast/city views from every room. The dramatic view transform into a tranquil and suttle living experience. Other features include a large master ensuite w/steam shower. The additional two bedrooms offer plenty of storage and a upgraded/remodeled bath. Indoor laundry on your way to the private backayrd featuring slate patio and lush landscaping. This zen-like paradise completes the space for outdoor entertaining at its very best! The kitchen combines beautiful Italian wood cabinets and quartz counters with high-end appliances and built-in refrigerator. The studio is a sperate space for guests or an extension of the property offering an exceptionally large view deck for BBQ&apos;s and relaxing siestas with ocean breezes. Wine cellar and separate storage! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,499,000 4 Beds 3 Baths 2,450 SqFt 
MLS# S685924
 
Dana Point 34052 Chula Vista Ave
 Unbelievable price on this beautiful home w/stunning views!This 4bdrm 4&amp;a half bath home was completed in 2008&amp;includes attention to every detail. Gourmet kitchen w/blt in refridgerator w/cabinet matching doors, granite counters, bun warmer, water faucet over stove&amp;large walk in pantry. Just a few of the upgrades include high vaulted wood beamed ceilings, hand distressed walnut flooring&amp;stairs, dumbwaiter&amp;two fireplaces. The gorgeous exterior includes stone facade w/stone hardscape as well. Entertain in your backyard w/sounds of the bubbly fountain and a BBQ for outdoor eating or take in the breathtaking views from inside the home as well as sitting and relaxing on your deck. You won&apos;t want to miss this opportunity to live on one of best culdesac streets in Dana Point in a newer Tuscan style home that has been built with such quality and details, complete with coastline, ocean views, forever city lights and close to ocean. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,450,000 4 Beds 5 Baths 3,200 SqFt 
MLS# L38888
 
Dana Point 91 Palm Beach Ct
 BREATHTAKING AWESOME OCEAN, WHITEWATER, COASTLINE AND DANA POINT HARBOR VIEWS. FABULOUS CATALINA SUNSETS AND JUST STEPS TO ONE OF THE MOST SPECTACULAR BEACHES ALONG THE COASTLINE. ALL THIS AND MORE FROM A BEAUTIFULLY LANDSCAPED SETTING WITH FOUNTAINS AND FLOWERING GARDENS. A WARM INVITING CUSTOMIZED, EXPANDED INTERIOR WITH EXTENSIVE ATTENTION TO DETAILS. A DREAM KITCHEN SO LIGHT AND BRIGHT WITH BEAUTIFUL HAND CARVED CABINETRY, GRANITE COUNTERTOPS AND ISLAND, HARDWOOD FLOORS. A CHARMING OPEN FLOOR PLAN FOR FAMILY FUNCTIONS AND EASY ENTERTAINING. A GRACIOUS WELL MAINTAINED HOME WITH 3 BEDROOMS, 2 1/2 BATHS, FIREPLACE, VIEWING DECK AND THE SECURITY OF A GATED COMMUNITY. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,450,000 3 Beds 3 Baths 2,400 SqFt 
MLS# S698822
 
Dana Point 33941 Pequito Dr
 SIGNIFICANT PRICE REDUCTION! What a beach house! This home is all about the spectacular panoramic sit-down ocean, coastline, whitewater and sunset views from almost every room in this beautifully designed custom home. It`s an entertainers delight. The elegance is unsurpassed! Take the gorgeous stairway to heaven to the breathtaking evening city lights view. Dual master suites on each floor. Interior elevator that reaches each level of the home! Redwood exercise room with convertible spa beneath. Third level ocean view deck. Dual heating and air conditioning systems on each level. Birdseye Cherrywood Custom Closets in the Master Suite. Ocean view deck is prefect for relaxing and enjoying the beautiful ocean and sunset views. Central vac. Elevator supports disability access. Perfect to use as a dumb waiter. This property possibly could work for single story buyers who want amazing ocean views since the elevator will take them from the garage to all the other levels. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,399,000 3 Beds 3 Baths 2,711 SqFt 
MLS# S701379
 
Dana Point 33692 Holtz Hill Rd
 Spectacular coastal living in the exclusive gated community on Holtz Hill. Enjoy amazing panoramic ocean views from every room in this architectural masterpiece. 2900 sq. ft. of living space divided into three extraordinary levels. Enter the impressive Foyer with chisseled stone floors and exotic black wood accents. The stunning Dining Area captures coastine views from Dana Point Harbor, as far south as San Clemente. The contemporary stainless steel kitchen includes top of the line Viking appliances, black granite counters and super sleek wrap around bar. Just off the kitchen is the perfect home office for the busy executive. Step down into the main living area with black stained wood floors, stone fireplace, and flanking french doors which lead to courtyard and oceanview deck. The third level includes resort like Master Suite, Spa Bath, fireplace and private deck. Guest Bedroom with own bath and laundry area completes the lower level. Truly World Class Southern California Living. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,399,000 2 Beds 3 Baths 2,900 SqFt 
MLS# S700374
 
Dana Point 32502 Crete Rd
 One of the best ocean views on Crete Road. Views of The St. Regis, Monarch Beach Golf Links, Ritz Carlton and the Headlands. Enjoy cooking in the updated kitchen with granite counters and ocean and hills views. Kitchen opens to family room with romantic fireplace and views of the ocean and hills. Travertine floors throughout most of the main living areas. Formal living room with romantic fireplace. Charming vaulted wood ceilings. Newer windows and doors. Newer interior solid core doors. Enjoy summer days in your private pool that has newer pool equipment. Mature landscape throughout the property. Vinyl patio covers and additional drainage. Located on a single loaded street. This lovely home is ready to call home. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,325,000 3 Beds 3 Baths 2,347 SqFt 
MLS# S700263
 
Dana Point 34322 Amber Lantern St D
 BEAUTIFUL! Stunning ocean, coastline, Dana Point Harbor and Marina view! There is no other place like this gated community of The Admiralty in South Orange County. Living room with French Doors to the large balcony, granite fireplace and wetbar and a spacious dining area. The gourmet&apos;s kitchen features granite countertops, two dishwashers, wine cooler, SubZero refrigerator, Gaggenau gas range, breakfast bar and so much more! The master bedroom is downstairs and has a retreat with a private, wrap-around patio (unique to this unit), luxurious bath with his and hers walk-in closets. Features include double paned windows, security system, dumb waiter, Plantation shutters, central vacuum, walter filtration, recirculation hot water and so much more! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,300,000 2 Beds 3 Baths 2,778 SqFt 
MLS# S690039
 
Dana Point 33851 Valencia Pl
 Endless coastline&amp;ocean views from every corner of this exquisite luxury estate!Located on a desired&amp;rare street to steet lot.Gorgeous home boasts numerous distinctive&amp;outstanding design features.Enter throuth custom hardwood gate into a courtyard covered w/flagstone.Massive double doors greet you into a foyer that opens to spacious living room w/double coffered volume ceilings&amp;french doors.All doors&amp;windows have crafted wood casing.Custom color scheme throughout.Dining room w/vaulted ceiling,fireplace enhanced w/Caesar stone hearth&amp;glass mosaic surround.New gourmet kitchen features top of the line appliances,custom crafted cabinetry w/glass front doors,Caesar stone counters/glass back spash&amp;nook w/custom fitted seating.Master suite w/ panoramic ocean&amp;coastline views,fireplace ,wet bar,huge walk-in closet,balcony.Luxurious master bath,for that spa experience.Enjoy the loft with walls of glass exposing the beautiful pacific.Entertainer&apos;s dream yard w/BBQ,fire pit. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,299,000 4 Beds 3 Baths 3,100 SqFt 
MLS# S700075
 
Dana Point 15 Saint Francis
 Looking for PANORAMIC OCEAN, COASTLINE and CATALINA VIEWS?!! You&apos;ll have them from this FULLY REMODELED home in the gated Regatta community of Monarch Beach. Remodeled kitchen includes granite counter tops, all new appliances, and new cabinets. New double pane windows and doors throughout plus plantation shutters. The bathrooms have been remodeled, the laundry has been cleverly moved to a new inside room (laundry was in the garage),and there is a hidden closet in the family room that could also make a great wine cellar!! New fireplace mantels, epoxy garage floor, and resurfaced master view deck are still more of the upgrades to this view home. The floors have been replaced with travertine, wood, and carpet. Enjoy sunsets from within the home, from the master bedroom and view balcony, or while relaxing in the spa or sitting around the firepit in the backyard. This special home is not one to miss seeing! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,228,000 3 Beds 3 Baths 2,063 SqFt 
MLS# S691568
 
Dana Point 23 Los Monteros Dr
 GORGEOUS OCEAN VIEW Single story located in guard gated community of Monarch Beach! LESS than 2 blocks to the WAVES&amp;walking distance to the summer concerts in the park or GOLF. Oriented beautifully with a western facing backyard. Relax on the deck,enjoy WONDERFUL OCEAN&amp;CATALINA ISLAND views or unwind in the spa. Entry&amp;living room W/20 foot vaulted ceilings, Birchwood floors, atrium w/glass doors, tranquil fountain&amp;sitting area. Gourmet kitchen, granite counters, garden window&amp;breakfast island, a perfect kitchen setting&amp;adjoined to the family room with a cozy fireplace. Master has an view ocean, vaulted ceilings, romantic fireplace, cedar lined closets with built-ins. Master bath with beautiful granite counters, dual sinks, step-in shower&amp;Jacuzzi tub! Guest bedrooms include 1 with a bath&amp;other is ample size with coffered ceilings. Home is a PERFECT location for BEACH LOVER! Enjoy local access to St. Regis&amp;Ritz Carlton Hotels&amp;golf. START LIVING YOUR BEACH LIFE! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $1,049,999 3 Beds 3 Baths 2,576 SqFt 
MLS# S660358
 
Dana Point 26832 Calle Maria
 Panoramic Ocean and Catalina View! MASSIVE PRICE REDUCTION! This beautiful custom home has been remodeled top to bottom. It features wood and slate floors throughout the home, with granite counters in the kitchen and bathrooms, stainless steel appliances, custom window treatments and window casings, custom lighting and decorator finishes. There is a downstairs bedroom suite with it&apos;s own full bathroom. The large back yard is an entertainer&apos;s dream with an expanded, covered outdoor living room and even your own vegetable and herb garden! In the front yard, relax on the front porch or do some putting on your own putting green! Enjoy ocean views from the front yard, every bedroom and very spacious master balcony and huge rooftop deck. Welcome home! You will never want to leave! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $899,000 4 Beds 4 Baths 3,000 SqFt 
MLS# S696465
 
Dana Point 34091 Pequito Dr
 Ocean view home in the Lantern District at the end of a Cul-De-Sac. Large 7700 sq ft down slope lot with no one to block the view faces Doheny State Beach and a Southerly ocean view. Sand and White Water can be seen through the trees at Doheny Beach from a sit down interior or outside deck vantage point. Full View of 4th of July Fireworks in the night sky above and can be seen from deck or inside living areas. Built New in 2001 this 3 Bedroom 3.5 Bath home has many upgrades including: Kitchen with;Granite Counter Tops,Stainless Steel Appliances,Wood Floors throughout Upper Level.Wired Security System and Fire Sprinkler System. All 3 lower level bedrooms have their own baths with Travertine floors. Master Bedroom Bath has a large dressing area, walk in closet, dual sinks,Jacuzzi tub. Open And Bright w/Natural Light. 2 large patio decks for entertaining. Walk to EVERYTHING! Including the sand on the beach! Shops, Dining and Dana Point Harbor are just down the street. No Mello Roos No HOA View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $750,000 3 Beds 4 Baths 2,460 SqFt 
MLS# S701718
 
Dana Point 33671 BLUE LANTERN C
 SPECTAULAR OCEAN VIEW WITH COASTLINE AND WHITE WATER FROM MAIN LIVING AREA AND LARGE STONE DECK GREAT FOR ENTERTAINING; REMODELED THROUGHOUT; KITCHEN WITH GRANITE COUNTERS PLUS STAINLESS STEEL APPLAINCES, MASTER BATH WITH SPA TUB, TRAVETINE FLOORING, STONE COUNTERS AND TWO SINKS; MASTER BEDROOM WITH TWO WALK-IN CLOSETS; 3RD BEDROOM IS USED AS A LARGE FAMILY ROOM WITH BUILT-IN OAK BAR; LIVING ROOM HAS HIGH CEILINGS AND BUILT-IN TV; HARDWOOD AND STONE FLOORING; NEWER WINDOWS; WOOD SHUTTERS; LOW HOA&apos;S A MUST SEE STANDARD SALE View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $749,500 3 Beds 2 Baths 1,934 SqFt 
MLS# S697053
 
Dana Point 17 Saint Kitts
 Ocean View Home in prestigious Monarch Beach Gated Community. Prime Location! West-facing,light and bright with sunset views of Catalina and San Clemente Island. Just a short walk to beach and world famous resorts, The Ritz Carlton and St. Regis Hotel. Lush Tropical Landscape with Palm trees, colorful flowers and upgraded Malibu lighting. Largest Antigua floorplan PLUS owners added a fully permitted office. 3 bedrooms 2.5 bath plus and upstairs den. Upgraded gourmet kitchen with granite countertops, travertine backsplash and stainless steel appliances. Wood floors throughout downstairs. Wake up every morning to an awsome Ocean View from the Master Suite. Enjoy forever ocean breeze. A MUST SEE! RESORT STYLE LIVING AT IT&apos;S BEST! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $749,000 3 Beds 3 Baths 2,141 SqFt 
MLS# S704314
 
Dana Point 24552 Sand Piper Ln
 Wonderful unit with panoramic ocean and coastline views from almost every room. This end-unit townhouse features new carpet, paint, vaulted ceilings, plantation shutters and more. Main floor master bedroom. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $678,000 3 Beds 3 Baths 1,943 SqFt 
MLS# S700332
 
Dana Point 24272 Selva Rd
 Incredible single story Ocean View Beach Home nestled on one of the most prestigious streets in Dana Point. 3 bed 2 bath charmer that sits up high on a large flat buildable lot. Great potential to build on this lot. RV Parking with enough room for both an RV and Boat. Walking distance to the Strand at Headlands development, Strands Beach as well as the Ritz Carlton and St. Regis Luxury resorts. An incredible piece of property and a must see! The address of this property is Selva Rd, however it sits on Chula Vista. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $650,000 3 Beds 2 Baths 1,178 SqFt 
MLS# S693169
 
Dana Point 24606 Moonfire Dr 276
 Enjoy sunrises and sunsets from this Sea Ridge townhouse with panoramic ocean and coastline views. This lovely townhome features open floorplan, hardwood floors, vaulted ceilings, upgraded kitchen, and is steps to a pleasant green belt. Sea Ridge also features pool, spa, tennis, renovated clubhouse, and large greenbelt. Just over a mile from beautiful Dana Point Harbor. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $629,000 3 Beds 3 Baths 2,090 SqFt 
MLS# S698927
 
Dana Point 33152 Sea Knoll Dr
 ABSOLUTELY STUNNING SINGLE STORY OCEAN VIEW HOME IN AN AMAZING NEIGHBORHOOD! EVERYTHING NEW in this 1968 home. Gorgeous glass front door, tile floors w/granite in-lays. Living room w/custom mantle&amp;travertine fireplace. GOURMET kitchen has ALL NEW maple cabinets, soft close drawers&amp;pull outs. Frigidaire appliances that have barely been used. Imagine cooking a special dinner while gazing at the OCEAN! Both baths have been remolded with EXQUISITE taste! Extra bath has Travertine walls w/decorative boarder, stunning custom molding&amp;beautiful cabinets along with a shower&amp;European tub. The Master Bath is equally as elegant with granite, custom cabinet&amp;lovely custom tile boarder in the step in shower. Extra Bed has an AMAZING built-in armoire. Seller added an inside laundry area. Other FANTASTIC upgrades include, new roof, ducting/furnace/cooling system, water heater, windows, garage door/opener. NOTHING TO DO BUT MOVE IN!ALSO, INCREDIBLE OCEAN, CITY/HILLS VIEWS&amp;1 MILE TO THE BEACH View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $625,000 3 Beds 2 Baths 1,675 SqFt 
MLS# S692857
 
Dana Point 25432 Sea Bluffs Dr 206
 Gorgeous retirement living - ocean view and Dana Point views in this condo -two bedrooms, two bathrooms, newly painted, granite tile kitchen counter, fireplace, spacious balcony, and included in the Monthly dues: enjoy gourmet meals twice a day, weekly housekeeping, transportation to Doctor appointments, maintenance, utilities and lots of activites. Parking in underground structure. Second person fee applies... come see this wonderful lifestyle. Located about one mile to Dana Point harbor, highly desired The Fountains senior community. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $524,900 2 Beds 2 Baths 1,355 SqFt 
MLS# S701008
 
Dana Point 15 Wimbledon Ct
 Super Ocean, Catalina Sunsets, Golf Course VIEWS! Former Tennis Villa Model.Marble Floors, Sub-Zero Frig, Gas cook Top,Single LEVEL_NO STAIRS!!! Large Wrap-Around Private VIEW Patio. Master suite has 2 Closets, FRENCH DOORS, SPA TUB, DUAL VANTIES. WALK TO PRISTINE SHORES OF SALT CREEK/STRANDS BEACH, LINKS GOLF, TNNIS CLUB AT MONARCH BEACH. MINUTES TO DANA POINT HARBOR, ACROSS FROM ST. REGIS RESORT&amp;SPA.selling FULLY Furnished. Call agent for key location View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $495,000 2 Beds 2 Baths 1,200 SqFt 
MLS# S699436
 
Dana Point 33691 Blue Lantern ST C
 AWESOME OCEAN VIEWS and much much more!!! View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $479,000 2 Beds 3 Baths 1,391 SqFt 
MLS# S675023
 
Dana Point 33901 Mariana Dr 8
 Upgraded to perfection!! Ocean view condo! Equity Sale no waiting! All the work has been done for you. The kitchen has been totally remodeled. Gourmet kitchen with slab granite counter tops, gorgeous Omega maple cabinets. Stainless Steel appliances. Most the flooring has just been replaced, porecian tile, and upgraded carpet. The master bathroom was remodeled was Corastone, handblown glass sinks, owner spent 30k for the remodel. Large balony off the master suite, very private. Secondary bedroom is currently being used as an office. The family room has a two sided fireplace, very cozy for the fall and winter nights. Separate laundry room. Gated building with gated garage. There are only 12 units in this wonderful complex. View Details 
 Slideshow 
 $429,000 2 Beds 2 Baths 1,300 SqFt   
Last Updated: 2012-07-12 17:30:43

The information being provided by CARETS (CLAW, CRISNet MLS, DAMLS, CRMLS, i-Tech MLS, and/or VCRDS) is for the visitor&apos;s personal, non-commercial use and may not be used for any purpose other than to identify prospective properties visitor may be interested in purchasing.

Any information relating to a property referenced on this web site comes from the Internet Data Exchange (IDX) program of CARETS. This web site may reference real estate listing(s) held by a brokerage firm other than the broker and/or agent who owns this web site.

The accuracy of all information, regardless of source, including but not limited to square footages and lot sizes, is deemed reliable but not guaranteed and should be personally verified through personal inspection by and/or with the appropriate professionals. The data contained herein is copyrighted by CARETS, CLAW, CRISNet MLS,

DAMLS, CRMLS, i-Tech MLS and/or VCRDS and is protected by all applicable copyright laws. Any dissemination of this information is in violation of copyright laws and is strictly prohibited.

CARETS, California Real Estate Technology Services, is a consolidated MLS property listing data feed comprised of CLAW (Combined LA/Westside MLS), CRISNet MLS (Southland Regional AOR), DAMLS (Desert Area MLS), CRMLS (California Regional MLS), i-Tech MLS (Glendale AOR/Pasadena Foothills AOR) and VCRDS (Ventura County Regional Data Share).
 

 
Areas of Service

 Aliso Viejo Cardiff By The Sea Carlsbad Corona del Mar Coronado Costa Mesa Coto de Caza Dana Point Del Mar Encinitas Huntington Beach Irvine Ladera Ranch La Jolla Laguna Beach Laguna Niguel Mission Viejo Newport Beach Newport Coast Oceanside Rancho Santa Fe San Clemente San Juan Capistrano Solana Beach San Diego Talega 
 
Dana Point MLS

 Dana Point MLS Home Search 

Dana Point Homes

 Dana Point Beach Front Homes Dana Point Bluff Front Homes Dana Point Ocean Front Homes Dana Point Water Front Homes Dana Point Gated Community Homes 

Dana Point View Homes

 Dana Point Ocean View Homes Dana Point Coastline View Homes Dana Point Canyon View Homes Dana Point Catalina Island Views Dana Point Pier View Homes Dana Point Harbor View Homes Dana Point Water View Homes Dana Point Golf Course View Homes Dana Point White Water View Homes Dana Point Panoramic View Homes 

Dana Point Map

 Dana Point Map Search for ALL Dana Point Homes for Sale In Dana Point 

Dana Point Home Sales

 Dana Point Home Sales - 2011 

Dana Point Short Sales

 Dana Point Short Sale Homes For Sale Dana Point Ocean View Short Sales Dana Point Coastline View Short Sales 

Dana Point Foreclosures

 Dana Point Forelcousres For Sale Dana Point Ocean View Forelcousres Dana Point Coastline View Forelcousres 

Dana Point Rentals

 Dana Point Rental Homes For Lease Dana Point Beach Front Rental Homes Dana Point Ocean View Rental Homes Dana Point Ocean Front Rental Homes 

Capistrano Beach Neighborhoods

 Beach Road - Capistrano Beach California Homes - Dana Point Camino Heights - Dana Point Capistrano Bluffs - Dana Point Capistrano Heights - Dana Point Custom Homes - Capistrano Beach Dana Bluffs - Dana Point Harbor Walk - Dana Point Marbella Racquet Club - Dana Point Mill Pond - Dana Point Palisades - Dana Point Sea Bluff Villas - Dana Point 

Lantern Village Neighborhoods

 Admiralty - Dana Point Beach Cottage - Dana Point Bluffside Villas - Dana Point Casa Dana - Dana Point Dana Light - Dana Point Diamond Ridge Estates - Dana Point Harbor Cove - Dana Point Headlands - Dana Point Lantern Bay Estates - Dana Point Lantern Bay Villas - Dana Point Lantern Village Central - Dana Point Lantern Village South - Dana Point Lantern Village Custom - Dana Point Lantern Village Homes - Dana Point Las Marianas - Dana Point Marina Vista - Dana Point Sea Ridge Homes - Dana Point 

Monarch Beach Neighborhoods

 Ritz Cove - Dana Point The Strand at Headlands- Dana Point Antigua - Monarch Beach Broadmoor Homes - Monarch Beach California Cortina - Monarch Beach Cape Cove - Monarch Beach Chelsea Point - Monarch Beach Corniche Sur Mer - Monarch Beach Emerald Ridge - Monarch Beach Estates At Monarch Beach - Monarch Beach Gardens Inland - Monarch Beach Gardens Ocean Side - Monarch Beach Marquesa - Monarch Beach Monarch Bay - Monarch Beach Monarch Bay Terrace - Monarch Beach Monarch Bay Villas - Monarch Beach Monarch Hills Condos - Monarch Beach Montego in Monarch Beach Niguel Beach Terrace - Monarch Beach Niguel Shores - Monarch Beach Pacific Island Villas - Monarch Beach Pointe Monarch - Monarch Beach Regatta - Monarch Beach Ritz Pointe - Monarch Beach Sea Village at St Regis - Monarch Beach Sea Villas at St Regis - Monarch Beach Tennis Villas - Monarch Beach Townhomes-Seaterrace - Monarch Beach Niguel Shores Villas - Monarch Beach Niguel Shores Villas II - Monarch Beach 

Dana Hills Neighborhoods

 Dana By The Sea - Dana Point Dana Crest - Dana Point Dana Light I - Dana Point Dana Vista - Dana Point Dana Woods - Dana Point Dk Properties - Dana Point Encantamar Condos - Dana Point Harbor Heights-Danawoods - Dana Point Lantern Hill - Dana Point Marinita Townhomes - Dana Point Marluna - Dana Point Point Vista - Dana Point Sea Knoll - Dana Point Silvertide - Dana Point Sunset Hill - Dana Point Terraza Del Mar - Dana Point Thunderbird Capistrano - Dana Point Thunderbird West - Dana Point Waterford Point Homes - Dana Point 

Del Obispo Neighborhoods

 Dana Knolls - Dana Point Harbor Creek - Dana Point 
 

 
 
Beach Cities Real Estate
3991 MacArthur Blvd. Suite 400
Newport Beach, CA 92660

301 Forest Avenue
Laguna Beach, CA 92651

163 Avenida Del Mar
San Clemente, CA 92672

7825 Fay Avenue Suite 200
La Jolla, CA 92037

California DRE License # 01290508 
Real Estate Services

 BCRE Agent Search Commercial Real Estate Property Management Contact Beach Cities Website Sign In 
 
Short Sale Homes

 Dana Point Short Sales Huntington Beach Laguna Beach Short Sales Newport Beach Short Sales San Clemente Short Sales 
 
Luxury Homes

 Pelican Hill Pelican Crest Emerald Bay
	</body>
</document>
