<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009248" url="http://www.menuism.com/restaurants/franks-famous-family-restaurant-palmetto-37754" time="2012-07-13-02:38" support="6" score="0.022555996908822262" bingtitle="Frank&apos;s Famous Family Restaurant - Reviews &amp; Menu - Palmetto 30268" webtitle="Frank&apos;s Famous Family Restaurant - Reviews&amp;Menu - Palmetto 30268">
			<query id="000793" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000790" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000807" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000811" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000799" bing-rank="86"/>
	<description>... Family Restaurant is a American, Diner, and Fast Food restaurant ... attached to a Citgo, just off a rather lonely exit between the Atlanta Airport and Newnan – this place ...</description>
	<body>
		Menuism - Restaurant and dish reviews 
 Explore Restaurant Reviews&amp;Menus 
 Restaurants Near Me Make Online Reservations Order Delivery&amp;Takeout Restaurant Week Directory Popular Cities Popular Chains What&apos;s Menu ism ? Monthly Review Contest 
 Remember Personal Dining Journal 
 My Favorites My Try List My Photos Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 
 Learn Foodie Education Blog 
 Food Primers Exclusive Interviews 
 
 FIND AROUND GO 
 Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 

 Not a member? To save, rate, and share reviews, sign up! Already a member? Log in (OpenID) Connect with Facebook 
 
 larger map / directions 
 
 - Actions - Write a Review Add to Try List Add to Favorites Suggest Corrections Upload Pics 

 - Pages - The Restaurant Map/Directions Dishes/Menu 
 Palmetto Restaurants » American » Frank&apos;s Famous Family Restaurant Share | 
Frank&apos;s Famous Family Restaurant
 
 4.66667 star rating           
  4.7 rating over 3 reviews 
 (770) 463-5678 

 1188 Collinsworth Rd ( ) 

 Palmetto , GA 30268-9426 

 View Nearby Businesses» 
 Send to Phone Email Listing Print Listing   
 View Menu Website Read Reviews (3) View Map/Directions 
 
 Information From the Restaurant Offers 
 
 Description:  Frank&apos;s Famous Family Restaurant is a American , Diner , and Fast Food restaurant where most Menuism users came for fun with friends , paid between $10 and $25 , and tipped more than 18% . Tags: American, Diner, Fast Food, Greek, Italian, Southern, Good For Kids, Takeout, and Good for groups Stats: 
 1 dish entered by diners at Frank&apos;s Famous Family Restaurant 
 
 
Nothing yet.
 
 Do you own Frank&apos;s Famous Family Restaurant? Contact us to connect with your diners. 
 
 Suggest Corrections/Menu 
 
Reviews for Frank&apos;s Famous Family Restaurant
 Write a review 
 3 reviews First reviewed by dhurstman 
 
 2 helpful votes over 3 reviews 
 dhurstman 
 3 Restaurant Reviews +2 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Frank&apos;s Famous Family Restaurant dhurstman 
 October 6, 2008 
 4.0 
 4.0 star rating           
 0 0 0 0 Votes   
Best &apos;Atlanta Southside - hole-in-the-wall&apos; Restaurant
 
We decided to visit Frank’s based on a Friend’s recommendation. The first time we went a couple things surprised us. How small the place was (since enlarged), and seeing several of the top Management folks from Chic-fil-A there. Then came to biggest surprise. The‘specials’menu was outstanding! For a little non-descript restaurant attached to a Citgo, just off a rather lonely exit between the Atlanta Airport and Newnan–this place was a real find. We have since been back several times and it has become one of our favorites. I once asked Frank (the Greek owner), why one of his signature dishes–the Greek Chicken–(very tender chicken breast grilled–with distinct oregano and lemon flavors served with a yellow rice that inludes very fresh Feta cheese) was so good. He responded,“because the chicken is FRESH …!”Apparently he get’s his chicken, and probably other meats and produce, for local houses.
 
Dishes I tried:
 
Greek Chicken
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
Possibly the best Greek Chicken I’ve ever had…!
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply Cherri S 
 from Insider Pages 
 
September 10, 2009
 
 5 star rating           
 
Frank&apos;s Famous Family Rstrnt is a must find.
 
This is the best hidden secret around. The portions are enormous. The Philly cheesesteak is delicious. The Greek salad is a must try. And the deserts are all wonderful.

 read full review» 
 Joaquin R. 
 from Judy&apos;sBook 
 
November 14, 2006
 
 5 star rating           
 
I&apos;m so excited to try it
 
Hello, I&apos;m visiting Serenbe in South Fulton right now and although I haven&apos;t tried Frank&apos;s I have heard all about it! I&apos;m headed there now and don&apos;t know if I will try the lasagna or the prime rib. Yum, Yum, Yum. Hope I have room for…

 read full review» 
 Read 4 reviews on Citysearch» 
Best Dishes at Frank&apos;s Famous Family Restaurant

These dishes from the Frank&apos;s Famous Family Restaurant menu are contributed by Menuism users directly, 
 as part of a restaurant review, or as part of an image upload.
 
Greek Chicken ( $14.00 ) 
 
 5.0 star rating           
 View all dishes 
 Cabinet Creations Just Picked Flowers Shermans Masonry Service Experts Heating&amp;Air Conditioning Dr Stein&apos;s Medical Weight Control Center Jazzercise Tyrone Rec Center Big Dawg Fitness Pak Mail Synergy Rehabilitation Rite Aid 
 Frank&apos;s Famous Family Restaurant is located near the cities of Tyrone and Fairburn. People found this by searching for: Frank&apos;s Restaurant Atlanta, Frank Restaurant In Palmetto Ga, Franks Palmetto Menu, Franks Restaurant Palmetto Ga, Frank&apos;s Famous Family Restaurant, Frank Old Restaurant, 1188 Collinsworth Rd, and Franks Restaurant Palmetto Ga Menu. 
Featured in Palmetto
 
 0.0 star rating           
 Just Picked Flowers TLO 
 Upload Pics Photos
 
Link to Frank&apos;s Famous Family Restaurant
 
Copy the link below and paste onto your website or blog to display badge.

 Copy 
 
Related Links
 Frank&apos;s Famous Family Restaurant Restaurant Review on Gayot 
 Follow Menuism around the web Find us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter Find us on Google+ 
 
 Learn More
 Advertise About
Advertise
FAQ
Privacy
Terms of Use 
 Take Action
 Link to Menuism / Badges and Widgets 
 Browse
 Restaurant Week Restaurant Locations Popular Cities Sitemap 
 
 ©2006 - 2012 Delta Beans, LLC
 Contact Menuism 

Some Images and Data provided by Citysearch .
	</body>
</document>
