<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009654" url="http://isouvlaki.playcompass.com/" time="2012-07-13-03:03" support="1" score="0.0016519664643239" bingtitle="iSouvlaki Home" webtitle="iSouvlaki Home">
			<query id="000906" bing-rank="243"/>
	<description>Hear the oral orders of customers from all over the ... The player runs his own Greek fast food restaurant, helping ... Bill, from Texas Boris, &quot;The Russian Guy&quot; ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Game Story Characters Tutorial Media&amp;Photos Contests Contact&amp;Support The Trailers Playcompass Home 
 
 

Welcome to iSouvlaki!

iSouvlaki is the tastiest and Greekest game for the iPhone!

Have you ever dreamed of running your own Greek fast food restaurant and serve people from all over the world? This is your chance!

Hear the oral orders of customers from all over the world, prepare them correctly and fast and make your restaurant famous!

Challenge your friends in creating the best Greek sandwiches!

 

iSouvlaki is a strategy game for iphone, which is very connected to the Greek mentality of delivering fast food delicacies. The player runs his own Greek fast food restaurant, helping a native Greek guy, called Mpampis, to deliver as many orders as he can in the shortest time possible. The game is based on listening to verbal orders asked by clients from all over the world who visit Athens, the capital city of Greece and delivering the correctly. Are you ready to deliver tasty and extra Greek sandwiches? This is your chance!

iSouvlaki features:

 Greek restaurant environment Greek traditional music Verbal orders Over 200 orders In 2 languages, Greek and English 24 different voice characters in Greek and English language 3 game modes:
 Scenario mode, play the original iSouvlaki story Quick game mode, play quick orders against time 1 vs 1 challenge mode, play against your friends 
 3 difficulty levels in scenario mode Online scoreboards Game Center support 
   
 Which character do you like more? 
 Mpampis from Thessaloniki Bill, from Texas Boris,&quot;The Russian Guy&quot; Johnny,&quot;The Candy Boy&quot; Jenny,&quot;The Sexy Lady&quot; Mary,&quot;The Watermellons Lady&quot; Tania,&quot;The Opera Singer&quot; 
   
 
 
 
Copyright©2010 Playcompass.com
	</body>
</document>
