<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009781" url="http://www.kings-priests.org/magazine/make-your-organization-unforgettable/" time="2012-07-13-03:10" support="12" score="0.022121874594762284" bingtitle="Make Your Organization Unforgettable : Kings &amp; Priests Today" webtitle="Make Your Vision Unforgettable  : KingsPriests Today">
			<query id="001039" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="001481" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000412" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="000163" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000538" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000600" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000561" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000258" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000537" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="001040" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="001064" bing-rank="167"/>
	<description>... visited a Chick-Fil-A restaurant and gave the cashier ... such exceptional customer service at a fast food restaurant. ... It will pay off. Give back to those outside your ...</description>
	<body>
		About 
 About Write For Us CONQUER 2012 Service Terms 
 CONQUER Registration 
 
 Contact Us 
 Kings&amp;Priests Today For Men and Women with a Higher Calling 
 Faith&amp;Ministry CONQUER 2012 
 CONQUER–Register Here Sponsor CONQUER 2012 CONQUER Information 
 Business&amp;Finance 
 Money Income Opportunities 
 Family Health Sex Leadership 
 Sports 
 Resources 
 Events Products Shopping Cart Order Status 
 Videos 
 
You are here: Home » Faith&amp;Ministry » Make Your Vision Unforgettable 
 
 Make Your Vision Unforgettable 
 Robert Watkins | March 12, 2012 | Comments (0) 
 What makes companies such as Amazon, Coca Cola and Tiffany unforgettable and memorable?  Here’s a hint, it’s not their logo, brand identity, or witty commercials.   Whether you are new church or a thriving ministry, let’s make this year the best ever…here’s how:

 Offer your visitors and new members something they can’t get elsewhere – Be willing to do something they can’t get someone else.   Separate your ministry by advising your network that all churches and ministries are not the same.  Emphasis the uniqueness ministry.  The more unique the service you provide your members, the more you’ll become the “go to ministry” when they ready to make a decision to join. 

 Make every experience memorable – I recently visited a Chick-Fil-A restaurant and gave the cashier my order.  Instead of just handing my order over the counter, she actually came from behind the counter, handed me my order, said “Thank you, Robert” with big smile.  I’ve never experienced such exceptional customer service at a fast food restaurant.  The experience impacted me so much I came back the next day. 

 Master free publicity –  More than 400 social media site exists today, companies and ministries are learning how to maximize free social media.   Coca Cola has over 36 million “likes” on Facebook.  Wal-mart has over 130,000 Twitter followers.   And, with more than a billion people visiting at least one website everyday for stuff, free social media can you put on equal footing with many of the world’s largest companies.   Ensure your ministry’s message is on top social media sites in your industry.  As you post on your media sites, make special offers and product discounts to attract prospects to your social media pages.  It will pay off. 

 Give back to those outside your community - Your ministry’s  long-term success cannot be measured in numbers alone, but also how you impact your local community.  For example, McDonald’s gives back through their Ronald McDonald House.  Most professional sport teams give back through various foundations.  Not only are they helping people but their company makes an emotional connection with those in and out of their community.  Your ministry’s involvement in your communities through local charities will make your ministry unforgettable.   People tend to support ministries who support them. 
 
Meet Robert Watkins


Business and ministry growth expert. Author of &quot;Never Chase A Paycheck Again&quot; and CEO of Kings&amp;Priests Ministries and Conquer Worldwide LLC. Currently on global speaking and book signing tour at www.robertjwatkins.com. 

A best-selling author and popular conference speaker, Robert Watkins is the founder and CEO of Kings&amp;Priests International and Conquer Worldwide LLC where he teaches business, leadership and personal success principles in corporations, churches and large conferences. A mentor to thousands of business, political, media and entertainment professionals, Robert received doctorate degrees in business and theology in 2005. Also, served proudly in the U.S. Army.

 View all posts by Robert Watkins → Blog Twitter Facebook 
 &quot;If you like this post, say thanks by sharing it.&quot; Share 
 Category : Faith&amp;Ministry , Leadership 
 
If you enjoyed this article, subscribe to receive more just like it.

 Subscribe via RSS Feed 
 Sign up for our E-Newsletter 0 comments 0 people listening Sign in 
 Comment help Get Livefyre 
 Post comment as + Follow conversation Following - Unfollow Post to Sort: Newest | Oldest 
 2 MinuteTestimonials
	</body>
</document>
