<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009110" url="http://www.booking.com/hotel/gb/camber-sands-holiday-park.en.html" time="2012-07-13-02:30" support="6" score="0.016828955406210797" bingtitle="Booking.com: hotel Pontins - Camber Sands Holiday Park, Rye ..." webtitle="Booking.com: Hotel Pontins - Camber Sands Holiday Park, Rye Harbour, United Kingdom - 68 Guest reviews. Book your hotel now!">
			<query id="000689" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="000707" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000713" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000702" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000696" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="000712" bing-rank="212"/>
	<description>Pontins Camber Sands Holiday Park has a fast food restaurant, pizzeria, family restaurant ... It offers bright, modern rooms, and has a free on-site car park. Most ...</description>
	<body>
		€ Euro   

 Hotel&apos;s Currency Top currencies: Australian Dollar Canadian Dollar Euro Pound Sterling Singapore Dollar U.S. Dollar All currencies: Argentine peso Australian Dollar Azerbaijan, New Manats Bahrain dinar Brazilian Real Bulgarian lev Canadian Dollar CFA Franc BCEAO Chilean Peso Chinese yuan Colombian peso Czech Koruna Danish Krone Egyptian pound Euro Fijian dollar Georgian lari Hong Kong Dollar Hungarian Forint Indian Rupee Indonesian rupiah Israeli New Sheqel Japanese Yen Jordanian dinar Kazakhstani tenge Korean won Kuwaiti dinar Latvian lats Lithuanian litas Malaysian ringgit Mexican Peso Moldovan leu Namibian Dollar New Taiwan Dollar New Zealand dollar Norwegian Krone Omani rial Polish Zloty Pound Sterling Qatar riyal Romanian new leu Russian Ruble Saudi Arabian riyal Singapore Dollar South African rand Swedish Krona Swiss Franc Thai baht Turkish Lira U.A.E. Dirham U.S. Dollar Ukraine Hryvnia Venezuelan bolívar English (US)   

 English (UK) English (US) Deutsch Nederlands Français Español Català Italiano Português (PT) Português (BR) Norsk Suomi Svenska Dansk Čeština Magyar Română 日本語 简体中文 繁體中文 Polski Ελληνικά Русский Türkçe Български عربي 한국어 עברית Latviski Українська Bahasa Indonesia Bahasa Malaysia ภาษาไทย Eesti Hrvatski Lietuvių Slovenčina Srpski Slovenščina Tiếng Việt Filipino Íslenska Sign in My Booking.com   Sign in Sign up Loading...   Email address: 
 Password: Sign in 
 Forgot your password? 

 Sign in using your booking number and PIN code 
 
Book faster every time

 Change upcoming bookings Get Secret Deals Access everything, anywhere 
 Booking Number: PIN Code: Sign in 
It&apos;s fast, free and secure!

 Change bookings Get Secret Deals Book faster 
 Email address: Password: Confirm password: Create my account 
 Welcome to the Booking.com community. 


 An email has been sent to .
Click the link in this email to activate your account. 



 Unactivated accounts will be removed in 7 days. 
 
   Bookings     Messages     Personalization   Settings     Viewed   Searched     Sign Out 
 Loading Loading Website Feedback Sign in to manage your bookings. Don&apos;t have an account yet? Sign up! You are here: Home &gt; 
   United Kingdom &gt; 
 11327 hotels East Sussex &gt; 
 224 hotels Rye Harbour &gt; 
 1 hotel Pontins - Camber Sands Holiday Park
   
 
Search Hotels
 
 Destination/Hotel Name: 
 
Check-in Date
 Day 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 Month July 2012 August 2012 September 2012 October 2012 November 2012 December 2012 January 2013 February 2013 March 2013 April 2013 May 2013 June 2013 
Check-out Date
 Day 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 Month July 2012 August 2012 September 2012 October 2012 November 2012 December 2012 January 2013 February 2013 March 2013 April 2013 May 2013 June 2013 I don&apos;t have specific dates yet 
Rooms
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 
adults
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 
children
 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 [Close] 
 adults children age(s) of children at check-out Add another room Room 1:  1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 
 Change Search 
Map
 
Pontins - Camber Sands Holiday Park will be shown on a map if you enable JavaScript.
 
Map
	</body>
</document>
