<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009053" url="http://www.clickorlando.com/lifestyle/health/-/1636830/-/104cas3/-/index.html" time="2012-07-13-02:27" support="1" score="0.0025589934491270167" bingtitle="Orlando | Food News, Recipes, Information and More from WKMG Local 6" webtitle="Orlando | Food News, Recipes, Information and More from WKMG Local 6">
			<query id="000373" bing-rank="109"/>
	<description>Visit ClickOrlando.com for local breaking news and headlines from Orlando, FL. Get latest Orlando, Fla., local TV news. Orange County, Fla., headlines, national news ...</description>
	<body>
		Back To Mobile Site 
Carsey-Werner/ABC Studios
 
 Where now? 
 
&apos;Cosby&apos; stars
 Click for More Just Weather.com Site Web Sponsored by 
 Home 
 Most Popular Sign Up For Email Newsletters ClickOrlando Mobile Sign Up for Text Alerts RSS Election 2012 Restaurant Inspections Contact Us 
 News 
 Local News US&amp;World Election 2012 Slideshows Money Politics Education Traffic Investigations Casey Anthony Trayvon Martin Case 
 Weather 
 Live Radar 8-Day Forecast Hurricane Headquarters Temperatures Beach&amp;Boating Travel Weather Video Forecast 
 Sports 
 Magic Predators UCF Gators Seminoles Canes Jaguars Dolphins Buccaneers High School Sports Golf 
 Entertainment 
 At The Movies TV Listings Theme Parks Social Local Live On Letterman Watch CBS TV Trending News CBS Fall Premiere ConnecTV 
 Lifestyle 
 Pets Food Family Consumer/Recalls Health Automotive Technology Law TV Your Health Your Home Travel Real Estate 
 Contests 
 Enter Our Contests 
 Interact 
 Blogs Flashpoint Community Calendar Community Partners Editorials Email News Tips Twitter Share Your Stories Social Local Dating 
 Seen On 
 News Team Inside Local 6 Behind the Kitchen Door Crime Tracker Schemes and Ripoffs Making A Difference Lottery Advertise TV Listings Contact Us 
 Marketplace 
 Shopping Coupon and Coupon Codes Hot Travel Deals Orlando Jobs 
 
 
 Home ›  Lifestyle › Health 
 
Top Story
 
iStock / MartiSaiz
 
 Study: Being underweight worse than being obese 
 
A new study suggests that it may be far more dangerous to have your doctor assess you as &quot;underweight&quot; than it is to be diagnosed as &quot;obese.&quot;
 More 
 Study: Being underweight worse than being obese 6 reasons health care costs keep going up Independent doctors declining in number Rare genetic mutation protects against Alzheimer&apos;s disease Why zombies, robots, clowns freak us out Judge lets Miss. abortion clinic stay open -- for now Drug Maker GlaxoSmithKline Hit With $3B In Penalties Doctors determine cause of Cambodia deaths Smoking orangutan forced to kick habit FDA announces new opioid safety plan 
 
Interactives
 
 
 Staying safe in the Summer sun 
 How many calories are in your beer? Is your workspace hurting your health? 
 View More 
Features
 
 
 How to create at-home first aid kit 
 Tips to protect your hearing Which painkiller is right for you? 
 View More 
Breast Cancer Awareness
 
 
 When pain and cancer collide, communication is key 
 Male patients fighting against breast cancer Are you wearing the wrong bra size? 
 View More 
 Severe Weather 
 JustWeather.com Severe Warnings Advertisement Advertisement Advertisement 
Recent Your Health Features
 
 4 reasons sunscreen is a must 
 
Wearing sunscreen not only reduces your risk of skin cancer, it also has other benefits for your skin.
 
 Women: Celebrate your health 
 
Now is the time to get yourself healthy, eat right and make good choices.
 
 Low-impact exercises can benefit those with injuries 
 
If an injury is keeping you from doing your usual workouts, consider these lower impact exercises instead.
 View More 
Features
 

 Download the ConnecTV app 

 ClickOrlando Mobile 

 Orlando Traffic 

 Tee Times - Golf News 

 THELAW.TV 

 Community Calendar 

 Your Home 

 Restaurant Inspections 

 Your Health 
Jerry Attrick/SXC
 Grilling tips make your barbecue great 
istock
 Stay Safe In The Sun This Summer 

 America&apos;s coolest water parks 
iStock/gmutlu
 10 simple ways to live longer, healthier 

 Picture-Perfect Pets 

 Orlando-area mug shot hall of shame Email Alerts RSS News Feed Mobile Live Streams Slideshows Video Set Click Orlando as Homepage | Back To Top Partners: washingtonpost.com © 2012 WKMG - Orlando Contact Us | Privacy Policy | Terms of Use | Advertising | Site Map
	</body>
</document>
