<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009304" url="http://www.17thmissouri.com/or_Pridge_curtis.html" time="2012-07-13-02:41" support="1" score="0.0016664762647598751" bingtitle="or_pearidge_curtis_3_6_62 - 17th missouri volunteers-Western ..." webtitle="or_pearidge_curtis_3_6_62">
			<query id="001197" bing-rank="173"/>
	<description>SIR: The general commanding is in receipt of yours of ... center, which was his proper place according to my order ... It must have been near 5 o&apos;clock when I brought this ...</description>
	<body>
		SUGAR CREEK HOLLOW, ARK.,
March 6, 1862.
CAPTAIN: Van Dorn, Price, and McCulloch are moving down on us. Have
ordered all my detachments to concentrate here, and I am locating my force
to repel an attack. The enemy is reported at from 20,000 to 30,000 fighting
men. They burned the Seminole College, in Fayetteville, night before last,
and last night their advance camp was at Elm Springs, about 21 miles from
here. Sigel last night was 4 1/1 miles southwest from Bentonville, 14 miles
from here, but he was to march at 2 this morning, and must be near by.
A detachment under Colonel Vandever entered and took Huntsville last night,
taking 2 prisoners. That detachment will also be in before the enemy can
reach me. We will give them the best show we can. The weather is very cold
and snowing.
SAML. R. CURTIS,
Brigadier-General.
Capt. N.H. MCLEAN,
Assistant Adjutant-General.
-----
HEADQUARTERS AMY OF SOUTHWEST,
Pea Ridge, Ark., March 9, 1862.
SIR: On Thursday, the 6th instant, enemy commenced the attack on my
right, assailing and following the rear guard of the detachment under General
Sigel to my main lines on Sugar Creek Hollow, but on that occasion ceased
firing when he met my re-enforcements about 4 p.m. During the night I became
convinced he had moved on so as to attack my right or rear. Therefore,
early on the 7th, I ordered a change of front to the right on my right,
my right thus becoming my left, still resting on Sugar Creek Hollow. This
brought my line crossing Pea Ridge, my new right resting on the head of
Cross Timber Hollow, which is the head of Big Sugar Creek. I also ordered
an immediate advance of cavalry and light artillery--Colonel Osterhaus&apos;--with
orders to attack and break what I supposed would be a re-enforced line
of the enemy. This movement was in progress when the enemy, at 11 a.m.,
commenced an attack on my right. The fight continued mainly at these points
during the day, the enemy having gained my position so hardly contested
by Colonel Carr at the Cross Timber Hollow, but being entirely repulsed,
with the loss of the commander, General McCulloch, in the center, commanded
by Colonel Davis.
The plan of attack on the center was gallantly carried forward by Colonel
Osterhans, who was immediately sustained and superseded by Colonel Davis&apos;
entire division, supported also by General Sigel&apos;s command, which remained
till near the close of the day on the left. Colonel Carr&apos;s division held
the right under a galling, continuous fire all day. In the evening, the
firing having entirely ceased in the center and there having been none
on the left, I re-enforced the right by a portion of the Second Division,
raider General Asboth. Before the day closed I was convinced the enemy
had concentrated his main effort on my right. I therefore commenced another
change of my front, so as to face the enemy where he had deployed on my
right flank in strong position. The change was only partially effective,
but fully in progress, when at sunrise on the 8th my right and center renewed
the firing, which was immediately answered by the enemy with renewed energy
and extended line. My left, under General Sigel, moved close to the hills
occupied by the enemy, driving him from heights and advancing steadily
toward the head of the hollows. I immediately ordered the center and right
wing forward, the right turning the left of the enemy and cross-firing
on his center. This final position inclosed the enemy in an arc of a circle.
A charge of infantry extending throughout the whole line completely routed
the whole rebel force, which retired in great confusion, but rather safely,
through the deep, impassable defiles of Cross Timber.
Our loss is heavy. The enemy&apos;s can never be ascertained, for the dead
are scattered over a large field, and their wounded too may many of them
be lost and perish. The foe is scattered in all direct ions, but I think
his main force has returned to Boston Mountains. General Sigel follows
towards Keetsville, while my cavalry is pursuing him toward the mountains,
scouring the country, bringing in prisoners, and trying to find the rebel
Major-General Van Dorn, who had command of the entire force of the enemy
at this battle of Pea Ridge. I have not as yet the statements of the dead
and wounded so as to justify a report, but I will refer you to dispatch
I will forward very soon.
The officers and soldiers in this command have displayed such unusual
gallantry I hardly dare to make distinctions. I must, however, name all
my commanders of divisions: General Sigel, who gallantly carried the heights
and drove back the left wing of the enemy; Brigadier-General Asboth, who
is wounded in the arm, in his gallant effort to re-enforce the right; Colonel
and Acting Brigadier-General Davis, who commands the center, where McCulloch
fell on the 7th, and pressed forward the center on the 8th; Col. and Acting
Brig. Gen. E. A. Carr, who is also wounded in the arm, and was under continuous
fire of the enemy during the two hardest days&apos; struggling, where the scattered
dead of friends and foe attest the hardest of the struggling. Commanders
of brigades Colonels Dodge, Osterhaus, Vandever, White, Schaefer, Pattison,
and Greusel, distinguished; but for their gallantry and that of others
I must refer to reports of division commanders.
I must also tender my thanks to my staff officers, Capt. T. I. McKenny,
acting assistant adjutant-general; Capt. W. H. Stark; Capt. John Ahlfeldt,
and Lieuts. J. M. Adams and R. A. Stitt, all acting aides, and Lieut. A.
Hoeppner, my only engineer officer. All the staff officers did gallant
service in conveying orders and aiding in their prompt execution.
Indiana, Illinois, Iowa, Ohio, and Missouri very proudly share the
honor of victory which their gallant heroes won over the combined forces
of Van Dorn, Price, and McCulloch at Pea Ridge, in the Ozark Mountains
of Arkansas.
I have the honor to be, captain, your obedient servant,
SAML. R. CURTIS,
Brigadier- Gcneral.
Capt. J. C. KELTON,
Assistant Adjutant-General.
-----
HEADQUARTERS DEPARTMENT OF TIIE MISSOURI,
Saint Louis, March 10, 1862.
Brigadier-General CURTIS,
Commanding in Arkansas:
I congratulate you and your command on the glorious victory just gained.
You have proved yourselves as brave in battle as enduring of fatigue and
hardship. A grateful country will honor you for both.
H. W. HALLECK,
Major-General.
-----
HEADQUARTERS ARMY OF THE SOUTIIWEST,
Pea Ridge, March 10, 1862.
CAPTAIN: The main force of the rebel Army, under Generals Van Dorn,
Price, and Pike retreated by a short turn and by-road from Cross Timber
Hollow toward Huntsville, camping the first night at Van Winkle&apos;s Mill,
on War Eagle, south of White River. Green, with some 8,000 or 10,000, moved
through Bentonville, my cavalry driving his rear guard out of that place,
with the loss of one man. These two movements probably contemplate a junction
in Boston Mountains.
I move two divisions a few miles forward to-day. A detachment of 100
men, under Captain Schaumberg, with a white flag, from General Van Dorn,
comes to assist in collecting and burying the dead.
The enemy has lost very heavily. Among their officers are Generals
McCulloch, Mcintosh, and Slack, killed; also Colonel McCulloch, a nephew
of the general; Captain Clark, son of Maj. Meriwether Clark, is killed,
besides many more whose names may be furnished.
I send copy of correspondence with General Van Dorn.
SAML. R. CURTIS,
Brigadier-General, Commanding.
Capt. N. H. McLEAN,
Assistant Adjutant-General, Saint Louis, Mo.
[Inclosure No. 1.]
HEADQUARTERS TRANS-MISSISSIPPI DISTRICT,
March 9, 1862.
To the COMMANDING OFFICER
Of the U.S. Troops on Sugar Creek, A rkansas :
SIR: In accordance with the usages of war I have, the honor to request
that you will permit the burial party whom I send from this army«13
R R--VOL VIII»with a flag of truce to attend to the duty of collecting
and interring the he bodies of the officers and men who fell during the
engagements of the 7th and 8th instant.
Very respectfully, sir, your obedient servant,
EARL VAN DORN,
Major-General, Confederate Army.
[Inclosure No. 2. ]
HEADQUARTERS ARMY OF THE SOUTHWEST,
Pea Ridge, Ark., March 9, 1862.
EARL VAN DORN,
Commanding Confederate Forces :
SIR: The general commanding is in receipt of yours of the 9th, saying
that in accordance with the usages of war you send a party to collect and
bury the dead. I am directed to say all possible facilities will be given
for burying the dead, many of which have already been interred. Quite a
number of your surgeons have fallen into our hands and are permitted to
act under parole, and under a general order from Major-General IIallcck
further liberty will be allowed them if such accommodations be reciprocated
by you. The general regrets that we find on the battle-field, contrary
to civilized warfare, many of the Federal dead who were tomahawked, scalped,
and their bodies shamefully mangled, and expresses a hope that this important
struggle may not degenerate to a savage warfare.
By order of Brig. Gen. S. R. Curtis:
T. I. McKENNY,
Acting Assistant Adjutant-General.
-----
HEADQUARTERS ARMY OF TIIE SOUTHWEST,
Pea Ridge, Ark., March 11, 1862.
SIR: I have finished burying the dead and made the best provisions
I can for the wounded. Two divisions have advanced 6 miles, and my cavalry
has scoured the country this side Fayetteville. The enemy has retreated,
as before, beyond the Boston Mountains. I send forward prisoners, some
500.
In reference to a verbal communication from General Van Dorn, I have
expressed a willingness to exchange prisoners of equivalent rank, and hope
in this way to obtain some officers that I very much desire. It is warm,
delightful weather, and roads are excellent. I move my headquarters near
to Bentonville, to get away from the stench and desolation of the battle
ground, and the better to overlook the approaches to the Boston Mountains.
A scout informs me that forces were to advance from Fort Scott five or
six days ago, but that Hunter and Lane were both absent. What is the matter
out there?
Respectfully,
SAML. R. CURTIS,
Brigadier-General, Commanding.
Capt. J. C. KELTON,
Assistant Adjutant`- General.
HEADQUARTERS ARMY OF THE SOUTHWEST,
Near Bentonville, Ark, March 13, 1862.
CAPTAIN: I visited Bentonville yesterday. Everything is quiet in the
vicinity. During the battle we lost six guns, but we recovered all back
and took five from the enemy. I have also taken a large number of small-arms
which the rebels threw away. My loss of killed and wounded will exceed
my estimate of 1,000. General Pike commanded the Indian forces. They shot
arrows as well as rifles, and tomahawked and scalped prisoners. I am credibly
informed that Colonel Rector, of Arkansas, has disbanded his regiment.
Was my dispatch of the 5th instant, telling you of the approach of
the enemy and my arrangements to receive him, taken by the enemy or received
at headquarters? Much mail matter was taken by him.
SAML. R. CURTIS,
Brigadier-General, Commanding.
Capt. J. C. KELTON,
Assistant Adjutant-General.
-----
HEADQUARTERS TRANS-MISSISSIPPI DISTRICT,
Van Buren, Ark., March 14, 1862.
General SAMUEL R. CURTIS:
GENERAL: I am instructed by Major-General Van Dorn, commanding this
district, to express to you his thanks and gratification on account of
the courtesy extended by yourself and the officers under your command to
the burial party sent by him to your camp on the 9th instant.
He is pained to learn by your letter brought to him by the commanding
officer of the party that the remains of some of your soldiers have been
reported to you to have been scalped, tomahawked, and otherwise mutilated.
He hopes you have been misinformed with regard to this matter, the
Indians who formed part of his forces having for many years been regarded
as civilized people. He will, however, most cordially unite with you in
repressing the horrors of this unnatural war, and that you may co-operate
with him to this end more effectually he desires me to inform you that
many of our men who surrendered themselves prisoners of war were reported
to him as having been murdered in cold blood by their captors, who were
alleged to be Germans.
The general commanding feels sure that you will do your part, as he
will in preventing such atrocities in future, and that the perpetrators
of them will be brought to justice, whether German or Choctaw.
The privileges which you extend to our medical officers will be reciprocated,
and as soon as possible means will be taken for an exchange of prisoners.
I am sir, very respectfully, yours,
DABNEY H. MAURY,
Assistant Adjutant-General.
-----
HEADQUARTERS ARMY OF THE SOUTHWEST,
Cross Timber, Ark., April 1, 1862.
CAPTAIN: The brief telegraphic report which I gave on the 9th ultimo
is not sufficient to present even the general outline of the battle of
Pea Ridge, and with the report of my commanders of divisions I now submit
a more general detail.
My pursuit of General Price brought me to Fayetteville, Ark. The entire
winter campaign from the 26th January to this time, including the march
from Roll to the Boston Mountains, 240 miles, was attended with continual
exhibitions of toil, privations, conflict, and gallantry, some of which
I have telegraphed to headquarters, and may hereafter deserve more full
development. After reaching Arkansas the forces of General Price were rapidly
re-enforced by regiments which had been stationed in Arkansas and the Indian
Territory. I therefore expected these combined forces would return upon
us to give us battle, and in conformity with the orders of the general
of the 22d of February I selected Sugar Creek as the strongest of several
strong places taken from the enemy to make a stand against any and all
odds.
I reported my force to you on the 12th February, after Colonel Davis&apos;
division had joined me, at 12,095 men and fifty pieces of artillery, including
four mountain howitzers. My long line of communications required garrisons
at Marshfield, Springfield, Castle, and Keetsville, besides a constant
moving three to guard my train. My force in Arkansas on the 7th ultimo
was therefore not more than 10,500 cavalry and infantry with forty-nine
pieces of artillery, including the mountain howitzers, one piece having
been sent out into Missouri and thus prevented front joining us in the
battle.
The scarcity of forage and other supplies made it necessary for me
to spread out my troops over considerable country, always trying to keep
it within supporting distance, convenient to rally on the positions selected
for battle. On the 4th of March this force was located as follows:
The First and Second Divisions, under Generals Sigel and Asboth, were
4 miles southwest of Bentonville, at Cooper&apos;s farm, under general orders
to move around to Sugar Creek, about 14 miles east.
The Third Division, under Col. Jefferson C. Davis, acting brigadier-general,
had moved and taken position at Sugar Creek, under orders to make some
preparatory arrangements and examinations for a stand against the enemy.
The Fourth Division was at Cross follow, under command of Col. E. A.
Car, acting brigadier-general. My own headquarters were also at this place,
within about 12 miles from Sugar Creek, on the main telegraph road from
Springfield to Fayetteville.
Large detachments had been sent out from these several camps for forage
and information. One from Cross Hollow to Huntsville, under command of
Colonel Vandever, ;and three from Cooper&apos;s farm to Maysville and Pineville.
One of these, raider Major Conrad, with a piece of artillery and about
250 men, did not reach us till after the battle. All the others came in
safe and joined in the engagement.
The enemy had taken position in the Boston Mountains, a high range
that divides the waters of the White River and Arkansas. General Price
had rallied the forces that had fought at Carthage, Wilson&apos;s Creek, and
Lexington, augmented by his exertions to recruit in Missouri during the
winter. On his arrival from Springfield, in Arkansas, he reported to Governor
Rector that between 4,000 and 5,000 of these had joined the Confederate
service previous to his leaving Springfield. The circulation of all manner
of extravagant falsehoods on his way induced the whole country to leave
their homes, and for fear we would kill them thousands joined his ranks.
General McCulloch brought at least eleven regiments to the field and General
Pike five. Besides these regularly-organized Confederate troops which General
Price met in Arkansas, there were many companies and regiments of&apos; Arkansas
volunteers, most of the country people being required to take up arms.
From this data and the general opinion of the country I estimated the force
of the enemy to have been at least 30,000 or 40,000. This was the force
in and near Boston Mountains, rallying to drive us from Arkansas and Missouri.
The two armies thus constituted and located were within hearing of
each other&apos;s cannon, about 30 miles apart. I submit an accompanying map,(*)
showing some of the topographic features of the country on the roads which
we traversed. Our troops were weary and somewhat exhausted in their long
forced marches and frequent conflicts. Our cavalry had especially suffered
in the breaking down and loss of horses. But our troops were generally
well armed, drilled, and anxious to encounter the enemy at any reasonable
hazard. They were all intelligent, ardent, flushed with our repeated success
in many encounters on our way, and all conscious of the righteousness of
their country&apos;s cause.
The arrival of Major-General Van Dorn on the 2d of March in the camp
of the enemy was the occasion of great rejoicing and the firing of forty
guns. The rebel force was harangued by their chiefs with boastful and passionate
appeals, assuring them of their superior numbers and the certainty of an
easy victory. Dispatches were published falsely announcing a great battle
at Columbus, Ky., in which we had lost three gunboats and 20,000 men; and
thus the rebel hordes were assembled. The occasion was now opened to drive
the invaders from the soil of Arkansas and give a final and successful
blow to a Southern Confederacy.
The 5th of March was cold and blustering. The snow fell so as to cover
the ground. No immediate attack was apprehended, and I was engaged writing.
About 2 o&apos;clock p.m. scouts and fugitive citizens came in, informing me
of the rapid approach of the enemy to give me battle. His cavalry would
be at Elm Springs, some 12 miles distant, that night, and his artillery
had already passed Fayetteville. Satisfied of the truth of this report,
I immediately sent couriers to General Sigel and Colonel Vandever, and
ordered them to move immediately to Sugar Creek, where I also ordered Colonel
Carr to move with his division.
I also sent you a dispatch, which may have been lost with other mail-matter
which I have since learned was captured by the enemy. I told you I would
give them the best reception possible. All my messengers were successful
in delivering their orders. Colonel Carr&apos;s division moved about 6 p.m.
Colonel Vandever had intelligence of the movement of the enemy before my
messenger reached him, and made immediate change in his march, so that
with great exertion he arrived on the 6th. General Sigel deferred his march
from Cooper&apos;s farm till 2 o&apos;clock in the morning of the 6th, and at Bentonville
tarried himself with a regiment and battery till he was attacked about
9 a.m.
I arrived at Sugar Creek at 2 o&apos;clock a.m. on the 6th, and immediately
detailed parties for early morning work in felling timber, to obstruct
certain roads to prevent the enemy having too many approaches and to erect
field works to increase the strength of my forces. Colonel Davis and Colonel
Carr early in the day took their positions on the high projecting hills
commanding the valley of the creek, leaving the right of the line to be
occupied by the First and Second Divisions, which were anxiously expected.
The valley of the creek is low, and from a quarter to a half mile wide.
The hills are high on both sides, and the main road from Fayetteville by
Gross Hollow to Keetsville intercepts the valley nearly at right angles.
The road from Fayetteville by Bentonville to Keetsville is quite a detour,
but it also comes up the Sugar Creek Valley; a branch, however, takes off
and runs nearly parallel to the main or Telegraph road, some 3 miles from
it. The Sugar Creek Valley, therefore, intercepts all these roads.
The Third and Fourth Divisions had before noon of the 6th deployed
their lines and cut down a great number of trees, which thoroughly blockaded
the roads on the left. Later in the day I directed some of the same work
to be done on the right. This work was in charge of Colonel Dodge, who
felled trees on the road which runs parallel to the main road to which
I have before referred. This proved of great advantage, as it retarded
the enemy some two hours in their flank movement. Breastworks of considerable
strength were erected by the troops on the headlands of Sugar Creek as
if by magic, and a battery near the road crossing was completely shielded
by an extensive earthwork, erected, under the direction of Colonel Davis,
by a pioneer company, commanded by Captain Snyder. About 2 o&apos;clock p.m.
General Asboth and Colonel Osterhaus reported the arrival of the First
and Second Divisions. This good news was followed immediately by another
report that General Sigel, who had remained behind with a detachment, had
been attacked near Bentonville and was quite surrounded by the enemy&apos;s
advance forces. I immediately directed some of the troops to return to
his relief. In the mean time he had advanced with his gallant little band,
fighting its way within 3 or 4 miles of our main forces. The two divisions
turned back in double-quick, and a large cavalry force also started, all
being anxious to join in a rescue of their comrades in peril.
Part of the First Division, under Colonel Osterhaus, soon met the retreating
detachment, and immediately opened with artillery and infantry, which checked
the further advance and terminated the action for the day. In the retreat
and final repulse, which occupied several hours, our loss was some 25 killed
and wounded. The enemy must have suffered more, as our artillery had telling
effect along the road, and the rebel graves in considerable numbers bear
witness of the enemy&apos;s loss.
The firing having ceased, I sent back other troops that had joined
the movement and designated the positions on the right, which were promptly
occupied by the First and Second Divisions. Our men rested on their arms,
confident of hard work before them on the coming day. The accompanying
map of the battle ground will fully illustrate the positions then and subsequently
assumed.(*) In my front was the deep, broad valley of Sugar Creek, forming
the probable approaches of the enemy, our troops extending for miles, and
generally occupying the summits of headlands on Sugar Creek. In my rear
was a broken plateau called Pea Ridge, and still farther in my rear the
deep valley of Big Sugar Creek, or Cross Timber. My own headquarters and
those of Generals Sigel, Asboth, and other commanders of divisions were
near Pratt&apos;s house. The lines A, B, and C show the different fronts assumed
during the progress of the battle.
The approach by Bentonville brought the enemy to my extreme right,
and during the night of the 5th and 6th he began a movement around my flank
by the road before mentioned, which crosses Pea Ridge some 3 miles northwest
of the main Telegraph road. I ascertained in the morning this flank movement
of the cnemy, which I perceived was designed to attack my right flank and
rear. I therefore immediately called my commanders of divisions together
at General Asboth&apos;s tent, and directed a change of front to the rear, so
as to face the road upon which the enemy was still moving. At the same
time I directed the organization of a detachment of cavalry and light artillery,
supported by infantry, to open the battle by an attack from my new center
on the probable center of the enemy before he could fully form. I selected
Colonel Osterhans to lead this central column, an officer who displayed
great skill, energy, and gallantry each day of the battle.
The change of front thus directed reversed the order of the troops,
placing the First and Second Divisions on the left, their left still resting
on Sugar Creek, Osterhaus and the Third Division in the center, and the
Fourth Division became the extreme right. While I was explaining the proposed
movement to commanders and Colonel Osterhans was beginning to rally and
move forward this attacking column, a messenger brought me intelligence
that my picket, commanded by Major Weston, of the Twenty-fourth Missouri,
had been attacked by infantry. This was at Elkhorn Tavern, where the new
right was to rest. Colonel Cart being present, he was ordered to move into
position and support the major as soon as possible.
This was the commencement of the second day&apos;s fight. It was about 10.30
o&apos;clock, and the officers separated to direct their several commands. The
fire increased rapidly on the right and very soon opened in the center.
After visiting the right, where I perceived the enemy was making a vigorous
attack, and finding Colonel Carr, under a brisk fire of shot and shell,
coolly locating and directing the deployment, I returned to my central
position near Pratt&apos;s house, and sent orders to Colonel Davis to move near
to Colonel Carr, to support him. In the mean time Colonel Osterhaus had
attacked the enemy and divided his forces; but he was soon pressed with
greatly superior numbers, that drove back our cavalry and took our flying
battery, which had advanced with it. The colonel, however, was well supported
by his infantry, and soon checked a movement that threatened to intercept
the deployment of other forces. I considered the affair so imminent that
I changed my order to Colonel Davis, and directed him to move to the support
of the center, which was his proper place according to my order for the
change of front. My new line was thus formed under the enemy&apos;s fire, the
troops generally moving in good order and gallant bearing. Thus formed,
the line was not continuous, but extended entirely across Pea Ridge, the
divisions in numerical order from left to right, Colonel Osterhaus remaining
in command of a detachment and operating with Colonel Davis in resisting
McCulloch and Mcintosh, who commanded the enemy&apos;s forces in the center.
I did not err in sending Colonel Davis to this point, although Colonel
Carr, on the right, also needed re-enforcements.
The battle raged in the center with terrible fury. Colonel Davis held
the position against fearful numbers, and our brave troops nobly stood
or charged in steady lines. The fate of the battle depended on success
against this flank movement of the enemy, and here near Leetown was the
place to break it down. The fall of Generals McCulloch, McIntosh, and other
officers of the enemy, who fell early in the day, aided us in our final
success at this most critical point; and the steady courage of officers
and men in our lines chilled and broke down the hordes of Indians, cavalry,
and infantry that were arrayed against us. While the battle thus raged
in the center the right wing was sorely pressed, and the dead and wounded
were scattered over the field. Colonel Carr sent for re-enforcements, and
I sent a few cavalry and my body-guard, with the little mountain howitzers,
under Major Bowen. These did good service at a most critical period. I
urged Colonel Carr to stand firm--that more force could be expected soon.
Subsequently Colonel Carr sent me word that he could not hold his position
much longer. I could then only reply by sending him the order to &quot;persevere.&quot;
He did persevere, and the sad havoc in the Ninth and Fourth Iowa and Phelps&apos;
Missouri and Major Weston&apos;s Twenty-fourth Missouri and all the troops in
that division will show how earnest and continuous was their perseverance.
Seeing no signs of approaching foes by the Telegraph road, I sent him
three pieces of artillery and a battalion of infantry of Colonel Benton&apos;s
command (part of the Third Division), which had been located at Sugar Creek
to guard the approaches. Each small accession to the Fourth Division seemed
to compensate an overpowering force. As to the left, I was repeatedly informed
it stood safe and firm, although threatened by the foe.
About 2 p.m. my aide, Captain Adams, who had communicated with that
wing informed me he had just seen Generals Sigel and Asboth on Sugar Creek,
and there was still no attack in that quarter and no appearance of an enemy.
About this time the enemy&apos;s forces melted away in the brushy center, and
the fire gradually ceased. Believing the left and center were no longer
menaced, and the enemy was concentrating on the right, I again sent word
to Colonel Carr that he would soon be re-enforced. I had now resolved to
bring up the left and center to meet the gathering hordes near Elkhorn
Tavern. To inform myself of the condition of the extreme left I went in
person to that point. On my way I ordered forward the remainder of Colonel
Benton&apos;s command, three pieces and a battalion, which had remained guarding
the crossing of the main Telegraph road.
I found Generals Sigel and Asboth with the troops on the hill near
the extreme left, where all was quiet, and the men, not having been under
fire, fresh and anxious to participate in the fight. It was now safe to
make a new change of front, so as to face Sugar Creek. I therefore ordered
this force forward. General Asboth moved by the direct road to Elkhorn
Tavern, and General Sigel went by Leetown to re-enforce Davis if need be,
but to press on to re-enforce Carr if not needed in the center. Both generals
moved promptly. I accompanied General Asboth, collecting and moving forward
some straggling commands that I found by the way.
It must have been near 5 o&apos;clock when I brought this force to the aid
of Colonel Cart. He had received three or four shots, one a severe wound
in the arm. Many of his field officers had fallen and the dead and wounded
had greatly reduced his force. He had been slowly forced back near half
a mile, and had been about seven hours under constant fire. His troops
were still fiercely contesting every inch of ground. As I came up the Fourth
Iowa was falling back for cartridges in line, dressing on their colors
in perfect order. Supposing with my re-en-forcements I could easily recover
our lost ground, I ordered the regiment to halt and easily about. Colonel
Dodge came up, explaining the want of cartridges; but, informed of my purpose,
I ordered a bayonet charge, and they moved again with steady nerve to their
former position, where the gallant Ninth was ready to support them. These
two regiments won imperishable honors.
General Asbboth had planted his artillery in the road and opened a
tremendous fire on the enemy at short range. The Second Missonri Infantry
also deployed and earnestly engaged the enemy. About this time the shades
of night began to gather around us, but the fire on both sides seemed to
grow fierce and more deadly. One of my bodyguard fell dead, my orderly
received a shot, and General Asboth was severely wounded in the arm. A
messenger came from General Sigel, saying he was close on the left and
would soon open fire. The battery of General Asboth ran out of ammunition
and fell back. This caused another battery that I had located on the right
of the rosa to follow, this latter fearing a want of support. The infantry,
however, stood firm or fell back in good order, and the batteries were
soon restored, but the caissons got quite out of reach. The artillery firing
was renewed, however, and kept up till dark, the enemy firing the last
shot, for I could not find another cartridge to give them a final round;
even the little howitzers responded, &quot;No cartridges.&quot; The enemy ceased
firing, and I hurried men after the caissons and more ammunition. Meantime
I arranged the infantry in the edge of the timber, with fields in front,
where they lay on their arms and held the positions for the night. I directed
a detail from each company to bring water and provisions, and thus without
a murmur these weary soldiers lay and many of them slept within a few yards
of the foe, with their dead and wounded comrades scattered around them.
Darkness, silence, and fatigue soon secured to the weary broken slumbers
and gloomy repose. The day had closed in some reverses on the right, but
the left had been unassailed, and the center had driven the foe from the
field.
My only anxiety for the fate of the next day was the new front which
it was necessary to form by my weary troops. I directed Colonel Davis to
withdraw all the remainder of his reserve from the center and move forward
so as to occupy the ground on Carr&apos;s immediate left. Although his troops
had been fighting hard most of the day and displayed great energy and courage,
at 12 o&apos;clock at night they commenced their movement to the new position
on the battle-field, and they too soon rested on their arms.
Nothing further had been heard from General Sigel&apos;s command after the
message at dark that he was on or near the left. His detour carried him
around a brushy portion of the battle-field that could not be explored
in the night. About 2 o&apos;clock he reported at my headquarters with his troops,
who, he said, were going to their former camps for provisions. The distance
to his camp, some 2 miles farther, was so great I apprehended tardiness
in the morning, and urged the general to rest the troops where they then
were, at my headquarters, and send for provisions, as the other troops
were doing. This was readily concurred in, and these troops bivouacked
also for the night. The arrangement thus completed to bring all four of
my divisions to face a position which&apos; had been held in check all the previous
day by one, I rested, certain of final success on the coming day.
The sun rose above the horizon before our troops were all in position
and yet the enemy had not renewed the attack. I was hardly ready to open
fire on him, as the First and Second Divisions had not yet moved into position.
Our troops that rested on their arms in the face of the enemy, seeing him
in motion, could not brook delay, and the center, under Colonel Davis,
opened fire. The enemy replied with terrible energy from new batteries
and lines which had been prepared for us during the night. To avoid raking
batteries the right wing fell back in good order, but kept up a continuous
fire from the new position immediately taken. The First and Second Divisions
soon got under way, and moved with great celerity to their position on
the left.
This completed the formation of my third line of battle. It was directly
to the rear of the first, and was quite continuous, much of it on open
ground. We then had our foe before us, where we well knew the ground. The
broken defiles occupied by him would not admit of easy evolutions to repel
such as could be made by us on the open plain. Victory was inevitable.
As soon as the left wing extended so as to command the mountain and rest
safely upon it, I ordered the right wing to move forward so as to take
position where I placed it the night previous. I repaired myself to the
extreme right, and found an elevated position considerably in advance which
commanded the enemy&apos;s center and left. Here I located the Dubuque battery,
and directed the right wing to move its right forward so as to support
it, and give direction to the advance of the entire right wing. Captain
Hayden soon opened a fire which proved most galling to the foe and a marker
for our line to move upon. Returning to the center, I directed the First
Iowa Battery, under Captain David, to take position in an open field, where
he could also direct a fire on the central point of the enemy. Meantime
the powerful battery of Captain Welfley and many more were bearing on the
cliff, pouring heavy balls through the timber near the center, splintering
great trees and scattering death and destruction with tempestuous fury.
At one time a battery was opened in front of Hayden&apos;s battery on the
extreme right, so near I could not tell whether it was the enemy or an
advance of Hayden&apos;s, but riding nearer I soon perceived its true character,
and directed the First Iowa and the Peoria battery, Captain Davidson, to
cross-fire on it., which soon drove it back to the common hiding place,
the deep ravines of Cross Timber Hollow. While the artillery was thus taking
position and advancing upon the enemy the infantry moved steadily forward.
The left wing, advancing rapidly, soon began to ascend the mountain cliff,
from which the artillery had driven most of the rebel force. The upward
movement of the gallant Thirty-sixth Illinois, with its dark-blue line
of men and its gleaming bayonets, steadily rose from base to summit, when
it dashed forward into the forest, driving and scattering the rebels from
these commanding heights. The Twelfth Missouri, far in advance of others,
rushes into the enemy&apos;s lines, bearing off a flag and two pieces of artillery.
Everywhere our line moved forward and the foe as gradually withdrew.
The roar of cannon and small-arms was continuous, and no force could
then have withstood the converging line and concentrated crossfire of our
gallant troops. Our guns continued some time after the rebel fire ceased,
and the rebels had gone down into the deep caverns through which they had
begun their precipitate flight. Finally our firing ceased. The enemy had
suddenly vanished. Following down the main road, which enters a deep cation,
I saw some straggling teams and men running in great trepidation through
the gorges of the mountains. I directed a battery to move forward, which
threw a few shots at them, followed by a pursuit of cavalry comprised of
the Benton Hussars and my escort from Bowen&apos;s battalion, which was all
the cavalry convenient at the time. General Sigel also followed in this
pursuit towards Keetsville, while I returned, trying to check a movement
which led my forces north, where I was confident a frightened foe was not
likely to go. I soon found the rebel forces had divided and gone in every
direction, but it was several hours before I learned that the main force,
after entering the canyon, had turned short to the right, following obscure
ravines which led into the Huntsville road in a due south direction. General
Sigel followed some miles north towards Keetsville, firing on the retreating
force that ran that way. Colonel Bussey, with cavalry and the little howitzers,
followed beyond Bentonville.
I camped on the field and made provision for burying the dead and care
of the wounded. The loss in the several divisions was as follows:(*)
O Officers. A Aggregate
M Enlisted Men.
--Killed-- -Wounded- Missing.
Command. O M O M O M A
1st (Sigel&apos;s) Division .... 11 4 89 2 38 144
2d (Asboth&apos;s) Division 3 17 3 60 .... 36 119
3d (Davis&apos;) Division 4 42 18 256 .... 9 329
4th (Carr&apos;s) Division 6 95 29 491 2 78 701
3d Iowa Cavalry (Colonel Bussey). .... 24 1 18 .... 9 52
Bowen&apos;s battalion .... 1 1 2 .... 2 6
Total 13 190 56 916 4 172 1,351
This sad reckoning shows where the long-continued fire was borne and
where the public sympathy should be most directed. The loss of the enemy
was much greater, but their scattered battalions can never furnish a correct
report of their killed and wounded.
The reports of division and other officers of my command are all submitted,
with such details as were seen or understood by local commanders. They
give interesting incidents and notice many deserving heroes.
I mentioned in my telegraphic report of the 9th March with high commendations,
and I now repeat, the names who have done distinguished services. These
are my commanders of divisions, Generals Sigel and Asboth, Colonel and
Acting Brigadier-General Davis, and Colonel and Acting Brigadier-General
Carr. They commanded the four divisions. I also again present commanders
of brigades, Colonels Dodge, Osterhaus, Vandever, White, Schaefer, Pattison,
and Greusel. The three first named I especially commend. I also renew the
just thanks due to my staff officers, Capt. T. I. McKenny, acting assistant
adjutant-general, Capt. W. H. Stark, Capt. John Ahlfeldt, Lieut. J. M.
Adams, and Lieutenant Stitt, all acting aides; also A. Hoeppner, my only
engineer. To these I must now add Major Bowen, who commanded my body-guard,
and with the mountain howitzers did gallant service in every battle-field,
in the pursuit, and especially at Pea Ridge. Captain Stephens, Lieutenant
Madison, and Lieutenant Crabtree, of this battalion, also deserve honorable
mention. Major Weston, of the Twenty-fourth Missouri, provost-marshal,
in camp and in battle did gallant service. Lieutenant David, ordnance officer
on my staff, took charge of me First Iowa Battery after Captain Jones was
wounded, and did signal service. I must also thank my commanders of posts,
who supported my line of operation and deserve like consideration, ss their
duties were more arduous--Colonel Boyd at Rolla, Colonel Waring at Lebanon,
Colonel Mills at Springfield, and Lieutenant-Colonel Holland at Cassville.
To do justice to all I would spread before you the most of the rolls
of this army, for I can bear testimony to the almost universal good conduct
of officers and men who have shared with me the long march, the many conflicts
by the way, and final struggle with the combined forces of Price, McCulloch,
Mcintosh, and Pike, under Major-General Van Dorn,at the battle of Pea Ridge.
I have the honor to be, very respectfully, your obedient servant,
SAML. R. CURTIS,
Major-General.
Capt. N.H. MCLEAN,
Assistant Adjutant-General, Saint Louis, Mo.
[Addenda.]
Return, of casualties in the Army of the Southwest, commanded by Brig.
Gen. Samuel R. Curtis, U.S. Army, at the battle of Pea Ridge, Ark., March
6-8, 1862.
[Compiled from nominal lists of casualties, returns,&amp;c.]
O Officers. A Aggregate
M Enlisted Men. C Captured or missing
--Killed-- -Wounded- -----C-----
Commands. O M O M O M A
FIRST AND SECOND DIVISIONS.
Brig. Gen. FRANZ SIGEL.
FIRST DIVISION.
Col. PETER J. OSTERHAUS.
FIRST BRIGADE.
17th Missouri .... .... .... 2 .... 8 10
25th Illinois .... 3 1 17 1 2 24
44th Illinois. .... 1 .... 2 .... .... 3
Total First Brigade .... 4 1 21 1 10 37
SECOND BRIGADE.
Col. NICHOLAS GREUSEL.
12th Missouri .... 3 3 26 .... 2 34
36th Illinois .... 4 .... 37 1 26 68
Jenks&apos; and Smith&apos;s companies Illinois cavalry .... .... .... .... ....
7 7
Total Second Brigade .... 7 3 63 1 35 109
ARTILLERY.
Missouri Light Artillery, Welfley&apos;s battery .... .... .... 5 .... ....
5
4th Ohio Battery .... .... .... 1 .... 4 5
Total artillery ..... .... .... 6 .... 4 10
Total First Division .... 11 4 90 2 49 156
SECOND DIVISION.
Brig. Gen. A. ASBOTH.
Staff ..... .... 1 .... .... .... 1
Return of casualties in the Army of the Southwest---Continued.
O Officers. A Aggregate
M Enlisted Men. C Captured or missing
--Killed-- -Wounded- -----C-----
Commands. O M O M O M A
FIRST BRIGADE.
Col. FREDERICK SHAEFER.
2d Missouri 2 6 .... 34 .... 11 53
15th Missouri .... .... .... .... .... 11 11
Total First Brigade 2 6 .... 34 .... 22 64
NOT BRIGADED.
2d Ohio Battery .... 1 1 1 .... .... 3
Missouri Horse Artillery, 1st Flying Battery .... 3 .... 8 .... 8 19
Benton Hussars, Missouri Cavalry.. .... 3 1 10 .... 3 17
Fremont Hussars, Missouri Cavalry 1 4 8 .... 3 16
Total not brigaded 1 11 2 27 .... 14 55
Total Second Division 3 17 3 61 .... 36 120
THIRD DIVISION.
Col. JEFF. C. DAVIS.
FIRST BRIGADE.
Col. THOMAS PATTISON.
8th Indiana 1 4 1 26 .... .... 32
18th Indiana .... 3 1 22 .... .... 26
22d Indiana 2 7 1 32 .... .... 42
1st Indiana Battery .... .... .... 5 .... 6 11
Total First Brigade 3 14 3 85 .... 6 111
SECOND BRIGADE.
Col. JULIUS WHITE.
37th Illinois .... 20 9 112 .... 3 144
59th Illinois .... 9 2 55 .... .... 66
2d Illinois Light Artillery, Battery .... .... .... 17 .... .... 17
Total Second Brigade .... 29 11 184 .... 3 227
1st Missouri Cavalry, detachment .... 2 .... 2 .... 2 6
Total Third Division 3 45 14 271 .... 11 344
FOURTH DIVISION.
Col. EUGENE A. CARR.
Staff .... .... 1 .... .... .... 1
FIRST BRIGADE.
Col. GRENVILLE M. DODGE.
4th Iowa 1 17 4 135 .... 3 160
35th Illinois .... 14 3 44 6 46 113
1st Iowa Battery .... 3 2 12 .... .... 17
Total First Brigade 1 34 9 191 6 49 290
SECOND BRIGADE.
Col. WILLIAM VANDEVER.
9th Iowa. 4 34 5 171 1 3 218
Phelps&apos; Missouri regiment 1 11 7 64 1 9 93
3d Illinois Cavalry .... 9 4 32 .... 13 58
3d Iowa Battery .... 2 2 15 .... 3 22
Total Second Brigade. 5 56 18 282 2 28 391
Total Fourth Division 6 90 28 473 8 77 682
Return of casualties in the Army of the Southwest--Continued.
O Officers. A Aggregate
M Enlisted Men. C Captured or missing
--Killed-- -Wounded- -----C-----
Commands. O M O M O M A
UNASSIGNED.
Bowen&apos;s battalion Missouri cavalry .... 1 1 2 .... 2 6
3d Iowa Cavalry .... 24 1 16 .... 9 50
3d Missouri(*) .... .... .... .... .... .... ....
24th Missouri .... 3 1 15 .... 7 26
Total unassigned .... 28 3 33 .... 18 82
RECAPITULATION.
1st Division .... 11 4 90 2 49 156
2d Division 3 17 3 61 .... 36 120
3d Division 3 45 14 271 .... 11 344
4th Division 6 90 28 473 8 77 682
Unassigned .... 28 3 33 .... 18 82
Grand total Army of the Southwest 12 191 52 928 10 191 1,384
-----
HEADQUARTERS ARMY OF THE SOUTHWEST,
Camp near Batesville, Ark., May 21, 1862.
Hon. B. F. WADE,
Chairman of Committee on Conduct of the Present War:
SIR: The absence from my immediate command of those men and officers
who are best acquainted with the facts in regard to the employment of Indian
savages has delayed my reply to your communication of April 2, 1862, (+)
until this time.
I have the honor to now lay before the committee the statements and
affidavits inclosed, from which it will appear that large forces of Indian
savages were engaged against this army at the battle of Pea Ridge, and
that the warfare was conducted by said savages with all the barbarity their
merciless and cowardly natures are capable of.
Very respectfully, your obedient servant,
SAML. R. CURTIS,
Major-General.
[Inclosures.]
HEADQUARTERS ARMY OF THE SOUTHWEST,
Forsyth, Mo., April 12, 1862.
Maj. Gen. SAMUEL R. CURTIS, Commanding:
SIR: In compliance with your request, conforming to the wish of the
joint committee of Congress &quot;to inquire into the fact whether Indian savages
have been employed by the rebels in their military service, and how such
warfare has been conducted by such savages against the Government of the
United States,&quot; I hereby certify upon honor that I was present at the engagement
near Leetown, Ark., on the 7th of March ultimo, when the main charge of
the enemy&apos;s cavalry was made upon our line; that there were Indians among
the forces making said charge; and that from personal inspection of the
bodies of the men of the Third Iowa Cavalry, who fell upon that part of
the field, I discovered that 8 of the men of that regiment had been scalped.
I also saw bodies of the same men which had been wounded in parts not vital
by bullets, and also pierced through the heart and neck with knives, fully
satisfying me that the men had first fallen from the gunshot wounds received
and afterwards brutally murdered.
The men of the Third Iowa Cavalry who were taken prisoners by the enemy,
and who have since returned, all state that there were great numbers of
Indians with them on the retreat as far as Elm Springs. Their affidavits
will be furnished to you as soon as possible.
Respectfully submitted.
JOHN W. NOBLE,
Adjutant, Third Iowa Cavalry.
UNITED STATES OF AMERICA,
Southwestern District of Missouri:
I, Daniel Bradbury, on my oath, say that I am orderly sergeant of Company
A, Third Iowa Cavalry, and that I was present at the battle of Pea Ridge,
near Leetown, Ark., on the 7th of March, 1862, and I then and there saw
about 300 Indians scattered over the battle-field, without commanders,
doing as they pleased. On the 8th of March I saw what I would judge to
be about 3,000 Indians marching in good order towards the battle-field,
under the command of Albert Pike.
DANIEL BRADBURY,
First Sergeant Company A, Third Iowa Cavalry.
Subscribed and sworn to before me this the 30th day of April, 1862.
GLENN LOWE,
Adjutant, Third Iowa Cavalry.
UNITED STATES OF AMERICA,
Southwwestern District of Missouri:
I, John H. Lawson, on my oath, say that I am a private in Company D,
Third Iowa Cavalry, and that I was present at the battle of Pea Ridge,
near Leetown, Ark., on the 7th of March, 1862, and I then and there saw,
as near as I could judge, about 150 Indians, scattered, they were afterwards
formed into companies and marched out of my sight in good order.
On the 8th of March I saw about 2,.000 Indians, said to be under the
command of Albert Pike and Martin Green, marching towards the battle-ground
in good order, These were all mounted, armed with shot-guns, rifles, and
large knives.
JOHN H. LAWSON.
Subscribed and sworn to before me this the 30th day of April, 1862.
GLENN LOWE,
Adjutant, Third Iowa Cavalry.
HEADQUARTERS THIRD IOWA CAVALRY,
Jacksonport, Ark., May 11, 1862.
Maj. Gen. SAMUEL R. CURTIS,
Commanding Army of the Southwest:
GENERAL: On the morning of the 7th of March I was on the battlefield
of Pea Ridge. While my command was engaging the enemy near Leetown I saw
in rebel army a large number of Indians, estimated by me at 1,000.
After the battle I attended in person to the burial of the dead of
my command. Of 25 men killed on the field of my regiment, 8 were scalped
and the bodies of others were horribly mutilated, being fired into with
musket balls and pierced through the body and neck with long knives. These
atrocities I believe to have been committed by Indians belonging to the
rebel army.
Very respectfully, your obedient servant,
CYRUS BUSSEY,
Colonel.
	</body>
</document>
