<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009026" url="http://huntersridge.posterous.com/?tag=marquettemanagement" time="2012-07-13-02:25" support="1" score="0.0005065173439249935" bingtitle="Hunters Ridge - Filed under &apos;Marquette Management&apos;" webtitle="Hunters Ridge - Filed under &apos;Marquette Management&apos;">
			<query id="001283" bing-rank="106"/>
	<description>Jester&apos;s is a fast food restaurant with a nice home feeling. ... A wide selection of sides and their prices are great. ... Bill Israel designed, posterous powered )</description>
	<body>
		Hunters Ridge 

Apartments
 Sep 9 
 Edit Delete Tags Autopost 
  
 Welcome Lakes of Schaumburg Apartments to Marquette Management! 
We are delighted to inform all residents and their family and friends of adding the Lakes of Schaumburg apartment community to Marquette Management! This gorgeous garden and lake community, ideally located in a prime Schaumburg spot, offers an excellent array of features and benefits that are sure to delight many who seek to make Schaumburg their home. With five different floor plans of 1 and 2 bedroom apartments, the Lakes of Schaumburg easily affords those seeking space, comfort and upscale suburban living. Please make sure to call the Lakes of Schaumburg should you and/or a friend or family member wish to schedule a time to view the apartments and settle into one of our apartment homes. The leasing team can be reached at 847-884-7990.
 ( download ) 
 Click here to download: Welcome_Lakes_of_Schaumburg_Ap.zip (986 KB) 
 
 Tweet Filed under  //  marquette management    schaumburg apartments    Feb 17 
 Edit Delete Tags Autopost 
  
 ELGIN NEIGHBORHOOD SPOTLIGHT: JESTER&apos;S FAST FOOD 

Jester&apos;s is a family owned restaurant. Celebrating 9 years of service to the gorgeous Elgin Community. Nick is the owner along with his son Andreas and daughter Maria all work at Jester&apos;s Fast Food Restaurant. Hunter&apos;s Ridge Apartments loves Jester&apos;s. Jester&apos;s is a fast food restaurant with a nice home feeling. There are times when you don&apos;t have time to cook just stop by Jester&apos;s. It&apos;s a nice sit down restaurant and the food is a step above the rest. They also have take out and delivery. Their menu has several options from burgers, gyros, burritos to a whole rotisserie chicken. A wide selection of sides and their prices are great. In the interim, while you become a resident, list below are the specials Jester&apos;s is offering thru February 28th to celebrate 9 years of service to the Elgin Community Hot Dogs $0.99
Hamburgers $1.99
Italian Sausage $1.99
BBQ Pulled Pork $1.99
Our Famous Gyros $3.69 
Jester&apos;s is located at 96 Tyler Creek Plaza, 847-622-0749 near the heart of Elgin. Make sure to stop by Jester&apos;s and let them know that we sent you! HAPPY EATING!!!! P.S. Make sure to come back next Wednesday for our Neighborhood Spotlight of the week!
 Tweet Filed under  //  Chicago Apartments    Elgin IL Apartments    Hunter&apos;s Ridge    Jester&apos;s Fast Food Restaurant    Marquette Management    Neighborhood Spotlight    Feb 14 
 Edit Delete Tags Autopost 
  
 VEGGIE VALENTINE 

You may not &quot;carrot&quot; all for me The way I care for you
You may &quot;turnip&quot; your nose When I plead with you
But if your &quot;heart&quot; should &quot;beet&quot; with mine
Forever &quot;lettuce&quot; hope There is no reason in the world
Why we two &quot;Cantaloupe&quot;
HAPPY VALENTINE&apos;S DAY!!!!!
 Tweet Filed under  //  Chicago Apartments    Elgin IL Apartments    Hunter&apos;s Ridge    Marquette Management    Valentine&apos;s Day Poems    Feb 11 
 Edit Delete Tags Autopost 
  
 VIP MEDIA MIXER! 

Join us tomorrow, 2/12 for our VIP MEDIA MIXER in the clubhouse 6pm - 9pm. Mix it up with the fans, and cool neighborhood businesses for a &quot;social media mixer&quot; including snacks, beverages, and a super fine announcement about the great i-pad drawing!
 Tweet Filed under  //  Chicago Apartments    Elgin IL Apartments    Hunter&apos;s Ridge    Marquette Management    Social Media Mixer    Feb 9 
 Edit Delete Tags Autopost 
  
 TUESDAY FAN FUN!!! 

POP on Facebook to become a fan. You will be entered to win a free movie night at the clubhouse for 10 people including popcorn, pizza, and of course, POP! YOU MUST BE A FAN TO WIN!!!!!
 Tweet Filed under  //  Chicago Apartments    Elgin IL Apartments    Hunter&apos;s Ridge    Marquette Management    Feb 8 
 Edit Delete Tags Autopost 
  
 FIVE DAYS OF FAN FUN!!! 

Win $208 on 02/08! Become a fan on Facebook and get entered in to win a $208 rent credit for March 2010! Stay tuned for Tuesdays Fan Fun!!!!
 Tweet Filed under  //  Chicago Apartments    Elgin IL Apartments    Hunter&apos;s Ridge    Marquette Management    Feb 4 
 Edit Delete Tags Autopost 
  
 Is It Summer Yet? 

 

Is it summer yet? Us over at Hunter&apos;s Ridge can&apos;t wait to get our feet wet when our pool opens! Laying out by the nice blue waters with an iced cold lemonade is exactly where we want to be right now! What do you think? Let us know where you want to be!
 Tweet Filed under  //  Apartments with Pools    Chicago Apartments    Elgin IL Apartments    Hunter&apos;s Ridge    Marquette Management    
 Hunters Ridge&apos;s profile » 
 
About




 Twitter FacebookPage 
 
 ( Bill Israel designed, posterous powered )
	</body>
</document>
