<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009170" url="http://au.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20080329170732AAIIZUi" time="2012-07-13-02:34" support="2" score="0.003048014987770794" bingtitle="When icebergs melt? - Yahoo!7 Answers" webtitle="When icebergs melt? - Yahoo!7 Answers">
			<query id="001158" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="001154" bing-rank="133"/>
	<description>Grab a 32oz cup. Available at any fast food restaurant. Put ice in the cup! Fill the r est with water. Now put it on the counter. Let the ice melt.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
 Mail 

 My Y!7 Yahoo!7 
 
 Yahoo! 7 Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo!7 Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Science&amp;Mathematics &gt; Earth Sciences&amp;Geology &gt; Resolved Question 
 yahwhooo... Member since: 15 February 2007 Total points: 255 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
When icebergs melt?
 What would happen? Now if I placed a huge iceberg into the sea the waterlevel would rise, but what happens when the iceberg melts? would the level stay at the same level as it was with the iceberg ? or would it increase ? Is the amount of water the same frozen or would it increase as it melts? Is the volume the same? or does the part of the iceberg sticking out of the water add volume? I think that wether part of the iceberg is out or not it still has the same mass and so therefore when it melts should not add to the level ? 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by zee_prim... Member since: 14 April 2006 Total points: 22,991 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 Nope, melting icebergs don&apos;t contribute to sea level rise, only icecaps on dry land, like Greenland, Antarctica and glaciers. If those all melted, sea level would rise about 80 metres. Try this experiment. Fill a glass with ice cubes. Carefully fill it to the brim with water and mop up any spilled water. You should see that when the ice has all melted, no water has overflowed, even though they projected above the rim. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: Thanx, I agree.. 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo!7 Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (5)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by atomic_o... Member since: 18 April 2006 Total points: 4,207 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 It stays the same 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by D J Member since: 12 December 2007 Total points: 20,899 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Try an experiment! Grab a 32oz cup. Available at any fast food restaurant. Put ice in the cup! Fill the r est with water. Now put it on the counter. Let the ice melt. The water created by the melting ice will not make the cup overflow.

So ice floating on the water in Antarctica breaks away and is float free. It does not affect the level of the water.

Global warming is not man made. Global warming is not significant. In fact the sun is settling into a calm period of solar activity and is cooling slightly.
Global warming advocates are trying to get money from the developed nation of the world.It is wealth envy.

Our air, water and soil is cleaner now than any time since the Industrial Revolution. If you believe the press America is killing the planet. China is the worse polluter in the world.

Do you own research, do not believe me or others. Don&apos;t drink the Kool-Aid of Global Warming. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Ben Member since: 14 September 2007 Total points: 1,069 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 the part of the iceburg sticking up + the density of the iceburg cancel out, so the same volume.

the oceans slowly rising because the glaciers (which are on land) and the icecaps are melting. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Jeff in Dallas Member since: 29 April 2007 Total points: 4,855 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Don&apos;t eat the yellow snow.

Apparently DJ below has eaten the yellow snow and lost her mind. There is a difference between glaciers and icebergs honey. I guess you&apos;re going to tell us that glaciers and icebergs melting is not a sign of warming? And that melting glaciers will not contribute to sea level rise?

Let me guess... you&apos;re a christian conservative. And you&apos;re toeing the christian party line by denying science once again. How&apos;s that worked out for you guys in the past? Not so well.

&quot;Researching&quot;the issue by putting ice and water in a cup is not going to inform anyone about global warming. If you want to do some research then go out and interview farmers about what crops grew 20 years ago at their farm but won&apos;t grow now due to climate change. Or about the time of year that they plant and harvest now compared to twenty years ago. Politicians and other people lie. The crops don&apos;t lie. Crops don&apos;t take political sides.

Ice in a cup and make up your mind about global warming? What a knucklehead. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by need help Member since: 30 March 2008 Total points: 185 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 we wouldnt be here if they melted 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 
Discover Questions in Earth Sciences&amp;Geology 

 Is phosphorus like the same thing as copper? Is flouride added by flouridation removed from water by the water cycle? What are the four ways to identify the age of the earth? Ok i have what i think is a diamond.does the scratch test really work? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Science&amp;Mathematics 
 Agriculture Alternative Astronomy&amp;Space Biology Botany Chemistry Earth Sciences&amp;Geology Engineering Geography Mathematics Medicine Other - Science Physics Weather Zoology 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo!7 does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo!7 Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo!7 Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo!7 Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
