<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009055" url="http://www.salemcountyava.org/Food_and_Nutrition.htm" time="2012-07-13-02:27" support="1" score="0.0004642665539604142" bingtitle="FOOD AND NUTRITION WEBSITES - Salem County AVA Center Home page" webtitle="FOOD AND NUTRITION WEBSITES">
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="250"/>
	<description>... their research results into a plan for a fast-food ... of a popular breakfast cereal (Usually 3/4 cup). ... Unfortunately, too many American children do not receive ...</description>
	<body>
		FOOD AND NUTRITION WEBSITES

 


 
Access these sites through your computers Internet 
connection. Open the underlined address (URL). Information can be printed 
or downloaded to your computer. Be sure to follow links to other sites and find 
your way back with the&quot;Back&quot;button. Note that a gateway site is one that is 
mostly links to a very large number of other sites on the topic. Also, we note 
where we found broken links in our sampling of links within a site. Teachers 
will need to replace these links with their own.
 

 
All of the sites listed were active as of May 12, 2006. The 
evaluation is by the AVA Center staff according to the amount of information 
given, the general appearance of the site and its potential use in the 
classroom.
 

 
NOTE: A lot of sites are sponsored or funded by commercial 
entities. We recommend only those parts of the site which are non-commercial.
 
           Websites         Lesson Plans&amp;Classroom Activities         Webquests 
 

 
 Websites
 

 
 THE ACCIDENTAL SCIENTIST: THE SCIENCE OF COOKING
 http://www.exploratorium.edu/cooking/ 
 Webcasts, activities and recipes that explain the science 
behind cooking while being fun. Excellent
 

 
APPLES 42EXPLORE             NEW!
 http://42explore.com/apples.htm 
 Basic information on apples along with activities and 
webquests. Excellent
 

 
BAKING BREAD VIRTUAL FIELD TRIP                NEW !
 http://www.field-trips.org/sci/bake/ 
 A virtual field trip about bread making for upper 
elementary/middle school students. Excellent
 

 
CHOCOLATE 42EXPLORE             NEW!
 http://www.42explore.com/choclat.htm 
 Basic information on chocolate with activities and webquests. 
Excellent
 
COOKALOTAMUS COOKING WITH KIDS        NEW!
 http://www.cookalotamus.com/ 
 A site that promotes parents and children cooking and eating 
together. Includes recipes, food facts, and much more. Sections: Whats Up?, 
Parents, Kids, Whats for Dinner?, Whos Cooking? (guest chef), and Media. The 
Kids section includes games and activities. Excellent
 

 
CORN 42EXPLORE            NEW!
 http://www.42explore.com/corn.htm 
 Basic information on corn with activities and webquests. 
Excellent
 

 
DOLE 5 A DAY                             
 http://www.dole5aday.com/ 
 This site is revamping and will be named Dole Superkids. Includes: Kids section Music, Games, Videos, Coloring Pages 
(online), Five a Day Facts, 5 a Day Friends (such as Randy Radish and Stuart 
Spinach), Reference Center (nutrition facts, vitamin levels, FAQs), and a Kids 
Cookbook (easy recipes for kids to do). The Teachers Section has Classroom 
Resources including Lesson Plans, Scope and Sequence Charts, kits to order and 
more. Excellent
 

 
EGGS 42EXPLORE            NEW!
 http://www.42explore.com/eggs.htm 
 Basic information on eggs with activities and webquests. 
Excellent   
                                                                                                                
5 A DAY THE COLOR WAY EAT YOUR COLORS! 
 http://www.5aday.com/ 
 The site emphasizes the colors of health as blue/purple, 
green, white, yellow/orange and red the colors of fruits and vegetables. It 
notes that we need to eat 5 or more servings of these foods a day for a healthy 
diet. It lists the foods that fit each color and includes recipes. The Kids 
section has coloring pages and activity sheets. The Educators section includes an entire curriculum to download called&quot;Theres a Rainbow on My Plate&quot;. Choose 
K-3 or 4-6. There are also lesson plans and activity sheets. 
Excellent
 

 
THE FOOD TIMELINE                NEW URL!
 http://www.foodtimeline.org/ 
&quot;Ever wonder what the Vikings ate when they set off to 
explore the new world? How Thomas Jefferson made his ice cream? What the 
pioneers cooked along the Oregon Trail? Who invented the potato chip...and why? 
Food is the fun part of social studies! The tricky part is finding recipes you 
can make in a modern kitchen, with ingredients bought at your local supermarket 
and bring into school to share with your class. This page is for you! We are 
also stocking up on teacher and parent food resources. Looking for social 
customs, manners&amp;menus? Try the Culinary History Timeline. Bon appetit.&quot; Click on the foods on the timeline, some (but not all) have detailed histories 
of that food. Click on the Recipes side for links to websites on that topic. 
Excellent
 

 
GIRL POWER! GET BODY WISE!
 http://www.girlpower.gov/girlarea/bodywise/index.htm 
&quot;Getting BodyWise is all about learning to love and take care 
of your bodyit&apos;s the only one you&apos;ve got! That means knowing how to choose 
nutritious foods, eat smart, and stay fit. It&apos;s important to learn about the 
vitamins and nutrients your body needs to keep you going. It&apos;s also important to 
get the facts about serious health problems like eating disorders.&quot; Sections: Body Image and You, Eating Right the Girl Power! Way, Feeling Fit!, 
Facts About Eating Disorders, Keeping Up with Your Body, and Resource Guide to 
Nutrition, Fitness and Eating Disorders. Excellent
 

 
KID CHEF WHERE KIDS RULE THE KITCHEN                NEW!
 http://www.kidchef.com/cda/index.cfm 
&quot;KidChef is a movement -- a movement aimed at getting kids, 
parents and new chefs into the kitchen. The creation of KidChef is a response to 
the current relationship between food and kids. Fast food has become more 
prominent, parents have less time to cook and our culture moves at an 
unbelievably fast pace.  Cooking is a great way to slow down and bring kids back 
in touch with the food they eat. It&apos;s a way for them to see how each individual 
ingredient works to create a flavor and texture. It&apos;s a way to allow kids to 
see, taste and experience the product of an effort put forth. Think of the 
educational value as well -- cooking is science, math and art all rolled into 
one - and what a tasty way to learn!&quot; Sections: Cooking Basics, Recipes, Fun 
Stuff, The Scoop, Parents and Shop. Excellent
 

 
NIEHS CHILDRENS FOOD FUN PAGE
 http://www.niehs.nih.gov/kids/baylor/homefood.htm 
 Fun food-based games and activities for kids. Includes: Food 
Pyramid Game, Lets Talk About the Food We Eat!, A Food Poem Puzzle!, We Can 
Make a Difference! and more. Excellent
 
NUTRITION CAF                 
 http://exhibits.pacsci.org/nutrition/ 
 Three fun activities for students: Grab a Grape 
(Jeopardy-type game), Nutrition Sleuth, and Have-a-Bite Caf (choose a healthy 
meal). Also includes the Food Guide Pyramid, a Glossary and Dietary Guidelines. 
Excellent
 

 
NUTRITION IN THE GARDEN
 http://aggie-horticulture.tamu.edu/nutrition/index/index.html 
 Information on the relationship between gardens and healthy 
eating. Geared toward upper elementary students. The Teachers section of the 
Gardening Ideas section includes ideas for classroom activities and lesson 
ideas. Excellent
 

 
NUTRITION ON THE WEB- FOR TEENS            NEW!
 http://library.thinkquest.org/10991/ 
 A student-created site on nutrition for teens. Two sections: 
Informative and Interactive. Informative includes: Exercises, World Nutrition, 
Myths, Case Files, Teen Health, Recipes, Links. Interactive includes: BMR and 
AMR, RDA, Diet Planner, Calorie Database, Nutri-Quiz, Forum and Live Chat. In 
English, Spanish and German. Excellent
 

 
PEANUT 42EXPLORE            NEW!
 http://www.42explore.com/peanut.htm 
 Basic information on peanuts with activities and webquests. 
Excellent
 
POTATO 42EXPLORE            NEW!
 http://www.42explore.com/potato.htm 
 Basic information on the potato with activities and 
webquests. Excellent
 

 
THE REAL TRUTH ABOUT FAST FOODS AND NUTRITION                NEW!
 http://library.thinkquest.org/4485/ 
 A student-create site about fast foods and nutrition. 
Sections: Welcome, All About Nutrition (and Whats Best for You), Advertisements 
(the small print), School Lunches and Other Lunch Facts, Which Meal is Healthier, Did You Know?, Who Says You Cant be 
Healthy? And Nutrition Guides for the most common fast food restaurants. 
Excellent
 

 
SMARTMOUTH.ORG                NEW!
 http://www.cspinet.org/smartmouth/ 
 A fun nutrition site for kids. Sections: Choose UR Chews, 
Articles&amp;Reports (incl. Recipes), Feed the Face, Bite Back, Trust Gus, 
Snacktoids, Video Clips and Links. Excellent
 

 
SPICES 42EXPLORE             NEW!
 http://www.42explore.com/spices.htm 
 Basic information on spices with activities and webquests. 
Excellent
 

 
VITAMINS AND MINERALS 42EXPLORE            NEW!
 http://www.42explore.com/vitamin.htm 
 Basic information on vitamins and minerals with activities 
and webquests. Excellent
 







 
                                                 

ALFYS PICKS FOR NUTRITION
 http://www.alfy.com/teachers/teach/thematic_units/Nutrition/Nutrition_1.asp 
 Games and links for primary students on nutrition. Many are 
listed on this list. Very Good
 

 
CIA FOR KIDS ( CULINARY INSTITUTE OF AMERICA)            NEW!
 http://www.ciakids.com/forkids/index.html 
 A site for kids from the CIA. Sections: Whats in the CIA 
Kitchen?, What Do Chefs Do?, What do Pastry Chefs Do?, The Uniform, Cooking 
Methods, Culinary Dictionary, Computers in the Kitchen, Planning to be a Chef, 
Safety in the Kitchen, Nutrition and Kitchen Clean Up. Very Good
 

 
COOL FOOD ADOZ (ADOLESCENTS)
 http://www.coolfoodplanet.org/gb/adoz/index.htm 
 A fun, lively site for adolescents on healthy eating habits. 
Sections: 10 Tips for Good Nutrition, Body Fit, Brain Fit, Sport Fit, Weight and 
Good Eating, Emotions and Eating, Building Healthy Habits, Food Myths, Eating 
Out, Safe Food, Reading Labels, Tell Us What You Want and Best Coolfood Sites. 
Very Good
 

 
COOL FOOD KIDZ
 http://www.coolfoodplanet.org/gb/kidz/ 
 A fun, colorful site for primary children on food and healthy 
eating habits. Sections: Building Healthy Habits, Eating Out, Tell Us What You 
See, Safe Food, 10 Tips for Kidz, Nutrition Quiz for Kidz, Body Fit, Brain Fit, 
Great Teeth and Whats a Food Label. Very Good
 

 
COUNT YOUR CALORIES BECAUSE CALORIES COUNT            NEW URL!
 http://www1.wfubmc.edu/Nutrition/Count+Your+Calories/ 
 Five activities/quizzes to assess your diet and physical 
fitness. Includes links. Very Good
 

 
DYING TO BE THIN            NEW!
 http://www.pbs.org/wgbh/nova/thin/ 
 A PBS site on eating disorders. Sections: Watch the Program 
Here (broken into 8 chapters) , A Transcript of the Program, Ask the Experts, 
Share Your Story, Minority Women: The Untold Story, Body Needs (Hot Science), 
and Help/Resources. Includes a Teachers Guide. Very Good
 
 

EAT SMART  
 http://www.eatsmart.org/ 
 Information on the food pyramid and portions. Includes lots 
of printed materials to print out or order. Note: The Essential Learning section 
includes the standards for Washington State only. The Games include Nutrition 
Caf and Calcium Calculator, both listed separately on this page.  Very Good
 

 
FOOD AD TRICKS
 http://www.zillions.org/Features/Foodadtricks/Food_ad001.html 
 Information for kids from Consumer Reports on how food ads 
trick us into wanting the product and how they are&quot;cosmetically&quot;enhanced to 
look more appetizing. Geared toward middle/junior high students. Very Good
 

 
FOOD AND AGRICULTURE OF THE WORLD
 http://museum.agropolis.fr/english/default.htm 
 Four virtual exhibitions on the history of food and 
agriculture: World Food (NEW), History of Food and Agriculture, Farmers and 
Farming Over the World, and the&quot;Banquet de lHumanit&quot;(different foods in 
different cultures). Very Good
 
FOOD AND NUTRITION GAMES
 http://www.schoolmenu.com/health.htm 
 Includes: Hidden Veggies Game, Food Group Maze, Food Pyramid 
Match Game, Food Guide Word Search Puzzle, and DJs Food Pyramid Maze. Plus DJs 
Spotlight on Nutrition and Its All Good for U. Very Good
 

 
THE FOOD FILES            NEW!
 http://library.thinkquest.org/11960/ 
 A student-created site on food. Sections: Nutrition, Healthy 
Eating, Miracle Diets?, Handling Food, Food Trouble, Food Facts, Food Fun!, and 
Discussion. Includes lesson plans for grades 9-12. Very Good
 

 
HOW STUFF WORKS FOOD
 http://www.howstuffworks.com/food.htm 
&quot;But what is food? What&apos;s in food that makes it so important? 
What happens to the food once you eat it? What is food made of? How does it fuel 
our bodies? What do words like&quot;carbohydrates&quot;and&quot;fats&quot;really mean 
(especially on those&quot;Nutrition Facts&quot;labels you find on almost everything 
these days)? What would happen if you ate nothing but marshmallows for a week? 
What is a calorie? Why can&apos;t we eat grass like a cow does, or wood like a 
termite?  If you have ever wondered about food and how your body uses 
it, then read on. In this edition of How Stuff Works, we&apos;ll give you all of the 
information you need to understand what a hamburger or a banana does to keep 
your body running every day!&quot; Very Good
 

 
ITS MY LIFE BODY FOOD SMARTS: WHATS IN YOU?            NEW!
 http://pbskids.org/itsmylife/body/foodsmarts/ 
 Nutrition information for kids from PBS. Sections: The Food 
Pyramid, Serving Size Surprises, Understanding Food Labels, The Choices are 
Yours, Myths and Facts, Real World Tips and Tricks, and Family Eating Habits. 
Good basic information. Includes a word search puzzle. Very Good
 

 
KIDNETICS RECIPES
 http://www.kidnetic.com/Recipes/ 
 A collection of fun and nutritious recipes that kids can 
make. Sections: Family Friendly, Breakfast Bonanza, Brown Bag Specials, Gross 
Out Delights, Featured, Super Sides, Smart Snacks, and Dinner Winners. Includes 
a Parents section. Very Good
 

 
KIDS IN THE KITCHEN            NEW!
 http://library.thinkquest.org/J0110321/index.htm 
 A website for students by students on food science and 
kitchen safety for kids. Sections: History, Science, Cooking, Safety, Games, 
Nutrition, Recipes, and more. Very Good

 KIDS WORLD NUTRITION
 http://www.agr.state.nc.us/cyber/kidswrld/nutrition/index.htm 
 Nutrition information for kids. Sections: Food Pyramid, 
5-a-Day, Nutrition Label, Coloring Book, Quiz, Links, Food Safety, General 
Agriculture&amp;History, and Plant Nutrition. Very Good
 

 
MOO MILK            NEW!
 http://www.moomilk.com/index.html 
 A site from the dairy industry for kids about milk and where 
it comes from. Includes: Connect the Dots, Moo Milk Quiz, Virtual Tour-The Story 
of Milk, FAQ, Dairy Cuisine, and more. Good
 

 
MYPYRAMID.GOV            NEW!
 http://www.mypyramid.gov/kids/ 
 A site for kids from the USDA on the food pyramid and 
nutrition. Includes games, posters, worksheets, coloring pages and tips. Very 
Good
 

 
NUTRITION AND THE FOOD PYRAMID            NEW!
 http://www2.lhric.org/pocantico/nutrition/nutrition.html 
 A website created by first graders for primary students about 
the food pyramid. Includes games, puzzles and riddles. Very Good
 

 
NUTRITION FACT SHEETS            NEW URL!
 http://www.eatright.org/cps/rde/xchg/ada/hs.xsl/nutrition_350_ENU_HTML.htm 
 A long list of printable fact sheets on nutrition topics such 
as: Fats, Oils&amp;Sweeteners; Kids Nutrition Needs; Nutrition for Everyone; 
Special Needs; Vitamins, Minerals and Functional Foods and Weight Management. 
Some are in PDF format. One brochure is available in Spanish. Very Good
 

 
 

PUTTING SCHOOL LUNCH TO THE TEST
 http://www.zillions.org/Features/Lunch/lunch001.html 
 Information for kids from Consumer Reports examining just how 
nutritious school lunches really are. Sections: School Lunch Nutrition Test, 
Sort&amp;Smush Game, Nutrition Test Results and Taste Survey. Very Good
 

 
VEGETARIAN FOOD PYRAMID                NEW URL!
 http://www.vegsource.com/nutrition/pyramid.htm 
 Shows an equivalent food pyramid guide which excludes meat. 
Very Good
 

 
VEGGING OUT!
 http://my.execpc.com/~veggie/index.html 
 Information on a vegetarian diet. Sections: Feature Article, Recipes, Veggie 
Kids and Cookbook Reviews. The Veggie Kids section has recipes suitable for 
children to make. Very Good
 
WEBSITE ON EATING DISORDERS
 http://www.something-fishy.org/ 
 Information on eating disorders such as bulimia, anorexia, 
compulsive overeating, etc. Includes Signs, Factors, Associated Dangers, 
Treatment Finder and more. Includes a Support section for those who are 
struggling with an eating disorder. For teachers and older students. Very Good
 

 
                                                   

AMERICAN DIETETIC ASSOCIATION
 http://www.eatright.org/Public/ 
 Includes: Food and Nutrition Information, Careers and 
Students, Government Affairs, Continuing Education, and Media. Also a Tip of the 
Day and a Monthly Feature. Good
 
ANTIQUE ROMAN DISHES
 http://www-2.cs.cmu.edu/~mjw/recipes/ethnic/historical/ant-rom-coll.html 
 A collection of recipes from ancient Rome. Good
 
 

ASK MR. VITAMINS
 http://www.askmrvitamins.com/ 
 Choose from the topics on the left for information about 
vitamins, minerals and herbs. Theres an explanation, how its used, where its 
found, etc. Good
 

 
AWESOME SNACKS KIDS MAKE AROUND THE WORLD
 http://www.sara-jordan.com/activities-snacks.shtml 
 A list of snacks that kids from several countries have 
submitted as their favorites. Good for ideas for kids. Good
 

 
THE BLONZ GUIDE: NUTRITION, FOOD AND HEALTH RESOURCES
 http://www.blonz.com/ 
 An extensive number of links to nutrition resources. For 
senior students and teachers. Good
 

 
CALORIE CONTROL COUNCIL
 http://www.caloriecontrol.org/ 
 Information on the importance of keeping track of the 
calories you consume and how to reduce them if necessary. Good
 

 
CALORIE COUNTERS FAST FOODS NUTRITIONAL GUIDE
 http://www.calorie-counters.net/ 
 Calorie, fat, sodium, carbohydrates, etc. counts for all 
kinds of foods from fast food restaurants. Search by type of food or see the 
charts by restaurant. Good
 

 
CALORIES IN FOOD CHARTS AND TABLES
 http://www.annecollins.com/calories/ 
 Calorie charts and tables for a variety of foods including 
fast food and takeout. Note: There is information on the site promoting a weight 
loss program. Just ignore the link. Good
 

 
CALCIUM AND NUTRITION                NEW!
 http://library.thinkquest.org/04apr/01368/ 
 A student-created site on the importance of calcium in our 
diets. Sections: Background Info, Experiments, Recipes and more. Good 
information for upper elementary students. Good
                                                                                                             
CALCIUM CALCULATOR 
 http://www.eatsmart.org/external/default.asp?URL=%2Fgames%2Fc%5Fcalculator%2F 
 Check how much calcium you are getting in your diet to build 
and maintain strong bones and teeth. The results tell you how much you are 
getting and what you need. Good
 

 
THE CENTER FOR FOOD SAFETY AND APPLIED NUTRITION
 http://vm.cfsan.fda.gov/ 
 The FDAs Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition. 
Includes: Recent News, National Food Safety Programs, Program Areas, Special 
Interest Areas, and more. Good
 

 
CHEESE!                         NEW!
 http://library.thinkquest.org/5417/ 
 A student-created site about cheese. Sections: Cheese Essays, 
Cheesy Links, Cheese by Hardness, Cheese Activities, Cheesy Facts, Cheese 
Recipes, Cheese Field Trip, and Bibliography. Good
 

 
THE COFFEE CRAZE            NEW!
 http://library.thinkquest.org/5441/ 
 A student-created site on coffee. Sections: The Craze, Coffee 
and Your Heart, Do You Know What You Are Ordering?, Coffee and Sleep, Glossary, 
Caffeine, The Graph, Digging Up Facts about Coffee, The Story of a Bean, From 
Bean to Cup The Game, The Map, Little Known Facts about Coffee, How Well Do 
You Know The Prices? and Links to the Outside World. Good
 

 
COOKING WITH KIDS            NEW!
 http://www.weeklyreader.com/parents/cooking/ 
 A list of recipes for cooking with your kids. Includes: Fruit 
Smoothie, Frozen Banana Bites, Pumpernickel People, Dinosaur Bone Cookies and 
more. Good
 

 
COOL MEALS                NEW!
 http://www.coolmeals.co.uk/ 
 A site for students ages 7-11 on nutrition. Food Facts and 
Activities (worksheets and coloring pages). Enter the Virtual Body Lab and see 
how the foods you eat measure up. (Note: students must register- free).&quot;The 
Body Lab section is an interactive area where children (and adults) can have a 
bit of fun, but also learn about nutrition. The aim of this section is to 
analyse what the individual has eaten over a period of a day and then compare it 
to the Health Education Authority&apos;s Balance of Good Health Food Plate model.&quot;This site refers to the British version of the US Food Guide Pyramid.  Good
 

 
CULINARY DICTIONARY                NEW!
 http://www.ciakids.com/forkids/dictionary/dictionary_a.html 
 A dictionary of culinary terms. Good
 

 
CULTURAL AND ETHNIC FOOD AND NUTRITION MATERIALS FOR TEACHING
 http://www.nal.usda.gov/fnic/pubs/bibs/gen/ethnic.html#12 
 Scroll down the page for fact and activity sheets for 
students on nutrition in the Spanish language. There is information in other 
languages but they are mostly Spanish. Good
 

 
THE DAIRY SPOT
 http://www.dairyspot.com/ 
 Promotes the benefits of dairy foods such as milk and cheese. 
Sections: For Your Health, Featured Recipe, Featured Farm, Dairy Tip, Whats 
Moo, Dairy Lovers Kitchen, Dairy Showcase, School Nutrition, Milk Vending, and 
Milk Products and Trends. Good
 

 
DECIPHERING FOOD LABELS
 http://www.kidshealth.org/parent/nutrition_fit/nutrition/food_labels.html 
 Information on the history of food labeling and how to read 
todays nutrition labels. Note: Although originally aimed at parents, this 
information is good for students, too. Good
 

 
DONT GROSS OUT THE WORLD            NEW!
 http://www.fekids.com/img/kln/flash/DontGrossOutTheWorld.swf 
 A fun quiz on international food customs. Good
 

 
FAST FOOD FACTS            NEW URL!
 http://www.fastfoodfacts.info/ 
 Learn about the nutrition in fast food items. Good
 

 
FAVORITE FOODS OF KIDS                NEW!
 http://library.thinkquest.org/6041/ 
 A student-created site on kids favorite foods. For 
elementary students. Sections: Basic Cooking Tips, Recipes, Wacky Foods, Jokes, 
Riddles, Word Games and Survey. Good
 

 
FIGURING OUT FOOD LABELS
 http://www.kidshealth.org/kid/stay_healthy/food/labels.html 
 Information for students on how to read and understand food 
labels. Good
 

 
FILL UP, NOT OUT FACT SHEETS
 http://lancaster.unl.edu/food/eatsmart.pdf 
 A four-page fact sheet for educators on smart eating tips and 
showing how calories and fat add up. Good
 

 
FOOD CALORIE CHART
 http://www.bhg.com/home/Food-Calorie-Chart.html 
 A chart with the calorie counts for foods in categories such 
as Meat and Seafood, Beverages, Dairy and Frozen Desserts, etc. Good
 

 
FOOD COLORING BOOK
 http://coloringbookfun.com/food/index.htm 
 Coloring pages to print out with food pictures. There are six 
pages with 12 to a page. Good
 
FOOD FIT
 http://www.foodfit.com/ 
 Lots of information on choosing healthy foods and a healthy 
lifestyle. Sections: Lose Weight, Healthy Eating, Healthy Cooking, Fitness, 
Community. Good
 

 
THE FOOD GUIDE PYRAMID FOR YOUNG CHILDREN
 http://www.usda.gov/cnpp/KidsPyra/ 
 The Food Guide Pyramid for young children (ages 2-6) with 
graphics and easy-to-understand wording. Download in .PDF format. (Software link 
included). You can download as an 8 1/2x 11 sheet in color or black and white or 
as a reproducible or a poster. Good
 

 
THE FOOD MUSEUM ONLINE
 http://www.foodmuseum.com/ 
&quot;Everything you&apos;d expect to find in the world&apos;s only 
independent food museum will be found here. For several years we have been 
building online exhibits about the world&apos;s foods. You can search for a 
particular food by name, by hemisphere, and by type.&quot; Check the food list 
for the history of particular foods. Good
 

 
FOOD PYRAMID GAME
 http://www.dairycouncilofca.org/activities/pyra_main.htm 
&quot;Test your knowledge of the 5 food groups, and how many 
servings you need from each group, with this game!&quot; A simple game where you 
move the food group game pieces to their place on the pyramid. Good
 

 
FOOD SAFETY WORD MATCH
 http://www.foodsafety.gov/~dms/fsematch.html 
 A word match game matching words with their definitions. Good
 

 
FOOD STUDENTS
 http://www.foodstudents.net/englisch/foodstudents.html 
 Site about food and how it produced. Sections: Encyclopedia, 
The Project, The Quiz, Experts, Theme of the Month, and Teachers Section. The 
Teachers Section includes Background sheets and Classroom Aids to print out. 
Good
 

 
GET INTO THE MOOD FOR FOOD A THINKQUEST SITE
 http://library.thinkquest.org/J002074F/?tqskip1=1 
&quot;Are you in the MOOOD for some fun?? If so, you&apos;re in 
luck. In our website you can learn all about food, nutrition, and overall 
good health. We&apos;ll teach you how to count cowlories, get mooving, and feel 
moovelous about yourself! Have fun grazing in our website!&quot; A 
student-created site for elementary students on food and nutrition. Sections: 
Pyramid, Cowlories, Get Mooving, and Disorders. Good
 

 
THE HEALTHY REFRIGERATOR OPEN THE DOOR TO A HEALTHY HEART 
JUST FOR KIDS      NEW!
 http://www.healthyfridge.org/justforkids.html 
 Sections: Facts about Hearth Disease and Children, Recipes, 
Take the Kids&quot;Healthy Fridge&quot;Quiz, and Seek-a-Word Game. Good
 

 
HOW TO READ A RECIPE                NEW!
 http://kidshealth.org/kid/stay_healthy/food/read_a_recipe.html 
 A brief description for kids on how to read and understand a 
recipe. Good
 

 
HUMAN DIGESTIVE SYSTEM
 http://www.enchantedlearning.com/subjects/anatomy/digestive/ 
 A site for primary students explaining how we digest what we 
eat. Good
 

 
KIDS NUTRITION
 http://www.ext.nodak.edu/food/kidsnutrition/ 
 Links for kids, teens and teachers on child nutrition. Good
                                                                                                                 
LUNCHBOX MAKEOVERS
 http://www.cspinet.org/new/school_lunch.html 
 Tips for packing healthy school lunches. Good
 

 
MARYANNS FOOD CLIPART
 http://www.maryannsart.com/cgi-bin/ImageFolio31/imageFolio.cgi?search=food&amp;cat=&amp;bool=and 
 Very good food clipart. Good
 

 
MIKES CALORIE AND FAT GRAM CHART FOR 1000 FOODS
 http://www.caloriecountercharts.com/ 
 Searchable database of the fat grams and calorie counts for 
foods. You can also check by protein count, cholesterol and carbohydrates. 
Includes nutrition links. Good
 

 
MISSION NUTRITION GAME             NEW!
 http://kidshealth.org/kid/closet/games/mission_nutrition.html 
 A simple, fun game for elementary students. Students click on 
the most nutritious food. Good
 

 
MYTHS AND REALITIES OF EATING DISORDERS
 http://www.mirror-mirror.org/myths.htm 
 Lists the myth and the reality of eating disorders. Good
 

 
NUTRITION CROSSWORD PUZZLE
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/xwords/20000302.html 
 A crossword puzzle using nutrition-related words such as 
cholesterol and digest. Good
 

 
NUTRITION.GOV                NEW URL!
 http://nutrition.gov/ 
 The portal to nutrition information on government websites. 
Includes: Food Facts, Food Safety, Lifecycle Issues, Health Management, Food 
Assistance, Research and Resources. Good
 

 
PLAY WITH YOUR FOOD                NEW!
 http://library.thinkquest.org/5434/ 
 A student-created site with kid-friendly fun recipes. 
Includes: Egg Mouse, Celery Wagon, Ants on a Log, Egg Mushroom, Marshmallow Man, 
Marshmallow Science and Egg Boat. Good
 

 
SHAPE UP AMERICA!
 http://www.shapeup.org/ 
 A site for healthy eating habits and fitness for life. Good
 

 
SINGAPORE FOOD PARADISE            NEW!
 http://library.thinkquest.org/20371/ 
 A student-created site on the food of Singapore, with several 
distinct cuisines. Sections: Nonya Food, Chinese Food, Malay Food and Indian 
Food. Good                                                                                                                         

SNACK TIME PRINTABLE WORD SEARCH   
 http://www.lessontutor.com/jm2.html 
 A printable word search puzzle using fruit and vegetable 
names to encourage students to think of fruits and vegetables for snacks instead 
of junk food. Good

 
 
10 OF THE WORST AND BEST CHILDRENS FOODS
 http://www.cspinet.org/nutrition/10b&amp;w.html 
 Lists 10 of the worst childrens foods such as soda pop and 
hamburgers and 10 of the best such as skim milk and crackers. Good
 

 
10 TIPS TO HEALTHY EATING AND PHYSICAL ACTIVITY
 http://www.kidsource.com/kidsource/content3/ific/ific.10tipskid.html 
 A brochure for kids from 9-15. Not very detailed but good 
information. Good
 

 
28 BILLION SERVED WORLD HUNGER            NEW!
 http://library.thinkquest.org/10786/ 
 A student-created site on world hunger. &quot;YOU WILL BE ABLE TO LEARN SOME 
INTERESTING
AND USEFUL INFORMATION ABOUT WORLDWIDE HUNGER SITUATIONS WHICH ARE RESPONSIBLE 
FOR THOUSANDS OF DEATHS EACH YEAR. OUR MAIN GOAL IN CREATING THIS SITE IS TO 
MAKE PEOPLE (THE YOUTH ESPECIALLY) REALIZE THAT BEING HUNGRY IS MORE THAN ONLY 
EATING TWO BIG MAC&apos;S AT LUNCH. MANY CHILDREN HAVE TO PASS DAYS WITHOUT SO MUCH 
AS A SCRAP OF BREAD AND SOLUTIONS ARE NEVER EASY TO REACH.&quot; Sections: Global 
Situations, Statistics, Organizations, Helpers, Links and Bibliography. Good
 
VEGETARIAN FOOD PYRAMID            NEW!
 http://www.vegsource.com/nutrition/pyramid.htm 
 A food guide pyramid for vegetarians. Good
 

 
VEGGIE POWER CYBER HUNT CROSSWORD            NEW!
 http://teacher.scholastic.com/products/instructor/veggiepower.htm 
 An online crossword puzzle on vegetables. Good
 

 
WEIRD FOODS FROM AROUND THE WORLD            NEW!
 http://www.weird-food.com/ 
 A list of foods that seem a little strange to Americans. 
Sections: Vegetable, Fish, Bird, Mammal, Reptile, Amphibian, Bugs, Drinks, 
Mineral, and Other. Good
 
WHATS THE RIGHT WEIGHT FOR ME?            NEW!
 http://kidshealth.org/kid/talk/qa/fat_thin.html 
 Information on kids health including a BMI (Body Mass 
Indicator) to give them an idea of what weight they should be for their size. 
Theres also a Recipes section for healthy recipes. Good
 

 
THE WIDE WORLD OF DOUGHNUTS            NEW!
 http://library.thinkquest.org/J003336/ 
 Information on the history and making of doughnuts. Includes: 
The History of Doughnuts, The One Stop Laugh Shack Doughnut Shop, Doughnut Wars, 
Doughnut Popularity, Doughnut Health, and Taste Test. A student-created site. 
Very well done. Good
 


 
 
 Lesson Plans&amp;Classroom Activities
 

 
COMPARISON FOOD SHOPPING: BUYING GROCERIES FOR TWO PEOPLE FOR 
ONE WEEK LESSON PLAN
 http://yn.la.ca.us/cec/cecmisc/cecmisc.75.txt 
A lesson plan on food shopping for senior high students. &quot;OBJECTIVE(s): 
(1) Teach students to use a simple food budget for two (2) Teach students to 
comparison shop through newspaper ads (3) Teach (or remind) students to include 
the basic four food groups daily (4) Teach (or remind) students about calorie 
content of common foods.&quot; Excellent
 
 CONSUMING HISTORY: INVESTIGATING FOODS FROM DIFFERENT TIMES 
AND PLACES AROUND THE WORLD LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20020626wednesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan on foods around the world for grades 6-12. &quot;In this lesson, students will research various foods as well as indigenous 
plants and animals from different historical eras around the world. They then 
use their research to create a design for&quot;theme&quot;restaurants.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 COOKING UP AN EXPLANATION: INVESTIGATING THE SCIENCE BEHIND 
VARIOUS FOODS LESSON PLAN 
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20021126tuesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
A lesson plan for grades 6-12 on food science. &quot;In this 
lesson, students will pose scientific questions about food items and research 
their explanations. They will then create&quot;recipe cards&quot;with the answers and 
present their findings in a cooking show format.&quot; Excellent

 

 CROPS 1: WHERE DOES FOOD COME FROM? LESSON PLAN
 http://www.sciencenetlinks.com/lessons.cfm?BenchmarkID=8&amp;DocID=376 
 A lesson plan for grades K-2 on where food comes from. &quot; In 
Crops 1: Where Does Food Come From?, students learn that most of the food they 
buy in stores originally comes from farms. Students are gathered together to 
sing a song about growing crops on a farm and learn from the lyrics the kinds of 
things that farmers do and need to grow plants well. They learn about the five 
steps in our food system and discuss its aspects in the context of a story about 
tomato farming and distribution.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 CROPS 2: WHAT PLANTS NEED TO GROW LESSON PLAN
 http://www.sciencenetlinks.com/lessons.cfm?DocID=377 
 A lesson plan on food crops for grades K-2. &quot; In Crops 2: 
What Plants Need to Grow, students focus on the second part of the central 
benchmark by learning how to grow plants and about the kinds of things that 
promote growth (warmth, sunlight, water, soil). Their activities involve 
learning about how seeds and plants grow and participating in a simple, in-class 
gardening project.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 THE CRUCIFEROUS CRUSADERS ALL-STAR CANCER FIGHTING TEAM 
LESSON PLANS
 http://www.leafy-greens.org/lessonplans.html 
 Lesson plans for grades 3-5 on leafy green vegetables. There 
are lessons for Language Arts, Math, Social Studies, Science/Health and 
Culminating Activities. &quot;Students are led through activities across the core 
curriculum by a team of five dinosaur characters dressed in baseball uniforms 
who are the&quot;Cruciferous Crusaders&quot;All-Star Cancer Fighting Baseball Team. 
(Cruciferous = vegetables in the leafy green family).&quot; Excellent
 

 
 COUNTING CALORIES: CREATING WORD PROBLEMS ABOUT CEREAL 
NUTRITION LESSON PLAN  NEW!
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20050210thursday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan for grades 6-12 on cereal nutrition. &quot;In 
this lesson, students evaluate the health of breakfast foods. They work in pairs 
to create and solve word problems using cereal nutrition data. For homework, 
they solve additional problems formulated in class and write short essays 
commenting on what they have learned.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 DYING TO BE THIN: SUPPORTING FRIENDS WITH EATING DISORDERS 
LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20001121tuesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan on eating disorders for grades 6-12. &quot;In 
this lesson, students role-play scenarios in which they encounter a friend or 
acquaintance who may have an eating disorder. Students brainstorm ways to help 
the friend. Students then create informational brochures with useful information 
about eating disorder prevention.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 EAT RIGHT, STAY FIT LESSON PLAN        NEW!
 http://school.discovery.com/lessonplans/programs/eatright/ 
 A lesson plan for grades 6-8 on eating healthy. &quot;Students 
will do the following: 1. Learn what a healthful diet is 2. Assess their eating 
habits to determine if they are getting the right foods to stay healthy 3. Learn 
about the relationships among metabolism, calories, and diet.&quot; Excellent

 EATING OVER THE RAINBOW: LEARNING HOW COLOR IS CONSIDERED IN 
CHOOSING A HEALTHFUL DIET OF FRUITS AND VEGETABLES LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20020514tuesday.html 
A lesson plan for grades 6-12 on healthy diets. &quot;In this 
lesson, students first examine their own diets, and then redesign the USDA&apos;s 
Food Pyramid to reflect nutrition experts&apos; latest advice.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 EDUCATORS REFERENCE BOOK NUTRITION LESSON PLANS
 http://eduref.org/cgi-bin/lessons.cgi/Health/Nutrition 
 A long list of lesson plans on nutrition. Includes: Balanced 
Meals, Fit for Life, Making a Sandwich, Pyramid Relay and more. Excellent
 

 
 FANTASTIC FOODS: LEARNING ABOUT HEALTHY AND DELICIOUS FOODS 
LESSON PLAN        NEW!
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20050719tuesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan for grades 6-12 on food and nutrition. &quot; In 
this lesson, students learn about the health benefits of dark chocolate. They 
research other foods which they consider to be both healthy and delicious for a&quot;classroom pantry.&quot;&quot; Excellent

 

 FAST FOOD AROUND THE WORLD LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nationalgeographic.com/xpeditions/lessons/10/g68/fastfood.html 
 A lesson plan on foods in other cultures for grades 6-8. &quot; Students will use the Internet or the library to research the cultures of four 
other countries. They will compile their research results into a plan for a 
fast-food restaurant in each of the countries, tailoring the restaurant to the 
cultural tastes of people in those countries.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 FOOD AND NUTRITION THEME UNIT
 http://www.abcteach.com/directory/theme_units/science/food_and_nutrition_theme_unit/ 
 Activity sheets, games, poetry and more on food and 
nutrition. Seems to be geared toward grades 2-4. Excellent
 

 
 FOOD FOR THOUGHT: INVESTIGATING NUTRITIONAL COMPONENTS OF 
FOOD IN THE SCIENCE OR HEALTH CLASSROOM LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/19990525tuesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan for grades 6-12 on nutrition. &quot;In this 
lesson, students explore various nutritional components found in foods to 
analyze their sources, effects on the human body, and relationship to a healthy 
diet. Each student researches a different nutritional component and then creates 
an informative poster incorporating the research.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 FOOD, GLORIOUS FOOD?: EXPLORING INTERNATIONAL PERSPECTIVES ON 
THE PROS AND CONS OF GENETICALLY MODIFIED FOODS LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20030212wednesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan on genetically modified food for grades 6-12. &quot;In this lesson, students learn about the different reactions that American 
and European consumers have had to genetically modified foods and represent 
different perspectives in a debate about whether grocery stores should stock and 
label them. Each student then designs a television advertisement encouraging or 
discouraging consumers from buying genetically modified foods.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 FOOD, NUTRITION AND FOOD SCIENCE LESSON PLANS             NEW!
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/LPview?grade=12 
 Scroll down the page for a long list of lesson plans on Food 
and Nutrition and Food and Science. For 12 th grade students. 
Excellent
 

 
 FOOD/NUTRITION TEACHING THEME
 http://www.bestteachersites.com/themes/science/food/ 
 Extensive resiources for teaching about nutrition. Sections: 
Bulletin Board Set, Downloads, Resource Materials, Sites for Backgroun 
Information, Hands On Activities, Web Quests, Interactive Sites for Students, 
Work Sheets, Lesson Plans, and Work Sheets You Can Customize. Excellent
 

 
 FOOD PRESERVATION LESSON PLAN            NEW!
 http://www.sciencenetlinks.com/lessons.cfm?DocID=396 
 A lesson plan for grades 3-5 on food preservation. &quot; In 
this lesson, students&apos; attention is drawn to the issue of food spoilage and the 
different methods that are traditionally used to prolong the freshness of food. 
Using a number of online resources, they learn about how Chilean fruit and 
lettuce for salad are carefully harvested, treated, packaged, and transported in 
refrigerated vessels to maintain their freshness. Students are then introduced 
to the canning, drying, freezing, and vacuum-sealing processes that are commonly 
used by food producers and in the home.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 FOOD PYRAMID POWER LESSON PLANS            NEW 
URL!
 http://illuminations.nctm.org/LessonDetail.aspx?ID=L63 
 A collection of lesson plans on food and nutrition for grades 
K-2. There are 6 lessons. 1/ Sorting Foods 2/ Eating Patterns 3/ Pyramid Power 
4/ Combining Foods 5/ Try for Five and 6/ Looking Back and Moving Forward. 
Excellent
 

 
 FOOD SAFETY LESSON PLANS
 http://www.extension.iastate.edu/foodsafety/Lesson/lessons.html 
 Four lessons on food safety: Whats Bugging You?, What are 
Consumer Control Points?, Where is the Danger Zone?, and Who is Fat Tom? Note: 
Use the Next button at the bottom to navigate through the lessons. There is a 
Teachers Guide to download. Excellent
 

 
 
 

 
 FOODS ALTERED EGO: UNDERSTANDING INTERNATIONAL POSITIONS ON 
THE USE OF GENETICALLY MODIFIED FOODS LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20000315wednesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan on genetically modified foods for grades 6-12. &quot;In this lesson, students investigate various countries&apos; positions on 
genetically modified foods and write a position paper from the perspective of 
their designated country.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 FRUITFUL QUESTIONS: POSING AND ANSWERING FOOD SCIENCE 
QUESTIONS LESSON PLAN        NEW!
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20050208tuesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan for grades 6-12 on food science. &quot;In this 
lesson, students examine a fruit-related Q&amp;A Science Times article. Students 
then write their own food science questions and then answer them in the same 
format as the article. For homework, they analyze their fruit consumption 
according to U.S. nutrition guidelines.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 GLOBAL BREAKFAST LESSON PLAN
 http://www.sciencenetlinks.com/Lessons.cfm?DocID=75 
 A lesson plan for grades 3-5 on food. &quot;In this 
interdisciplinary lesson, students explore the concept of global interdependence 
by investigating the origins of the foods they eat. Students will recognize the 
fact that many of the foods they eat, and the ingredients that go into making 
them, are produced in other countries. They will speculate about why certain 
foods are produced in different regions of the world, and what might happen if 
the production and/or distribution of these goods was to stop.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 GOOD FOR YOU?: INVESTIGATING THE HEALTH BENEFITS OF CHOCOLATE 
 LESSON PLAN            NEW!
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20051101tuesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan for grades 6-12 on chocolate. &quot;In this 
lesson, students share opinions about nutrition. They then compare the 
nutritional values of a snack product claiming health benefits with a candy 
product. Learning is synthesized by reflecting on the responsibility of 
companies, individuals and the government in determining whether a product lives 
up to its claims.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 &quot;GOT MILK?&quot;OR&quot;NOT MILK&quot;, THAT IS THE QUESTION!: CRITICALLY 
ANALYZING INFORMATION ABOUT DAIRY PRODUCTS ON THE INTERNET LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20000926tuesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan on the controversy over milk for grades 6-12. &quot;In this lesson, students critically analyze Web sites that present different 
sides of the controversial milk debate (good for you/not good for you).&quot; Excellent
 

 
 GUESS WHOS COMING TO DINNER LESSON PLAN
 http://www.econedlink.org/lessons/index.cfm?lesson=EM522 
 A lesson plan for middle/junior high students on food 
regulation. &quot;Your task in this lesson will be to read about some of the 
government rules that protect our nations food supply, identify reasons buyers 
and sellers seek government regulation and information in a market economy, and 
to use information on food labels to make a consumer choice.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 HEALTH TEACHER NUTRITION LESSON PLANS
 http://www.healthteacher.com/lessonguides/default.asp#nutrition 
 A collection of lesson plans on nutrition for grades K-12. 
Excellent

 HEALTHY CHOICES FOR KIDS CURRICULUM GUIDES
 http://www.healthychoices.org 
 A set of curriculum guides on health and nutrition. 1/Eat a 
Wide Variety of Foods 2/Choose a Healthy and Active Lifestyle 3/ Eat Plenty of 
Fruits, Vegetables&amp;Grains 4/ Choose Healthy Snacks. Excellent
 

 
 HEY, MOM! WHATS FOR BREAKFAST? LESSON PLAN
 http://www.econedlink.org/lessons/index.cfm?lesson=EM41 
 A lesson plan for upper elementary students on breakfast 
foods. &quot; In this lesson you will: Discuss food items you consume for 
breakfast. Investigate elements of foreign culture, particularly food. Use 
map skills to locate selected foreign nations. Increase your knowledge of the 
these definitions: Economic wants are things people would like to have. 
Goods and services are provided to fulfill these wants. Those who create the 
goods and provide the services are producers Those who use them are consumers. 
 Consumers found in different parts of the world may have differing wants. 
Foods for satisfying hunger are a common economic want. Foods can vary greatly 
from one part of the world to another.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 HUNGRY FOR HISTORY: EXPLORING THE HISTORY OF FOODS WE SIMPLY 
CANNOT LIVE WITHOUT LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20030611wednesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan on the history of food for grades 6-12. &quot; In 
this lesson, students examine what their diets would be like without the 
inclusion of staple crops such as corn, wheat and sugar, and discover the value 
that chocolate had for the Mayan people. They then research the evolution of the 
uses of specific staple crops in various cultures and create display boards for 
a food festival called&quot;Historical Cravings.&quot;Finally, students reflect upon how 
their researched foods play a role in their daily lives.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 INTERNATIONAL FOOD COURT LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nationalgeographic.com/xpeditions/lessons/04/g68/foodcourt.html 
 A lesson plan for grades 6-8 the types of food found around 
the world. &quot;This lesson helps students learn about the characteristics of the 
world&apos;s regions by investigating the types of food that are common in different 
parts of the world. Students will conduct research to find out about the 
climate, landscape, and cultures of a few countries. They will compile their 
findings into a plan for an international food court in a local mall, describing 
the types of food that will be served, the decor, and the entertainment.&quot; Excellent
 


 
 
 JUNK FOOD JUNGLE LESSON PLAN            NEW!
 http://www.media-awareness.ca/english/resources/educational/lessons/elementary/advertising_marketing/junk_food_jungle.cfm 
A lesson plan for grades 4-6 on food advertising. &quot; This 
lesson familiarizes children with the nutritional value of foods advertised on 
television and in magazines. The lesson begins with a class discussion about 
different types of foods and where snack food fits into a healthy diet. Students 
then compare TV&apos;s version of a great meal to the kinds of foods that their 
mothers would recommend, and categorize the foods they enjoy according to 
whether or not they would be considered part of a healthy diet. In groups, 
students survey television and magazine food ads to determine what types of 
foods are promoted most often.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 A MEAT BY ANY OTHER NAME: SOCIAL VIEWS TOWARDS THE ANIMAL WE 
EAT: A LESSON FOR THE SOCIAL STUDIES CLASSROOM LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/19980824monday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan on food and culture for grades 6-12. &quot;Students will discuss how food reflects different aspects of a culture and 
reasons why cultural differences in food are seen as bizarre or, oftentimes, 
cruel by members of other societies.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 MMMMMMMM AND GOOD LESSON PLAN            NEW!
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20041124wednesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan for grades 6-12 on food and nutrition. &quot; In 
this lesson, students will consider their own diets and examine an op-ed article 
about organically produced foods. They then research alternatives to various 
foods for the creation of a supermarket and reflect on their own diets after 
keeping a food journal.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 MY BODY HELPS ME GET FOOD LESSON PLAN
 http://www.sciencenetlinks.com/lessons.cfm?DocID=383 
 A lesson plan for grades K-2 on food. &quot;This lesson focuses 
on students learning that some parts of their body help to keep their body 
nourished with food. At the K-2 level, you can expect that students will think 
of their body parts as rather separate entities, with each part having its own 
function. It is not until they are older that they begin to understand their 
body parts in terms of a system.&quot;Children at this level think each organ has 
its own independent function. The eyes are for seeing, the brain is for 
thinking, the stomach is for digesting food, and so forth. Only later will 
students be able to learn how organs work in coordinated ways to make systems. 
One can expose young children to some of the facts in response to their 
questions, but they cannot understand those facts until they are older.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 NATURES SUPERHEROES: BRINGING TO LIGHT NEW RESEARCH ON 
VITAMINS AND THE HUMAN BODY LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20020806tuesday.html 
 A lesson plan for grades 6-12 on vitamins . &quot;In this 
lesson, students compare their prior knowledge about the relationship between 
sunlight and cancer with new findings. They then research how different vitamins 
and minerals affect the human body.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 NUTRIENTS BY THE NUMBERS: USING MATH TO EXPLORE NUTRITION 
LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20021003thursday.html 
 A lesson plan for grades 6-12 on nutrition. &quot;In this 
lesson, students strengthen their percentage and fraction skills in comparing 
the nutritional values of similar food products. They then individually 
calculate their daily intake of various nutrients and compare their diets to 
recommended daily percentages.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 NUTRITION EXPLORATIONS: EDUCATORS LESSON PLANS
 http://www.nutritionexplorations.org/educators/main.asp 
 Nutrition lesson plans and worksheets for teachers. Excellent

 ORGANIC FEUD: ASSESSING REASONS TO BUY OR ABSTAIN FROM THE 
ORGANIC FOODS MARKET LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20030325tuesday.html 
 A lesson plan on organic foods for grades 6-12. &quot; In this 
lesson, students examine possible pesticide exposure in their fruit and 
vegetable consumption. They then compile fact sheets exploring various organic 
food issues and interview their parents about the food choices they make for 
their children.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 A PICTURE OF HEALTH: EVALUATING SOCIETAL AND INDIVIDUAL 
NUTRITION AND EXERCISE HABITS LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20000201tuesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan on nutrition and health for grades 6-12. &quot; In 
this lesson, students explore why Americans failed to meet health goals for the 
year 2000 and ways in which Americans can shape up to meet the 2010 goals. 
Students maintain a food and exercise diary for one week, evaluate their 
nutrition and exercise habits, and propose ways in which they can improve their 
health.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 REGIONAL FOODS LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nationalgeographic.com/xpeditions/lessons/04/g35/foods.html 
 A lesson plan for grades 3-5 on foods eaten in different 
regions of the U.S. and the world. &quot;In this lesson, students will explore the 
culture of different regions by learning about differences in foods and recipes. 
They will create maps of the United States and the world, based on what they 
have learned about various regions through Internet research.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 SCIENCE NETLINKS NUTRITION LESSONS: 

        NUTRITION 1: 
FOOD AND THE DIGESTIVE SYSTEM - LESSON PLAN
        http://www.sciencenetlinks.com/lessons.cfm?Grade=3-5&amp;BenchmarkID=6&amp;DocID=57 
A lesson plan on nutrition for grades 3-5. &quot; This lesson 
will focus on the digestive system in order to address the latter part of the 
benchmark-that undigested food is eliminated. In addition, it will begin to 
explore where nutrients come from and their importance for particular tasks in 
the body. This Science NetLinks lesson is the first of a three part series . 
It works in conjunction with Nutrition 2: Good Food, Good Health, a lesson that 
teaches about the food groups and how vitamins and minerals help the body 
function properly, and Nutrition 3: Got Broccoli?, a lesson that encapsulates 
what students have learned about nutrition.&quot; Excellent
 

 
       NUTRITION 2: GOOD 
FOOD, GOOD HEALTH - LESSON PLAN
        http://www.sciencenetlinks.com/lessons.cfm?DocID=56 
A lesson plan on nutrition for grades 3-5. &quot;As you go 
through this lesson, you also should be aware that younger elementary students 
often believe that the contents of the body are what they have seen being put 
into or coming out of it. They also know that food is related to growing and 
being strong and healthy, but they are not aware of the physiological 
mechanisms. You should make it clear that food is a source of matter for growth, 
not a requirement for growth.&quot; Excellent

        NUTRITION 3: 
GOT BROCCOLI? - LESSON PLAN
        http://www.sciencenetlinks.com/lessons.cfm?DocID=58 
A lesson plan on nutrition for grades 3-5 . &quot;This lesson 
encapsulates what students have learned about nutrients, their different forms, 
and their importance for particular tasks in the body. It works in conjunction 
with Nutrition 1: Food and the Digestive System and Nutrition 2: Good 
Food, Good Health , which are Science NetLinks lessons on the digestive 
system and nutrition.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 SHAPE CALIFORNIA CLASSROOM CURRICULUM
 http://www.ausd.k12.ca.us/shape/lessons/curriculum/page5.html 
 A curriculum for nutrition education from a consortium of 70 
California school districts. Each section has 1-4 lesson plans. Sections: 
Fitness, Making Nutrition Come Alive for You, Kids Cooking Week, Fat!, Getting 
to the Root of 5 a Day, Sugar Awareness, and All Foods Can Fit. Unfortunately, 
the other sections have broken links. Excellent
 

                                                                                                             

 
 SIZING UP SERVINGS: ASSESSING DEFINITIONS OF RECOMMENDED FOOD 
PORTIONS LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20030722tuesday.html 
 A lesson plan on recommended food portions for grades 6-12. &quot; In this lesson, students learn the definition of a suggested serving size 
and re-define their daily food intake in terms of these recommended amounts.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 SKATING ON THIN ICE: EXAMINING EATING DISORDERS AND THE 
VARIOUS MEANS TO TREAT THEM LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20020611tuesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan on eating disorders for grades 6-12. &quot;In 
this lesson, students research various eating disorders and their treatments. 
They then create fictional case studies of teenagers suffering from these 
disorders and synthesize their understanding by writing suggestions for 
treatment.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 SOUL FOOD: EXPLORING CONNECTIONS BETWEEN GEOGRAPHY, CULTURE 
AND THE FOODS WE EAT LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20000503wednesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan on food and culture for grades 6-12. &quot; In 
this lesson, students explore the connections between food and culture by 
investigating the production, preparation, and historical and cultural ties of 
foods significant to cultural groups with which they identify. Students then 
participate in a Cultural Food Festival to share this information and these 
&apos;cultural&apos; foods with their classmates.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 SPICE GEOGRAPHY LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nationalgeographic.com/xpeditions/lessons/16/g68/ingredient.html 
 A lesson plan for grades 6-8 on spices and their origins. &quot;This lesson encourages students to think about where the ingredients in their 
food come from and how they are produced. Students will investigate the origins 
of a variety of spices from around the world and map these locations. They will 
then research and create presentations describing the climate, terrain, and 
agricultural practices in the places they have mapped.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 SPICES IN YOUR FAVORITE FOODS LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nationalgeographic.com/xpeditions/lessons/16/g35/favfoods.html 
 A lesson plan for grades 3-5 on the significance of spices in 
their food. &quot;Studying spices is a tasty way for students to learn about 
natural resources, trade, and our use of international products. In this lesson 
students will learn a little bit about the importance of spices in history and 
will focus on the significance of spices in the foods they eat. They will 
research some of the spices in their favorite foods and will map the origins of 
these spices. Students will conclude by planning meals that use these spices and 
writing fact sheets that describe the spices to the people eating the meal.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 SUGAR-COATING THE FACTS: EXAMINING THE FOOD INDUSTRYS 
INFLUENCE ON NUTRITIONAL HABITS AND ANALYZING NUTRITION CHARTS LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20020219tuesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan on nutrition and the food industry for grades 
6-12. &quot;In this lesson, students explore the food industry&apos;s influence on 
American children&apos;s nutritional habits and analyze the nutrition charts found on 
food packaging. They then synthesize their knowledge by designing&quot;warning 
labels&quot;to be placed on products that are targeted to children to better 
represent the contents&apos; nutritional value.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 SUNDAE NEWS: CELEBRATING ICE CREAM THROUGH A 
STUDENT-MADE TELEVISION PROGRAM LESSON PLAN                    NEW! 
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20040701thursday.html 

 A lesson plan for grades 6-12 on ice cream.  In this lesson, students research topics related to ice cream and create a 
news magazine program based on their research. Then students develop public 
service announcements promoting ice cream consumption.  Excellent 

   

 TASTY MODELS LESSON PLAN            NEW!
 http://www.pbs.org/saf/1401/teaching/teachinghs.htm 
 A lesson plan for senior high students in which they construct models of 
nutrient molecules. &quot;Understanding the arrangement of atoms within nutrient 
molecules often helps explain their chemical behavior, health attributes and 
role in weight balance. Although atomic representations do not accurately 
represent electron configurations, they can be used to show the arrangement of 
nuclei and bond type. In the following activities, you&apos;ll construct several 
different molecular models that represent substances that play an essential role 
in our nutritional needs.&quot; Excellent

 TOO MUCH OF A SWEET THING: A HEALTH, SCIENCE AND LANGUAGE 
ARTS LESSON INVESTIGATING AMERICANS CONSUMPTION OF PROCESSED SUGAR LESSON 
PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/19990921tuesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
A lesson plan for grades 6-12 on sugar consumption. &quot;Students will examine the growing prevalence of processed sugar in the American 
diet, first through a demonstration that makes graphically clear the amount of 
sugar an average boy and girl consumes on a daily basis. They then will explore 
the issue in greater depth through the featured article. Finally, student teams 
will devise illustrated posters for a Sweet Health campaign, aimed at persuading 
other children and parents of the potential dangers of processed sugar 
over-consumption and the value of healthy eating alternatives.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 USING YOUR MELON FOR MATH: APPLYING FRACTION MULTIPLICATION 
AND DIVISION TO RECIPES LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/19990715thursday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan using recipes and math for grades 6-12. &quot;In 
this lesson, students use recipes to practice their fraction multiplication and 
division skills by calculating the amounts of ingredients needed to make 
specific recipes, given varied numbers for the &apos;yield&apos; quantity. Students will 
also use these fraction skills to convert small units of cooking measures to 
larger units.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 
 

 
 WHERES THE BEEF?: INVESTIGATING THE BENEFITS AND CHALLENGES 
OF A VEGETARIAN DIET FOR YOUNG PEOPLE LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/20000725tuesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan for grades 6-12 on vegetarian diets for teens. &quot; In this lesson, students create and conduct a community survey to evaluate 
the demographics of vegetarians in their community. Students compile data, 
create graphs, calculate percentages, and draw conclusions about their survey 
data. Students create an informational awareness pamphlet for other young people 
about the benefits and challenges of a vegetarian diet.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 YOU ARE WHAT YOU EAT: EVALUATING THE NUTRITIONAL COMPONENTS 
OF ONES DIET LESSON PLAN
 http://www.nytimes.com/learning/teachers/lessons/19981229tuesday.html?searchpv=learning_lessons 
 A lesson plan on diet for grades 6-12. &quot;In this lesson, 
students evaluate their eating habits, focusing on the ways in which one 
assesses whether or not his or her diet is nutritious. Students work in small 
groups to design a menu for a healthy lunch and write a paragraph justifying 
their choices. For homework, students maintain a food diary over the course of a 
week and write a reflective essay discussing their food intake and proposing 
ways to make their diet healthier.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 YOUVE GOTTA HAVE A GIMMICK!: A LESSON IN JUNK FOOD 
ADVERTISING LESSON PLAN
 http://www.media-awareness.ca/english/resources/educational/lessons/elementary/advertising_marketing/gotta_have_a_gimmick.cfm 
 A lesson plan for grades 5-7 on how advertisers get them to 
buy junk foods. &quot;To familiarize students with the marketing techniques used 
in television and magazine snack food ads.&quot; Includes student handouts, 
guided discussion and classroom activities. Excellent
 







 
                                                 

 CALCIUM BONE BUILDERS LESSON PLAN
 http://www.teachers.net/lessons/posts/1953.html 
 A lesson plan for middle school students about the role of 
calcium. They will learn about the role of calcium in the body, the foods we get 
it from and will construct a calcium-rich menu. Very Good
 

 
 FOOD GROUP/NUTRITION LESSON PLAN
 http://www.teachers.net/lessons/posts/1534.html 
 A lesson plan for primary students on food groups. &quot; Let 
child cut out different foods from newspapers and magazines. Glue pictures on 
paper plate. Do one for each meal. (breakfast, lunch, snack, dinner) Allow child 
to decorate a sheet of construction paper, color of choice, as a placemat. Glue 
paper plate to paper. Then discuss why each food is or is not healthy for you or 
your teeth, and what food group to which it belongs. Make suggestions on healthy 
meals.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 FOOD GROUPS CLASS BOOK LESSON PLAN
 http://www.teachers.net/lessons/posts/2022.html 
 A lesson plan for elementary students on food groups. &quot;Purpose: to introduce the six food groups of the food pyramid and choose foods 
to fit in appropriate categories in order to make a food group class book. 
Objective: students will demonstrate understanding of the food groups by 
categorizing foods in the proper areas in order to make a class book (by working 
in cooperative groups).&quot; Very Good
 

 
 THE FOOD GUIDE PYRAMID LESSON PLAN
 http://www.teachers.net/lessons/posts/1719.html 
 A lesson plan on the food guide pyramid for elementary 
students . &quot;Following a computer assisted lesson on the Food Guide Pyramid, 
grade four students will be able to
write out a one day menu including all of the proper foods and amount of 
servings with 100% accuracy.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 THE FOOD GUIDE PYRAMID AND ITS IMPORTANCE LESSON PLAN
 http://www.teachers.net/lessons/posts/1325.html 
 A lesson plan on the food guide pyramid for elementary 
student. &quot;The students will demonstrate and understanding of the food groups 
by categorizing foods in the proper area. Given the six food groups in the food pyramid each student will be given 
twenty pictures of foods and asked to place them under the correct category 
without any errors.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 FOOD RISKS: PERCEPTION VS. REALITY THEMATIC UNIT
 http://www.cfsan.fda.gov/~dms/risk-toc.html 
 An 8 lesson unit on food safety and the myths and reality of 
food risks. Very Good
 

 
 FOOD SAFETY AT HOME, SCHOOL AND EATING OUT AN ACTIVITY BOOK
 http://www.foodsafety.gov/~dms/cbook.html 
&quot;The first coloring book page is already colored for 
you--check it out! All the other pages are full page drawings that can be printed out and colored 
with pencils or crayons. You can even color the second drawing with your 
computer.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 KITCHEN MATH LESSON PLAN
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=1192 
 A lesson plan in math using food measurements. Very Good
 

 
 MEASURING CALORIES LESSON PLAN
 http://yn.la.ca.us/cec/cecsci/cecsci.188.txt 
 A lesson plan for grades 5-8 in which students measure the 
energy in food by measuring the calories of energy produced when the food is 
burned. Very Good
 

 
 NUTRITION LESSON PLAN
 http://www.teachers.net/lessons/posts/1707.html 
 A lesson plan for middle school students on nutrition in 
which students create their own food pyramid by cutting pictures from magazines 
of the different foods in the food groups. Very Good
 

 
 A POEM WITH HEALTH AND NUTRITION LESSON PLAN
 http://www.teachers.net/lessons/posts/1673.html 
 A lesson plan for primary students using nursery rhymes to 
teach nutrition. It uses the story of Jack Sprat and his wife to identify the 
basic food groups and learn about the food pyramid chart. Very Good
 

 
 REHYDRATION LESSON PLAN            NEW!
 http://www.nasaexplores.com/show_58_teacher_st.php?id=03010990844 
 A lesson plan for grades 5-8 on rehydrating dried foods in 
which students rehydrate foods and measure how much water they need to do so. &quot;Freeze-drying and other drying methods remove most of the water in foods. This 
food type (once rehydrated) provides a more solid-type diet and adds variety to 
the space flight menu. Onboard the Space Shuttle, dehydrated foods and drinks 
make up a significant part of the menu selection. The major reason for using 
these dehydrated foods and drinks is because water is produced by the fuel cells 
as a byproduct, making water abundantly available for Space Shuttle food 
preparation. A significant weight reduction is achieved by rehydratable food and 
drinks. For the ISS, electrical energy requirements are best met by using a 
renewable energy source. Solar arrays, which convert solar energy into 
electrical energy, do not produce water as a byproduct. The ISS food manifest 
has reduced the amount of food rehydratables significantly. Drinks, however, are 
still best handled in a rehydratable package for storage ease.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 

 SALAD PARTY LESSON PLAN
 http://ofcn.org/cyber.serv/academy/ace/sci/cecsci/cecsci107.html 
 A lesson plan for grades 3-4 on the importance of plants in 
our diets. Very Good
 

 
 SOUPERSERVICE KIDS CURRICULUM UNIT            NEW!
 http://www.learningtogive.org/lessons/unit103/A 
 A curriculum unit for grades K-2 on growing and using foods 
to feed the community. &quot;The students grow and harvest vegetables that will 
eventually be used to feed the hungry of the community. During the unit, 
students will grow in an awareness of healthy foods that are necessary for 
everyone. They will be introduced to the concepts of hunger and homelessness, 
which leads to the desire to help out in a small way. They will learn about how 
foods are processed and stored for later and for sharing with others. They will 
assemble jars of dried soup mixture and distribute the jars of soup to 
individuals eating at a local soup kitchen. The project is designed to involve 
the students&apos; parents/caregivers.&quot; Includes 7 lessons. Can be adapted to 
exclude growing vegetables. Very Good
 

 
 UTAH NUTRITION EDUCATION LESSON PLANS
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/LPview.cgi?core=7 
 Note: The links at the bottom of the page of each lesson 
contain the worksheets, guidelines and other information used in the lesson.
 

 
 ●●BALANCE BENEFITS LESSON PLAN 5 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=956 
 A lesson plan for grade 5 on the benefits of a balanced diet. 
Very Good
 

 
 ●●BALANCE EQUALS BEAUTY LESSON PLAN 3rd
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=974 
 A lesson plan for 3 rd grade students on how a 
healthy diet increases the likelihood of physical wellness. Very Good
 

 
 ●●THE BASIC NUTRIENTS LESSON PLAN 9 th -12 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=1153 
 A lesson plan on nutrients for grades 9-12. &quot;Students will 
identify the basic nutrients found in each food group: vitamins, minerals, fats, 
proteins, water, and carbohydrates.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 ●●CALORIE BURNING ACTIVITIES LESSON PLAN 4 TH
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=103 
 A lesson plan for 4 th grade students on activities 
that burn calories. &quot;Students will use problem solving, decision making and 
basic math skills to calculate calories used during different activities.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 ●●CHOICES LESSON PLAN 4 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=953 
 A lesson plan for grade 4 on making healthy choices in diet 
and exercise. Very Good
 

 
 ●●COOKING METHODS LESSON PLAN 6 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=977 
 A lesson plan for grade 6 in which students learn about 
different methods of cooking such as frying, steaming, boiling, baking, etc. 
Very Good
 

 
 ●●DESIGN-A-MEAL LESSON PLAN 3 rd
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=68 
 A lesson plan for 3 rd grade students on meal 
planning. Very Good
 

 
 ●●DIETARY BASICS LESSON PLAN 6 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=968 
 A lesson plan for grade 6 reviewing basic dietary guidelines. 
Very Good
 

 
 ●●DIETARY GUIDELINES LESSON PLAN 5 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=955 
 A lesson plan for grade 5 on recommended dietary guidelines. 
Very Good
 

 
 ●●DIETARY GUIDELINES LESSON PLAN 7 th -8 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=1165 
 A lesson plan for grades 7-8 on dietary guidelines. &quot;Students will incorporate the dietary guidelines into their lives by setting 
personal goals. &quot; Very Good
 

 
 ●●DIETARY SOLUTIONS LESSON PLAN 4 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=952 
 A lesson plan for grade 4 on solving nutritional problems 
such as undereating, overeating and deficiency. Very Good
 

 
 ●●EFFECTS THAT DIET MAY HAVE ON THE BODY LESSON PLAN 7 th -8 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=1160 
 A lesson plan for grades 7-8 on the effects diet may have on 
the body. &quot;Students will research the effects that diet may have on the body: 
anemia, osteoporosis, heart disease, obesity, diabetes, and mental health.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 ●●EVALUATING YOUR DIET LESSON PLAN - 3rd
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=966 
 A lesson plan for 3 rd grade students on diet. &quot;Ask the children to get out a piece of blank paper. Have them fold it 
lengthwise into thirds. (A fun way to tell them is to fold it the&quot;hot dog&quot;way 
for lengthwise.) Ask the children to remember what they ate for lunch. Have them 
write the foods in the first column on their paper. In the second column, have 
them write the food group from which each food came and evaluate if it was a 
balanced lunch. In column number three, they should list any food(s) that they 
would add to the meal to make it well balanced.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 ●●EVALUATING YOUR EATING HABITS LESSON PLAN 5 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=957 
 A lesson plan for grade 5 on evaluating eating habits by 
recording everything eaten during a day. Very Good
 

 
 ●●FAST FOOD RESTAURANT MENUS LESSON PLAN 7 th -8 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=1158 
 A lesson plan for grades 7-8 in which they analyze fast food 
restaurant menus and rank foods by their nutritional content. Very Good
 

 
 ●●FAST FOODS LESSON PLAN 6 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=971 
 A lesson plan for grade 6 in which students learn that fast 
foods can be healthy or unhealthy. Very Good
 

 
 ●●FOOD GROUP INFO LESSON PLAN 9 th -12 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=1152 
 A lesson plan for grades 9-12 on food groups. &quot;Students 
will identify names, correct portions, and food types for each food group.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 ●●FOOD INTAKE AND PHYSICAL ACTIVITY LESSON PLAN 4 TH 
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=159 
 A lesson plan for 4 th grade students on how food 
intake relates to physical activity. &quot;Students graph their estimations of 
caloric intake and caloric expenditures.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 ●●FOOD LABELS LESSON PLAN 9 th -12 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=1154 
 A lesson plan for grades 9-12 on food labels. &quot; Students 
will evaluate various types of food using the new food labels.&quot; Very Good

 ●●FOOD PREFERENCES LESSON PLAN 6 th 
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=970 
 A lesson plan for grade 6 on food preferences. Very Good
 

 
 ●●THE FOOD PYRAMID LESSON PLAN 7 th -8 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=1159 
 A lesson plan for grades 7-8 on the food pyramid. &quot;Students will identify names, correct portions, food types and basic nutrients 
for each food group in the food pyramid.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 ●●HEALTHY PARTY FOODS LESSON PLAN 7 th -8 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=1157 
 A lesson plan for grades 9-12 on healthy foods that would be 
good for parties. &quot;Students will identify nutrient dense healthy party foods 
that would be enjoyed by teenagers. Using the new nutrition labels, they will 
analyze the nutritional value, as well as the cost of various food.&quot; Very 
Good
 

 
 ●●IMPORTANT VITAMINS AND MINERALS LESSON PLAN 4 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=949 
 A lesson plan for grade 4 on vitamins and minerals. Very Good
 

 
 ●●ITS SUGAR TIME! LESSON PLAN 5 TH
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=233 
 A lesson plan for 5 th grade students on the place 
of sugar in a healthy diet. &quot;Good health depends upon many things, including 
heredity, lifestyle, personality traits, mental health, attitudes, and the 
environment. Good eating habits for both animals and humans, proper exercise, 
and a moderate use of sugars can help keep you healthy.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 ●●LABELING LESSON PLAN 6 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=969 
 A lesson plan for grade 6 in which students learn about the 
labels on food products and what they tell us. Very Good
 

 
 ●●MEDIA INFLUENCES ON NUTRITIONAL PRACTICES LESSON PLAN 
7 th 8 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=1161 
 A lesson plan for grades 7-8 on how the media affects our 
food choices. &quot;Students will compare specific types of media influences on 
nutritional practices, including specific types of nutritional quackery and peer 
pressure that influence teens.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 ●●NUTRIENT DENSITY LESSON PLAN 9 th -12 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=1164 
 A lesson plan on nutrients in our foods. &quot;Students will 
analyze snacks for nutrient density and ease of preparation.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 ●●NUTRIENTS LESSON PLAN 3rd
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=967 
 A lesson plan for 3 rd grade students on nutrients. 
Very Good
 

 
 ●●NUTRIENTS IN OUR FOODS LESSON PLAN 5 TH
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=259 
 A lesson plan for 5 th grade students on nutrients. &quot;Students will use the Internet to learn of, and research, information on 
health and nutrition. Students will study the six essential nutrients.&quot; Very 
Good
 

 
 ●●NUTRITIONALLY WELL LESSON PLAN 4 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=951 
 A lesson plan for grade 4 on how nutrition affects growth and 
wellness. Very Good

 
 

 
 ●●NUTRITIOUS BREAKFASTS LESSON PLAN 7 th -8 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=1163 
 A lesson plan for grades 7-8 on breakfast. &quot; Students will 
plan nutritious breakfasts which they can prepare.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 ●●PLAN TO BALANCE LESSON PLAN 3rd
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=965 
 A lesson plan for 3 rd grade students on the 
importance of a healthy diet. &quot;Plan a balanced evening meal. Ask the children 
to name the food groups they know. Talk about their answers, and guide them to 
see how the groups are formed. List the names of the correct food groups on the 
board.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 ●●SALT: TO USE OR NOT TO USE? LESSON PLAN 5 TH
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=248 
 A lesson plan on the role of salt in our diets for 5 th grade students. &quot;Salt is important to human life. Potassium, added to salt, 
helps the kidneys regulate the body&apos;s fluid levels. Salt, made from sodium and 
chloride, is found in many beverages and foods we eat. Some people consume 10 
times more salt than required daily. What are the real risks connected to our 
salt intake?&quot; Very Good
 

 
 ●●THE SEVEN DIETARY GUIDELINES LESSON PLAN 7 th -8 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=1162 
 A lesson plan for grades 7-8 on dietary guidelines. &quot;Students will identify the seven dietary guidelines and set goals to apply the 
guidelines into their lives.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 ●●SPECIFIC ILLNESSES THAT ARE DIET-RELATED LESSON PLAN 9 th -12 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=1155 
 A lesson plan for grades 9-12 on the relationship between 
diet and illness. &quot;Students will identify specific illnesses that are diet 
related: anemia, osteoporosis, heart disease, obesity, diabetes, and eating 
disorders.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 ●●VITAMINS AND MINERALS LESSON PLAN 4 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=959 
 A lesson plan for grade 4 on the function of vitamins and 
minerals in the body. Very Good
 

 
 ●●WELL-ROUNDED DIET LESSON PLAN 4 th
 http://www.uen.org/Lessonplan/preview.cgi?LPid=976 
 A lesson plan for grade 4 on eating a balanced diet. Very 
Good
 

 
 WHATS FOR DINNER CURRICULUM UNIT
 http://commtechlab.msu.edu/sites/letsnet/noframes/bigideas/B4/b4u2.html#plans 
 A curriculum unit on nutrition for middle school students. &quot;In this unit, students will conduct Internet searches to find recipes for 
appetizers, main courses, side dishes, and desserts that appeal to them. They 
will then plan (and, optionally, cook) a dinner for their families or friends, 
taking into consideration the cost of the items they will need to buy in order 
to do their cooking, and the amounts they will need to buy in order adequately 
to feed a given number of people. Students will report on their dinners and 
compile their menus into a class Web cookbook.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 WHERES THE BEEF? - LESSON PLAN
 http://www.econedlink.org/lessons/index.cfm?lesson=EM490 
 A lesson plan for middle school students on meat consumption 
as an indicator of economic prosperity. &quot;In this lesson, you will be choosing 
a family and doing a survey of their meat consumption. You will learn a little 
about the prosperity of the American Colonists and about how much meat they ate. 
Then you will compare your chosen family&apos;s consumption to that of Colonial and 
other modern-day American families.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 YUMMY PLANT PARTS LESSON PLAN        NEW!
 http://school.discovery.com/lessonplans/programs/plantparts/ 
 A lesson plan for grades 6-8 on edible plants. &quot;Students 
will: 1. Understand the structure and function of roots, stems, and leaves. 2. 
Identify the parts of a plant by looking at an entire plant or a part of a 
plant. 3. Understand the importance of plants for animals (humans) existence.&quot; Very Good
 

 
                                                                                                                        
 

 
 ENERGY IN FOOD EXPERIMENT CLASSROOM ACTIVITY            NEW!
 http://www.mr-damon.com/experiments/3svt/food_energy/index.htm 
 Students various foods to determine the amount of energy they 
contain. Good
 

 
 THE FOOD GUIDE PYRAMID LESSON PLAN
 http://www.teachers.net/lessons/posts/1682.html 
 A lesson plan on the food guide pyramid for elementary 
students. The teacher uses three different types of pizza to help students sort 
foods into their food groups. Good
 

 
 MEASURING CALORIES LESSON PLAN            NEW!
 http://www.col-ed.org/cur/sci/sci188.txt 
 A lesson plan on calories for grades 5-8. Students conduct 
experiments to determine calorie counts. Good

 NUTRITION: ONE HOT TOPIC! LESSON PLAN
 http://www.libsci.sc.edu/miller/nutrition.htm.htm 
 A lesson plan for primary students on nutrition. &quot;When 
students learn the content of the food groups, they are better prepared to 
maintain a healthy diet and lifestyle.&quot; Good
 

 
 SNACK TIME HEALTHY FOODS WORD SEARCH PUZZLE        NEW!
 http://www.lessontutor.com/jm2P.html 
 A printable word search puzzle with healthy food words. Good

 SUGAR FOR BREAKFAST LESSON PLAN        NEW!
 http://www.pecentral.org/lessonideas/ViewLesson.asp?ID=917 
 A lesson plan for grades 6-12 on portion size of sugary 
cereals. &quot;As a demonstration of how easy it is to consume additional&quot;hidden&quot;empty calories, measure out one serving of a popular breakfast cereal (Usually 
3/4 cup). Place the measured amount in a cereal bowl. Naturally, the amount of 
cereal is not that impressive. Next, ask for a volunteer who has had cereal for 
breakfast. Ask the student to pour the amount of cereal they had that morning 
into the bowl. The student usually pours 2 to 4 times the actual serving size. 
Ask the student, or members of the class, to estimate the number of calories in 
the bowl. Calculate the number of carbohydrates (subtracting the fiber) 
for the student&apos;s bowl of cereal. Measure this amount of refined white sugar 
into a different bowl. Clarify for students that this amount of sugar is what 
they are eating with their morning bowl of cereal.&quot; Good
 

 
 WHAT IS CHOLESTEROL? LESSON PLAN            NEW!
 http://www.pecentral.org/lessonideas/ViewLesson.asp?ID=918 
 A lesson plan for grades 9-12 on cholesterol . &quot;Students 
are given an assignment to find an article (newspaper, magazine, or World Wide 
Web) about cholesterol and to write a summary of the article (no more than 1 
page in length). Have them bring the article to class. After a brief discussion 
about cholesterol, each student is asked to go to the board and write ONE fact 
about cholesterol based on what they read in their articles. Tell the students 
they are not allowed to write a fact that repeats anything that someone else has 
already written on the board. This is very challenging. The board will soon look like a wall filled with cholesterol 
graffiti. After each class member has written an interesting fact, a discussion 
of these facts follows. Each student contributes to the discussion by adding to 
the information that he or she wrote on the board. After this discussion, a 
handout on the basics about cholesterol can be given as a study sheet.&quot; Good
 

 
 WHATS COOKING A COLONIAL RECIPE LESSON PLAN
 http://www.jerseyhistory.org/activity_recipe.html 
&quot;The recipe page from The Ashfield Recipe Book allows 
students to gain information about colonial life. In analyzing this primary 
material example, students will use a recipe page to find out about colonial 
foods and daily practices and employ mathematical applications in everyday life. 
They will compare and contrast the world they know today with the past.&quot; Good
 

 
 YUMMIES FOR TUMMIES LESSON PLAN        NEW!
 http://scifiles.larc.nasa.gov/text/educators/activities/2000_2001/inclass/yummies_for_tummies.html 
 A lesson plan for elementary students on making candy. Good
 
 

 
 
 Webquests
 

 
 APPLES! APPLES! WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://its.guilford.k12.nc.us/webquests/Apples/apples.htm 
 A webquest on apples for elementary students. &quot;The Task:● Use the internet to find and record information on the different 
varieties of apples.●Use the information you found to complete an online quiz 
comparing the apple varieties.●Track down information on the internet about 
Johnny Appleseed and complete clues about his life in order to uncover a hidden 
message and to write a new tall tale about his journeys.&quot; Includes a quiz 
and puzzle as part of the webquest. Excellent
 

 
 ARE YOU AWARE OF EATING DISORDERS? WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://www.montana.edu/webquest/health/grades6to12/hallock/ 
 A webquest for grades 6-12 on eating disorders. &quot; Using the 
suggested resources, you will have the opportunity to gain a better 
understanding of eating disorders, including signs&amp;symptoms and recovery&amp;coping. Visit the suggested internet sites to identify yourself with eating 
disorders and to learn how you can make an impact in the life of one who has an 
eating disorder. To gain the full benefits of this webquest, visit the suggested 
internet sites and complete one of the following assignments:There is a possibility that one of your very close friends is 
struggling from an eating disorder. Compose a nonfiction story about the signs 
and symptoms that are leading you to this hypothosis. In the story, describe 
what you would do, as a friend, to help your friend cope and recover from this 
eating disorder.Imagine that you are responsible for the grocery shopping 
this week. Your mother has not made a grocery list or given you the menu for the 
weekly meals, but she has given you a budget. Create a scenario in which you 
must plan 3 nutritious meals a day for 7 days. Include how many people are in 
your family (one of your siblings has been struggling with anorexia nervosa), 
other health problems, nutritional needs, etc. Be sure to look at the 
nutritional value of the foods that you are planning to buy.Do a case study of a student (you choose the gender, physical 
characteristics, body composition, etc.) using the Healthy Body Calculator. You 
may use yourself as the case study if so desired. Describe the subject&apos;s eating 
patterns, explain whether or not they are eating correctly, and create a revised 
eating plan for the subject if needed.&quot; We found some broken links on this 
site. Excellent
 

 
 CAN DIET AFFECT ATHLETIC PERFORMANCE? WEBQUEST             NEW!
 http://studenthome.nku.edu/~webquest/health/hovan/Performance.htm 
A webquest for 10 th grade students on nutrition 
and sports. &quot;Central State University has hired a new head football coach. 
The team has had 2 straight losing seasons and the administration is looking to 
get the program back on the winning track. The new head coach has had a chance 
to look at his new team and is ready to make some changes. The previous head 
coach had no nutritional specialist on his staff and just based the teams diet 
on what he had been taught in the past. Realizing this, the new head coach is 
looking to hire an expert in nutrition to serve as his dietitian. Being the 
expert on nutrition that you are, you apply for the position. After an excellent 
interview, the coach decides that you are the person for the job. Is it possible to make dietary modifications and expect to see an 
improvement in physical performance?&quot; We found one broken link on this site. Excellent
 

 
 THE CHEMISTRY BEHIND COOKING WEBQUEST            NEW! 
 http://chsweb.lr.k12.nj.us/kshimp/cooking/chemwebquest.htm 
 A webquest for middle students and up on cooking. &quot; You 
will use information on solutions (concentrations, saturation, phase changes), thermochemistry, chemical reactions and the gas laws to inform your audience of 
the&quot;Chemistry Behind Cooking&quot;. In order to do this you will:●Define and 
describe each of the following&quot;chemistry&quot;terms for your audience during your 
explanation: solutions, thermochemistry, chemical reactions, and the gas 
laws.  ●Be prepared to talk about the chemistry behind the making of an ice 
cream sundae with pressurized whipped cream and TWO of the following desserts: 
candy apples, lollipops, homemade fudge, Bananas Foster, Creme-Brulee, an apple 
pie, a chocolate cake, or something you choose that is approved by Emeril and 
your teacher.  ●Put together a tri-fold pamphlet to distribute to your 
audience. The pamphlet must have a title page with pictures, an 
introduction behind the chemistry of cooking, and one page each on the 
chemistry behind making 1) an ice cream sundae with pressurized whipped cream, 
2) dessert choice #1, and 3) dessert choice #2.&quot; We found a couple of broken 
links on this site. Excellent
 

 
 CHOCOLATE CHIP COOKIES: TO EAT OR NOT TO EAT WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://www.collier.k12.fl.us/weblessons/cookiewq/index.htm 
 A webquest on chocolate chip cookies for grades 3-5. Students 
investigate whether chocolate chip cookies are healthy and their place in a 
healthy diet. Excellent
 

 
 THE DILEMMA OF THE DANGEROUS MEAT LOAF WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://imet.csus.edu/imet1/scotty/webquest/meatloaf.htm 
 A webquest on nutrition for 7 th grade students. &quot; Introduction: Your family may or may not eat meat loaf. Many people love this 
traditional dish, but others have been known to hate it! Whether you like a 
certain food or not, it is wise to check on whether it is healthy for you. It 
would be terrible if something you liked and ate often wasn&apos;t good for you. But 
on the other hand if you don&apos;t like it, then maybe you wouldn&apos;t have to eat it 
if it wasn&apos;t healthy... Your job will be to determine whether meat loaf is a 
healthy food or a dangerous food that could make you ill unless you eat it only 
occasionally or start making it differently. You will use health research and 
science, and some math to make your case. If you are more interested in another 
food, check with your teacher it will probably be OK to research this food 
instead. Important: Each student must complete everything on this page for 
credit! Please read the entire page carefully!&quot; Excellent
 

 
 EATING DISORDERS WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://coe.west.asu.edu/students/jklein/eatingdisorderwq.html 
 A webquest for grades 9-12 on eating disorders . &quot;The above 
headline was about a girl at your school. She was a cheerleader, popular and an 
A student. No one was aware that she had an eating disorder. Since this case has 
hit so close to home, your school has asked your Foods&amp;Nutrition class to 
prepare an&quot;Eating Disorders&quot;presentation that will be featured at the next 
student assembly and in the school newspaper.&quot; Excellent

 EATING DISORDERS: A PUBLIC SERVICE ANNOUNCEMENT WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://www.mathrocks.net/webquests/ED_Webquest/ 
 A webquest on eating disorders for 7 th and 8 th grade students. &quot;You want to bring the message of eating disorders to the 
middle school student body. After talking with your friends, you have decided 
that the best way to reach people, especially teens, is with a public service 
announcement (psa).A public service announcement is usually a minute or less, 
but the principal and counselor thought that you could have up to fifteen 
minutes for your presentation.You will need to decide which information is the most 
important to share with others.You can share your presentation in a video or an iMovie, just 
as it might appear on television.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 FAST FOOD CHOICES: YOU ARE WHAT YOU EAT WEBQUEST         NEW!
 http://can-do.com/uci/lessons98/Nutrition.html 
 A webquest on fast food for grades 5 and up. &quot;So you&apos;ve 
got the munchies... you take a hike (or your bike) to the nearest fast food 
joint to feed your need. Just what are you getting with your burger and fries? 
Usually more than you bargained for in fat! How do you please your taste buds 
but still keep your arteries clear and your bathroom scale from groaning when 
you walk by?&quot; Excellent
 

 
 FAST FOOD FAT WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://studenthome.nku.edu/~webquest/Pidgeon/fast%20food%20webquest.htm 
 A webquest for 4 th grade students on fast food. &quot;The school cafeteria is under construction without any warning. The 
construction will take at least two weeks!!! The school has decided to provide a 
fast food lunch everyday!!! The lunch will consist of a daily cheeseburger, 
medium fries, and a medium soft drink. Sounds great ,huh? The school 
nutritionist is a little worried, as well as the principal. Is this a healthy 
choice? Your student team has been selected to lend a hand, and discover the 
answer.&quot; We found a couple of broken links on this site. Excellent
 

 
 FOOD FLIGHT CAF WEBQUEST
 http://www.manteno.k12.il.us/webquest/high/Vocational/FoodFlightCafe/FOOD%20FLIGHT%20CAFE.htm 
 A webquest for middle/junior high students on food choices. &quot; Almost every student in school has been complaining about the school&apos;s 
cafeteria food. Some say the food is too fattening, too bland, or there just are 
not a lot of choices. As a student who is involved in sports and other 
extra-curricular activities, you know it is important to have plenty of energy 
and eat right. Of course you want to look good too. What you want to find out is 
which foods are good for you and how you can get the school cafeteria to offer 
some better food choices.&quot;  We found one broken link on this site. 
Excellent
 

 
 FOOD QUEST FOR HEALTH WEBQUEST
 http://www.cyberbee.com/foodquest.html 
 A webquest on nutrition for upper elementary/middle school 
students. Excellent
 

 
 FRUIT AND VEGETABLES WEBQUEST                NEW!
 http://its.guilford.k12.nc.us/webquests/fruitveg/plants.htm 
 A webquest on fruits and vegetables for elementary students. &quot;The Task: You will research ten fruits and vegetables to learn as much as 
you can about them. You will use the information from your research to fill out 
the charts and worksheets about your ten fruits and vegetables. Then you will 
use the worksheets to make a fruit and vegetable riddle book entitled: Which 
Fruit or Vegetable Am I?&quot; Excellent

 GE FOODS (GENETICALLY ENGINEERED) FRIEND OR FOE? WEBQUEST
 http://home.earthlink.net/~spcemonk/webquest.html 
 Foods are now being genetically engineered to increase 
certain nutrients, reduce fat and calories and much more. Many people feel that 
genetically engineered foods are dangerous. Student teams will examine the 
issues and report at the World Food Conference. Very detailed. Excellent
 

 
 GLOBAL FOOD TREK WEBQUEST             NEW URL!
 http://education.iupui.edu/webquests/worldfood/index.htm 
 A webquest for grades 3-5 on the foods of other cultures. &quot; You and four globe-trotting companions have been assigned to tour 
five countries in the world to learn about each culture, specifically noting the customs and the cuisine associated with each nation. Each one of 
you will contribute to this endeavor by reporting on certain facts that you 
discover on your journey. After all of the information has been gathered, 
using both online and offline resources, the trekking team will create a Web 
page to share with your sedentary friends back in the United States.  So, 
grab your gear and a comfortable pair of hiking boots and, were off!&quot; Excellent
 

 
 THE GREAT GOOD FOOD CAPER WEBQUEST
 http://curry.edschool.virginia.edu/go/edis771/webquest2000/student/ssmippolito/home.html 
 A webquest for grades 1-2 on food and nutrition. &quot;Divide 
into groups of 3 or 4 and learn about one of the food groups-fruit, vegetable, 
dairy, meat and bread group. Click here: to find out more about the food groups. A. Name your food group. B. Should we eat food from that food group? Why or Why not? C. How many servings of food should we eat from the food 
group? D. Which are your favorite foods from this food group? What nutrients 
does it have for the body? 1. After you have collected enough information 
about your food group, decide which 3 to 5 foods from your food group you 
think the thief stole out of Healthy Harry&apos;s refrigerator. 2. For each of 
the foods that you chose, decide how much Harry should have in his refrigerator 
to eat for one day. 3. Create a poster that shows what you have learned about 
your food group. Be creative! ( Maybe the thief saw a poster like yours 
and that&apos;s why he took good food from Healthy Harry&apos;s refrigerator.) Sell your 
food! 4. Present your poster for your classmates to show what you have learned 
about your food group.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 HEALTHY MENUS WEBQUEST             NEW!
 http://studenthome.nku.edu/~webquest/Callahan/Nutrition%20Webquest.htm 
 A webquest on nutrition for 1 st grade students. &quot;Bbuurr! What a winter we had!  Because of all of the snow we 
had in January, we need to make up our snow days by extending our school days 
from 7:45 am to 8:00 pm for three days. Since students will be at school 
that long, the cafeteria workers will need to make the entire school dinner as 
well as breakfast and lunch, and that&apos;s where you come in. Your job is to 
help create a three day school menu that is well-balanced and healthy for the 
three extended school days. So put your hair nets and oven mitts on 
because off to the kitchen we go!!!&quot; We found a couple of broken links on 
this site. Excellent
 

 
 A HEALTHY RESTAURANT? RADICAL! WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://studenthome.nku.edu/~webquest/health/wyatt/AHealthyRest.final.htm 
 A webquest for grades 1-2 on healthy eating out. &quot;What the 
world needs is more restaurants that serve healthy and delicious foods! Thats where you come in. You, and two other people, are going to be world 
class chefs who design healthy meals for your own restaurant. People will 
love to eat at your restaurant, you might make lots of money, and your meals 
will make the world a healthier place! How exciting!&quot; We found a 
couple of broken links on this site. Excellent
 

 
 HOW DO YOU HELP SOMEONE OVERCOME THEIR EATING DISORDER? 
WEBQUEST     NEW!
 http://www.arches.uga.edu/~jreddick/webquest.html 
 A webquest for grades 9-12 on eating disorders. &quot;As a friend, you cannot 
ignore your suspicions; however you do not want to wrongly accuse your friend of 
having an eating disorder. You will be given a scenario in which you will use 
the Internet to research several disorders and figure out which disorder your 
friend is suffering from. After determining the disorder, your group will devise 
a set of strategies that can be used to help your friend overcome their problem.    You will prepare a Powerpoint presentation concerning the 
information you have researched and present it to the class. In this 
presentation, your group will discuss the eating disorder, as well as the set of 
strategies that you formulated to help your friend.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 I SCREAM, YOU SCREAM, WE ALL SCREAM FOR ICE CREAM WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://teachers.emints.org/burtonk/icecream/index.html 
 A webquest for 3 rd grade students on ice cream. &quot;Everyone loves ice cream. You are studying to be an ice cream connoisseur. Your job is to learn about the history of ice cream, how to make ice cream, and 
finally design your own flavor and packaging to fulfill the requirements to get 
your certification as an official ice cream connoisseur. Good luck!&quot; Excellent
 

 
 JUNK FOOD WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://www.icsd.k12.ny.us/northeast/library/junkfood/ 
 A webquest on junk food for 5 th grade students. &quot;Your task is to convince Mrs. Moss not to eat that burger. While youre at it, 
you might as well find out about other kinds of junk food, too, because Mrs. 
Moss eats candy bars, sweet breakfast cereals, and snacks like those little 
snack cakes with the white icing inside, and cheese-flavored chips. She drinks 
sports drinks and sodas, especially Dr. You-Know-Who.  Please, hurry, kids! Find out all you can before Mrs. Moss becomes so 
overweight, diabetic, heart-diseased, and sluggish that she cant do any more 
homework . . . and flunks out of School Librarian School!&quot; Excellent

 LETS EAT, TO LIVE! WEBQUEST
 http://www.mtnbrook.k12.al.us/mbjh/webpages/pe/laughlin/wqmain.html 
 A webquest for middle school students on a healthy diet. &quot;Congratulations! You have been hired by a National Public Relations Firm, 
Lifequal, that specializes in improving and maintaining quality lifestyles. Your clients include many celebrities and sports figures, who need your 
expertise to insure that they stay healthy and present a positive image. As an 
employee of this firm, you will be responsible for meeting with your 
celebrity/sports figure and establish nutrition/exercise guidelines. Many 
celebrities need this information because their schedules are so full. They, 
like many Americans, are on a tight time frame and they tend to eat junk foods 
and they do not make time to exercise. During your first week on the job, you 
will be required to make a report on the status of your healthy lifestyle 
choices. This report will include the following: a list of the foods you 
presently eat, 7 day eating plan (discuss/share ideas with your co-workers 
on improving your food choices for well balanced and nutritious meals), and make 
a presentation to staff so you can better communicate to your client that you 
too live the positive and healthy lifestyle. You must project the image that the 
client expects.&quot;   Excellent

 LETS PLAN A PICNIC! WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://studenthome.nku.edu/~webquest/Schwartz/WebQuest.htm 
 A webquest for 1 st grade students on nutrition. &quot; What if there 
was no such thing as candy? What if there were no more potato chips, french fries or ice cream? Our only choices of what to eat would have to be 
healthy food. Would you be able to plan a meal with only healthy food as 
your choices?The class is going for a picnic at the park. Your team&apos;s job is to plan 
a healthy lunch menu for the class.&quot; Excellent

 M&amp;M SPACE FOOD WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://schoolweb.missouri.edu/moniteau.k12.mo.us/mathys/mandmwebquest.html 
 A webquest for upper elementary students on food in space. &quot;Have you ever 
wondered what life is like on a space shuttle or on the space station? 
Astronauts do many of the same things you do everyday - such as sleep, eat, 
wash, play, and even go to the bathroom! The only difference is that in 
space there is no gravity, so astronauts must use special equipment to do these 
everyday tasks. What is gravity? Watch this BrainPOP movie to find out! 
Everything on Earth relies on gravity to work properly. Look at your desk. Why is everything laying on it? Gravity holds all your papers, books, and 
pencils in place. Earth toilets rely on gravity to flush. Space 
toilets use suction (like a vacuum cleaner). The ink flows out of your 
pens onto your paper on Earth. Pens are pressurized like spray cans to 
work in space. You don&apos;t need a bed in space - just straps to keep you 
tied to a wall. Instead of using cups to drink from, astronauts squeeze 
fluid-filled bags with tubes into their mouths. But what about eating small 
candies like m&amp;ms in space? You can&apos;t dump the bag out into your hand - 
the m&amp;ms would fly everywhere! So, what would you do? You&apos;d need a 
zero-gravity dispenser. Where would you get one? You&apos;d need to 
invent one!&quot; We found a couple of broken links in this site. Excellent

 MEXICAN FOOD WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://teacherweb.com/WI/Cushing/Gliniecki,J-WebQuest/ 
 A webquest on Mexican food for middle school students. &quot;As 
the owners, you will need to make some decisions. Your group needs to agree on a 
name for your restaurant, the hours of operation, its location, and decide on 
the foods, drinks, and desserts you will be serving. Your restaurant must also 
have a&quot;specialty&quot;, or the food that your group would most like to try, and you 
need to describe it to the class. After these decisions have been made, you will 
be creating a sample menu with the foods you have decided on and their prices 
(in Mexican Pesos and American Dollars), as well as creating a skit that will 
represent a visit to your restaurant.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 MRS. BLYTHES NUTRITION WEBQUEST
 http://teacherweb.com/In/Parkview/wqsblythe/ 
 A webquest for upper elementary/middle school students in 
which students must choose items for a nutritious dinner. &quot;Your task, as a 
group of 4, is to determine what to prepare for your mom&apos;s nutritious dinner. 
Your group will design a brochure or create a TV commercial promoting the 
product your group selects. The nutrition labels will help you analyze which 
product is the healthiest choice. Since you will want mom to know just how 
healthy her meal is, the brochure or TV ad will explain this. After looking in 
the pantry, you find 4 items to evaluate; a box of Easy Mac, a can of Spaghetti 
O&apos;s, a can of Campbell&apos;s Vegetable Soup, and a can of Dinty Moore Beef Stew. 
Which is most nutritious?&quot; Excellent
 


 


 
 MUNCHING MANIA WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://studenthome.nku.edu/~webquest/pike/Munching%20Mania.htm 
 A webquest for 2 nd grade students on nutrition. &quot;If you are like this Mushy Monster, you eat things like cookies, cakes, 
chocolates and chips. He rarely chooses healthy foods. Instead you should eat things like bananas, apples, cheese 
and yogurt. This is how to cure Munching Mania. Your job is to learn about healthy eating and then help the 
children at our school by curing Munching Mania!&quot; Excellent
 

 
 MY FRUIT IS THE BEST! WEBQUEST             NEW!
 http://www.lausd.net/lausd/offices/di/Burleson/workshops/WQ_Workshop/sample/ 
 A webquest on fruit for grade 2 students. &quot;There are so 
many different kinds of fruits. Everyone has their favorite. Some 
kids like apples, some kids like oranges. Which fruit is your favorite? Today you will learn some interesting facts about your favorite fruit.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 NUTRITION MISSION WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://studenthome.nku.edu/~webquest/Hurley/WebQuest.htm 
 A webquest for 2 nd grade students on nutrition. &quot;Your goal is to plan a healthy meal for the Jolly Postman to help keep his 
energy up to finish his route. He has lots of important letters to deliver 
today! You are going to work in groups to create a delicious nutritious 
meal using foods from all 5 of the food groups. Remember you need to 
include fruits and vegetables, breads or other grains, meat, chicken, or fish, 
good dairy foods and a small bit from the sweets group.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 NUTRITION: THE QUEST FOR BETTER HEALTH WEBQUEST
 http://collier.k12.fl.us/WebLessons/WebQuest/Nutrition/ 
 A webquest for kindergarten students on nutrition. &quot;Help! 
A group of aliens from another planet on an exploration mission have landed on 
Earth! Thank goodness theyre friendly, but there is one problem. They are 
eating foods theyve never had before, mostly junk food. Theyre especially 
crazy about Milky Way and Mars candy bars. They know nothing about nutrition and 
are very unhealthy. Your help is needed to teach these alien beings how to eat 
better and get healthy so that they can return to their home planet of Munch.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 

 NUTS ABOUT NUTRITION WEBQUEST
 http://coe.west.asu.edu/students/aperhamus/WQ/ 
 A webquest on nutrition for elementary students. &quot;Your 
task is to create a practical eating plan for your whole family. You realize 
this won&apos;t be easy, but once it has been accomplished, you will all be much 
happier. There is a lot of work to be done before you can create the plan. You 
will have to find out what nutrients are most important and why. Which foods 
contain them? How much of these foods should you eat? If you don&apos;t change your 
eating habits, what will happen to your family&apos;s health? What food does your 
family like and dislike? What is your family food budget? How much time does 
your family have to prepare meals? After gathering this information, you will 
need to create a practical eating guide for your family to follow. In order to 
be better motivated, you will all need to understand why this guide is better 
than your old habits.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 PHYTOCHEMICALS AND A HEALTHY DIET WEBQUEST
 http://www.glencoe.com/sec/science/webquest/content/phytochemicals.shtml 
 A webquest on healthy foods for junior/senior high students. &quot;Your job in this WebQuest is to learn all about the phytochemicals found in 
fruits and vegetables, and the benefits of eating these foods as part of a 
balanced diet. You will discover what phytochemicals have been studied 
scientifically, and what these research studies have discovered. You will learn 
about the different phytochemicals that can be found in natural foods, and the 
health benefits of each type. You will fill in a table in which ten different 
foods or groups of foods are listed. For each food or group of food, you will 
list the important phytochemical(s) each contains, and the health benefits of 
eating that food. Finally, you will answer a few questions about phytochemicals 
to demonstrate what you have learned in your Internet research.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 SEND ZOINK HOME WEBQUEST
 http://192.107.108.56/portfolios/c/chazan_e/Webquest/introductionupdate1.htm 
 A webquest for 3 rd grade students on nutrition. &quot; I am a third grade student in New Jersey and I need your help! I came home 
yesterday and found a small, scared, green creature who reminded me of a Dr. 
Seuss character crying in my kitchen. Zoink told me he had no idea what to eat, 
and he is not allowed to return to his planet until he solves this problem. The only way to accomplish this is to plan and create a 5-day balanced menu, so 
Zoink can go home. Please help Zoink!&quot; Excellent
 

 
 THE SKINNY ON TEEN OBESITY WEBQUEST         NEW!
 http://studenthome.nku.edu/~webquest/health/mcclurg/TheSkinnyonTeenObesity.htm 
 A webquest for grade 11-12 on teen obesity. &quot;We are going 
to create a teen oriented health fair in our classroom. Our task is to 
design stations for the health fair that will educate teens about obesity. We want our stations to be creative, inviting, and informative. Each group 
will design their own booth and a pamphlet, brochure or poster to be displayed 
and distributed at their booth. You will also need to develop an 
interactive component to your display. This may be a demonstration an 
activity or something else creative.&quot; We found a couple of broken links on 
this site. Excellent
 

 
 STRENGTH AND NUTRITION WEBQUEST         NEW!
 http://www.manteno5.org/webquest/high/Science/StrengthNutrition/strength.htm 
 A webquest for grades 9012 on nutrition and sports. &quot; Choose a professional athlete to be your client and develop an individualized 
diet and exercise program that will increase their overall health and athletic 
performance over a one month period. You have two weeks to complete your task. 
1. Search for your client&apos;s age, height, and weight and list their professional 
sport. 2. Develop a four week exercise program that corresponds to your 
professional athlete&apos;s sport. 3. Develop a two week menu that incorporates 
proper nutritional habits for your client. 4. Give your client specific 
explanations for their diet and exercise program.&quot; We found some broken 
links on this site. Excellent
 

 
 TINKERING WITH MOTHER NATURE GENETICALLY-MODIFIED FOODS 
WEBQUEST         NEW!
 http://gmhsscience.com/GMO/index.htm 
 A webquest on genetically-modified foods for grades 7 and up. &quot;You are attending the International Conference for Genetic Technology. The focus question of the conference is&quot;How should governments regulate the 
production and distribution of genetically modified food products?&quot; From 
discussion generated at the conference, a consensus opinion will be generated 
that will be used as the basis for a public service information product created 
and distributed by the Conference organizers. Task: In groups, you will research 
the topic of genetically modified or altered foods. Based on your 
research, you will construct a Blog that expresses the consensus opinion of the 
group and provides the public with evidence to support your decision.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 WEBQUEST MCCAESAR ROMAN FOOD WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://www.webkwestie.nl/roman%20food/ 
 A webquest for junior/senior high students on Roman foods . &quot;The two of you are slaves in service of a rich senator. One of you is head of 
the household and the other is the cook. The senator is an enterprising man. He 
wants to open the first Roman Restaurant where Roman people can have (a take 
away) breakfast, lunch or dinner. He wants you to run the restaurant that he 
calls McCaesar in honour of the great Roman leader. If the McCaesar-restaurant 
is successful, the senator will consider opening more of those restaurants 
throughout the Roman Empire and maybe he will put you in charge of that 
operation.&quot; Excellent
 

 
 WHERE DOES MILK COME FROM? WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://www.manteno.k12.il.us/mcordes/dairycow.htm 
A webquest for kindergarten students on milk. &quot;In a whole 
group session, we will begin the journey by using the Destination computer to 
find out where milk comes from. Let&apos;s learn about the story of Milk. We will begin by looking at cows on a farm and then discover how it it arrives 
at the store for your family to buy. We will find out the importance of 
milk in our diets.&quot; Excellent
 

 

 
                                         

 BASIC HAZARDS COMMON TO FOOD SERVICE KITCHENS WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://www.manteno5.org/webquest/high/Science/HazardsInFoodService/Basic.htm 
 A webquest for middle school students and up on basic kitchen 
and food safety. &quot;Today, we will be talking about the basic hazards common to 
kitchens. Our kitchens are full of potential dangers for ourselves and those we 
serve. It is important for us to be aware of these dangers and prevent them as 
much as possible. This unit will be done in five parts:●Class discussion 
covering basic kitchen hazards●Each group will become familiar with one 
kitchen hazard.●Each group will point out areas of improvement in the kitchens 
visited according to their particular hazard.●Each group will use the 
information gathered to look at their own home kitchens and see which hazards 
need to be eliminated.●Each Group will understand why Food Safety is not a&quot;sometime&quot;procedure.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 

 CHOCOLATE WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://www.cr-cath.pvt.k12.ia.us/allsaints/information/chocolate.html 
A webquest for middle school students. &quot;Your final project 
should consist of: A children&apos;s non-fiction picture book of at least 8 - 10 half 
pages that explains&quot;The History of Chocolate&quot;,&quot;From Cacao Bean to Chocolate&quot;, 
or&quot;How and Where Cacao Beans are Grown&quot;. A cover page for the book to include 
the title of your book, your name as the author and a related graphic. Book 
pages that each contain at least one fact about the topic and one graphic per 
page. A last page that lists a bibliography of the websites you used.&quot; Very 
Good
 

 
 CHOCOLATE COVERED CREATIONS WEBQUEST         NEW!
 http://mws.mcallen.isd.tenet.edu/tiftech/ci/projects/radame/aajWebquest.html 
 A webquest for middle school students on chocolate. &quot;Using 
the internet web sites below, you will research the history of chocolate. During 
your delicious adventure you will tour a chocolate factory, create a new candy 
bar, develop a slogan, design an advertisement, and be prepared to sell your 
famous new candy bar!&quot; We found a couple of broken links on this site. Very 
Good
 

 
 THE COPABACANA RESTAURANT WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://the_english_dept.tripod.com/foodquest/index.html 
 A webquest with a lot of activities that was designed for ESL 
students but can be adapted to nutrition classes. &quot;The Copabacana Restaurant 
at Viva Village has been built and decorated but a number of things still needs 
to be done before the innauguration. You will need to :●define the kind of 
restaurant you want the Copabacana to be, based on group discussions and feeback 
from students on the forum.●compose the menu according to what you have 
chosen.●find the appropriate recipes.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 FAST FOOD DILEMMA WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://studenthome.nku.edu/~webquest/health/holloway/fast_food.htm 
 A webquest for 5 th grade students on fast food. &quot; Oh no!!! Your parents have gone on a fast food strike! They say no more trips 
to the local fast food places because they feel it is too unhealthy. Life as you 
know it is over, no more drive-thrus, happy meal toys, play lands, AAAAHHHH! 
Your brain is wheeling; how can you convince them that fast food is ok as long 
as it is not all you eat?&quot; Very Good
 

 
 FIESTA, FOOD AND FUN WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://www2.franciscan.edu/Webquests/fiestafoodfun/ 
 A webquest for 3 rd grade students on the foods of 
Mexico. &quot;You have been invited to a Mexican fiesta. You need to find a 
Mexican recipe and prepare it for the party. You will search the internet to 
find recipes, graphics, and nutritional information for your menu item. You will create a poster to display with your completed Mexican dish at the 
fiesta. Your poster will include your recipe. Create a report describing 
your shopping experience and your cooking adventure. You will also be required 
to turn in a copy of your grocery list.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 FOOD FOR THOUGHT FRUITS AND VEGETABLES WEBQUEST
 http://curry.edschool.virginia.edu/go/edis771/98webquests/student/slindasaltzburg/home.html 
 A webquest for elementary students on fruits and vegetables . &quot;In order to get ready for your trip, you need to know&quot;what&apos;s so&quot;about fruits 
and vegetables. You need to be able to answer questions like these: What is 
the difference between a fruit and a vegetable? Is the tomato a fruit or a 
vegetable? Where in the world did fruits and vegetables originate from? What 
edible plants grow where you live? Is Mom right? Should you eat your veggies? 
Vegetarian or Vegan-To be or not to be? Was Thomas Jefferson a vegetarian? Are 
there fruitarians too? What does&quot;organic&quot;mean? If you are what you eat, 
shouldn&apos;t fruits and vegetables be food for thought?&quot;  We found a few 
broken links on this site. Very Good
 

 
 FOOD IS FUEL WEBQUEST
 http://curry.edschool.virginia.edu/go/edis771/webquest2000/student/tsusancarter/home.html 
 A webquest on nutrition for elementary students. &quot;Your job 
is to create a three day menu including three meals and at least two snacks each 
day for your family. This menu will follow the food pyramid guidelines and 
fulfill the daily requirements (RDA) of one specific nutrient (vitamin or 
mineral) of your choice.&quot; We found a couple of broken links on this 
site. Very Good
 

 
 HEALTH AND NUTRITION WEBQUEST
 http://www.mpsaz.org/webquest/Lynch/final%20health.htm 
 A webquest on health and nutrition-related conditions for 
middle school students .&quot; You have just graduated from one of the top medical 
schools and have been assigned your first job as an emergency room Doctor on E.R. 
Your task is to work with your patient, your Physician&apos;s Assistant, and your 
Nurse to evaluate your patients symptoms. After the diagnosis is made, you and 
your colleagues will work together to compile typical warning signs, side 
effects of the conditions, and what other people can do to prevent the health 
illness.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 HYBRID FRUIT WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://www.sheboygan.k12.wi.us/kbrennan/webQuest.html 
A webquest for 1 st grade students on fruits. &quot; You are a gardener and you were hired by Piggly Wiggly Grocery Store to develop 
a new type of fruit! Your job is to work with a partner and create a 
delicious new fruit that all people can enjoy. You and your partner will 
create a poster or Kid Pix picture illustrating your new fruit and then present 
it to the class.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 INTERNATIONAL FOODS WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://www.dedham.k12.ma.us/webquest/fall2000/js/WebQuest.htm 
 A webquest on international cuisines for 9 th grade 
students. &quot;The United States is a&quot;melting pot&quot;of culture. People from 
all backgrounds and nationalities have immigrated to this country for any number 
of reasons. The reasons have been political, social and economic. Two groups of three students will research the cuisine of two different 
countries. One group will research France and the other will research Greece. The groups will consist of one chef, one nutritionist and one agriculturist . 
Are the foods these countries consuming advantageous to their health and 
well-being?&quot; Very Good
 

 
 NUTRITION AND FOODS WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://teacherweb.com/TN/TTU/nutritionwebquest/index.html 
 A webquest on nutrition for middle school students on 
nutrition. &quot; You will be helping create a menu for a new fast food franchise 
in your town. As a group, you will need to find the most nutritious menu that 
will meet the requirements of a dietitian, a parent, a teenager, and a fast food 
franchiser. You will have the chance to compare various fast food menus and what 
you eat in a usual day. Examine the roles listed below and decide which one you 
would like to do. Once you have picked the role you would like to do, go to the 
home page and select your chosen role. Dietitian Fast Food Franchiser 
Parent Teenager.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 PYRAMID POWER WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://education.nmsu.edu/webquest/wq/food/NutritionWebquest.html 
 A webquest on the Food Guide Pyramid for middle school 
students. &quot;You will be serving on a committee to formulate the menu for a new 
fast food franchise in your town. As a committee, you will need to find 
the most nutritious menu that will meet the specified requirements of a 
dietitian, a parent, a typical teenager, and a fast food franchiser. You 
will have the opportunity to compare various fast food menus as well as what you 
eat in a typical day. Be prepared to justify all selections you make. Look briefly at the following roles and select the one that you would like to 
do. As you complete your task, you may need information from others in the 
group. Don&apos;t hesitate to communicate with them and get the information you 
need to be successful. Go to the task for the role you have selected and 
follow the task outlined there. Remember that the teacher is also a 
resource!&quot; Very Good
 

 
 REAL FOOD FOR REAL KIDS WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://teachers.emints.org/FY04/krausi/NutritionWebQuest/ 
 A webquest for 4 th grade students on healthy 
eating. &quot;The School Board is looking to hire a company to provide balanced 
nutritional meals that kids will want to eat. Your company has been asked to 
present a proposal that will convince the School Board to hire your company. The 
School Board has requested that your company provide a seven day meal plan that 
meets the nutritional requirements for breakfast and lunch for upper elementary 
students. In addition, they are requesting a suggested afternoon nutritional 
snack and dinner plan for busy parents.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 WATERMELON: FRUIT OR VEGETABLE? WEBQUEST                     NEW!
 http://www.ga.unc.edu/NCTA/NCTA/WebQuest/Inborden/WebQuest/index1.html 
 A webquest for grades 1-2 on watermelons. &quot; In the book, Watermelon Day by Kathi Appelt, young Jesse must endure waiting all summer 
for her watermelon to grow. Her father says that her watermelon will be a 
big one, just in time for Watermelon Day. Your quest is to discover 
many juicy facts about the watermelon. Then make a decision about whether a 
watermelon is a fruit or vegetable.&quot; Very Good
 

 
 WHAT A TANGLED FOOD WEB WE EAT WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://www.rblewis.net/technology/EDU506/WebQuests/foodchain/foodchain.html 
 A webquest for grades 2-4 on food chains. &quot;While studying 
this website, you will find out some facts that you probably were not aware of 
about how plants and animals help each other stay alive! You will read, try out 
quizzes, and do FUN activities that will require you to record your answers 
concerning what you&apos;ve read. Don&apos;t worry, if you miss something, you will have 
the opportunity to do it again. Having fun yet? Once you finish these 
activities, you will create your own food chain! Isn&apos;t that amazing?!●Define 
what the food chain is.●Determine what organisms are included in the food 
chain.●Develop a knowledge of what roles various organisms play in the food 
chain and what they eat.●Create your own food chain!&quot; We found some broken 
links on this site. Very Good
 

 
 WHAT IS YOUR FOOD&amp;NUTRITION PROFILE? WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://people.eku.edu/resorc/your%20food%20profile.htm 
 A webquest for junior/senior high students in which they 
determine their nutrition profile by examining their diet, BMI and level of 
fitness. They then predict how their diet will affect their future. Very Good
 

 
                                                         
 
 APPLES WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://wneo.org/WebQuests/TeacherWebQuests/Apples/apples.htm 
 A webquest for 1 st grade students on apples. &quot; You 
are going to be working as a team of students. You will explore the cycle 
of an apple and use your five senses to discover many things about apples. You will use classroom resources and the Internet to complete your assigned 
group tasks.&quot; Good
 

 
 CAFETERIA STRIKE! WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://studenthome.nku.edu/~webquest/health/hodge/webquest.htm 
 A webquest for 5 th grade students on nutrition. &quot;How many times have you complained about the cafeterias food? Now is 
your chance to have a say in what is served. The cafeteria workers have 
gone on strike. Your group is now in charge of planning the menu for the 
week. Dont get too excited, there is going to be some work involved in 
your planning.Every lunch meal that you plan must be 500 or less calories!  Another problem is that you are not allowed to cook so you must order the food 
in from different fast food restaurants.&quot; We found a couple of broken links 
on this site. Good
 

 
 FABULOUS FIVE NUTRITION WEBQUEST
 http://www.hobart.k12.in.us/phelps/nutrition/intro.html 
 A webquest for upper elementary students on the five food 
groups. &quot;Your job is to assume the role of one of the Fabulous Five. You will 
research where your food group fits on the food pyramid, what foods are in your 
group, how many servings you need a day, and then design a meal and a snack with 
the rest of your team.&quot; Note: Only one of the links on this page worked. Good
 

 
 FAST FOOD FOR A FAST GENERATION WEBQUEST
 http://coe.west.asu.edu/students/jklein/janwebquest2.htm 
A webquest for grades 9-12 on nutrition. &quot; As a&quot;Foods&amp;Nutrition&quot;class, you have been asked to assist the students in your high school 
by researching the&quot;Fast Food&quot;life style and preparing a reference guide to 
assist students in making wise decisions regarding on-the-go eating and a 
prevention campaign to be adopted by your school. Teens may have little control 
over their lifestyle, but with a little guidance, they may be able to make wiser 
choices. Your job then will be to creatively sell your fellow teens on the idea 
of healthy on-the-go choices for a healthy life.&quot;  We found several 
broken links on this site. Good
 

 
 FISHING FOR FOOD WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://www.teachnet.ie/gmcweeney/fish/index.html 
 A webquest for middle school students fish in the diet. &quot; You 
live in a maritime county where fish is readily available. You and the members 
of your class have been given the task of researching the different types of 
fish and explaining the importance of fish in the the diet.&quot; Good
 

 
 FOOD AND NUTRITION WEBQUEST
 http://www.west-bend.k12.wi.us/webquest/foods/!foodnut.htm 
 A webquest for elementary students on nutrition. &quot;Find out 
as much as you can about the food guide pyramid using various web sites. Find 
out why fruits and vegetables are good for you. 
Find out what you should eat and how much exercise you should get. Find out 
about foods that are served in fast food restaurants. The information you 
discover in this webquest will answer the questions above. Your job will 
be to use complete sentences while filling in the worksheet carefully. For each 
number you will see an underlined and/or different colored word or words. Click on the word to find out your information.&quot;  We found several 
broken links on this site. Good
 

 
 INSECTS AS FOOD? WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://www.macomb.k12.mi.us/wq/webq98/insects.htm 
 A webquest for middle school students on insects as food. &quot;Pizza, hamburgers, fries, and Coke are all favorite American foods. Lobster, 
caviar, and escargot are considered a delicacy by some people. What about eating 
insects? Would you ever consider eating them? Are there places in the world 
today where insects are part of the people&apos;s diet?&quot; Several of the links are 
broken and will need to be replaced. Good
 

 
 JUNK FOOD NUTRITION WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://home.indy.rr.com/indianaokey/Nutrition/JunkFood2.htm 
 A webquest for grades 6-9 on junk food in which students must 
create a 7-day healthy meal plan. Good
 

 
 MEAT- FARM TO FORK WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://www.teachnet.ie/gmcweeney/2004/ 
 A webquest for middle school students on meat in the diet. &quot;We live in a country where Meat is readily available. You and the members of 
your class have been given the task of researching and investigating the 
different types of meat and outlining the importance of meat in the the diet.&quot; Good
 

 
 THE MISPLACED MENUS WEBQUEST        NEW!
 http://studenthome.nku.edu/~webquest/health/lilleston/TheMisplacedMenus1.htm 
 A webquest for 4 th grade students on healthy 
eating . &quot;Help! The president has just informed me that he wants to 
visit our school and eat a healthy lunch with the students. The cafeteria 
staff had something very nutritious on the menu, but somehow they have misplaced 
the menu. The cafeteria staff has contacted me to have you help them out. It is up to you to figure out what goes into making a nutritious meal, and help 
the cafeteria staff plan for the big event. We want the president to leave 
our school thinking that our school is one of the most nutritious schools he has 
ever eaten at! Are you up for the challenge? Good, I knew I could 
count on you. Go to the task to see your mission in more detail. Good Luck and happy planning!&quot; We found several broken links on this site. 
Good
 

 
 NUTRITION WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://pangea.tec.selu.edu/~cmcnabb/etec645/nutrition/Whann.htm 
 A webquest for 7 th grade students on nutrition. &quot;Yucky! Gross! Disgusting! These are some of the comments the 
students at Bayou Land High School are saying about the food in the cafeteria. The cafeteria supervisor has hired our class to help her create good, healthy, 
and appetizing meals and snacks for the cafeteria. Typical cafeteria foods at Bayou Land High School include 
hamburgers, broccoli, pizza, chicken nuggets, strawberries, french fries, bread, 
apples, jambalaya, ketchup, hot dogs, brownies, and green beans. Which foods 
sound good to you? Are those foods GOOD FOR YOU to eat? Do you know which ones 
are and which ones aren&apos;t? Do you know how much of each kind of food you need? 
Just like a car cannot run without gasoline, your body cannot run without food. FOOD IS FUEL! Food contains energy and other nutrients to keep your body 
healthy. In this webquest, you will learn about good nutrition and 
even plan good, healthy, and appetizing meals for the cafeteria!&quot; We found a 
couple of broken links on this site. Good
 

 
 NUTRITION WEBQUEST
 http://teach.fcps.net/trt10/Webquests/nutrition.htm 
 A webquest for middle school students on nutrition. &quot;Nutrition is a very important issue in the health of any individual. Unfortunately, too many American children do not receive the proper nutrients 
needed to be healthy. As a writer for a newsletter for the Nutrition for 
Children Association, you hope to help correct this situation. After 
completing this webquest and learning about the nutrients, food pyramid, and 
dietary guidelines, you will write a newsletter that will be sent to the homes 
of many American adolescents.&quot;   We found several broken links on this 
site. Good

 A QUEST FOR HEALTHY FOOD        NEW!
 http://www.biopoint.com/wq2/health/A_Quest_for_Healthy_Food.html 
 A webquest for 5 th grade students on healthy food. &quot;Sean is Sarah&apos;s 14 year-old brother. He has been working at a new job 
helping to clean the school during the summer. He is working very hard moving 
and cleaning desks, washing windows, and delivering boxes. Each day, Sean and 
his co-worker Mike go to a fast food restaurant for breakfast and lunch. One 
day, Sean told his mom that he seemed to be gaining weight even though he is 
working very hard. Why is Sean gaining weight? How can he eat more wisely?&quot; Very few links. Good
 

 
 TOP OFF YOUR NUTRITION TANK WEBQUEST            NEW!
 http://www.biopoint.com/wq2/SportsnutritionMiniQuest/TopoffHomepage.html 
 A webquest for middle school students on proper nutrition for 
teens involved in sports. &quot;In this WebQuest, you will help Kim find out what 
and when her teammates should be eating on game day. The candy wrappers on the 
gym floor mean that she might also need to advise them on foods they should be 
avoiding.&quot; Two of the three links given are broken. Youll need to add your 
own. Good
 

 
 YOU ARE WHAT YOU EAT WEBQUEST
 http://www.flatrock.k12.in.us/hhs/dalton/nutrition.htm 
 A webquest for elementary students on a healthy diet. &quot;Your assignment will be to create a nutritional brochure that explains the 
importance of good nutrition and exercise. Put yourself in the role of a 
dietician that is trying to help Sally and Joey become more healthy individuals 
by eating right and getting the right amount of exercise.&quot;   We found a 
couple of broken links on this site. Good
 

 
 YOU ARE WHAT YOU EAT WEBQUEST
 http://www.yorkville.k12.il.us/webquests/webqsbirch/webqsbirch.html 
 A webquest for 1 st grade students on nutrition. &quot; Plan and make a meal with foods from all of the food groups.&quot;  We 
found a couple of broken links on this site. Good
 

 


                                                       

Disclaimer: We cannot check every link within 
each site.



Prepared by the Cumberland County AVA Center 
staff. Please call #856-451-0817 or email: avactr@salemnj.org with questions or 
suggestions for future web site lists. This list is also posted on our website 
at http://www.cumbavac.org 

The site list is also posted on two other web 
sites:
 
 http://www.atlanticava.org 

 http://www.cjims.org/links.htm 
 


May 2006

 You are welcome to post our lists on 
your website. If you do, you must post the list in its entirety and credit 
Carol Lyn Hutton,
Cumberland County AVA Center, 
Bridgeton, NJ and link back to this site.  http://www.cumbavac.org 



 top of page 

Food clipart on this page from Maryanns Food 
Clipart
 http://www.maryannsart.com/cgi-bin/ImageFolio31/imageFolio.cgi?search=food&amp;cat=&amp;bool=and 
 
Photos and clipart from Microsoft Digital 
Design Gallary Live EULA
 http://dgl.microsoft.com/mgo1en/eula.asp?nInterface=0&amp;tPhrase=
	</body>
</document>
