<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009041" url="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB125319598236119629.html" time="2012-07-13-02:26" support="15" score="0.03178668195083602" bingtitle="Entrepreneur Steve Ells: Starting Chipotle From Scratch - WSJ.com" webtitle="Entrepreneur Steve Ells: Starting Chipotle From Scratch - WSJ.com">
			<query id="000224" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="000410" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000441" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000976" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="001258" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="001038" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000724" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000161" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000536" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="001290" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="001447" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000256" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="000287" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000945" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="001415" bing-rank="129"/>
	<description>... you are the ones who make the food, and our menu board ... idea to a start a restaurant, especially a fast-food restaurant. ... WSJSmallBiz: Old Brands Get a Second Shot: http ...</description>
	<body>
		WSJEurope 
 WSJEurope Facebook Twitter 
 Market Watch 
 Market Watch 
 Barron&apos;s 
 Barron&apos;s 
 All Things Digital 
 All Things Digital 
 WSJ Live 
 WSJ Live 
 Financial News 
 Financial News 
 BigCharts 
 BigCharts 
 Factiva 
 Factiva 
 More 
 SmartMoney FINS Europe Virtual Stock Exchange WSJ Classifieds WSJ Classroom WSJ Radio 
 
 SEARCH 
 headline gold man 
 
 Companies GOLD Ran gold Resources Ltd. ADS U.S. 
 
 View All Search Results» 
 
 
 | 
 The Wall Street Journal How I Built It 
 Welcome, Logout 
 Customer Center My Journal Help Message Center ( new) 
 
 
 Europe Edition Home ↓More 
WSJ.com is available in the following editions and languages:
 
 U.S. Asia 
 India China Japan 
 Europe 
 Deutschland 
 Americas 
 en Español em Português 
 
 Register for FREE 
 Register for FREE 
 
Thank you for registering.

We sent an email to: 

Please click on the link inside the email to complete your registration
 
Please register to gain free access to WSJ tools.
 
An account already exists for the email address entered.

 Forgot your username or password? 
 
This service is temporary unavailable due to system maintenance. Please try again later.
 
The username entered is already associated with
another account. Please enter a different username
 
The email address you have entered is already in use.
Please re-enter the email address.
 
 First Name Last Name Email (your email address will be your login) Confirm Email Create a Password Confirm Password Company Size (Optional) Please make a selection 1-99 100-499 500-999 1,000-2,499 2,500-4,999 5,000-9,999 10,000-14,999 15,000-24,999 25,000+ Not Applicable 
 
From time to time, we will send you e-mail announcements on new features and special offers from The Wall Street Journal Online.

 
Create a profile for me in the Journal Community 
 
 Why Register? 

 Privacy Policy | Terms&amp;Conditions 
 
As a registered user of The Wall Street Journal Online, you will be able to:

 
Setup and manage your portfolio
 
Personalize your own news page
 
Receive and manage newsletters
 
 
 Login/Register to set your edition 
 
 Today&apos;s Paper Video Blogs Emails Journal Community Mobile Tablet 



 Subscribe Log In 

 
 
 
 World »More 
 
 World »More 
 Loading… 
 Europe »More 
 
 Europe »More 
 Loading… 
 U.K. »More 
 
 U.K. »More 
 Loading… 
 U.S. »More 
 
 U.S. »More 
 Loading… 
 Business »More 
 
 Business »More 
 Loading… 
 Markets »More 
 
 Markets »More 
 Loading… 
 Market Data »More 
 
 Market Data »More 
 Loading… 
 Tech »More 
 
 Tech »More 
 Loading… 
 Life&amp;Style »More 
 
 Life&amp;Style »More 
 Loading… 
 Opinion »More 
 
 Opinion »More 
 Loading… 
 Real Estate »More 
 
 Real Estate »More 
 Loading… 
 Jobs »More 
 
 Jobs »More 
 Loading… 
 
 Europe Asia Earnings Economy Health Law Autos Management CFO Journal   Small Business   
 Accounting Advertising Airlines Banking Broadcasting&amp;Entertainment Careers Chemicals Computer Hardware Computer Software Consumer Products Defense&amp;Aerospace Energy Financial Services&amp;Insurance Food&amp;Tobacco Hospitality Industrial Goods&amp;Services Marketing&amp;Strategy Media Agencies Media&amp;Marketing Metals&amp;Mining Paper&amp;Forest Products Pharmaceutical&amp;Biotech Real Estate Retail Semiconductors Small Business Telecommunications Transportation Utilities 
 
 
Dow Jones Reprints: This copy is for your personal, non-commercial use only. To order presentation-ready copies for distribution to your colleagues, clients or customers, use the Order Reprints tool at the bottom of any article or visit www.djreprints.com 
 See a sample reprint in PDF format. Order a reprint of this article now 
 
 HOW I BUILT IT September 22, 2009, 5:40 p.m. ET 

Starting Chipotle From Scratch
 
 Article Stock Quotes Comments 
 more in Small Business | Find New $LINKTEXTFIND$ » 
 smaller Larger 
 
By COLLEEN DEBAISE 

After graduating from the Culinary Institute of America, Steve Ells dreamt of opening a fine-dining restaurant but–like many first-time entrepreneurs–lacked start-up funds. His solution in 1993 was to open Chipotle Mexican Grill , an easy-to-operate joint that could be the &quot;cash cow&quot; for his upscale establishment. But the idea took off, and the Denver-based eatery with its foil-wrapped burritos soon won loyal customers and big backers such as McDonald&apos;s Corp. In 2006, the company went public, and now has over 900 locations, 24,000 employees, $1.3 billion in annual revenue and a focus on naturally raised ingredients. Mr. Ells, 43 years old, remains Chipotle&apos;s chairman and co-chief executive. He still hasn&apos;t opened his fancy restaurant.

Edited interview excerpts follow:
 
 Q. Let&apos;s hear about your early days. 

A. Having never taken a business class, the economics of restaurants scared me. I opened Chipotle with the idea that I could step away from it and use it to support my full-scale restaurant. There were very few moving parts. We served just a few things, burritos and tacos, and it was put together very simply with plywood. It had a very funky, raw look to it. Of course it also had a low investment cost. And so what resulted was this restaurant that was, in fact, quite replicable.

 Q. As a classically trained chef, you didn&apos;t set out to open a fast-food chain. Have you stayed because of the success, or did your passion change? 

A. One of the pivotal moments for me was realizing that our &quot;food with integrity&quot; approach at Chipotle was satisfying my passion. That&apos;s about bringing the best quality, sustainably raised ingredients to everyone: chicken without antibiotics; beef without hormones. These ingredients were only available in high-end restaurants, not mainstream places. Today, we buy more naturally raised meat than any other restaurant company in the world. I don&apos;t know if I would ever have that kind of impact with one full-scale restaurant.

 Q. What inspired the focus on natural ingredients? 

A. About 10 years ago, I was reading an article in Ed Behr&apos;s &quot;The Art of Eating&quot; about the Niman Ranch farmers up in Iowa, who were raising pork outdoors or in deeply bedded barns, and had a very special protocol about raising animals humanely, feeding them a vegetarian diet and not giving them growth hormones. I sent for a sample and made carnitas with it–and they were significantly better.

Most pork comes from factory farms or confinement hog operations. I toured these places, and I knew I didn&apos;t want my success or Chipotle&apos;s to be based on the exploitation I saw. Not only the brutal treatment of the animals but the disregard to the environment, to the displacement of the family farmer and to the working conditions.

 Q. All of the pork and chicken used in Chiptole restaurants is naturally raised; 60% of the beef is. How does that affect your overhead? 

A. Our food costs are about 31.5% of sales–this is significantly higher than most fast-food restaurants–but you can taste the difference. That&apos;s why customers are loyal. They&apos;re not asking for free-range meat or organic beans. Ultimately, if you give people great-tasting food, they&apos;ll come back. Our economic model allows us to invest a disproportionate amount in our food costs. We have a very efficient system: customers go through a single line, the people who serve you are the ones who make the food, and our menu board is not cluttered.

 Q. People thought McDonald&apos;s (which invested in 1998 and shed its stake after Chipotle&apos;s IPO) was an odd pairing, considering your all-natural focus. Why the partnership? 

A. I don&apos;t think it was an odd pairing. It was a great period where they funded our growth. In deciding where to get money, I talked to a lot of people. McDonald&apos;s seemed the only one that was interested in the brand, food and culture I wanted to create. Everybody else was considering their returns and exit strategy.

 Q. You&apos;ve made financially savvy choices along the way. Does that come naturally to you? 

A. My undergraduate degree was in art history! Raising money for Chipotle was really my MBA. The money for my first restaurant came from my dad; the second from mostly cash flow; the third was an SBA loan. After my dad invested $1.5 million to open a few more, he suggested I raise the money myself for the experience. It took me about a year to raise $1.8 million. People [friends and private investors] asked a lot of question about the business that forced me to take a critical look at how it ran.

 Q. You don&apos;t franchise–have you considered it? 

A. Our current model works for us. We want to own the economics of the business. We have plenty of capital. And we want to give people who work in our restaurants today the opportunity to become general managers.

 Q. What advice do you give to other entrepreneurs starting out? 

A. So many people told me it was not a good idea to a start a restaurant, especially a fast-food restaurant. There was so much wrong with it–it was too spicy; everything was done by hand, from scratch. Everything was wrong. But that&apos;s why customers liked it; it&apos;s different, in the right way. If you have an idea, just go for it. If everybody is telling you that it&apos;s wrong, maybe that&apos;s an indication that it&apos;s an original idea.

 Write to Colleen DeBaise at colleen.debaise@wsj.com 
 
Copyright 2012 Dow Jones&amp;Company, Inc. All Rights Reserved

This copy is for your personal, non-commercial use only. Distribution and use of this material are governed by our Subscriber Agreement and by copyright law. For non-personal use or to order multiple copies, please contact Dow Jones Reprints at 1-800-843-0008 or visit

 www.djreprints.com 
 Join the discussion More In Small Business» 
 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 
 Das Erfolgsmodell Brasilien hat ausgedient 
 
 Chinas Konjunkturdaten könnten geschönt sein 
 
 Der Anlagenotstand wird eskalieren 
 
 
 
 Back To 
 
 
 
 Voltar ao 
 
 
 Back To 
 MSN Money Homepage 
 
 MSN Money Investing 
 
 
Available to WSJ.com Subscribers

 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 
 Madrid Austerity Plan Boosted 
 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 
 Monti: Italy Faces Economic &apos;War&apos; 
 

 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 
 Work Perk: Free-Meal Rule Widens 
 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 
 Monti&apos;s Blunt Words Mark Shift for Italy 
 
 
 From the HomePage 

 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 
 GM Ousts Head of European Operations 

General Motors has ousted the head of its struggling Opel/Vauxhaull division amid frustration with the pace of the turnaround of the European business.
 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 
 GM, Peugeot Take Aim at European Woes 

General Motors and France&apos;s Peugeot took dramatic steps aimed at overhauling their ailing European operations that could spark a broader restructuring of the Continent&apos;s beleaguered auto industry.
 
 Troops Called In to Plug Olympic Security Gap 

Just two weeks before the Olympics begin, the U.K. government is increasing the role of the military to help secure the event, a last-minute expansion that is prompting questions about how security plans are being managed.
 
 Libya Liberal Bloc Closes In on Win 

An alliance of parties led by a U.S.-educated economist is handily leading Libya&apos;s legislative elections, according to unofficial results, promising that liberal lawmakers will shape the country&apos;s next government and the continuing regional debate about the role of Islam in politics.
 
 
Want to be an entrepreneur?

Find opportunities in our business and franchise databases.
 Businesses For Sale | Franchises | Opportunities All Business Categories RETAILING BUSINESSES  - Apparel and Accessory Stores  - Automotive Dealers  - Bars/Taverns  - Blding Mat., Hardware, Garden  - Convenience Stores  - Florists  - Gasoline Service Stations  - General Merchandise Stores  - Home Furniture&amp;Furnishings  - Liquor Stores  - Marine Dealers&amp;Equipment  - Miscellaneous Retail  - Other Eating&amp;Drinking Places  - Other Food Stores  - Pet Shops&amp;Supplies  - Restaurants  - Supermarkets  - Vending Machines SERVICE BUSINESSES  - Agents&amp;Brokers  - Amusement&amp;Recreation  - Auto Repair, Parts&amp;Services  - Beauty Salons, Barber Shops  - Computer&amp;Software Services  - Drycleaning/Laundry Services  - Educational Services  - Engineering&amp;Accounting Svcs  - Finance, Banking, Loans, etc.  - Freight, Moving/Delivery  - Health, Medical&amp;Dental  - Hotels&amp;Other Lodging Places  - Landscaping&amp;Yard Services  - Legal Services  - Marine Repair, Parts&amp;Services  - Membership Organizations  - Miscellaneous Repair Services  - Miscellaneous Services  - Motion Pictures  - Museums, Art Galleries, Zoos  - Other Business Services  - Other Personal Services  - Other Travel&amp;Transportation  - Passenger Transportation  - Pet Care&amp;Grooming  - Social Services  - Storage&amp;Warehousing  - Travel Agencies INTERNET BUSINESSES  - Business Services (B2B)  - Consumer Services (B2C)  - Domain Name/Basic Site  - General Internet  - ISP/ASP Services  - Software  - Web Design/Tech Services MANUFACTURING BUSINESSES  - Apparel&amp;finished fabrics  - Chemicals&amp;Allied Products  - Electronic&amp;Electrical Equip.  - Fabricated Metal Products  - Food and Kindred Products  - Furniture and Fixtures  - Industrial&amp;Comm. Machinery  - Leather and Leather Products  - Lumber and Wood Products  - Measuring&amp;Analyzing Instr.  - Miscellaneous  - Paper&amp;Allied Products  - Petroleum Refining  - Primary Metal Industries  - Printing, Publishing  - Rubber and Plastic Products  - Stone, Clay, Glass, Concrete  - Textile Mill Products  - Tobacco Products  - Transportation Equipment WHOLSALE/DIST. BUSINESSES  - Durable Goods  - Nondurable Goods CONSTRUCTION BUSINESSES  - Building  - Heavy  - Special Trades BUSINESS REAL ESTATE  - For Lease  - For Sale Agriculture Communications Electric, Gas, Water, Sanitary Svcs Mining Non-classifiable Establishments State   Alabama   Alaska   Arizona   Arkansas   California   Colorado   Connecticut   Delaware   District of Columbia   Florida   Georgia   Hawaii   Idaho   Illinois   Indiana   Iowa   Kansas   Kentucky   Louisiana   Maine   Maryland   Massachusetts   Michigan   Minnesota   Mississippi   Missouri   Montana   Nebraska   Nevada   New Hampshire   New Jersey   New Mexico   New York   North Carolina   North Dakota   Ohio   Oklahoma   Oregon   Pennsylvania   Rhode Island   South Carolina   South Dakota   Tennessee   Texas   Utah   Vermont   Virginia   Washington   West Virginia   Wisconsin   Wyoming U.S. Territories Africa Asia/Pacific Australia/New Zealand Canada Caribbean Mexico/Central America Europe South America County Search Advanced Search Businesses For Sale | Franchises | Opportunities All Franchise Categories Automotive Business Opportunities Business Services Child Related Cleaning And Maintenance Computer And Internet Food And Restaurant Health, Beauty, and Fitness High Capital Franchises Home Based Businesses Home Services Low Cost Franchises Retail Franchises Sports And Recreation Travel And Lodging State Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware District of Columbia Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming All Amounts to Invest Up to $25,000 Up to $50,000 Up to $100,000 Up to $250,000 Up to $500,000 Up to $1,000,000 Up to $5,000,000 Search Advanced Search Businesses For Sale | Franchises | Opportunities All Business Categories Auctions Business Connections Business Opportunities Business Services Capital Available Capital Wanted Financial Services Internet Services Legal Services Marketing Services Professional Services Search   
 Recent Columns 

 
 Ground Zero in Greek-Yogurt Craze 
 
 Can Tumblr Turn a Profit? 
 
 Hardship Inspired Franchise 
 
 
More in Small Business

 
 Battle Armor: Dispute Ensnares Entrepreneurs 
 
 Bane of Merchants: &apos;Swipe Fees&apos; 
 
 Price of Using Credit Cards May Rise 
 
 Cybercriminals Sniff Out Vulnerability 
 
 Smartwatch Becomes Kickstarter Test Case 
 
 
 Most Popular In Europe 

 Read Emailed Video Commented 
 
 1. 
 News-Sharing Site Digg Sells for $500,000 
 2. 
 Opinion: Karl Rove: Obama&apos;s Shrinking Majority 
 3. 
 Mystery Solved: Mogul Bought &apos;Scream&apos; 
 4. 
 Housing Passes a Milestone 
 5. 
 Madrid Austerity Plan Boosted 
 
 
 1. 
 Housing Passes a Milestone 
 2. 
 Sleeping Anytime, Anywhere 
 3. 
 A Cruise Without the Cruise Ship 
 4. 
 Deeper Slowdown Suspected in China 
 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 5. 
 Fed Weighs More Stimulus 
 
 
 1. 
 Sisters Spend $150 Million for Two Houses 
 2. 
 Top &apos;Knifeletes&apos; Compete for Cutting Championship 
 3. 
 Buyer of Munch&apos;s &apos;The Scream&apos; is Revealed 
 4. 
 A Luxury Penthouse With Outdoor Shower and Hot Tub 
 5. 
 The Quest to Build a 90,000 Square Foot Mansion 
 
 
 1. 
 NAACP Cool Toward Romney&apos;s Overtures 1222 comments 
 2. 
 Opinion: Holder&apos;s Jim Crow Politics 632 comments 
 3. 
 Opinion: Obama&apos;s Shrinking Majority 533 comments 
 4. 
 Opinion: Henninger: Mitt Romney&apos;s Summer Vacation 523 comments 
 5. 
 Opinion: Air Jordan and the 1% 403 comments 
 
 
 Most Read Articles Feed Most Emailed Feed Most Popular Video Feed Most Commented Feed Most Popular Feeds 
 
Editors&apos; Picks

 
 The Song That Conquered Radio 
 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 
 Brokerage Scandal Shakes Iowa Town 
 
 Web Video Inflames Fight Over TV Fees 
 
 Keeping a Close Eye on Shoppers&apos; Retinas 
 
 A Cut Above: In These Knife Fights, Only Pride Gets Wounded 
 
 Loading... 
 Market Data Center 
 
Footnotes*

Real-time U.S. stock quotes reflect trades reported through Nasdaq only; comprehensive U.S. stock quotes reflect trading in all markets and are delayed at least 15 minutes. All quote volume is comprehensive and reflects trading in all markets, delayed at least 15 minutes. International stock quotes are delayed as per exchange requirements.
 
 Small Business Video 

 previous   next 

   
 Tax Surprise In Restricted Stock 
 1:24   
 Women: Now Is The Time To Plan For Retirement 
 2:18   
 Wealth: How To Ignore the Noise 
 2:33   
 Recruiting Talent: The Shirt, Dogfish Head Brewery 
 2:58   
 On Partners: The Shirt, Dogfish Head, Intelius 
 4:07   
 Raising Capital: The Shirt, Dogfish Head, Intelius 
 4:23   
 How To Dress For Success in Business 
 4:18   
 Productivity Far Outpaces U.S. Factory Wages 
 1:44   
 Steps To Take Before You Sell Your Business 
 3:07   
 Heirs Fight Over An Inheritance, Advisers Referee 
 2:26   
 Wealth: Predicting Interest Rates, ETF Risks 
 3:01   
 Mark Matson On Advising Main Street 
 3:08   
 How to Land a Referral Without Annoying a Client 
 3:15   
 All Bets Are Off In May: It&apos;s An Election Year 
 1:05   
 Treading Lightly In World Markets With ETFs 
 3:41 
 
Most Recommended

 Comments Comments Commenters Commenters 

 1. 
 “Where is the leftist legacy medi...;” 
 - Jonathan Murray 145 Recommendations 2. 
 “I usually like what Henninger...;” 
 - Jared Potter 116 Recommendations 3. 
 “The article did not mention the...;” 
 - Mary Childs 103 Recommendations 4. 
 “An open letter to Attorney Gener...;” 
 - Jon Barecky 94 Recommendations 5. 
 “The bigger mistake is allowing...;” 
 - William Encanta 90 Recommendations 

 William Encanta 1878 Recommendations Peter Venetoklis 1637 Recommendations Gary Myers 1381 Recommendations Mary Childs 1318 Recommendations Matilda Anders 1269 Recommendations 
 
Most Active Discussions

 Journal Community 
 
 
Question of the Day

 Should the Bush-era tax cuts be extended for one year for families earning less than $250,000? 
 
Religion&amp;Ethics

 Do we need religion to have ethics? Is it possible that a world without religion can be, on the whole, a better place to live? 
 
Question of the Day

 What does the housing market look like in your area? 
 
Small Talk

 Would you pay a surcharge to use a credit card instead of cash? 
 
Question of the Day

 Which person should Mitt Romney choose as his running mate? 
 

 See all Discussion Groups 
 
More in Small Business

 
 Battle Armor: Dispute Ensnares Entrepreneurs 
 
 Bane of Merchants: &apos;Swipe Fees&apos; 
 
 Price of Using Credit Cards May Rise 
 
 Cybercriminals Sniff Out Vulnerability 
 
 Smartwatch Becomes Kickstarter Test Case
	</body>
</document>
