<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009640" url="http://forums.redflagdeals.com/archive/index.php/t-951323.html" time="2012-07-13-03:02" support="44" score="0.06114096292442217" bingtitle="Why many people don&apos;t use credit card? [Archive] - RedFlagDeals ..." webtitle="Why many people don&apos;t use credit card? [Archive]  - RedFlagDeals.com Forums">
			<query id="000579" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="001216" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000455" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001464" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="000740" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000381" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="001291" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000563" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000303" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="001311" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="001398" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000300" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="001385" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="001196" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000586" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000394" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000397" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="001404" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="000588" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="000591" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="001055" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="001218" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000568" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000573" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000576" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="001307" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000737" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="001461" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="001209" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000458" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="001219" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="001215" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000583" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="001405" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001052" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="000725" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000590" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="001408" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001214" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="001407" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="001304" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001039" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="000587" bing-rank="18"/>
	<description>However, I worked as a cashier at a fast food restaurant and ... i prefer not using my credit card at a restaurant, i can explain why. ... can happen, a waiter can accidentally put ...</description>
	<body>
		RedFlagDeals.com Forums &gt; Personal Finance &gt;Why many people don&apos;t use credit card? PDA 
View Full Version : Why many people don&apos;t use credit card? 
 
 oneandone Oct 12th, 2010, 11:24 AM I have to say, I love the credit card much. it is convenient, wuth no monthly fee compared to my debit card, no password or signature needed for small purchase, and aslo gives cash back. so I always use cc everywhere I could, with no cash in my wallet.

However, I worked as a cashier at a fast food restaurant and I noticed many customs won&apos;t use cc for even such a small purchase, even they have a cc with them. 90% of the card I received are debit card, and too often I observed they present their cc but found it was mistake, said sorry and then gave me another debit card instead.

I was always confused about this. Maybe it is not safe to use cc for small purchase? maybe too many small purchases appear on bills are not good for keeping a good credit record? or maybe some people cann&apos;t controll their wallet by using cc? but it just a five or six dollar&apos;s meal! TripleHelix Oct 12th, 2010, 11:41 AM I have to say, I love the credit card much. it is convenient, wuth no monthly fee compared to my debit card, no password or signature needed for small purchase, and aslo gives cash back. so I always use cc everywhere I could, with no cash in my wallet.

However, I worked as a cashier at a fast food restaurant and I noticed many customs won&apos;t use cc for even such a small purchase, even they have a cc with them. 90% of the card I received are debit card, and too often I observed they present their cc but found it was mistake, said sorry and then gave me another debit card instead.

I was always confused about this. Maybe it is not safe to use cc for small purchase? maybe too many small purchases appear on bills are not good for keeping a good credit record? or maybe some people cann&apos;t controll their wallet by using cc? but it just a five or six dollar&apos;s meal!

Most Fast food places didn&apos;t accept CC&apos;s until recently so that may be why.

Most people prefer debit over CC because it&apos;s easier for them to track their money. Other people just don&apos;t have the control to not spend all the credit they have on the CC.

I personally use my CC whenever I can to get the points. will2009wpg Oct 12th, 2010, 11:54 AM Most Fast food places didn&apos;t accept CC&apos;s until recently so that may be why.

Most people prefer debit over CC because it&apos;s easier for them to track their money. Other people just don&apos;t have the control to not spend all the credit they have on the CC.

I personally use my CC whenever I can to get the points.

I think a big part of it is that a lot of people get a debit card in their teens but don&apos;t get a credit card untill they are 18 or older. They get in the habit of using debit and when they get a cc they either switch or they don&apos;t.

Some people do indeed lack the willpower to use a CC responsibly.

I laugh though when my friends are paying $1.50 debit charges at some places and I&apos;m paying with my visa and getting 1% cash back instead.

As long as its a no fee card and gives you some sort of cashback/points then its silly to use debit TrevorK Oct 12th, 2010, 12:09 PM Many people in this country carry a balance on their CC&apos;s so perhaps it&apos;s a mental thing for them - that they don&apos;t want to go into debt to buy their Big Mac, so they use their debit card. oneandone Oct 12th, 2010, 12:32 PM Thanks for all your replies. As I am new to Canada, there is still lots to learn.

At first I thought they may consider reasons dealing with their credit records, or security. So once I even thought maybe I should upgrade my debit card and use it for small purchases. As my current debit card only offers ten transactions free each month.

Now clear. I should continue to use my cc everywhere, even in Dollarama, with cash back, extra warranty and convenience. I can control my wallet even give me a cc with a 50,000 limit. :) I think it also important for me to build up some good records for the future. (I have been using cc for over 5 years with good record in my home country, but it helps nothing here.) netwise Oct 12th, 2010, 12:50 PM Paying with a credit card works great if you have a 0 balance and pay in full each month. Most people don&apos;t. So if you have a $1000 balance from some TV you bought, then spend $200 in little charges and pay $200 to cover those little charges - that $1000 TV/balance just keeps accumulating. Given that a lot of people have a balance, I&apos;m sure this is why they don&apos;t pay with credit. While having ht e1% cash back and no interac fees is good, for most people I suspect the best habit to be in is to use interac as an&quot;if I don&apos;t have the cash, I shouldn&apos;t spend it&quot;sort of approach.

Just a personal observation.... TrevorK Oct 12th, 2010, 06:05 PM Now clear. I should continue to use my cc everywhere, even in Dollarama, with cash back, extra warranty and convenience. I can control my wallet even give me a cc with a 50,000 limit. :) I think it also important for me to build up some good records for the future. (I have been using cc for over 5 years with good record in my home country, but it helps nothing here.)

Just remember, because skimming credit cards is common (Whereby someone steals your credit card information and uses it) I would recommend having a couple cards. This way, if one is skimmed you still have another that can be used while you are being sent a replacement card. There are enough 1% cash back/no fee credit cards it shouldn&apos;t be a problem finding two of them.

Also, keep the credit card information in a secure easily accessible location so that if something happens you have easy access to the appropriate phone numbers to call to save yourself the hassle of looking for it when you&apos;re already stressed out. starchyk Oct 12th, 2010, 06:24 PM Some people find it more difficult to control spending using a credit card - I use my credit card a fair bit, but not so much for the small daily purchases. When I pay with debit, the charge shows up in my bank account immediately, but when I pay with a CC it takes anywhere from a couple of days to a week before the charge shows up on my online banking. My solution is to save my receipts and enter the info into my budget software so I can keep track of my spending - but it&apos;s just too much hassle for every small purchase. I suspect most people don&apos;t track spending at all, and find that using a CC results in a nasty end of the month suprise.

I also have a great deal on unlimited banking, so I don&apos;t pay for debit transactions. If I did, I would go cash for the small stuff. dealguy2 Oct 12th, 2010, 06:32 PM It might sound illogical but I always notice that people who use debit cards at grocery stores etc instead of credit cards seem to me to be bad with money. nauru Oct 12th, 2010, 07:14 PM Slight thread hijack-

Speaking of payment methods at the grocery store, why is it that cashiers look so shocked/surprised when they offer me a receipt and I don&apos;t want it? I mean when I buy 15 bucks worth of groceries, or a snack at Tim Horton&apos;s, or other items which are food items and obviously not going to be returned at a future date for defects, in amounts which are less than 20 bucks.... Why would I want a receipt? I can&apos;t imagine a situation in which I would need to prove to somebody that I bought a donut. Do most people actually hoard all their receipts from tiny purchases, and tally up how many coffees and donuts they bought at the end of the month? Am I actually the peculiar one because I don&apos;t do that? :)

Have been wondering this for some time, I guess. HBP Oct 12th, 2010, 08:14 PM Slight thread hijack-

Speaking of payment methods at the grocery store, why is it that cashiers look so shocked/surprised when they offer me a receipt and I don&apos;t want it? I mean when I buy 15 bucks worth of groceries, or a snack at Tim Horton&apos;s, or other items which are food items and obviously not going to be returned at a future date for defects, in amounts which are less than 20 bucks.... Why would I want a receipt? I can&apos;t imagine a situation in which I would need to prove to somebody that I bought a donut. Do most people actually hoard all their receipts from tiny purchases, and tally up how many coffees and donuts they bought at the end of the month? Am I actually the peculiar one because I don&apos;t do that? :)

Have been wondering this for some time, I guess.

To make sure you were charged correctly? PrairieGal Oct 12th, 2010, 08:49 PM Using credit cards is a slippery slope for many people. fly Oct 12th, 2010, 09:21 PM Now clear. I should continue to use my cc everywhere, even in Dollarama, with cash back, extra warranty and convenience. I can control my wallet even give me a cc with a 50,000 limit. :) I think it also important for me to build up some good records for the future. (I have been using cc for over 5 years with good record in my home country, but it helps nothing here.)

POS services charge debit card transactions per transaction whereas credit card transactions by % of the charge. A business such as Dollarama wouldn&apos;t like to be charge a % since their margin on each unit would decrease. Hence, Dollarama only accepts debit and cash. Debit card is also immediate whereas with credit cards there could be a hold depending on the service company&apos;s relationship; in case of chargebacks. Again, hence not all stores accept credit cards for that reason.

There&apos;s also cost in dealing with cash. Banks typically charge per bill deposit. Every method of payment costs the merchant money so they usually favour one over another depending on their business model. desertfox Oct 12th, 2010, 09:58 PM I used my cashback credit card on everything and don&apos;t carry cash on my wallet. This is no brainer and a win, win situation. You earn cashback by using your card as long as you pay your balance in full and the money you&apos;ll be paying your card earned interest in a HISA before it&apos;s due date. xlfe Oct 12th, 2010, 10:01 PM i prefer not using my credit card at a restaurant, i can explain why.

It&apos;s because i don&apos;t trust the waiter. what they do is take my card if it&apos;s a cc and do a pre-authorize and then give me back the bill and my card and i fill in the amount for a tip.
at that point in time, i have to write the tip amount onto the bill and they&apos;ll pick it up
read it and then transfer the amount i wrote onto their payment processor.

mistakes can happen, a waiter can accidentally put in another number.
and i would only realize it when i check my statement. then what i have to go back to the restaurant and complain? such a hassle.

i prefer to pay by cash anyways as i know the tip goes to the waiter anyways. desertfox Oct 12th, 2010, 10:09 PM i prefer not using my credit card at a restaurant, i can explain why.

It&apos;s because i don&apos;t trust the waiter. what they do is take my card if it&apos;s a cc and do a pre-authorize and then give me back the bill and my card and i fill in the amount for a tip.
at that point in time, i have to write the tip amount onto the bill and they&apos;ll pick it up
read it and then transfer the amount i wrote onto their payment processor.

mistakes can happen, a waiter can accidentally put in another number.
and i would only realize it when i check my statement. then what i have to go back to the restaurant and complain? such a hassle.

i prefer to pay by cash anyways as i know the tip goes to a waiter&apos;s anyways.

This is not my custom when using my card in a restaurant. I would agree with you 100% that I don&apos;t trust waiters. I don&apos;t give my card to the waiters at all. I&apos;ll make sure that I will hand in my card to the cashier myself. There are a lot of things can happen when your card is not in a your position. Fraudster can use use your card by&quot;skimming&quot;or simply copying details of your card and the rest will be history. mada726 Oct 12th, 2010, 10:23 PM there are many people out there who can&apos;t afford to have their own credit card or tired of having it&quot;tied&quot;to their parents&apos; credit card. It took me almost 2 years to get my own credit card - after providing some feedback from my fellow RFDers on this board.

Prepaid Credit Cards - don&apos;t necessarily build your credit - but many secured credit cards can encourage to build credit or strengthen it. I would had applied my own secured credit card - but the drawbacks is sending in the deposit and the annual fees.

If we only have Visa/MasterCard debit in Canada right now, it would have freed things up - but the recently passed code of conduct unveiled by the Canadian federal government prevent it from happening. Jucius Maximus Oct 12th, 2010, 10:47 PM Due to the differing structure in merchant account fees, it becomes very expensive for small businesses to accept CCs for small transactions. Interac debit is MUCH more friendly (i.e. cheaper to process) from the perspective of the small business owner. Somebody using credit for small purchases at small businesses might be seen as either very rude/insensitive or incredibly broke. Drew_W Oct 12th, 2010, 10:50 PM Somebody using credit for small purchases at small businesses might be seen as either very rude/insensitive or incredibly broke.

I regularly pay for IKEA breakfast ($1.05-$2.10) with my Visa. I was the fourth person in line and everyone ahead of me was paying via chip CC. Line took forever. Guess we all want our points...even if it is only one or two. :P Squawk7600 Oct 12th, 2010, 10:59 PM I regularly pay for IKEA breakfast ($1.05-$2.10) with my Visa. I was the fourth person in line and everyone ahead of me was paying via chip CC. Line took forever. Guess we all want our points...even if it is only one or two. :P

lol..ur ONE of THOSE ppl..ahaha..tru say..i charge almost everything to plastic champlinD Oct 12th, 2010, 11:07 PM I know at least 3 people who don&apos;t use it. Because they don&apos;t get approved for cc. Very bad credit.
I use cash places like grocery store. Before that I used cc few times at No Frills and no sig required.
Use it at FS/BB or any consumer electronics shop.

I think some store has polic of no cc use if amount is less than $5-10 Drew_W Oct 12th, 2010, 11:09 PM lol..ur ONE of THOSE ppl..ahaha..tru say..i charge almost everything to plastic

I&apos;m allergic to coins. Squawk7600 Oct 12th, 2010, 11:18 PM I&apos;m allergic to coins.

u might wanna a see doctor/banker abt that ;) redwings_patriots Oct 12th, 2010, 11:25 PM Due to the differing structure in merchant account fees, it becomes very expensive for small businesses to accept CCs for small transactions. Interac debit is MUCH more friendly (i.e. cheaper to process) from the perspective of the small business owner. Somebody using credit for small purchases at small businesses might be seen as either very rude/insensitive or incredibly broke.

This is why small businesses should offer a cash payment discount. If they offered 1.5-2% off for paying cash, I wouldn&apos;t be inclined to pay with cc for the sake of collecting points. punisher101 Oct 12th, 2010, 11:30 PM As mentioned most people are afraid of debt and are even more afraid of there will power in overspending. I&apos;m happy using my cashback card - the credit card company is paying me to use there service - that&apos;s as it should be. ricoboxing Oct 13th, 2010, 08:33 AM I use my CC for almost everything unless there is a cash discount. Most places have paypass so you don&apos;t even have to sign. Red Queen Oct 13th, 2010, 08:40 AM For me the debit card can be more expensive to use. I have a 15 transaction limit for my checking account before I have to pay the montly service fee (3.50) and pay 60 cents per transaction after.

But like someone else posted earlier, I can see how using a CC can be more intimidating when you have accumulated unpaid debt on the Card.

My card has a relatively low limit ($2500), and I also have it set up to be automatically paid off every month, so I have nuthing to worry about. Dystopia Oct 13th, 2010, 11:21 AM Many people in this country carry a balance on their CC&apos;s so perhaps it&apos;s a mental thing for them - that they don&apos;t want to go into debt to buy their Big Mac, so they use their debit card.$1 to use debit on a Big Mac vs. 11 or so % to use credit and let the balance roll over.
This is why I face palm...

I use credit for absolutely everything.
Get weekly notices on your balance, pay on time.
It sounds hokey but, make the banks work for you lol. CorSter Oct 13th, 2010, 11:41 AM I generally use my Credit Card everywhere, but i&apos;ve found recently i&apos;ve been using Cash more and more, mostly at small businesses when I grab lunch. I don&apos;t mind.. The_Madz Oct 13th, 2010, 11:55 AM i prefer not using my credit card at a restaurant, i can explain why.

It&apos;s because i don&apos;t trust the waiter. what they do is take my card if it&apos;s a cc and do a pre-authorize and then give me back the bill and my card and i fill in the amount for a tip.
at that point in time, i have to write the tip amount onto the bill and they&apos;ll pick it up
read it and then transfer the amount i wrote onto their payment processor.

mistakes can happen, a waiter can accidentally put in another number.
and i would only realize it when i check my statement. then what i have to go back to the restaurant and complain? such a hassle.

i prefer to pay by cash anyways as i know the tip goes to the waiter anyways.

paranoid much?

if there are mistakes you call the credit card company. superping Oct 13th, 2010, 12:28 PM Credit card is safer than debit. It&apos;s much easier to get your money back from credit card for fault charges. Debit card take months to get your money back, if you are lucky to get them back at all. You signed the agreement that your pin is like your signature. If the debit pin is compromised, it&apos;s your responsibility.

The only danger for credit card is that you can over spend on money that you don&apos;t have. TrevorK Oct 13th, 2010, 03:32 PM Slight thread hijack-

Speaking of payment methods at the grocery store, why is it that cashiers look so shocked/surprised when they offer me a receipt and I don&apos;t want it? I mean when I buy 15 bucks worth of groceries, or a snack at Tim Horton&apos;s, or other items which are food items and obviously not going to be returned at a future date for defects, in amounts which are less than 20 bucks.... Why would I want a receipt? I can&apos;t imagine a situation in which I would need to prove to somebody that I bought a donut. Do most people actually hoard all their receipts from tiny purchases, and tally up how many coffees and donuts they bought at the end of the month? Am I actually the peculiar one because I don&apos;t do that? :)

Have been wondering this for some time, I guess.

I believe that many stores have a policy of the staff giving the customer the receipt to ensure that the transaction was recorded and the money was put into the till. It&apos;s often a scam for the staff to pretend to ring up the transaction (or not even pretend at all) and pocket the money. The staff can become quite proficient at it when they serve the same items (such as fast food) because they know the after-tax price off the top of their heads.

The easiest way to combat this is to enact a policy that every customer is given a receipt. Then any (well most) shortages are blatantly obvious when the money is counted. brunes Oct 13th, 2010, 05:16 PM People use ther debit card instead of CC for one of four reasons

a) They have been deluded by the bank and/or Interac advertising into thinking that it is safer for them (when in fact, it is more dangerous)

b) They have no credit history and thus can not get a CC

c) They have poor self control and think/know that if they use their CC they will lose track of their spending

d) Bad habits are tough to break. brunes Oct 13th, 2010, 05:18 PM SWhy would I want a receipt? I can&apos;t imagine a situation in which I would need to prove to somebody that I bought a donut. Do most people actually hoard all their receipts from tiny purchases, and tally up how many coffees and donuts they bought at the end of the month? Am I actually the peculiar one because I don&apos;t do that? :)


I always take my receipts home and shred them. They are a prime source of identity theft. Not all stores blank out part of your CC number, sometimes the number is right there for everyone to see. And even the ones that blank it out, blank out different portions. So if someone grabbed from the trash two of your receipts from a random shopping trip, they might have your whole number.

I bring home all receipts, just shove them in my pocket. When I get home, ones for items I may return, go into the filing cabinet, others go to the shredder. It is not difficult or troublesome in any way. pchi Oct 13th, 2010, 06:44 PM Everyone has different methods for handling their finances. Some people are afraid of credit. Some people just don&apos;t know the benefits of a credit card. One rule to go by is to always pay off your balance on the due date. Never spend more than what you can afford.

For me, I use my MBNA Smart Cash Mastercard for most of my purchases unless the merchant doesn&apos;t take credit card. And yes, MBNA updates your transaction automatically on their website. I charge even $1 to my Mastercard. I&apos;m such a plastic user and pay off my balance every month! Great cash back rewards, no annual fee. I haven&apos;t had any problems with credit card fraud. I do online purchases to using my card at restaurants.

Although, my debits are free. I bank with PC Financial. I hardly use debit because I don&apos;t keep a balance in my chequing account. It&apos;s usually whisked away to pay off bills or into savings.

Everyone has their own form of payment method. Choose yours wisely ;) goob3r Oct 13th, 2010, 06:57 PM I always use my CC, even if I were to buy a 69 cents bottle of water from SDM. Why? Cause I don&apos;t like carrying change. Plus you get cash back and points and what not. It all gets paid off at the end of the month. Guess I never really understood how people treat credit cards as free money. Imagine if business saw&quot;net 30&quot;on their invoices as free money... desertfox Oct 13th, 2010, 07:24 PM I&apos;ve already received $150 cheque for using my smart cash MBNA card since I&apos;ve got it in MAY and the money I&apos;m paying for my CC is also earning interest in HISA b4 it&apos;s due date. Would I get same benefit if I was using my debit card? NO. I&apos;ts not rocket science. Very simple apart from the exceptions mentioned previous posts.
	</body>
</document>
