<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009561" url="http://portfolio.datafabrication.com/talcott/main_content.asp?siteid=1&amp;sectionid=210&amp;articleid=311&amp;pagenumber=3" time="2012-07-13-02:56" support="1" score="0.0018560168530636252" bingtitle="ARTICLE PAGES: - Chef Magazine" webtitle="Chef Magazine">
			<query id="000725" bing-rank="150"/>
	<description>... Institute of Virginia College in Birmingham, Ala., worked as a fast-food restaurant cashier ... This is evident from the number of African-Americans passed over because ...</description>
	<body>
		Home 

 Current Features 

 Chef Profile / Insight 

 Events 

 Savor / Recipes / Cards 

 Contests 

 Nutrition 

 Editorial Advisory Board 

 Subscribe 

 Contact Our Staff 

 
 --- Media Kit --- Media Kit Home 


 
 
 
 
 ARTICLE PAGES: 
[  A certified chef  ]
[  Making a positive difference  ]
[  Open minds open doors  ]


 june
 Open minds open doors 
 Thursday, June 10, 2004 

ACF African-American advocate, Dennie Streeter, discusses how taking chances brings opportunities
by Melanie Wolkoff
When Dennie Streeter, C.E.C., C.C.E., executive chef/instructor, Culinard, at the Culinary Institute of Virginia College in Birmingham, Ala., worked as a fast-food restaurant cashier, upper management took a chance on her and asked her to join the management team. Now Streeter has taken a chance on herselfand others like her.
I made a decision to do something different. I wanted to return and finish college, says Streeter who enrolled in Jefferson State Community College Arts Program in Birmingham, Ala. I was ready to take my career to a new level, says Streeter. My friends encouraged me. The thrill of cooking motivated me to forge ahead.
Today, Streeter combines her love of cooking and love of people as executive chef/instructor of fundamental food production at Culinard; a position she began in 2001. When I was offered the chance to teach, the decision was easy. It was a God-sent situation, since people and cooking are my passions, teaching brings them together, she says. I enjoy all facets of instruction, but teaching beginners is an opportunity to impact developing careers.
Just as Streeter received opportunities, she intends to reciprocate to others. One way she does this is through her new role as a recruiting agent/representative for the school. In this role, Streeter visits schools and speaks with students who desire culinary arts training.
A place to belong
Streeter also reaches out through her involvement with the American Culinary Federation (ACF). She joined the ACF Birmingham, Ala., chapter while attending culinary school. My first impression of the ACF was it was a place I could be a part of, she says. Most of the certified chefs in my area were involved and encouraged me to join.
As a junior member, Streeter served as vice-president of the Junior ACF Birmingham, Ala., chapter and as chapter president in 2003. In 2001 she was honored as Chef of the Year for the ACF Birmingham, Ala., chapter. Currently, she is chairman of the board and the ACFs African-American advocate.
Edward Leonard, C.M.C., A.A.C., ACF national president, and Louis Perrotte, C.E.C., A.A.C., Southeastern regional vice president, approached Streeter about the advocate position. Chef Leonard noticed the low conference attendance of African-American chefs, says Streeter. Many chefs I spoke with expressed they didnt feel welcomed since most literature, media exposure, activities and presentations lacked interest to an African-American chef. Chefs Leonard and Perrotte expressed a sincere concern to make all members feel welcome and ensure the organizations face represents all the members.
Streeters advocate duties include attending conferences and conventions and speaking with nationwide African-American ACF members to allow those voices to be heard. Oftentimes, we [African-American chefs] have a space available for networking, discussing and just getting to know each other. The forums allow us to talk about anything that concerns us. We strive to supply support for each other, especially our junior members, says Streeter.
Streeter feels the biggest challenge African-Americans chefs face occurs within upper management. Stereotyping is the biggest challenge on an upper management scale, she says. This could happen in any profession, not just culinary. This is evident from the number of African-Americans passed over because it is assumed they do not have the training, skills or discernment to move into executive chef, culinary educators or program director positions. In an effort to combat these assumptions, African-Americans do seek higher education.
Steps in the right direction
The fact that diversity acceptance is addressed is a good sign of things to come. The adoption of an African-American advocate displays serious interest on ACFs part, she says. Our president is passionate about our concerns and open to suggestions.
While Streeter focuses on African-American issues, being a women in a male-dominated field is also an issue she takes to heart. I have worked in foodservice for more than 33 years; 11 years as a chef. I have seen very little change for females in this industry, she says. We continue to hold the least lucrative positions. The reasons could be that students prefer male instructors over female instructors, or large establishments prefer male executive chefs as opposed to female executive chefs.
Streeter remains hopeful. Many believe change will never come. I believe its inevitable and forthwith, she says. It is said that diversity is a touchy subject. Actually, it is an un-touched subject. For anyone to become better educated on any issue, they must express a desire to be educated.
Some issues can be dispelled when all persons involved become mindful of others, just by showing respect for each other, she continues.
Creating an environment that encourages an open-door policy for diversity is one way to bring a sense of easiness to the classroom or workplace, says Streeter. Use eye contact, smile, talk about specific experiences in your cultural ways of preparing foods and allow others to do the same, she says. Look for ways to embrace diversity and keep the focus on hiring the most qualified applicant.
Streeter believes the culinary community is making headway. We have the responsibility to do the best we can; I believe our actions will make a difference in the culinary community presently and in the future, she says. As a result of diversity coming to the forefront, many African-American students will become active ACF members and continue the journey. We are more alike than different.
SIDE BAR
Workplace Diversity
Restaurants employ more minority managers than any industry in the country.
Nearly one out of four eating-and-drinking-place firms (23 percent) are female-owned.
Close to 24 percent are owned by other minorities.
Fifty-six percent of foodservice supervisors are female.
Sixteen percent of foodservice supervisors are African-American.
Thirteen percent of foodservice supervisors are Latino.
Three percent of foodservice supervisors are Asian-American.
Source: National Restaurant Association

 
 
 
 
 
 Executive chef/instructor, Dennie Streeter, C.E.C., C.C.E. 

 
 
 Published by Talcott Communications Corporation.   
Copyright©2012 Talcott Communications Corporation. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
