<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009489" url="http://www.chineseop.com/Dining-Out/Does-Taco-Bell-use-lard-in-their-re-fried-beans-or-are-they-vegetarian-.html" time="2012-07-13-02:52" support="3" score="0.007833971528589693" bingtitle="Does Taco Bell use lard in their re-fried beans or are they ..." webtitle="Does Taco Bell use lard in their re-fried beans or are they vegetarian?-About Food&amp;Health">
			<query id="000049" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="000612" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000895" bing-rank="182"/>
	<description>when you pay with a credit card at a fast food restaurant and they ask for a tip; Question: when you pay with a credit card at a fast food restaurant and they ask...</description>
	<body>
		Home | Sitemap | RSS Feed | Bookmak Us Catalogue Home Cooking Recipes General Cooking Entertaining Cuisine Non-Alcoholic Drinks Health Vegetarian&amp;Vegan Beer wine Others 
 

 Related Resources 
 You are: Home &gt; Dining Out &gt; 

Does Taco Bell use lard in their re-fried beans or are they vegetarian?
 Views:    Font: [ Large Medium Small ] 
 Here are some friends with simlar question as we.And I have this question for many days,anyone help us?
Kitty said: Yes. Does Taco Bell use lard in their re-fried beans or are they vegetarian? -I try seach this on internet but no results found.Maybe this is a stupid question.
Mike said: oh,no,you are wrong.I have found as below for this question( Does Taco Bell use lard in their re-fried beans or are they vegetarian? ),it will help you,my kids.
 
 Question: 
Does Taco Bell use lard in their re-fried beans or are they vegetarian?

 Answer: 
They are vegetarian.......no lard is used.

&quot;Several Taco Bell? items do not include meat as an ingredient. Popular ones include the classic Bean Burrito, 1/2 lb. Cheesy Bean&amp;Rice Burrito, 7-Layer Burrito, and Cheesy Fiesta Potatoes side item (the last two feature sour cream, which contains a very small amount of gelatin which is naturally animal-based). Of course you can also request that any item on the menu be prepared without meat or sour cream. The enzymes used in the production of our cheese, tortillas, and flatbread are not from an animal source.&quot;

 
 Read this: All the information of cooking and health post by website user,chineseop.com not guarantee
correctness,It&apos;s Non-profit and only for informational purposes. 
PRE: what&apos;s a good Brazillian restaurant in SF to celebrate a bday??  NEXT: are you a water, juice, or a soda drinker? 

Related Question about Food and Health
 Which resturant would you recommend in Edmonton? 
Question: Which resturant would you recommend in Edmonton? Answer: There are man...
 How many calories do the Quiznos Bread Bowls have? 
Question: I emailed Quiznos asking them for the information but they havent gott...
 What time does Bob Evans open up for breakfast? 
Question: What time does Bob Evans open up for breakfast? Answer: I think it is ...
 wad can this do? 
Question: wad can this do? Answer: wad??? Isnt that a roll of money, pay the bil...
 Where can I find really great souffles (savory and sweet)? 
Question: Convenient places for me in descending order: Pasadena San Gabriel Val...
 when you pay with a credit card at a fast food restaurant and they ask for a tip 
Question: when you pay with a credit card at a fast food restaurant and they ask...
 im hungry! but were redoing our kitchen what should i make, or go get? 
Question: im hungry! but were redoing our kitchen what should i make, or go get?...
 germen speakers please help!? 
Question: i need translations, how do you say: i am going to go to japan this su...
 

Popular Question about Food and Health
 How do I tip servers if I only carry a debit card? WHY do White Castle burgers give you diarrhea? What does it take to become a sushi chef.? Good restaurants in North Kansas City? Tesco toilets? KFC or McDonalds and why???? Has Anyone here ate at Texas Roadhouse ? Rumors about mcdonalds!? 
 
 About | Contact | Sitemap | Top 
©2007 - 2008 chineseop.com Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
