<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009471" url="http://www.ahabreviewsandtips.com/2011/08/choose-from-jollibee-menu-online.html" time="2012-07-13-02:51" support="3" score="0.0015321836807958718" bingtitle="Choose from Jollibee Menu Online - Ahab Reviews &amp; Tips" webtitle="Choose from Jollibee Menu Online">
			<query id="000604" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000609" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000623" bing-rank="179"/>
	<description>There is no doubt that Jollibee is the number one fast food restaurant in the ... is to view the online Jollibee menu and choose the items that you want to order.</description>
	<body>
		skip to main | skip to sidebar Ahab Reviews&amp;Tips 
 Choose from Jollibee Menu Online 
 Posted by Ishmael Fischer Ahab | 
 
Sunday, August 21, 2011 Food and Dining , Jollibee , Jollibee delivery , Jollibee Delivery.com , Jollibee Menu , Jollibee online delivery 0
comments 
 There is no doubt that Jollibee is the number one fast food restaurant in the Philippines. The proof of this is the fact that Jollibee&apos;s name and the giant red bee mascot is already etched in the Filipino culture. Ask a a kid in the Philippines what is his favorite restaurant and the usual answer will be“Jollibee.”Due to its popularity, Jollibee created an online store where customers can choose and order their favorite“Langhap Sarap”meals. This online store is the Jollibee Delivery.com. . 
 Jollibee Delivery.com makes it easier for customers to choose the meal that they want to order. The online store showcases all the items available in the Jollibee menu . Customers can view all items from Jollibee value meals to kiddie meals with toy. Everything is just few clicks away, which is quite different when ordering via the Jollibee hotline that compels customers to view Jollibee brochures (if they have any) or ask the Jollibee employee at the other end of the line.
. 
 Jollibee online delivery procedures. 
 
 There are three easy steps when using Jollibee Delivery.com First is to view the online Jollibee menu and choose the items that you want to order. Then click on the“Add to Cart”button located below the item that you want to order. Submit the contents of your“cart”and just wait for Jollibee to deliver your meal right at your doorstep. Be reminded that Jollibee only delivers for 200 pesos minimum order. Jollibee also charge 10% for deliveries. You can cancel your order within 5 minutes after ordering.

Jollibee Delivery.com accepts order from Metro Manila, Pampanga, Cavite and Cebu. If Jollibee Delivery.com is not available in your place, then you can still order using the Jollibee hotline .

Read about my favorite Jollibee items to help you decide what to order on Jollibee Delivery.com .

---

Visit Before the Eastern Sunset and read about my experience on traveling by Philtranco bus .

Follow me in Facebook , Twitter , Flickr , Tumblr and YouSayToo . 
 
 Share this on : Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 

 0
comments 


 Post a Comment 
 Newer Post Older Post Home Subscribe to: Post Comments (Atom) 
Sites to Visit
 
 Before the Eastern Sunset 
 
Blog Archive
 
 ►  2012 (47) 
 ►  July (3) 
 JRS Express Rates for Letters The Hunt for Croc Bigger than Lolong is On Thumbs Down for Jollibee&apos;s Crisscut Fries 
 

 ►  June (10) 
 Chowking Delivery Website is Under Construction New on Chowking Menu: Chow Pao Lolong is Guinness&apos;Largest Crocodile New Float and Fries on Jollibee Menu Mascots for Jollibee Party Package My Favorite Mang Inasal Menu Items with Unli Rice Online PAGASA Weather Forecast for the Rainy Seaso... Top 5 Pacquiao Wallpaper Jollibee Branches in NAIA Two Bo Sanchez Books that I Like 
 

 ►  May (8) 
 Two Yummy Cakes from Red Ribbon Bakeshop How to Plan Your Jollibee Party New Item on Jollibee Menu: Chicken and Mushroom Pa... New Cebu Pacific Piso Fares CENOMAR NSO Birth Certificate Delivery - Part 2 NSO Birth Certificate Delivery Authorized Payment ... NSO Birth Certificate Delivery–Part 1 
 

 ►  April (11) 
 NSO Birth Certificate CDR King USB: Curve Card Reader How to Cancel Your Jollibee Online Delivery How to Order on Jollibee Online Delivery Jollibee Delivery Menu Philippine Airlines Flight Status Philippine Airlines Online Booking: The Step by St... Online Writing Service for Working Students Philippine Airlines Online Booking New on Chowking Menu: Chef Bowls Avengers EMH 
 

 ►  March (5) 
 New on Jollibee Menu: Milo Blast How to Retrieve Your Lost BPIExpressOnline Usernam... How to Retrieve Your Lost BPIExpressOnline Passwor... How to Retrieve Your Lost BPIExpressOnline Passwor... Which Merchants Can You Pay Using BPIExpressOnline... 
 

 ►  February (5) 
 More Fun in Cebu Pacific Promo Fares How to Pay Bills Using BPIExpressOnline Party Items for My Bestfriend Jollibee Themed Joll... Party Items for Barbie Themed Jollibee Party Packa... PPUR Officially Included in the New7Wonders 
 

 ►  January (5) 
 Party Items for Transformers Themed Jollibee Party... Party Items for Jollitown Themed Jollibee Party Pa... How to Reserve aTicket at ZestAir Reminders for PUPCET Examinees How to Search for Jollibee Party Stores 
 
 

 ▼  2011 (112) 
 ►  December (3) 
 Jollibee Party Package Brochures Nokia C3-01 New Cebu Pacific Promo Fares 
 

 ►  November (10) 

 ►  October (8) 

 ►  September (15) 

 ▼  August (13) 
 There is Jollitown Online? Chowking Number Cebu Pacific Says: Good Buy August Order Online from Chowking Delivery My Favorites on Chowking Menu Choose from Jollibee Menu Online What Team Azkal can Learn from the Philippine Drag... Be SmArt! Visit the 2011 Korea Electronics Show How PHIVOLCS Measure the Strength of Earthquakes ECOTRADE: Leading the Way for Green Technology in ... PHIVOLCS Liquefaction Susceptibility Map PHIVOLCS Landslide Susceptibility Maps Avast Anti-Virus Software 
 

 ►  July (12) 

 ►  June (13) 

 ►  May (10) 

 ►  April (12) 

 ►  March (7) 

 ►  February (3) 

 ►  January (6) 
 

 ►  2010 (28) 
 ►  December (1) 

 ►  November (2) 

 ►  October (1) 

 ►  September (4) 

 ►  June (2) 

 ►  May (3) 

 ►  April (3) 

 ►  March (4) 

 ►  February (1) 

 ►  January (7) 
 

 ►  2009 (18) 
 ►  December (4) 

 ►  November (7) 

 ►  October (6) 

 ►  September (1) 
 
 Ahab Reviews&amp;Tips: Choose from Jollibee Menu Online
 SEO Consultant + Web Design Consulting = Bringing your business online.
	</body>
</document>
