<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009657" url="http://www.giiresearch.com/report/pf31099-product.html" time="2012-07-13-03:03" support="1" score="0.00161566216988468" bingtitle="On-the-Go Eating: Consumer Mindsets, Menu Trends, and Product ..." webtitle="On-the-Go Eating: Consumer Mindsets, Menu Trends, and Product/Packaging Innovation - GII">
			<query id="001047" bing-rank="115"/>
	<description>Delivery time; Payment options ... Table 3-3: Fast-Food Restaurant Usage Indexes: Overall, by Companion, and by Meal Occasion ...</description>
	<body>
		Site Map User Guide Global Information, Inc. 
 Loading 

 
 Home Market Research Publishers About Us Contact Us 
 
 
 
 Home &gt; Market Research Report &gt; Food &gt; Snack &gt;On-the-Go Eating: Consumer Mindsets, Menu Trends, and Product/Packaging Innovation 
 

 Delivery time User License Payment options 
 
 Food (2676) Alcoholic Beverage (540) Breakfast food (15) Confectionery (167) Dairy Product (141) Diet Foods (27) Food Additives (199) Food Services (143) Frozen food (15) Fruits and Vegetables (30) Health Drinks (139) Health Food (208) Meat (36) Nutraceutical (181) Oil&amp;Fat (37) Packaged Food (190) Snack (54) Soft Drinks (445) Tea and Coffee (128) 
 
 Market Research Report 
On-the-Go Eating: Consumer Mindsets, Menu Trends, and Product/Packaging Innovation

 Published by Packaged Facts Published July, 2005 Product code 31099 Content info 150 pages Price Not Available 
 
 
 Introduction Related Reports 
 
This publication has been discontinued on July 19, 2011.
 
 Introduction 

Abstract

Current consumer trends bode well for companies able to develop healthy foods that taste good,
are good for you, and are also good for eating on-the-go. Only 60% of all meals today are prepared
and eaten in the home, largely because the increasing number of two-working-parent and single-parent
households means less time to cook. At the same time, Americans are taking a more balanced approach
to eating on-the-go, realizing the need to combine convenience with healthier fare. Simmons Market
Research Bureau data show that over half of adults (51%) like the trend toward healthier eating, and
this trend--combined with tremendous consumer demand for convenience and the desire for more
flavorful foods, including premium and gourmet offerings--is driving foodservice and retail sales
across many breakfast, lunch, dinner, and snack food categories in many retail and foodservice
venues.

Eating on the Go: Consumer Mindsets, Menu Trends, and Product/Packaging Innovation, an all-new
Packaged Facts report examines trends in convenient and hand-held foods in quick-service and
fast-casual restaurants, mass-market food retailers, and alternative channels such as convenience
stores and vending. Key trends covered include the steadily growing demand for gourmet sandwiches in
foodservice channels and their untapped market potential in supermarkets, convenience stores, and
other mass-market retailers; the impact that litigation and new and proposed legislation is having
on food producers and marketers; and the increasing focus on combating obesity and related illnesses
in the United States via healthier fare, including among kids. Drawing on diverse consumer attitude,
consumer purchasing, sales-tracking, and new product data, this report delineates current and
potential demographic markets, identifies strategies for new products and packaging, and profiles
leading players in each channel including Subway, Applebees, Panera Breads, Quiznos, H.E. Butt
Grocery, Wegmans, 7-Eleven, Sheetz, Canteen Vending Services, and many others.

Report Methodology

The information in Eating on the Go: Consumer Mindsets, Menu Trends, and Product/Packaging
Innovation is based on both primary and secondary research. Primary research involved on-site
examination of the retail milieu, interviews with marketing, public relations and industry analysts
within the food market and consultants to the industry. Market size data was derived from
Information Resources, Inc. Secondary research entailed data-gathering from relevant trade,
business, and government sources, including company literature. New product information is gathered
via literature research, personal interviews and data compiled by ProductScan, a service of
Marketing Intelligence Service Ltd. Consumer information was derived from Simmons Market Research
Bureau, fall 2004 National Consumer Survey.

What Youll Get in this Report

Eating on the Go: Consumer Mindsets, Menu Trends, and Product/Packaging Innovation makes
important predictions and recommendations regarding the future of this market, and pinpoints ways
current and prospective marketers can capitalize on current trends and spearhead new ones. No other
market research report provides both the comprehensive analysis and extensive data that Eating on
the Go: Consumer Mindsets, Menu Trends, and Product/Packaging Innovation offers. The report
addresses the following segments:

 The Market (including market size and composition, and projected market growth) The Competitors Competitive Profiles (of the mainstream competitors, specialists and up-and-coming niche
players, and analyses of the products they market) Retail Strategies The Consumer (whos buying what, and where) The Products Trends and Opportunities

Plus, youll benefit from extensive data, presented in easy-to-read and practical charts, tables
and graphs.

How You Will Benefit from this Report

If your company wants to understand the new, on-the-go eating paradigm of todays consumer, you
will find this report invaluable, as it provides a comprehensive package of information and insight
not offered in any other single source. You will gain a thorough understanding of the current market
for on-the-go foods, as well as projected sales and trends through 2009. Contributing to that
understanding will be a complete analysis of sales data, and a detailed discussion of the consumer
based on Simmons data.

This report will help:

 Marketing Managers identify market opportunities and develop targeted promotion plans for
on-the-go foods and beverages. Research and development professionals stay on top of competitor initiatives and explore demand
for portable food and beverages. Advertising agenciesworking with clients in the food industry understand the product buyer to
develop messages and images that compel consumers to purchase these products. Business development executives understand the dynamics of the market and identify possible
partnerships. Information and research center librarians provide market researchers, brand and product
managers and other colleagues with the vital information they need to do their jobs more
effectively.

Table of Contents

Chapter 1: Executive Summary

Scope and Methodology Scope of Report Report Methodology Healthy and On-the-Go Eating Trends
Among U.S. Consumers The Driving Trends: Convenience and Health Less Time for Food Preparation
Figure 1-1: Consumer Attitudes About Healthy Foods vs. Time Constraints, 2004 (U.S. adults) Consumer
Demographics by Meal Occasion Meals vs. Snacks Time In Cars Increases Quick-Service and Fast-Casual
Dining Restaurants The Market Landscape Fast-Food and Family Restaurant Consumer Demographics
Drive-Through vs. Curbside Appeal Nutrition Trends and Menu Offerings Low-Carb Craze Waning; General
Health Concerns Rising The&quot;Anti-Health&quot;Backlash Food Stores and Supercenters Shifting
Demographics Reshaping American Shopping and Eating Patterns Less Time in the Kitchen Eating In with
Takeout Eating on the Road Convenience as a Consumer Value Supercenters Gaining Ground Healthier
Packaged Snacks on the Rise Alternative Channels Convenience Stores Broadening Their Appeal
Drugstores: Room to Grow Vending Trends Looking Ahead Trends and Opportunities Table 1-1: Projected
Population of the United States by Age, Sex, and Race/Ethnicity, 2000-2010 (in thousands)

Chapter 2: Healthy and On-the-Go Eating Trends Among U.S. Consumers

 The Driving Trends: Convenience and Health Less Time for Food Preparation Figure 2-1: Consumer Attitudes About Healthy Foods vs. Time Constraints, 2004 (U.S. adults) Consumer Demographics by Meal Occasion Meals vs. Snacks Commuting: Time In Cars Increases Convenience as a Consumer Value Trends in Healthy Eating Low-Carbs Future Is Critical Question Consumers Focus on General Health Better Health Through Portion Control The Trans-Fat Front The Revised Food Pyramid Threat of Litigation, Legislation Driving Change Rising Interest in Ethnic Foods Trend Overview by Channel Foodservice Food Stores Alternative Channels Variations in Consumer Attitudes About Eating by Retail Channel Table 2-1: Shopper Indices by Retail Channel for Agreement with Statement: Try to Eat Healthier
Foods These Days, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 2-2: Shopper Indices by Retail Channel for Agreement with Statement: Like Trend Toward
Healthier Fast Food, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 2-3: Shopper Indices by Retail Channel for Agreement with Statement: Dont Have Time to
Prepare/Eat Healthy Meals, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 2-4: Shopper Indices by Retail Channel for Agreement with Statement: Fast Food Fits My
Busy Lifestyle, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 2-5: Shopper Indices by Retail Channel for Agreement with Statement: Rarely Sit Down to a
Meal Together at Home, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 2-6: Shopper Indices by Retail Channel for Agreement with Statement: Often Eat Store-Made,
Pre-Cooked Meals, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 2-7: Demographic Indices by Meal-Time Attitudes, 2004 (U.S. adults)

Chapter 3: Quick-Service and Fast-Casual Dining Restaurants

 Trend Overview The Market Landscape Fast-Food and Family Restaurant Consumer Demographics Restaurant Trends by Meal Breakfast: Meeting the In-Home Challenge Lunch:&quot;Desktop Dining&quot;Increasingly Common Dinner: Wooing the Late-Night Diner Table 3-1: Fast-Food Restaurant User Demographics, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 3-2: Family Restaurant User Demographics, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 3-3: Fast-Food Restaurant Usage Indexes: Overall, by Companion, and by Meal
Occasion/Companion, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 3-4: Family Restaurant Usage Indexes: Overall, by Companion, and by Meal
Occasion/Companion, 2004 (U.S. adults)

 Keeping It Moving
 Drive-Through vs. Curbside Appeal Sandwiches Are Tops Expanding Portable Sandwich Options Burgers Remain a Mainstay
 Making It Healthy
 Nutrition Trends and Menu Offerings Legal and Regulatory Trends Lawsuits Tarnish the Golden Arches Low-Carb Craze Waning; General Health Concerns Rising he&quot;Anti-Health&quot;Backlash Table 3-5: Demographics for Adults Who Agree with Statement: Like Trend Toward Healthier Fast
Food, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 3-6: Fast-Food Usage Overview Among Adults Who Agree with Statement: Like Trend Toward
Healthier Fast Food, 2004 (U.S. adult fast-food consumers) Table 3-7: Fast-Food Usage by Chain Among Adults Who Agree with Statement: Like Trend Toward
Healthier Fast Food, 2004 (U.S. adults)
 Beyond the Basics
 The Decline of the Value Meal Customer Satisfaction, Healthier Choices, and Premium Items Drive Sales Targeting Women with Health and Convenience
 Competitive Profiles
 Applebees: Convenience, Healthy Choices, and Curb Appeal Boston Market: Home Meal Takeout Specialist McDonalds: More Healthy Eating Options Moes Southwestern Grill: Menu Appeals to Health-Conscious Panera Bread: Healthy Gourmet Focus Drives Sales Quiznos: Healthy Food Made Fresh To Go Schlotzskys: Heart-Healthy and Hot Sandwiches Subway: New Menu Choices Wendys: Entree Salads and Fresh Fruit


Chapter 4: Food Stores and Supercenters

 Trend Overview Shifting Demographics Reshaping American Shopping and Eating Patterns Less Time in the Kitchen Eating In with Takeout Eating on the Road Convenience as a Consumer Value

 Supermarkets/Food Stores vs. Mass Merchandisers/Supercenters
 Supercenters Gaining Ground Supermarket/Food Store Trends Shopper Demographics Supermarket Shopper Attitudes Toward Convenience Foods and Healthy Eating Building Up Takeout Trend Profile: H.E. Butt Trend Profile: Harris Teeter Trend Profile: Wegmans Mass-Merchandiser/Supercenter Trends Shopper Demographics Trend Profile: Wal-Mart Stores, Inc. Portable Private-Label Growing Competition from Alternative Channels Looking to Restaurants for Inspiration Table 4-1: Monthly Shopping Trip Patterns by Retail Channel: Supermarkets/Food Stores vs. Mass
Merchandisers/Supercenters, 2004 (U.S. adults in millions) Table 4-2: Supermarket/Food Store Shopper Demographics, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 4-3: Mass Merchandiser/Supercenter Shopper Demographics, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 4-4: Shopper Indices by Retail Channel for Agreement with Statement: Try to Eat Healthier
Foods These Days, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 4-5: Shopper Indices by Retail Channel for Agreement with Statement: Often Eat Store-Made,
Pre-Cooked Meals, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 4-6: Shopper Indices by Retail Channel for Agreement with Statement: Fast Food Fits Busy
Lifestyle, 2004 (U.S. adults)
 In-Store Trends
 Healthier Packaged Snacks on the Rise On-the-Go Across Categories Healthier, Portable Breakfast Foods Yogurt/Yogurt Drinks Riding the Wave Sandwiches: An Untapped Market The Soup Connection Hand-Held Meat Snacks Coming on Strong Deli Foods To-Go: Freshness/Packaging Is Key Value-Added Vegetables and Fruits The Fresh Fruit Challenge Beverages to Go Natural/Organic On the Rise Table 4-7: Usage Rates for Selected On-the-Go Food Products, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 4-8: IRI-Tracked Sales of Selected Packaged Food Products: Snack Bars/Granola Bars,
2000-2004 (in millions of dollars) Table 4-9: IRI-Tracked Sales of Selected Packaged Food Products: Frozen Breakfast Entrees,
2000-2004 (in millions of dollars) Table 4-10: IRI-Tracked Sales of Selected Packaged Food Products: Instant Breakfast, 2000-2004
(in millions of dollars) Table 4-11: IRI-Tracked Sales of Selected Packaged Food Products: Refrigerated Yogurt//Yogurt
Drinks, 2000-2004 (in millions of dollars) Table 4-12: IRI-Tracked Sales of Selected Packaged Food Products: Frozen Hand-Held Entrees
(Non-Breakfast), 2000-2004 (in millions of dollars) Table 4-13: IRI-Tracked Sales of Selected Packaged Food Products: Ready-to Serve Wet Soup and
Ramen/Dry Soup, 2000-2004 (in millions of dollars) Table 4-14: IRI-Tracked Sales of Selected Packaged Food Products: Dried Meat Snacks, 2000-2004
(in millions of dollars) Table 4-15: IRI-Tracked Sales of Selected Packaged Food Products: Fresh-Cut Salad, 2000-2004 (in
millions of dollars)
 Package Types and Trends
 Rigid Packaging Portable Cups Squeezable Tubes Aseptic Packages Stand-Up and Retort Pouches Resealable and Easy-Open Packaging Portion Control and Serving Sizes Ergonomic and Burn-Proof Packaging


Chapter 5: Alternative Channels

 Convenience Stores Trend Overview: Broadening the Appeal Convenience Store Shopper Demographics Snack Market Stronger than Ever Portability Rules Healthy Eating Trends a Mixed Bag Growth Potential: Lunch and Dinner Trend Profile: 7-Eleven Trend Profile: Sheetz, Inc. Table 5-1: Convenience Store Shopper Demographics, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 5-2: Convenience Store Shoppers: Usage Rates and Indices for Selected On-the-Go Food
Products, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 5-3: Convenience Store Shopper Indices for Agreement with Selected Lifestyle- and
Food-Related Statements, 2004 (U.S. adults)

 Drugstores
 Room to Grow Drugstore Shopper Demographics Trends in Packaged Foods Emphasizing Health and Convenience Table 5-4: Monthly Shopping Trip Patterns by Retail Channel: Drugstores, 2004 (U.S. adults in
millions) Table 5-5: Drugstore Shopper Demographics, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 5-6: Drugstore Shopper Indices for Agreement with Selected Lifestyle- and Food-Related
Statements, 2004 (U.S. adults) Table 5-7: Drugstore Shoppers: Indices for Selected On-the-Go Food Products, 2004 (U.S. adults)
 Vending
 Trend Overview Marketing and Product Trends Sodas and Snacks Still Out Front More Healthy Fresh Food Options Hot and Cold Alternatives More Diverse Customers Laws Prompt Healthy Vending in Schools Staying Ahead of the Courts Making it Healthy College Vending and Foodservice Trend Profile: Canteen Vending Services


Chapter 6: Looking Ahead

 Spotlight on Health and Convenience Beyond&quot;All in the Family&quot; Growing Ethnic Diversity Impact of Revised Dietary Guidelines Functional Foods to Address Key Health Concerns Segregation vs. Integration of Organic Products Packaging Trends Dollar Store Potential Table 6-1: Projected Population of the United States by Age, Sex, and Race/Ethnicity, 2000-2010
(in thousands)

Appendix: Addresses of Selected Marketers
 
 Related Reports 
 
 Snack Report 

 
 Consumer and Innovation Trends in Cereal Products Published : May, 2012 Price : US $ 3450 
 
 
 Mealtime and Snacking Trends in Australia Published : April, 2012 Price : US $ 3450 
 
 
 Consumer Trends in the Bakery&amp;Cereals Market in France Published : April, 2012 Price : US $ 7495 
 
 
 
 Food Market Report by Packaged Facts 

 
 Food and Beverage Packaging Trends in the U.S.: Consumer Viewpoints and Marketer Opportunities Published : June, 2012 Price : US $ 3500 
 
 
 Chocolate Candy in the U.S., 9th Edition Published : May, 2012 Price : US $ 3750 
 
 
 Ice Cream and Frozen Desserts in the U.S.: Markets and Opportunities in Retail and Foodservice; 7th Edition Published : April, 2012 Price : US $ 3750 
 
 
 Notify me when related publications are released 
 Introduction Related Reports 
 
 

 User Guide About Us Policies Site Map Int&apos;l: +1-860-674-8796 US: +1-866-353-3335 (Toll Free) | EU: +32-2-535-7543 The Vertical Markets Research Portal
©Copyright 1997-2012, Global Information, Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
