<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009733" url="http://newlife919blog.blogs.com/new_life_919_blog/" time="2012-07-13-03:08" support="12" score="0.01566433027580599" bingtitle="New Life&apos;n" webtitle="New Life&apos;n">
			<query id="001433" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="001151" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="000741" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="000366" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000428" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000179" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000398" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="001465" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000459" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="001024" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000679" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000304" bing-rank="119"/>
	<description>You have to leave the bathroom with your cup. Great, I ... wife is standing next to a booth at the fast food restaurant. ... Adjust, tweak, rearrange, change the diaper. If ...</description>
	<body>
		New Life&apos;n 


 

 
 
 
The school I trusted with my kids...
 
 
 
 
Recent Posts
 
 &quot;I&apos;d be a horrible God&quot; Your energy as a compass Want to help me put a little dent in discouragement? Clueless doggie Chill. And run. What if they&apos;re NOT Martians? Do you argue with people in your head? The mean man with the scissors This isn&apos;t about being skinny &apos;Scary Hope&apos; is now on Kindle 
 
 Archives 
 
 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 July 2011 

 More... 
 Blog powered by TypePad Subscribe to this blog&apos;s feed 
 &quot;I&apos;d be a horrible God&quot; 
 
My daughter said that a few days ago. I&apos;m still thinking about it.

&quot;I&apos;d be mad at everyone all the time,&quot;she said.&quot;Especially at people like me.&quot;

My wife agreed.&quot;I&apos;d be shaking people by the shoulders right and left. You&apos;d walk down the street and see people shaking.&quot;

But God doesn&apos;t seem to be mad at everyone and we don&apos;t see people shaking.

Is he just holding back? Maybe he&apos;s really mad inside and is gritting his teeth to keep from showing it.

Or maybe one of the things that makes him God is the ability to be completely right all the time and yet patiently tolerate people who seem so completely wrong. It takes strength to not do something that you have the power and right to do.

But why be tolerant? And why use your strength to not do what you could?

 Love? 

One time I was frustrated and carelessly broke some new juice glasses my wife had just bought. She didn&apos;t get mad. It was like she didn&apos;t even have to try to not be mad. It was weird. And very powerful.

It didn&apos;t make me want to break more juice glasses. It made me want to love her back.
 
 Posted by Gary on Thursday, June 21, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (3) 
 
 Your energy as a compass 
 
Energy is like income, a checkbook, your IQ. You don&apos;t have the same as everyone else, and you&apos;re not supposed to.

And you have different energies available for different things.

Using up energy causes stress if you end up with less energy than you need. Then stress uses up more energy. Then you experience more stress because you have less energy. It&apos;s a circle. 

 God may give you less energy in some areas so that you won&apos;t focus on areas where he doesn&apos;t want you. 

If you do mis-focus, you run out of gas to force you back to where you should be.

You know those times when you&apos;re going hard but you&apos;re not tired and you feel like you could go on forever?

Maybe that&apos;s your true north.
 
 Posted by Gary on Monday, June 04, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (0) 
 
 Want to help me put a little dent in discouragement? 
 
I&apos;m looking for a few readers for&quot;From Beer to Eternity,&quot;a Kindle ebook of how a life can change radically. That life was mine, and by the way, I think everyone should write their story.

This is a little backwards -- usually you ask for readers before the writing is done, to get feedback to make it better, and I&apos;ll probably do that in the future.

In this case the ebook is already written and edited. It&apos;s an update, expansion, and refinement of the link on the sidebar on the right.

I&apos;m looking for feedback that I can use in the book description on Amazon, so when potential readers see the book they immediately see what others think.

 Your words could influence someone to get the ebook and read it and then who knows what might happen. I know what happened with me and it changed my life. You could be a small part of that with someone else. 

You don&apos;t have to write a review on Amazon -- it&apos;s not there yet (but I&apos;d love for you to do that when it gets there!). Just send me an honest review of what you read. I&apos;ll pick a few words to include on the book page. No promises that I&apos;ll use yours, but know I&apos;ll read it and it will help.

You don&apos;t have to say something good, but I&apos;m obviously going to pick good ones (if I get any) for the book page because, you know, I want people to read the book!

It might be more interesting to you if you&apos;re familiar with addiction, either your own or someone you care about. You can read it in an hour or less.

I&apos;ll send you a simple PDF of the ebook. That doesn&apos;t mean you&apos;re committed -- you don&apos;t have to do anything, and I won&apos;t follow up with you. Just write a review if you want to.

If you want the free PDF and know darn well you won&apos;t write a review, that&apos;s great too -- I&apos;d love for you to read it. Just ask and don&apos;t feel guilty. And feel free to pass it on to anyone you want.

You can request the PDF by emailing me at garysmorland-at-gmail-dot-com. Then if you write a review, just send it to the same email. I thank you, and future encouraged addicts and their families and friends thank you.

-----

(You can also get &quot;Scary Hope: Courage and a kick to hug hope, face fear, and get going&quot; on Kindle now for 99-cents. Read it all in 75 minutes and be encouraged)
 
 Posted by Gary on Thursday, May 31, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (0) 
 
 Clueless doggie 
 
 

Doesn&apos;t she know when she tugs and strains and pulls on the leash it just makes me shorten the leash and give her less freedom?

She insists on stopping to sniff. She insists on going the other way. She insists on being in charge of our walk.

The insisting is what I react to.

 The more you insist, and the more independent you are, the less freedom you get 

On other occasions she pauses and looks up at me and I know she&apos;s asking to slow down or go this way. I don&apos;t mind that. I kind of like it. She respects me and knows she needs my permission. That&apos;s good. Makes me feel close to her. Often my reaction is, &quot;Sure, friend, we can go that way . . .&quot; 

But bullheadedness and independence--as if it doesn&apos;t matter what I want--I hate that. I fight her over that. I&apos;ll bet she thinks I&apos;m unreasonable and against her.

It&apos;s amazing how much freedom I give her when I can trust her to stick with me and respect my will.

 Does God ever seem unreasonable and against you? 

Maybe you’re getting the short leash.
 
 Posted by Gary on Monday, May 28, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (3) 
 
 Chill. And run. 
 
You are a created thing. You didn&apos;t make yourself up. You&apos;re not your own idea.

Your maker knows how he made you. He knows your strengths, your weaknesses, your pace, your abilities, your potential, your limits. Did you ever think that maybe he did it on purpose? All of it?

He knows the level of your ability to deal with life depending on yourself (your natural ability), and depending on him (your supernatural ability). Did you ever think that he limited your ability so he could make up the difference?

He engineered placing you in your family, with those parents and siblings, or without any of them. And he engineered your school and friends and job and marriage, or the lack of them. He&apos;s overseen, or permitted, all your experiences and circumstances. 

He created time, and how it moves, and how much there is. Weeks, days, hours, and minutes are the same for everyone. He knows what&apos;s available to you today for any moment, for any project, for your life. He knows every interruption and glitch.

He knows the assignment he&apos;s given you and what it&apos;s for. He knows everything involved and needed to do it. He knows it&apos;s YOUR assignment, and he gave it fully aware of you and the time available.

Knowing all this, what&apos;s the stress? Where&apos;s that come from? Chill.

And why are you letting discouragement drag you down? Run.
 
 Posted by Gary on Tuesday, May 22, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (5) 
 
 What if they&apos;re NOT Martians? 
 
Say you&apos;re attacked by Martians. They&apos;re little green men, they&apos;re acting aggressively, and there&apos;s a large red&quot;M&quot;on the side of their spaceship.

It would be normal for you to defend yourself.

You&apos;ve seen War of the Worlds. So you fight. And you lose. Or maybe you win and go&quot;whew!&quot;

Later, amidst the carnage of battle, you discover they aren&apos;t Martians at all. They&apos;re from the planet Maloomba.

And that aggressive behavior you observed was not aggressiveness -- it&apos;s normal conduct on their planet as they go about daily life. What looked like weapons are tools they use to survive and do their work. To them, you attacked first.

 Oops 

They aren&apos;t for you, they aren&apos;t against you. They&apos;re just being who they are.

 But you didn&apos;t know any of that 

Until now.

You only had your own limited judgment, perspective, and experience. And you put total confidence in it.

You&apos;ll react differently the next time little green men in a spaceship with an&quot;M&quot;on the side appear. Your perspective has changed.

And if little BLUE men in a spaceship with a&quot;Q&quot;on it show up, you&apos;ll react different. You&apos;ll be cautious for yourself, but you&apos;ll also be cautious about jumping to conclusions.

 Perspective matters 

Choose yours with patience and humility. Get all the help you can to make sure you know what you&apos;re seeing.

Save your energy for the real battles. There will always be plenty.
 
 Posted by Gary on Friday, May 18, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (1) 
 
 Do you argue with people in your head? 
 
I do it often. Maybe not arguing as much as talking.

Almost always it&apos;s when I&apos;m trying to understand where someone is coming from or convince them of something that I think they just don&apos;t get.

I think it&apos;s normal. It&apos;s part of your effort to understand it all yourself, to sort it out. It&apos;s like sifting -- you want to separate the big rocks from the little rocks and the sand. It takes time.

 You can go too far with this 

When I find myself repeating the same things over and over in my head, having the same conversation, making the same arguments, I know I&apos;m crossing over to the dark side.

 The dark side of control 

&quot;If I just think hard enough, talk to myself enough, work hard enough, I&apos;ll be able to make this thing I&apos;m dealing with turn out the way I think it should. I&apos;ll understand. They&apos;ll understand. And I&apos;ll have peace.&quot;

 Baloney 

Those faux conversations are useful up to a point. They help you gain some perspective and insight, and they help you rehearse a real conversation. All good.

Problem is, it&apos;s NOT a real conversation. It&apos;s all just you.

You&apos;re imagining what the other person is thinking and saying. You&apos;re making it up! You don&apos;t really know!

And for me, I subtly transfer trust for the results away from God and to my own powers of logic and persuasion. 

When that conversation in your head starts repeating itself, that&apos;s the sign to

 stop. 

 And trust 
 
 Posted by Gary on Thursday, May 10, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (3) 
 
 The mean man with the scissors 
 
 

Three years ago I planted three knockout rose bushes under the front window.

They grew and bloomed right away. But they didn&apos;t get thick and bushy like I wanted and like I knew they could.

I don&apos;t want thin, scraggly knockouts. Maybe I planted them too close to the house. Maybe they don&apos;t get enough sun. They seem happy enough just to survive and show a few flowers.

But I&apos;m not happy.

So I cut them back in March. Hard. Right when they were starting to bud. Cut them back to about a foot above the ground. I think it made them mad.

I heard them complaining:&quot;What&apos;s up with that? You want flowers and now you&apos;re cutting them off?&quot;

They recovered quick. Six weeks later, more buds. But still spindly.

I cut them off again. Not as hard this time. Just shaped them some.

 Do you ever feel like someone&apos;s against you? 

&quot;This guy doesn&apos;t love us. This guy doesn&apos;t know what he&apos;s doing. This guy says he wants one thing and then he cuts off the thing he says he wants. You can&apos;t trust this guy. We&apos;re working our tails off here!&quot;

But I do know what I want. I know what I see now and in the future. I know what I want these plants to become in this spot. It might not be what they expect. If I have to cut off what they&apos;ve worked for and start over, I will. I chose these plants on purpose for this spot and I won&apos;t give up.

They don&apos;t know any of this. They think it&apos;s all about making flowers now and being like all the other knockouts even though their conditions are different. They just want to be left alone.

If they could pull themselves up and walk off, they would.

They can&apos;t.

 But you can. 

You can leave the job, leave the relationship, find a new church, give up the goal and the dream. You can look for ways to end the frustration of always getting cut off, always starting over. Haven&apos;t you done enough?

It feels mean. It feels like punishment. It feels like you&apos;ve been forgotten and someone doesn&apos;t care.

 It&apos;s pruning 

It&apos;s love.
 
 Posted by Gary on Monday, May 07, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (0) 
 
 This isn&apos;t about being skinny 
 
I tell my wife she looks skinny.

She tells me to shut up.

I say,&quot;Here, let me take a picture.&quot;She&apos;s standing in the kitchen.

I take the picture with my phone. She looks at it and goes,&quot;You did that with an app. You have a skinny app.&quot;

I know I have her now.

I say,&quot;Here, take my picture and see if it looks like me.&quot;

She takes my picture. It looks like me.

I say,&quot;So see, it&apos;s true, that&apos;s what you look like.&quot;

 What do you refuse to believe about yourself? 

 Just because you&apos;ve repeated something to yourself for years (good or bad) doesn&apos;t make it true. 

Brutal reality has two sides. We usually major on facing one or the other.

 Face both. 

One side is that you ain&apos;t all that.

The other side is that inside you is the drive to create, contribute, connect, and leave a mark. But in a way that looks just like you.

 It&apos;s hard to embrace your calling if you refuse to accept your gifting. 
 
 Posted by Gary on Friday, May 04, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (5) 
 
 &apos;Scary Hope&apos; is now on Kindle 
 
For 99 cents. But just so you know, it will also be free on Kindle a few times in the near future. (You can only give eBooks away on Amazon in doses.)

You can read it all in 75 minutes and find courage and a kick to hug hope, face fear, and get going.

 Why might Scary Hope be for you or someone you care about? 

Because you&apos;re not here to live a disconnected, depressed, non-contributing, helpless, excuse-filled, humdrum life. That&apos;s hopelessness. 

Because inside you is the drive to create, contribute, connect, and leave a mark. That&apos;s hope. 

Because we all need stories that encourage and challenge us so that we&apos;ll acknowledge that drive within and cooperate with it. But that&apos;s scary. 

 If you&apos;re doubting, stuck, or hoping for you-don&apos;t-know-what, then this is for you. 

 Scary Hope started as&quot;31 Days of Scary Hope&quot;on this blog last October. The free PDF had over 1000 readers but is now disabled in order to be part of the Kindle Select program which requires exclusivity.

 Click HERE to get Scary Hope on your Kindle 

You can also read it on the Kindle app for your phone, PC, or Mac.

If Scary Hope is new to you, click HERE to see a summary and excerpts (that might be enough for you). You&apos;ll even find a few videos and links to stories that were not able to be in the PDF or Kindle versions. Or send a friend there if you think it will help them.
 
 Posted by Gary on Sunday, April 29, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (0) 
 
 A message for artists and dreamers from a 9-year old 
 
Caine is a 9-year old boy who created a wonderful cardboard arcade inside his dad&apos;s used auto parts store.

It&apos;s awesome, in a kid kind of way. But no one shows up to play.

One day he gets a visitor who makes a video and organizes a flashmob and Caine ends up with the greatest day of his life and a $200,000 college scholarship fund.

 

Even 9-year olds know what all artists and dreamers know:

 You do it because you love it and you&apos;re convinced how it should be done 

You do it for yourself. Caine smiles and gets joy just from the doing.

 BUT -- the thing you do is done FOR others 

It&apos;s a thing that exists FOR people. It&apos;s incomplete without people coming to it and using it. So it&apos;s for them, but you can&apos;t do it for them; you have to do it for yourself (yes it&apos;s weird).

 The joy is the work, but it&apos;s incomplete until the people come 

Caine gets joy out of creating but expects people to engage his dream. He waits for them.

 At some point you need help 

You need a gallery or employees or cash or an editor or a horse trainer or a stage or people who know how to do techy things. Or a guy with a video camera who shows up serendipitously.

You may not know both the WHAT to do and the HOW to get to the people. Caine knows the&apos;what&apos;but doesn&apos;t know how to get the people to his&apos;what.&apos;

 When the people DO come, it feels normal 

It doesn&apos;t feel like a&quot;Makeover&quot;reveal moment of melting joy. It&apos;s very satisfying--yes joyful--but NORMAL. Because this is what&apos;s supposed to happen. You didn&apos;t do it for this reason but this needs to happen for it to be complete.

Caine smiles and is happy at the crowds, but he doesn&apos;t seem shocked. He&apos;s not as surprised as you might anticipate. As if he EXPECTS people to be there because of course they&apos;ll be there. If they&apos;re not, you&apos;re not done.
 
 At times it makes me quite melancholy that the result is always&quot;unsaleable.&quot;Work in spite of all indifference is not easy to keep up, but what is easy isn&apos;t worth much. -- Vincent Van Gogh
 
 Posted by Gary on Thursday, April 26, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (2) 
 
 I just noticed two age spots on my hands 
 
When we were teenagers&quot;bombing around&quot;(that&apos;s what we called it) with our friends, my brother sometimes yelled out the car window at senior citizens,&quot;Hey you old bag! You oughta be dead!&quot;Then he&apos;d laugh. He thought he was hilarious.

Today he&apos;s really a good guy. Back then, like all teens, his brain was not fully formed yet.

When you&apos;re growing up it&apos;s easy to think you&apos;re on a different road than your parents, a different road than&quot;old people.&quot;

 It&apos;s the same r oad 

Parents and others are just farther down that same road than you. And the farther you go, the more people there are behind you; people who think they&apos;re on a different road.

 Somewhere along the road you realize this. 

That&apos;s when the catharsis begins. The confrontation with the brutal reality that you&apos;re not an exception. For some it&apos;s too much--you keep the look, the clothes, the hair style. Or you adopt the look, the clothes, the style of those now at the age you refuse to leave behind.

 Everybody sees the comb-over but you 

Best to embrace this road we&apos;re all on.

Do not despise the era and generation in which the Lord has chosen to give you influence. It&apos;s on purpose. You&apos;ll not pass this way again.
 
 Posted by Gary on Tuesday, April 17, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (1) 
 
 The only score you keep in marriage 
 
is what you owe them.

And if you think you&apos;ve got them paid back? Check the numbers again.
 
 Posted by Gary on Friday, February 17, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (2) 
 
 Everybody carries a pee cup 
 
 

The nurse steered me into the bathroom and handed me the plastic cup.

“When you get done, put it in the little door over there.”

‘Over there’ was on the wall across the hall from the bathroom. You have to leave the bathroom with your cup.

Great, I just know that as soon as I get done and open the bathroom door, that waiting room door is going to open and the nurse will walk into the hall with someone else and I’ll be standing here with a cup of pee.

 That’s exactly what happened 

Before I opened the door, I even listened closely for a second to see if all was quiet in the hall. It was. And as soon as I opened the door, the waiting room door opened and we all almost bumped into each other.

“Excuse me,” I said, and we did the awkward “No you go ahead” dance. I almost said, “Hi! This is my pee! That came from inside me! You know, that no one EVER SEES! Until now.”

I didn’t say that. But it’s what I felt. Exposed. Like a big flashing yellow neon arrow was pointing at the cup in my hand.

 Then… 

I noticed the new patient in the hall had her empty cup in her hand. She was next in the bathroom.

 I wasn’t alone. 

Every patient in that office—dozens a day—listens at the bathroom door and then walks out into public holding their pee in their hand. And feels alone but isn’t.

Isn’t that how it is?

You try to hide the ‘private’ stuff, the stuff that’s so personal you just know no one else has this, does this, knows this, feels this, experiences this, thinks this, or had this happen to them.

 And then for a second you stop thinking of yourself and look down and you see they’re holding a cup of pee too. 

You’re so busy walking around trying to hide it that you don’t realize everyone else is trying to hide theirs.

 We all just need to fess up 

“Hi, this is my stuff I don’t want anyone to see. I see you have yours too. Now can we just move on and stop pretending we can hide?”

Pretending and hiding takes a lot of energy that could go towards other more fun, beneficial things.

You can spread a lot of encouragement with the energy you save by not worrying about hiding what everyone knows anyway.

 You’re not alone 

I’ll give you grace and you give me grace. I won’t point and laugh at your pee and you don’t laugh at mine.

Now let’s go have a Mountain Dew.

------

 Get Scary Hope: Courage and a kick to hug hope, face fear, and get going on Kindle now for just 99 cents. 
 
 Posted by Gary on Tuesday, February 14, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (9) 
 
 What if you knew... 
 
 that 

 with the measure you use it will be measured to you 

That in the end, somehow, it all balances out, actually more than balances, and in the end you get back more than you give.

 What if you knew that was true? 

In every area you can think of.

I’m not saying it is. But what if it is?

Be generous with time and you get more time (how does that work?).

 Forgive and you get forgiven.

Give the benefit of the doubt and people give it to you.

Get mad at drivers in traffic and they get mad a you.

Give mercy and you get it.

 Trust and you’re trusted.

 Blame and be blamed.

 Resent and be resented.

Be kind , patient , encouraging – ditto.

 Unloved ? You know what to do.

Oh yeah, and money . And tips at restaurants.

 If you knew it was true in all areas, that with the measure you use it will be measured to you, 

 would you do anything different today? 

 --------- 
 
 As you wish that others would do to you, so do to them… 

 Love your enemies, and do good, and lend, expecting nothing in return, and your reward will be great… 

 Judge not, and you will not be judged; condemn not and you will not be condemned; forgive and you will be forgiven; give and it will be given to you. Good measure, pressed down, shaken together, running over, will be put into your lap. For with the measure you use it will be measured to you. -- Luke 6.27-38
 
 Posted by Gary on Sunday, February 12, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (0) 
 
 Expect the basement 
 
 

Sooner or later you always get to the basement, in every relationship, family, workplace, organization, neighborhood, church.

The basement is not where the bodies are. It’s not where the bad stuff is.

 The basement is where you see the stuff you don’t like 

 It’s where the sausage is made. It’s the tangled underside of the quilt you love. 

It’s the first argument where you realize that new special person doesn’t really play fair. And they think the same of you.

It’s underwear on the floor and the toilet seat up, but to them it’s you griping about normal stuff like underwear on the floor and toilet seats up. All multiplied times a thousand.

It’s HR polices, decisions that seem silly, lack of appreciation, misunderstandings, quirky bosses, and ‘personalities.’ 

It’s the pastor’s long stories, the style of music, the ministries they emphasize, the ministries they don’t emphasize, offenses all around, and ‘it shouldn’t be this way, this is church.’

 The basement is different for everybody 

The things you find in the basement are not the same things others find. Some see you in the basement. And you see them.

I think in any new thing, you can expect to see the basement within a year or two. Maybe three. The more involved you are, the sooner you find it. The longer you&apos;re there, the more you see.

At first everything is wonderful. Upstairs is bright and welcoming. The lights are on, the floors are swept, the dishes clean. This doesn’t mean it’s phony or fake; it’s just the way it is.

When you see the basement at the beginning, you leave, right? It&apos;s the reason you don&apos;t marry that person or take that job or go to that church. The lights aren&apos;t bright to you.

 So what do you do when you finally find the basement later? 

That, of course is up to you.

What is not up to you is whether or not the next person or place has a basement. They do, guaranteed.

 Expect the basement 

Expect that the nature of the basement is that you disagree with what’s there and don’t like it.

And expect the temptation to fool yourself that the next basement will for sure be better than this one.
 
 Posted by Gary on Monday, February 06, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (11) 
 
 &apos;You can&apos;t substitute comfort for calling&apos; 
 
 

A friend said that a month ago. I’m still thinking about it.

You hear those words and think about your job or your life direction, and you think you’ve got to make major changes because, you know, “calling” is such a massive, all-consuming idea.

 It is 

But

 What if your calling is 

to love, give grace, and be generous?

 What if your calling is 

to be committed to your marriage and family, and to put them ahead of your boss and your career?

 What if your calling is 

to kindness and forgiveness? With those people, you know, them .

These things are massive, too. As massive as career changes and callings into ‘the ministry.’

 These callings take work, initiative, energy, and sacrifice 

It’s not easy or comfortable to love and give grace. It’s not comfortable to be generous, kind, and forgiving. It’s not comfortable putting your family first and committing to their destiny and legacy.

But you can’t substitute comfort for calling.
 
 Posted by Gary on Thursday, February 02, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (0) 
 
 The incredibly awesome power of habit 
 
I am undisciplined.

I don’t have much will power.

I got guilt over routine things I think I should do and ways I think I should be.

Example: I read how Howard Hendricks, a wonderful godly man, would always wipe off the bathroom sink when he finished getting ready in the morning; even when he was on the road, in a hotel or at someone’s home.

I thought I should do that. But I never did.

Then one day I did. Used a wad of toilet paper on the sink and faucet right at the end of my morning routine. Took about 20 seconds. It felt good to see a clean sink when I turned the light off and left the bathroom. Was pretty satisfying. So I did it again the next day. And the next.

Today, six months later, I was in a big hurry, rushing, no time! Leaving the bathroom I glanced down at the sink. “Oooh, water.” Drops and puddles on the counter and faucet. I just had to wipe it off. “It’ll only take a second.”

It hit me: Awesome! I’ve changed!

I’m not the kind of guy to wipe down the bathroom sink every day. It’s just a habit.
 
 Posted by Gary on Friday, January 27, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (0) 
 
 One way to know you&apos;re on to something 
 
 

 How do you know if you’re on the right track? 

 When you’re on that track you’re full of energy for it 

Energy is like income, a checkbook, IQ. You don’t have the same as everyone else and you’re not supposed to. And you have different energies available for different things.

Using up your energy causes stress. And stress uses up energy – it’s a circle. Less is available for other things.

God may give you less energy in some areas than others, so that you won’t focus on areas where he doesn’t want you. If you do misfocus, you run out of gas to force you back to where you should be.

 There may be a reason why you feel like you have a full tank of gas  

 It’s so you’ll GO 

And if you’re tank feels empty it may be so you’ll stop.
 
 Posted by Gary on Wednesday, January 25, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (1) 
 
 Have you noticed? 
 
 

We’re getting about a half-hour more of daylight now than a month ago. That’s a half-hour less of dark.

When it’s been dark, SO DARK for SO LONG and it starts to turn around, you don’t notice it at first.

It can take awhile to realize.

Then one day you can’t miss it.

You’ll see.
 
 Posted by Gary on Sunday, January 22, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (1) 
 
 I went to Dealey Plaza 
 
 

But I don’t know why.

I was in Dallas anyway, and thought I should visit the place where Kennedy was shot. Why?

I had already been there twenty years ago. Saw everything. Why go again? I’m not interested in the Kennedys.

I was 12 when it happened. I remember the announcement in school, and that our family shopped for furniture the weekend of the funeral. My parents bought a round, green rug where I played with my dachshund Fritz, and where later my kids crawled when we visited grandma.

They kept that furniture until they died.

What does furniture and being 12 have to do with why I would want to go?

My wife Brenda says it’s just because it’s a big historic thing. I don’t know. We’ve visited a lot of big historic things. This seemed different.

At the Plaza, the few people there were almost loitering, standing around alone or in small groups. You expected an announcement: “C’mon people, it was almost 50 years ago! Nothing to see here…move on!”

It was like they were trying to figure something out, but couldn’t. Me too.

I thought maybe if I started writing this, I’d understand why I had to go.

Nope.
 
 Posted by Gary on Thursday, January 19, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (0) 
 
 That thing you want might be important. Here&apos;s why. 
 
 

We’re probably not talking about a car/house kind of thing. More meaningful than that.

 Imagine you just died 

and you’re in heaven engaged in a heavy duty conversation with God.

He’s showing you some things that didn’t happen in your life, some things that for some reason you didn’t do. Maybe a project, idea, vocation, relationship, ministry…something like that.

And you say, “That’s exactly what I really wanted!”

And he says, “I know.”

And you realize

 That thing you wanted was what he wanted, too 

That’s why you wanted it. He made you want it, so you would cooperate with him, trust him, and do it.

But you didn’t.

So now, after you wake from your Scrooge dream and find you’re still alive, what are you going to do?

Not believe it?

Be afraid?

Be lazy?

Avoid it?

Make excuses?

 The dream conversation could turn into a real one at any second. 
 
 Posted by Gary on Tuesday, January 17, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (3) 
 
 He coulda been a hero 
 
 

Guy’s wife is standing next to a booth at the fast food restaurant. He walks up with their bag of food and says, “I’d rather sit at a table.”

She pauses. “But, I’d really like a booth.” She looks at him.

This is the moment where heroes are made.

He looks away from her toward the table and starts walking. “Well, I’d really like a table.” He’s not mean. He just wants what he wants.

 Would you rather have a table or a happy wife? 

Put it another way: would you rather have a table or a wife who sees you as caring, unselfish, giving, and sacrificing.

 Just letting her sit where she wants will make her happy? 

She won’t add up the good all at once. She may not even notice that you gave her what she wanted. But if you repeat it, and it’s a lifestyle, she’ll feel honored, and in her heart you’ll get the credit.

When you get the credit, through her attitude of gratitude towards you, you’ll be happy. It will be a happiness that affects every part of your relationship together. It will be a happiness that you didn’t anticipate. A happiness that grows on you.

 And then something magical happens 

 You begin to feel selfish for being generous and selfless. 

You feel selfish because the good will you’re getting from your wife feels pretty good, and is worth more than what you gave up. You look for more chances to be selfless. The more you do it, the better she feels, and the better you feel.

The more you do it for her, the more she does it for you. Before you know it, your disagreements are about giving in, not getting: “I promise I just want what you want..really, it will make me happy.” And you mean it.

 Or 

you could get your way for twenty minutes and take the table and eat your burger and live with a woman who knows you care more about yourself than her.

She won’t say anything. But she’ll feel it. And you will too.
 
 Posted by Gary on Monday, January 09, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (1) 
 
 Two GUARANTEED ways to NEVER be bored again 
 
 
 
                                             photo by tonydetroit 
 
 #1. 

 Get a smartphone 

No matter where you are or what you’re doing you will always be able to occupy yourself in a wonderful variety of ways.

You got your phone, email, song library, camera, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, Pandora, podcasts, Angry Birds, weather radar, TED videos, sports blogs, news, plus anything that pops into your head you can immediately research to discover that the movie with the circus horse that jumped off the tower into the water was called “Wild Hearts Can’t Be Broken.”

In line at the DMV, the Walgreens, the stop light (honk!)? Waiting at the doctors office or in the car while hubby runs into Home Depot? You’ll never complain about any long wait again.

AND, best of all, you’ve got a built in distraction to keep you from #2.

 #2. 

 Embrace the reason you were put on this earth.  

Not sure what that reason is? #1 can keep you distracted from discovering that, too.
 
 Posted by Gary on Thursday, January 05, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (4) 
 
 Knowledge is the easy part 
 
 Knowing what to do is not that hard 

You can ask, find out, learn, get schooling, get experience. We major on knowledge and knowing what to do because it’s easier and definable. 

You can learn to do a budget. You can count calories. You can make a list of books to read. You can know those things and be broke, overweight, and unread. 

When I was part of a morning radio show, we were interviewed on our philosophy and approach to our job. I was amazed at the knowledge that came out of our mouths -- we really were exprienced, knowledgable, talented morning guys. The interviewer was impressed. We were impressed. But we weren&apos;t doing any of the stuff we talked about. We knew how, we knew what, we wanted to do it, we meant to do it. But we didn&apos;t.

 The will is the hard part  

For example, here are two easy to answer questions. You could ask these in any decision, big or small, about how to spend this moment, hour, day:
 
 1.  Is this contributing to what I want to accomplish?

 2.  Could this potentially hinder what I want to accomplish?
 
Pretty easy to answer those most of the time; it&apos;s yes or no. And you can see how the answers could keep you on track any time you make a decision. Answer those questions and you&apos;ve got valuable knowledge.

 But in a million years would you make it a lifestyle to ask those questions and then live by the answers? Even though you know your life would be better? 

I don’t, even though I see great value if I did. I don’t have the will.

Read this next thing and see if you don’t agree that it&apos;s wise. But do you have the will to apply it?
 
 We defeat our own purposes when we spread ourselves too thinly, striking everywhere and hitting hard nowhere – Vance Havner
 
Inside I do a fist pump. It&apos;s genius. I agree with it.

Do I follow it? Or does it stay knowledge that I can quote even though I don&apos;t do it? If you don&apos;t do it, it&apos;s not finished. We let each other get away with unfinished knowledge all the time, and we&apos;re impressed with each other! Look how much he knows!

Those two questions and that quote are not the point. The point is...

 If knowledge is the cake batter, your will is the oven 

How impressive is cake batter?
 
 Posted by Gary on Tuesday, January 03, 2012 | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBack (0) 
 
 Three minute pep talk to end the year 
 
They titled this wrong. It should be called,&quot;You can dent the world for good more than you realize, and I should know.&quot;Forty seconds.

  

 

Your life can be&quot;...some crazy sacrifice that nobody can understand, including mom...(but) the world may not like it...&quot;Two minutes.

   
 
 Posted by Gary on Saturday, December 31, 2011 | Permalink | Comments (0) 
 
 Find your perfect devotional for the new year 
 
 

It’s very simple:

 Choose one that talks to you 

THAT&apos;S IT. The rest is explanation and suggestions…

You want to feel like it&apos;s been spying on you. If sometimes you feel violated while reading, even better.

Violated doesn’t mean in-your-face: it means personal, like it was written by someone who knows your feelings, your fears, and your thoughts.

 You’re not looking for nice and comfy 

Nice and comfy means you’ve arrived. Have you arrived? If not, you need to have the not-arrived parts pointed out to you.

 I promise you’re telling lies to yourself, about how good you are and how bad you are 

 You need to be called on it 

The right devotional will do that, in private, before you get embarrassed in public. Humility and confidence are a delicate balance.

If you’re a woe-is-me person, you need to be reminded that the power that raised Jesus from the dead is for you and in you. Personally, I can’t hear that enough

 Some signs a devotional might be for you: 

 you don’t understand it all. You have to read sentences twice, or three times, to understand. when you do understand, you sometimes don’t like what it says you have to stop reading, lift your eyes, and think about it you wish you could take a piece you just read and somehow inject it in your bloodstream and make it part of you you highlight, underline, and write down things when you finish, you’re encouraged, even when it hurts 

I have a small collection of devotionals. Each year I decide which one to use based on knowing how each talks to me. Sometimes I rotate between two. I think it’s a good idea to try different ones to know how each talks to you.

 Here’s my little collection to get you started: 

 My Utmost for His Highest by Oswald Chambers. I’ll probably use it for the third year in a row. It talks to me more than any other. You can read it online for free; I have this page bookmarked on my phone and read it every morning.

 The Indwelling Life of Christ by Major Ian Thomas. Not really a devotional, but 50 short chapters that to me are the best description of the Christian life.

 Jesus Calling by Sarah Young. Maybe the most popular devotional in the world right now.

 Daily Light by Samuel Bagster and Anne Graham Lotz. Bagster wrote this for his family a bazillion years ago. Billy Graham’s family uses it, and Anne has added some helpful things. I love the little leather version.

 Morning and Evening by Charles Spurgeon. Old school. Rich.

 Leadership Promises for Every Day by John Maxwell. Straight ahead practical for leaders.

Any suggestions for devotionals that talk to you?
 
 Posted by Gary on Thursday, December 29, 2011 | Permalink | Comments (2) 
 
 A gift for you to help start the New Year 
 
 

It’s a short book about hope and change. You read it on your computer.

It’s encouragement and inspiration to help you have hope, face fear, and get going so this next year can be different.

It’s free. And if it helps you, you can email it to a friend to help them.

You can read it in an hour.

It’s called Scary Hope. It&apos;s a compilation of the 31 Days of Scary Hope series from October, all in one readable package, with a few new pieces.

Get it free right now by clicking the button. 

 

Then all you do is click and give your name and email (the distributor requires your name/email -- I won&apos;t send you anything else unless you want me to). The price will show zero, nada, nuttin. Another click, wait a few seconds, and it&apos;s yours. 

Thank you.
 
 Posted by Gary on Tuesday, December 27, 2011 | Permalink | Comments (2) 
 
 Christmas is over. Now what? 
 
 &quot;When the song of the angels is stilled,  
 When the star in the sky is gone,  
 When the kings and princes are home,  
 When the shepherds are back with their flock,  
 The work of Christmas begins:  
 To find the lost,  
 To heal the broken,  
 To feed the hungry,  
 To release the prisoner,  
 To rebuild the nations,  
 To bring peace among others,  
 To make music in the heart.&quot;  
         – Dr. Howard Thurman 
 
 Posted by Gary on Tuesday, December 27, 2011 | Permalink | Comments (2) 
 
 It&apos;s going to be all right 
 
You know how The Polar Express has a kind of creepy animation, plus a bunch of edge-of-your-seat and what’s-going-to-happen-next moments?

Little Sarah is 6, and all through the movie she kept asking, “Is it going to be all right?”

We had to reassure her, “Yes, Sarah, it’s going to be all right.”

Of course it’s going to be all right.

Because it’s Christmas.

 Without Christmas, I’m left guessing 

Does anyone really care? Does anyone know? Does anyone understand? Is anyone there? Is it going to be all right?

God could have left me his letter and expected me to just believe it. But, he did more.

He did more because there was something to be done on earth. Of course, he could have snapped his fingers and done that something from heaven. He could have rigged it so that no work on earth was necessary. But he didn’t.

He came here himself and did the work that he rigged to only be done by himself on earth in a human body.

 He showed up in person and lived like I have to 

He put on my clothes and lived in my house, and experienced first-hand what it’s like to live in my body. Which isn’t pretty.

He already knew what it’s like to live in my body, but, he experienced it first-hand so I would KNOW he knew.

 He played in the dirt without getting all dirty 

The work he did without getting dirty meant I could get cleaned up from my dirtiness, if I would only come to him for the cleaning.

Plus, he rigged it so I don’t even have to get dirty again, if I would only stick with him when I do my playing.

 I’m not alone 

 Someone cares 

 Life is now rigged to turn out all right 

Because of Christmas.
 
 His divine power has given us everything we need for a godly life through our knowledge of him who called us by his own glory and goodness. 

 Through these he has given us his very great and precious promises, so that through them you may participate in the divine nature, having escaped the corruption in the world caused by evil desires. – 2 Peter 1.3-4
 
 Posted by Gary on Tuesday, December 06, 2011 | Permalink | Comments (0) 
 
 Is God a crutch? 
 
 You’ve heard it 

Maybe you thought it or said it yourself: God is a crutch. Man invented God because man needs a God. You need something to lean on because you can’t handle life.

The moral is that strong, well-adjusted people don’t need crutches.

 Is food a crutch? 

Jesus says just like food is necessary for physical life, so he is necessary for eternal life. No food, no life. No Jesus, no Life.

 Is food an invention of man in his weakness and if only you were strong and well-adjusted you wouldn’t need to eat? 

If you argued that food doesn’t really exist, and neither does physical life, what would people think? Would they think you were a kook? 

Jesus doesn’t say food is a crutch or that physical life isn’t real, but he does argue in John 6 that eternal/spiritual life is  more  real than physical life; that the eternal impacts the physical every day.

And not only does he put the priority on the spiritual over the physical, he says he is the center and source of that eternal life. I don’t know if they thought he was a kook, but after that, everybody went the other way. 

 Maybe you could say that pretending that the physical is all there is, is a crutch 

You know, something to lean on because you can’t handle the truth.
 
 It is the Spirit who gives life; the flesh is of no avail  – John 6.63
 
 At Christmas, the spiritual became physical, so that the physical could become spiritual.  
 
 Posted by Gary on Monday, November 28, 2011 | Permalink | Comments (0) 
 
 Thankful for fog 
 
 

Right now I’m thankful for mystery, confusion, frustration, and the fog.

You can major so much on the things you know that you forget there’s much you don’t know or understand.

 Fog confronts you with your ignorance and blindness that you’d like to ignore 

 “Alright smart guy, now what do you see?” 

It’s easy to trust yourself and your strengths, abilities, and experience. It’s easy to trust what you know.

It’s easy to walk in the light, when everything as far as you can see is illuminated.

 Fog forces faith 

I’m thankful.
 
 Posted by Gary on Thursday, November 24, 2011 | Permalink | Comments (0) 
 
 How to be rescued 
 
   
 
 for they were too mighty for me -- Psalm 18.17
 
 You have to know you need it 

Let yourself exhale in the hopeless place. Feel it. Admit it.

Be hopeless and desperate and convinced there&apos;s only one person who can help.

Of course, you’d also leave to God the timing of it, and for what rescue looks like. You might have to stare at it before you realize that&apos;s it.

 The biggest hold-up to experiencing God’s rescue? 

It&apos;s something that’s good and honorable and SO hard to let go of:

 A flicker of hope that somehow you can work things out 

 If you have that flicker of hope, you don&apos;t need rescued. Yet. 
 
 Posted by Gary on Tuesday, November 22, 2011 | Permalink | Comments (2) 
 
 The end of scary hope 
 
 

For the moment, this is all I have to say about scary hope. I think this is the 42nd post, so we went a bit beyond the 31 Days of idea.

A Scary Hope eBook is coming soon, for free. Everything here (plus more) will be compiled for convenient reading, and for easy sharing with anyone you know who needs courage and a kick to embrace hope, face fear, and get going.

You can start at the beginning of the series, and see an index of all the posts HERE .

 The purpose of this blog is to encourage you to see hope where you are now, and to not be ruled by how things look and feel at the moment. I want to help you (and me) see that each moment is a step on a journey, part of a bigger thing than we can imagine. Lets try to connect the dots between the feelings and confusion of now, and that bigger thing. That purpose continues beyond Scary Hope.

To subscribe to receive each new post for free, click HERE .

Thanks so much for reading. If you have any feedback, suggestions, or comments, you can email me at gary-at-newlife-nine-one-nine-dot-com.
 
 Posted by Gary on Sunday, November 20, 2011 | Permalink | Comments (0) 
 
 A little story of misplaced hope 
 
 Enter Marilynn’s doll studio and right away you see it’s bright, clean and orderly, with built-in cubbyholes, shelves, and drawers for doll and clothing parts. No chaos or confusion.

A few dozen beautiful dolls are displayed along one wall. Each with it’s own personality, dress, and story to tell.

On a workbench lie several dolls in various stages of construction. A few heads, some arms, a torso. Scraps of fabric. A bit of construction debris. If you’ve survived any home remodeling, you know how destructive things get before they improve. This little spot is like that.

 That’s when you hear the praying 

Urgent, wailing prayer.

The dolls on the workbench are convinced their future is hopeless and out of control. How can anything good ever come of this? Arms! Legs! Heads! Oh the humanity! They cry in prayer, desperate for relief from their predicament.

Marilynn enters, and the praying intensifies. You catch scattered phrases: “Oh no!…Please, Oh Lord, build a hedge of protection!…Rebuke the devil!… NOT THE SCISSORS! ”

 They don’t realize Marilynn is working to fulfill their deepest longings 

 And even their longings are created by her. 

She treats every doll as a beloved individual. She has a personal plan for each, and prays over each one as she works and creates. Each finished doll is one-of-a-kind, with it’s own personality and mission. To Marilynn, every doll is like her own child.

 The workbench dolls see only the present. 

They see the gorgeous, unique dolls on display, but don’t make a connection between those dolls and themselves. They don’t realize that each of those dolls was also once in pieces without hope on the workbench.

 If only they knew the love and mastery of their creator and designer 

If only they knew the hope Marilynn holds in her heart for each one of them, and how nothing will stop her from pursuing that hope.

Well, some things might stop her, or slow her down: sometimes dolls roll off the workbench and hide to avoid the pain and uncertainty. Sometimes they try to resist and save themselves. They try to make Marilynn’s job more difficult; they hope she’ll get frustrated and give up.

 Their hope is in relief, in escaping the process. 

 Their hope is not the same as her hope for their future: 

 

 See more of Marilynn’s creations HERE . 

-----

To start at the beginning of the 31+ Days of Scary Hope series , click HERE . To subscribe to receive each new post for free, click HERE 
 
 Posted by Gary on Friday, November 18, 2011 | Permalink | Comments (0) 
 
 I think this is why we spend so much time with TV and the internet 
 
 

 It’s because we have a purpose 

We were made to be fruitful, and multiply, and have authority over things in our domain, and to connect with people. You see that in the first couple of chapters of Genesis.

 But it’s hard work 

Not just physically hard, but emotionally, spiritually, and mentally. It’s work to engage and think. It’s risky to take action, initiate, and not just sit there. It’s risky because it’s unpredictable and might not happen.

 And something in us fights the work and the purpose 

 The thing that happened in the garden – the fall – put into us the urge to disengage and avoid what God made us for, so that we won’t do it. 

 That urge to disengage and avoid needs a cover to hide behind 

TV and the internet (and a million other vagrant amusements and addictions) engage just enough to occupy that part of you that’s designed to pursue your purpose. It feels like something’s happening, but it’s not.

 You hear the noise of the engine running, but the car isn’t going anywhere. The noise gives your inner Ferrari an excuse to stay in neutral. 

When I read The Gulag Archipelago , I kept wondering why the Russians went to the effort of mock trials and verdicts. Why didn’t they ship their enemies off to labor camps to start with and avoid all the trouble of rigging and manufacturing evidence?

It was to give the people a reason to believe the lie.

The Russians knew that only a small excuse is needed to kick in our default setting of disengaging and avoiding: “ See , they had a trial – it was fair…”

 Your purpose, hope, and calling require engagement and action 

 Engagement and action are looking for an excuse to cool it 

 Vagrant amusements love to derail engagement and action 

Just as alcohol is risky for an alcoholic, so too much TV, the internet, books, food, shopping, sports, music, travel, and etc. are risky to hope.

 They deaden hope and muffle its voice 

Took me three days to write this. Again, talking to myself.

-----

Thanks for reading. A Scary Hope eBook is coming, probably by Christmas, unless I get sidetracked by vagrant amusements. To start at the beginning of the series, click HERE . To subscribe to receive each new post for free, click HERE .
 
 Posted by Gary on Wednesday, November 16, 2011 | Permalink | Comments (1) 
 
 Confession 
 
This whole 31+ days of Scary Hope series that I can’t stop?

I’d like to say it’s “by popular demand” but it’s really by my own internal demand.

I probably should have told you I’ve been talking to myself all along. Hope that&apos;s OK.
 
 Posted by Gary on Monday, November 14, 2011 | Permalink | Comments (6) 
 
 The coolest quote ever on hope 
 
 “He did see it. That’s why it’s here.” 
 
-- response to the comment, “Too bad Walt Disney didn’t live to see all this,” made on the day Walt Disney World opened, five years after Disney’s death.
 
 Posted by Gary on Saturday, November 12, 2011 | Permalink | Comments (2) 
 
 A pep talk from one who made it out of the wilderness of hope 
 
 

 I can’t talk about my years in the wilderness , my persistent hope despite long odds, and then breaking through into something resembling fulfillment.

Well, I CAN talk about the wilderness part, but not the rest, because I’m still in the wilderness, which is pretty neat since that’s often the best part of the story anyway; and once you’re out, that part of the story ends.

 Steven Pressfield , however, can talk about the whole arc of hope.

 The wilderness comes first 

Pressfield hoped for 17 years before earning a paycheck, and then ended up a novelist, screenwriter, and an author of historical fiction (some of which even serves as curriculum for soldiers).

Let’s let him tell his own story of his wilderness. Substitute your specific hope for his of writing:
 
When I was struggling to teach myself how to write, I was so far gone that the idea of choice never entered the equation. The question wasn’t, Does this make sense? Am I getting anywhere?

 The question was, “Am I out of my mind? How much farther down is this road gonna take me?” 

From time to time I’d make a stab at returning to reality. I’d get a real job. I’d work hard, I’d make friends, sometimes I even had a girlfriend. But I could never stick. I had to write. All through this time, I was estranged from my family.

My Dad could make no sense of the choices I had made; I broke his heart. I had long ago driven my wife away. My mother thought I was crazy.

What mainstream friends I had were on my side, but, on the rare occasions when I saw them, they regarded me partly with pity, partly with puzzlement, but mainly with that look that people get when they’re afraid they’re standing too close to something contagious
 
 The wilderness is called that for a reason; all hope seems lost  

Your particular wilderness, of course, looks different from his. But if you have any passionate attachment or commitment to your hope, you probably can relate. Pressfield says he felt he was crazy, he had no reason to hope, and even his mother ignored him. 
 
Sometimes in a city at night I would walk past a ballet studio and look up at the dancers hard at work. I envied them. They had each other, they had a troupe, a class. I envied actors who had rep groups and theaters.

 I had nobody. Not a soul who believed in me or thought I wasn’t crazy. 
 
What keeps a person going? As I write this, I’m aware that there are people reading who know exactly what I’m talking about. Young painters and film-makers and novelists who are in that exact same place. Lemme say this to you:
 
 Don’t quit. Bleed from your eyeballs if you have to, but don’t stop. 

What kept me going was the same thing that kept those dancers working at the barre. I just loved it. Even when the work was garbage, which was 99.9% of the time, I had to keep trying—and if you’re trying now, God bless you. Keep hammering. If you have a choice,
 
Pressfield tells the story of a painter friend who “beat her brains out to get better” but didn’t. She kept painting these little paintings that weren’t any good. A year later he caught up with her and her work was suddenly spectacular. No one knew what had happened, but she broke though and “found her gift.”

 What if the depth of your wilderness was equal to the depth of the coming fulfillment of your hope? 

 Makes it feel a little different, eh? 

Pressfield’s words for you and me, looking back at us from outside the wilderness:

 “Don’t quit. 

 Keep slugging. 

 It takes time. 

 There’s a price. 

 Keep hammering.” 

-----

Thanks for reading! A Scary Hope eBook is coming, probably by Christmas. It will contain much of what you’ve read here during the 31+ Days of Scary Hope : encouragement to go from IS to COULD BE , plus several additional chapters. To start at the beginning of the series, click HERE . To subscribe to receive each new post for free, click HERE .
 
 Posted by Gary on Friday, November 11, 2011 | Permalink | Comments (1) 
 
 Find the end of your story 
 
Jim Stockdale was a POW in Vietnam for over seven years. Four of those years he was in solitary confinement. Do you think he had hopes of going home? He did, but HOW he hoped determined if his hope would be fulfilled.

Here’s what Stockdale said in the book Good to Great , about how he hoped:

 &quot;I never lost faith in the end of the story… 
 
 I never doubted not only that I would get out, but also that I would prevail in the end and turn the experience into the defining event of my life, which, in retrospect, I would not trade.&quot; 
 
 This hope is more than optimism 

Stockdale said the optimistic POW’s DIED . How’s that?
 
they were the ones who said,&apos;We&apos;re going to be out by Christmas.&apos;And Christmas would come, and Christmas would go. Then they&apos;d say,&apos;We&apos;re going to be out by Easter.&apos;And Easter would come, and Easter would go. And then Thanksgiving, and then it would be Christmas again. And they died of a broken heart.
 
Get it? Picking a date to believe in was just blind wishing and hoping.

 True hope does not just make stuff up. True hope does not fantasize. 

Here’s how Stockdale puts it:
 
 You must never confuse faith that you will prevail in the end – which you can never afford to lose – with the discipline to confront the most brutal facts of your current reality, whatever they might be. 
 
 Hope embraces brutal reality – and still believes 

 Hope is not in a day, or a person, or an amount, or a place. Hope is in what happens thru those things. 

I have hopes for a small, modest property in rural North Carolina where a few people can come and gather for encouragement, and to gain a fresh, life-changing perspective on heaven, earth, and living. The place would also serve the same purposes for our family.

But, if I could have the place without the results, OR, if I could have the results without the place, which would I take? No question – I’d take the results. So my hope is not really in the place; it’s in the purpose of the place. 

 That hope you have? Ask yourself ‘Why?’ 

 Your answer to ‘why’ is the end of your story. Put your hope there. 

-----

 More of  31+ Days of Scary Hope : encouragement to go from IS to COULD BE.  To start at the beginning, click HERE .  To subscribe to automatically receive each day, click  HERE . Thanks for reading! 
 
 Posted by Gary on Wednesday, November 09, 2011 | Permalink | Comments (3) 
 Next » 
Get updates by RSS or email:
 

 
   Subscribe in a reader 
 
Enter your email address:

 
 
Delivered by FeedBurner 
 
Other writings
 
 The Scary Hope book on Kindle 
 From Beer to Eternity -- a bit of Gary&apos;s story 
 
 
 About 
 
Gary&apos;s Girls
 
 Nesting Place (daughter The Nester) 
 Chatting at the Sky (daughter Emily)
	</body>
</document>
