<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009820" url="http://www.kathysfastfoodtoys.com/TacoBell.html" time="2012-07-13-03:13" support="3" score="0.002878157216585692" bingtitle="KATHY&apos;S FAST FOOD TOYS - Taco Bell" webtitle="KATHY&apos;S FAST FOOD TOYS - Taco Bell">
			<query id="001057" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000180" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="85"/>
	<description>For payment we accept PayPal, money orders, personal checks or cash. Prices are not ... COMMENT: Other character cup toppers and cups that complimented Taco Bell&apos;s set were ...</description>
	<body>
		Menu

TOYS FOR SALE

 


TV, MOVIE AND CHARACTER TOYS
 A to J K to R S to Z 


FAST FOOD CHAINS
AND STORES
 A &amp; W Arby&apos;s Big Boy Blockbuster Braum&apos;s Burger King Carls Jr. Chick Fil A Dairy Queen Denny&apos;s Domino&apos;s Pizza Hardee&apos;s Hungry Jack&apos;s IHOP Jack In The Box KFC K Mart Little Caesar&apos;s Long John Silver&apos;s McDonald&apos;s 1 McDonald&apos;s 2 Pancho&apos;s Pizza Hut 7 Eleven Showbiz Pizza Place Sonic Subway Taco Bell Target Walmart Wendy&apos;s Whataburger White Castle Wienerschnitzel 


OUR PERSONAL COLLECTION
 Our Collection 1 Our Collection 2 Our Collection 3 
 
 


Need Help?
 Search our website 
 

 TACO BELL 


 Back To Home Page 


If you are interested in buying any of the items on this page, just email us at katriggs@tx.rr.com and please include your zip code (country if outside the USA) so we can include shipping cost when we reply.
For payment we accept PayPal, money orders, personal checks or cash.
Prices are not included here on the web site, but will be promptly provided once we receive your e-mail.
We mail very quickly by USPS--usually within 24 hours or less of receiving payment--and every package in the USA is shipped with a delivery confirmation number.

MIP = Mint in Package
NP = No Package
U3 = Rated Safe For Children Under The Age Of Three

 

 Taco Bell -Miscellaneous Toys- 

 
 
Click for larger image 
 1986 Taco Bell ZOOBILEE ZOO HIDDEN PICTURE BOOKS
-Lot of Two- NPs &quot;Lookout Bear and The Who Monster&quot;, and &quot;Lookout Bear&apos;s Bigfoot Adventure&quot; (both paperback books
come with &quot;Magic Hide &apos;n&apos; See Lens&quot;) 
 
 


 
 
Click for larger image 
 1996 - 1997 Taco Bell GOOSEBUMPS -Lot of Four- MIPs 1996 Goosebumps &quot;Slappy&apos;s Candy Keeper&quot;, and &quot;Skullmobile&quot;, plus &quot;Don&apos;t Make Me Laugh&quot; mini-storybook and 
1997 Goosebumps &quot;The Abominable Snowman&apos;s Cool Activities&quot;
 Everything but &quot;Slappy&apos;s Candy Keeper&quot; has sold. 

 
 
 


 
 
Click for larger image 
 1997 Taco Bell STAR WARS -Lot of Fourteen- MIPs&amp;NPs &quot;Millennium Falcon Gryo&quot; (missing piece), &quot;R-2 D-2 Playset w/Princess Leah&quot; (x4), &quot;Balancing Boba Fett&quot;, &quot;Exploding Death Star&quot; (x3), &quot;Millennium Flacon Gyro&quot; (x2, missing
pieces), and U3 &quot;Yoda&quot; (x3) 
 
 


 
 
Click for larger image 
 1998 Taco Bell GODZILLA -Lot of Three - MIPs&amp;NP &quot;Godzilla&quot;, and &quot;Helicopter&quot; (x2 MIP)
 &quot;Godzilla&quot; has sold. 
 
 


 
 
Click for larger image 
Click for larger image 
Click for larger image 
 1999 Taco Bell STAR WARS EPISODE 1
-Lot of Eleven- MIPs&amp;NPs &quot;Walking Sebulba&quot; w/Box, &quot;Joking Jar Jar Binks&quot; w/Box, and &quot;Sith Probe Droid Viewer&quot; w/Box





&quot;Anakin&quot;, &quot;Darth Maul&quot;, &quot;Watto&quot; and &quot;Sebulba&quot; 32-oz. Cup Toppers





&quot;Anakin&quot;, &quot;Darth Maul&quot;, &quot;Watto&quot; and &quot;Sebulba&quot; 32-oz. Cups 
 COMMENT: Other character cup toppers and cups that complimented
Taco Bell&apos;s set were available at KFC and Pizza Hut. The four toppers and cups above were available at
Taco Bell, four others at KFC and four more at Pizza Hut. 
 


 
 
Click for larger image 
 2003 - Unknown Date Taco Bell MISCELLANEOUS -Lot of Two- MIPs Unknown Date NCAA &quot;Basketball Clip&quot;

2003 Racin&apos; Rockets 2 &quot;Sports Car with Launch Ramp&quot;
 
   
 

 Our Personal Taco Bell Collection 
 
Menu

REFERENCE ONLY

 


McDONALD&apos;S CATALOGS
 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 

 


RESTAURANTS OTHER THAN McDONALD&apos;S CATALOGS
 2010 

 


RESTAURANT WEB SITE
 Taco Bell 
 


BOOKS


 

 

 ©2010 kathysfastfoodtoys.com - All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
