<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009207" url="http://www.foxnews.com/travel/2011/10/12/ex-skid-row-frontman-sebastian-bach-shares-his-favorite-canadian-cities/" time="2012-07-13-02:36" support="1" score="0.0009180620855361202" bingtitle="Ex-Skid Row Frontman Sebastian Bach on What&apos;s Cool in Canada | Fox ..." webtitle="Ex-Skid Row Frontman Sebastian Bach on Whats Cool in Canada | Fox News">
			<query id="000675" bing-rank="227"/>
	<description>Bach: My favorite fast food restaurant is in Canada. ... 10 Most Precious Places on Earth—And How to ... Is Airport Lounge Access Worth a New Credit Card?</description>
	<body>
		Fox News Digital Network   Fox News   Fox Business   uReport   Fox News Radio   Fox News Latino   Fox Nation   Fox News Insider 
 Register Login 
 Account 
You&apos;re logged in as Account 

 Edit Profile Logout 
 

 Search Site 
 On Air Now › 

 On Air Personalities › 

   
 
 Home Video Politics U.S. Opinion Entertainment SciTech Health Travel Lifestyle World Sports On Air 
 
 Previous Slide Next Slide 
 
 Travel Home Vacation Guides Slideshows Flight Tracker Airport Information In 5: Travel Explorer 
 
Ex-Skid Row Frontman Sebastian Bach on What&apos;s Cool in Canada
 
By Avi Ramsadeen , Ashley Dvorkin

Star Traveler

Published October 12, 2011 

 FoxNews.com 
 
 
Sebastian Bach (AP) 
 
 
Ex-Skid Row frontman Sebastian Bach has been rocking out for over two decades. He has gracefully moved from concert stages, to Broadway, to the small screen.

The rocker&apos;s tenure with his former band has turned him into an icon in the hair metal movement and a household name. 

Skid Row&apos;s debut album sold over 5 million copies and their follow up album hit number one on the Billboard 200 chart.

Despite showing off his acting talents on Broadway and TV, taking stage roles in such productions as &quot;Jesus Christ Superstar&quot; or making guest appearances on TV shows like the &quot;Gilmore Girls,&quot; rock and roll is definitely Bach&apos;s calling. 

The Canadian rocker continues his successful solo career with his newest album &quot;Kicking and Screaming,&quot; which debuted at number 6 on Billboard&apos;s Hard Rock Album&apos;s list.

Like all rockers, Bach has left his mark with fans in many places, but it seems that Canada has left a mark with him.

After speaking to the musician, one can surmise that Canada is a lot more than maple syrup and Celine Dion . 

Bach spoke to Fox411 about the country that raised him, specifically about his top three favorite Canadian cities, Quebec City, Vancouver and Toronto.

 Sebastian Bach: I used to live in Canada. It&apos;s a beautiful country with a lot of different kind of topographic regions. There&apos;s mountains, there&apos;s plains, there&apos;s water. If you drive across Canada, Ontario is very flat. There&apos;s lot of lakes, as you get out West between Calgary and Vancouver there is some of the most spectacular views you&apos;ve ever seen of just mountains, snow covered peaks and valleys, quite spectacular.

 Fox411: To get the full Canadian experience, what are must-see cities for a traveler?

 Bach: I would say number one would be Quebec City. Quebec City is the most European of any city in North America, they speak French all the time. There is a part of town called Old Quebec which is really like being in France . The architecture is just gorgeous, food, shopping. I&apos;d say Quebec city is the most beautiful city in North America I&apos;ve seen. 

Toronto, you&apos;ve got to visit because it&apos;s the epicenter of Canada, as far as the main kind of town. And then I would say Vancouver, it&apos;s beautiful. It&apos;s kind of like California, a little colder, but it&apos;s a great city.

 For more on Toronto, check out FoxNews.com&apos;s vacation guide&gt;&gt; 

 Fox411: No vacation is complete without good food. So, what would you recommend?

 Bach: My favorite fast food restaurant is in Canada. It&apos;s called &quot;Harvey&apos;s&quot; and the theme song is, &apos;Harvey&apos;s makes hamburger a beautiful thing!&apos; And let me tell you, they sure do! I never really knew what fine cuisine was when I was a little boy in Canada. For me, Italian food was &quot;Kraft Dinner&quot; or pizza. When I moved to New York that&apos;s when I discovered all the Italian food.

 Fox411: In your opinion, you can&apos;t leave Canada without doing...what?

 Bach: I would say a must-do in Canada would be to go skiing at Whistler in Vancouver. You could take a chair lift for like a half hour to the top of this mountain and you ski down, it takes like so long to get to the bottom. You go past the clouds. It&apos;s absolutely incredible.

 For more on Vancouver, click over to FoxNews.com&apos;s vacation guide&gt;&gt; 
 
 
 
   Print   Email   Share   Comments Recommend Tweet 
 
Related Video
 
 

 Sebastian Bach&apos;s Canada 


 
Share This Article

 
 
Newsletter Signup
 
Sign up for free e-mail news alerts from FoxNews.com and FoxBusiness.com.
 Newsletter Signup 
 View Article 
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. 
You must login to comment.
 
 View Article 
 
Advertisement
 
More Destination Guides
 
 View All 
 
 
 Orlando, FL 
 
 Las Vegas 
 
 Miami 
 
 Los Angeles 
 
 Chicago 
 

 
 New York City 
 
 Denver 
 
 Puerto Rico 
 
 Cancun 
 
 Montreal 
 
 
 FLIGHT TRACKER 
 
 By Flight By Route 
 Flight Tracker 
 Airline Select an airline... Others... Aer Lingus - EI Aeroflot Airlines - SU Aeromexico - AM Air Canada - AC Air China - CA Air France - AF Air India - AI Air Inuit - 3H Air Jamaica - JM Air New Zealand - NZ Air Transat Canada - TS AirTran - FL Alaska Airlines - AS Alitalia - AZ All Nippon Airways - NH Allegiant Air - G4 American Airlines - AA Avianca - AV Bahamasair - UP Bearskin Airlines - JV British Airways - BA British Midland - BD Brussels Airlines - SN Canadian North - 5T Cathay Pacific - CX China Eastern Airlines - MU China Southern Airlines - CZ Continental Airlines - CO Copa Airlines - CM Delta Air Lines - DL ERA Aviation - 7H EVA Airways - BR Easyjet - U2 El Al Israel Airlines - LY Emirates - EK Finnair - AY First Air - 7F Frontier Airlines - F9 Garuda Indonesia - GA Great Lakes Airlines - ZK Hawaiian Airlines - HA Iberia - IB Icelandair - FI Iran Air - IR Japan Airlines - JL Jet Airways - 9W JetBlue Airways - B6 KLM Royal Dutch Airlines - KL Korean Air Lines - KE Labrador Airways LTD - WJ Lufthansa - LH Malaysia Airlines - MH Mesa Airlines - YV Mexicana - MX Midwest Airlines - YX Olympic Airways - OA Penair - KS Philippine Airlines - PR Qantas Airways - QF Qatar Airways - QR Salmon Air - S6 Saudi Arabian Airlines - SV Scandinavian Airlines SAS - SK Scenic Airlines - YR Singapore Airlines - SQ South African Airways - SA Southwest Airlines - WN Spanair - JK Spirit Airlines - NK Sun Country Airlines - SY Sunwing Airlines - WG Swiss Intl Airlines - LX Thai Airways - TG Turkish Airlines - TK US Airways - US USA3000 - U5 United Airlines - UA Virgin America - VX Virgin Atlantic - VS WestJet Airlines - WS Xiamen Airlines - MF Or Airline Code Flight Number Date 

Missing or invalid entries. Please search again.
 Track By Route 
 Departure Airport Select an airport... Albany, NY - ALB Albuquerque, NM - ABQ Anchorage, AK - ANC Atlanta, GA - ATL Austin, TX - AUS Baltimore, MD - BWI Bangor, ME - BGR Baton Rouge, LA - BTR Billings, MT - BIL Birmingham, AL - BHM Bismarck, ND - BIS Boise, ID - BOI Boston, MA - BOS Bozeman, MT - BZN Buffalo, NY - BUF Burbank, CA - BUR Burlington, VT - BTV Casper, WY - CPR Cedar Rapids, IA - CID Charleston, SC - CHS Charleston, WV - CRW Charlotte, NC - CLT Chicago, IL (O&apos;Hare) - ORD Chicago, IL (Midway) - MDW Cincinnati, OH - CVG Cleveland, OH - CLE Colorado Springs, CO - COS Columbus, OH - CMH Dallas, TX (Dallas/Ft Worth) - DFW Dallas, TX (Love Field) - DAL Dayton, OH - DAY Denver, CO - DEN Des Moines, IA - DSM Detroit, MI - DTW El Paso, TX - ELP Fairbanks, AK - FAI Fargo, ND - FAR Fort Lauderdale, FL - FLL Fort Myers, FL - RSW Fort Wayne, IN - FWA Grand Junction, CO - GJT Grand Rapids, MI - GRR Greensboro, NC - GSO Greenville, SC - GSP Gulfport, MS - GPT Hartford, CT - BDL Honolulu, HI - HNL Houston, TX (Intercontinental) - IAH Houston, TX (Hobby) - HOU Indianapolis, IN - IND Jackson, MS - JAN Jacksonville, FL - JAX Juneau, AK - JNU Kahului, Maui, HI - OGG Kailua-Kona, HI - KOA Kansas City, MO - MCI Knoxville, TN - TYS Las Vegas, NV - LAS Lincoln, NE - LNK Little Rock, AR - LIT Long Beach, CA - LGB Los Angeles, CA - LAX Louisville, KY - SDF Madison, WI - MSN Manchester, NH - MHT Memphis, TN - MEM Miami, FL - MIA Milwaukee, WI - MKE Minneapolis, MN - MSP Myrtle Beach, SC - MYR Nashville, TN - BNA New Orleans, LA - MSY New York, NY (Kennedy) - JFK New York, NY (LaGuardia) - LGA Newark, NJ - EWR Norfolk, VA - ORF Oakland, CA - OAK Oklahoma City, OK - OKC Omaha, NE - OMA Ontario, CA - ONT Orange County, CA - SNA Orlando, FL - MCO Pensacola, FL - PNS Philadelphia, PA - PHL Phoenix, AZ - PHX Pittsburgh, PA - PIT Portland, ME - PWM Portland, OR - PDX Providence, RI - PVD Raleigh Durham, NC - RDU Rapid City, SD - RAP Reno, NV - RNO Richmond, VA - RIC Rochester, NY - ROC Sacramento, CA - SMF Salt Lake City, UT - SLC San Antonio, TX - SAT San Diego, CA - SAN San Francisco, CA - SFO San Jose, CA - SJC Savannah, GA - SAV Seattle, WA - SEA Shreveport, LA - SHV Sioux Falls, SD - FSD Spokane, WA - GEG St. Louis, MO - STL Syracuse, NY - SYR Tampa, FL - TPA Tucson, AZ - TUS Tulsa, OK - TUL Washington, DC (Dulles) - IAD Washington, DC (National) - DCA West Palm Beach, FL - PBI Wichita, KS - ICT Arrival Airport Select an airport... Albany, NY - ALB Albuquerque, NM - ABQ Anchorage, AK - ANC Atlanta, GA - ATL Austin, TX - AUS Baltimore, MD - BWI Bangor, ME - BGR Baton Rouge, LA - BTR Billings, MT - BIL Birmingham, AL - BHM Bismarck, ND - BIS Boise, ID - BOI Boston, MA - BOS Bozeman, MT - BZN Buffalo, NY - BUF Burbank, CA - BUR Burlington, VT - BTV Casper, WY - CPR Cedar Rapids, IA - CID Charleston, SC - CHS Charleston, WV - CRW Charlotte, NC - CLT Chicago, IL (O&apos;Hare) - ORD Chicago, IL (Midway) - MDW Cincinnati, OH - CVG Cleveland, OH - CLE Colorado Springs, CO - COS Columbus, OH - CMH Dallas, TX (Dallas/Ft Worth) - DFW Dallas, TX (Love Field) - DAL Dayton, OH - DAY Denver, CO - DEN Des Moines, IA - DSM Detroit, MI - DTW El Paso, TX - ELP Fairbanks, AK - FAI Fargo, ND - FAR Fort Lauderdale, FL - FLL Fort Myers, FL - RSW Fort Wayne, IN - FWA Grand Junction, CO - GJT Grand Rapids, MI - GRR Greensboro, NC - GSO Greenville, SC - GSP Gulfport, MS - GPT Hartford, CT - BDL Honolulu, HI - HNL Houston, TX (Intercontinental) - IAH Houston, TX (Hobby) - HOU Indianapolis, IN - IND Jackson, MS - JAN Jacksonville, FL - JAX Juneau, AK - JNU Kahului, Maui, HI - OGG Kailua-Kona, HI - KOA Kansas City, MO - MCI Knoxville, TN - TYS Las Vegas, NV - LAS Lincoln, NE - LNK Little Rock, AR - LIT Long Beach, CA - LGB Los Angeles, CA - LAX Louisville, KY - SDF Madison, WI - MSN Manchester, NH - MHT Memphis, TN - MEM Miami, FL - MIA Milwaukee, WI - MKE Minneapolis, MN - MSP Myrtle Beach, SC - MYR Nashville, TN - BNA New Orleans, LA - MSY New York, NY (Kennedy) - JFK New York, NY (LaGuardia) - LGA Newark, NJ - EWR Norfolk, VA - ORF Oakland, CA - OAK Oklahoma City, OK - OKC Omaha, NE - OMA Ontario, CA - ONT Orange County, CA - SNA Orlando, FL - MCO Pensacola, FL - PNS Philadelphia, PA - PHL Phoenix, AZ - PHX Pittsburgh, PA - PIT Portland, ME - PWM Portland, OR - PDX Providence, RI - PVD Raleigh Durham, NC - RDU Rapid City, SD - RAP Reno, NV - RNO Richmond, VA - RIC Rochester, NY - ROC Sacramento, CA - SMF Salt Lake City, UT - SLC San Antonio, TX - SAT San Diego, CA - SAN San Francisco, CA - SFO San Jose, CA - SJC Savannah, GA - SAV Seattle, WA - SEA Shreveport, LA - SHV Sioux Falls, SD - FSD Spokane, WA - GEG St. Louis, MO - STL Syracuse, NY - SYR Tampa, FL - TPA Tucson, AZ - TUS Tulsa, OK - TUL Washington, DC (Dulles) - IAD Washington, DC (National) - DCA West Palm Beach, FL - PBI Wichita, KS - ICT Departure Date 

Missing or invalid entries. Please search again.
 
 AIRPORT INFO 
 Select Airport 
 Select an airport... Albany, NY - ALB Albuquerque, NM - ABQ Anchorage, AK - ANC Atlanta, GA - ATL Austin, TX - AUS Baltimore, MD - BWI Bangor, ME - BGR Baton Rouge, LA - BTR Billings, MT - BIL Birmingham, AL - BHM Bismarck, ND - BIS Boise, ID - BOI Boston, MA - BOS Bozeman, MT - BZN Buffalo, NY - BUF Burbank, CA - BUR Burlington, VT - BTV Casper, WY - CPR Cedar Rapids, IA - CID Charleston, SC - CHS Charleston, WV - CRW Charlotte, NC - CLT Chicago, IL (O&apos;Hare) - ORD Chicago, IL (Midway) - MDW Cincinnati, OH - CVG Cleveland, OH - CLE Colorado Springs, CO - COS Columbus, OH - CMH Dallas, TX (Dallas/Ft Worth) - DFW Dallas, TX (Love Field) - DAL Dayton, OH - DAY Denver, CO - DEN Des Moines, IA - DSM Detroit, MI - DTW El Paso, TX - ELP Fairbanks, AK - FAI Fargo, ND - FAR Fort Lauderdale, FL - FLL Fort Myers, FL - RSW Fort Wayne, IN - FWA Grand Junction, CO - GJT Grand Rapids, MI - GRR Greensboro, NC - GSO Greenville, SC - GSP Gulfport, MS - GPT Hartford, CT - BDL Honolulu, HI - HNL Houston, TX (Intercontinental) - IAH Houston, TX (Hobby) - HOU Indianapolis, IN - IND Jackson, MS - JAN Jacksonville, FL - JAX Juneau, AK - JNU Kahului, Maui, HI - OGG Kailua-Kona, HI - KOA Kansas City, MO - MCI Knoxville, TN - TYS Las Vegas, NV - LAS Lincoln, NE - LNK Little Rock, AR - LIT Long Beach, CA - LGB Los Angeles, CA - LAX Louisville, KY - SDF Madison, WI - MSN Manchester, NH - MHT Memphis, TN - MEM Miami, FL - MIA Milwaukee, WI - MKE Minneapolis, MN - MSP Myrtle Beach, SC - MYR Nashville, TN - BNA New Orleans, LA - MSY New York, NY (Kennedy) - JFK New York, NY (LaGuardia) - LGA Newark, NJ - EWR Norfolk, VA - ORF Oakland, CA - OAK Oklahoma City, OK - OKC Omaha, NE - OMA Ontario, CA - ONT Orange County, CA - SNA Orlando, FL - MCO Pensacola, FL - PNS Philadelphia, PA - PHL Phoenix, AZ - PHX Pittsburgh, PA - PIT Portland, ME - PWM Portland, OR - PDX Providence, RI - PVD Raleigh Durham, NC - RDU Rapid City, SD - RAP Reno, NV - RNO Richmond, VA - RIC Rochester, NY - ROC Sacramento, CA - SMF Salt Lake City, UT - SLC San Antonio, TX - SAT San Diego, CA - SAN San Francisco, CA - SFO San Jose, CA - SJC Savannah, GA - SAV Seattle, WA - SEA Shreveport, LA - SHV Sioux Falls, SD - FSD Spokane, WA - GEG St. Louis, MO - STL Syracuse, NY - SYR Tampa, FL - TPA Tucson, AZ - TUS Tulsa, OK - TUL Washington, DC (Dulles) - IAD Washington, DC (National) - DCA West Palm Beach, FL - PBI Wichita, KS - ICT 
 
TRENDING IN TRAVEL
 
 
1

 10 common cruise myths debunked 
 Facebook Twitter 
2

 12 oldest places in America 
 Facebook Twitter 
3

 What&apos;s It Like to Work on a Cruise Ship 
 Facebook Twitter 
4

 US carriers move closer toward &apos;do it yourself&apos; boarding 
 Facebook Twitter 
5

 Will you really have to sit next to a pig on a plane? 
 Facebook Twitter 
 See all trends 
 More 
 
 
 Can Women Turn the Economy Around? 
 
 
 How Big a Role Will Taxes Play in the 2012 Elections? How to Launch a New Company at an Industry Event 
 
Advertisement
 
Also on the web
 
 WATCH: 50,000 Bees Removed From Man&apos;s Home Arizona Officials Investigating Who Buried This Cat Alive In Concrete (WARNING: GRAPHIC VIDEO) Man Says Drinking Wife&apos;s Breast Milk And Blood Helps His E.D. Problem &apos;JACK THE GRIPPER&apos;: Alleged Serial Hugger Could Face Charges World&apos;s Heaviest Woman Credits Sex For 98-Pound Weight Loss 
 
 Five High-Style Hotels in London to Love Right Now In the Spotlight: One by the Five — Paris Spotlight on Jamaica: What to Do and Where to Stay 5 Unusual (and Awesome) Honeymoon Ideas My “Branded” Tears, or What I Loved About Hotel Impossible at The Dude Rancher 
 
 10 Common Cruise Myths—Debunked 12 Most Colorful Towns in the World 12 Oldest Places in America 6 Foolproof Tricks for NOT Embarrassing Yourself in a Foreign Language One-Tank Escapes for 8 Cities 
 
 Sleep Cheap in the Bachelorette&apos;s Suite Make the Most of London During the Olympics Idle on the Islands at the Top 10 Caribbean Resorts How to Seal the Deal in Hollywood Apply Sunscreen and Visit Hawaii&apos;s Top 10 Beaches 
 
 The Airport Experience in 2025 Six Foolproof Tricks for NOT Embarrassing Yourself in a Foreign Language Newsflash: You Can Put Your Vacation on Layaway Travel Peacefully with Colleagues Using These Expert Tips How to Protect Yourself From Hacker Attacks Abroad 
 
 STAYCATION! SWEET HEAT RELIEF! (FOR SOME...) Heat continues this weekend... Happy 4th of July eve! Summertime heat, Pat Benatar rocks Fox and Friends! 
 
Sections
 
 Home Video Politics U.S. Opinion Entertainment SciTech Health Travel Lifestyle World Sports Weather 
 
Shows
 
 America Live America&apos;s News HQ America&apos;s Newsroom Cavuto Fox News Sunday Fox&amp;Friends First Fox&amp;Friends Fox&amp;Friends Weekend Fox News Watch Fox Report Geraldo at Large Greta Hannity 
 
 
 
 Happening Now Huckabee Justice with Judge Jeanine Red Eye w/ Gutfeld Special Report Specials Studio B The Cost of Freedom The Five The Journal Editorial Report The O&apos; Reilly Factor War Stories 
 
Tools
 
 Trending uReport Newsletters&amp;Alerts Blogs Mobile Podcasts Radio Fox News Store Apps&amp;Downloads 
 
About
 
 Careers Internships - FNCU Fox Around the World Advertise With Us Terms of Use Privacy Policy Ad Choices Contact Us Email Newsroom FAQ Media Relations 
 
Follow
 
   Facebook   Twitter   Google+   LinkedIn   RSS   Newsletters 
 
 
This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.©2012 FOX News Network, LLC. All rights reserved. All market data delayed 20 minutes.
	</body>
</document>
