<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009700" url="http://sports.espn.go.com/rpm/news/story?series=2&amp;id=2915442" time="2012-07-13-03:05" support="2" score="0.0028651638276948463" bingtitle="Long Haulin&apos; coast-to-coast with Peter Rabbit and the No. 18 gang ..." webtitle="Long Haulin&apos; coast-to-coast with Peter Rabbit and the No. 18 gang - Racing - ESPN">
			<query id="000695" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="001135" bing-rank="220"/>
	<description>The big rig is put in park, but for drivers ... gallons of coffee, ate at six different fast-food restaurant ... In line waiting for my order, some female truckers ...</description>
	<body>
		EDITIONS: 
 USA DEPORTES 
 More Asia Australia Brazil United Kingdom 
 
 CITIES: 
 BOSTON CHICAGO DALLAS LOS ANGELES NEW YORK 
 ESPN Sprint Cup Shop 
Long Haulin&apos; coast-to-coast with Peter Rabbit and the No. 18 gang

Long Haulin&apos; coast-to-coast with Peter Rabbit and the No. 18 gang.
 Updated: July 1, 2007, 7:27 PM ET By Chase Thompson | ESPN.com 
 Recommend 0 Tweet 0 Comments 0 Email Print 
 
 An ESPN crew followed J.J. Yeley&apos;s hauler from Sonoma, Calif., to Huntersville, N.C. here is their story. 


 Tuesday: Joe Gibbs Racing, 8:12 p.m. EST 
The No. 18 Hauler arrives into the back parking lot of Joe Gibbs Racing in Huntersville, N.C., just outside of Charlotte.


The big rig is put in park, but for drivers Peter Rabbit and Bob, the work is not done. Bob and his wife, who he phoned for a ride home from the shop, have to quickly wash the truck&apos;s exterior before he can go home. Meanwhile, Peter has a little better evening as he can go directly home for 12 hours only to return to the shop Wednesday morning to drive the hauler up to Loudon, N.H., site of this weekend&apos;s Nextel Cup Series race. By comparison, a much easier road trip at 15 hours and just over 1,000 miles.


 Tuesday: Great Smokey Mountains, 5:28 p.m. EST 
Crossing state lines usually never gets this big of an ovation, but this time was special.

 Chase Thompson/ESPN.com The No. 18 hauler finally comes to rest at the Joe Gibbs racing shop in Huntersville, N.C. 

We slipped over the border from Tennessee into North Carolina in a huge downpour. We didn&apos;t care that we were driving 15 mph or that the rain was limiting the visibility. That line through the mountains represented the end of our journey as that would be the last state line we would cross. The word happy doesn&apos;t even come close to describing the feeling in the car.


In all we used 6 cameras, traveled 2758.5 miles, visited 10 states, each changed clothes once, drank gallons of coffee, ate at six different fast-food restaurant chains, killed one tick, filled up the minivan seven times (with Regular because we&apos;re cheap), crossed four U.S. time zones, and absolutely zero showers were taken.


 Tuesday: One more for the road, 5:05 p.m. EST 
On the outskirts of Knoxville, Tenn., at a Pilot Travel Center Truck Stop we gather some last-minute video and soundbites from Peter Rabbit and Bob for our story.

 Chase Thompson/ESPN.com Peter Rabbit, left, and Bob are accustomed to long trips, but there aren&apos;t many like the haul from Sonoma, Calif., to the shop in North Carolina. 

The No. 18 hauler drivers are very accommodating with our request but you can tell how anxious they are to get home. They give us some great sound bites about the job, friends and


They recognize how hard the trip was but understand it&apos;s part of the job they&apos;ve chosen. We break down our gear, load up the car and point it towards North Carolina.


 Tuesday: Just outside Nashville, Tenn., 3 p.m. CST 
The crew is getting giddy about getting on the home stretch. From Nashville, Interstate 40 is almost a straight shot to Huntersville, N.C. We have only one more highway -- Interstate 77 -- after I-40 and then we&apos;re there.


Peter Rabbit and Bob can&apos;t wait to see their families. The smiles on their faces go ear to ear as the miles click by. The long haul from Sonoma to Huntersville has to be the most trying of the Cup Series road trips. It&apos;s hard on equipment and people but for NASCAR to put on the best show possible, the hauler drivers have to do their jobs without question.


The minivan gang of Jen, Chase, Joe and Kevin are quiet in the car, maybe doing some reflecting on the journey or more likely exhaustion has set in. The silence is only broken with the retelling of stories from the road that get huge belly laughs from the tired travelers. Over 2,000 miles and we&apos;re still friends on good speaking terms.


 Tuesday: I-70 between Kansas City and St. Louis, 4:15 a.m. CST 
I had finally fallen asleep and was dreaming of going into the Beyond section at Bed, Bath&amp;Beyond with Alyssa Milano, when Jen grabs my left leg all the way from the driver&apos;s seat. She tells me she swore she saw the Silver Surfer from the Fantastic Four movie coming out of the back of the No. 18 haulerand can I take over driving for a while.


Like the Southern Gentleman I am, I agree.


 Tuesday: Just past Kansas City, Mo., 3:21 a.m. CST 
So Peter Rabbit and the No. 18 Hauler pull into yet another Pilot gas station for yet another $500 fillup and a good stretch of the legs.
We do the same until we see those lovely plastic bags covering all the pumps designated for autos. Our driver at the time, Jen, asks the cashier (who happens to be smoking outside at a gas station), if they have any gas at all. The slightest hesitation on the cashier&apos;s part and a misdirected point prompt Jen to immediately peel out of the Pilot and head across the street to another gas station. This solidifies my thought that if Jen hasn&apos;t cracked, she&apos;s definitely run out of patience.


We did find someone who cracked. The lonely female gas station attendant who apparently was not expecting any customers this night. While Peter and Bob were smoothly filling up their dual 125 gallon tanks, we on the other hand were finding it difficult to fill up our 20 gallon tank. First the attendant came out from behind her bulletproof cage and accused me of breaking the pump because I was slamming the nozzle against the start button.


Then she told me to move the car to another pump, but Jen had the car keys and was inside looking at celebrity magazines. She finally came out, noticed I had not put a drop of gas in the car, and was deep in conversation with the attendant. Jen&apos;s fuse becoming shorter, she said &quot;I can&apos;t listen to this,&quot; and got in the car and shut the door.


Meanwhile, inside the car Joe was mesmerized by a giant moth that had landed on the back of Kevin&apos;s seat. He claims it was so big it was wearing combat boots. At that point, Kevin decided to stretch his arms behind his head, touching the giant moth. Kevin, 6-foot-1 and a solid 210 pounds, jumped out of his seat and out of the car.


 Tuesday: Kansas City, Mo., 2:54 a.m. CST 
A welcome sports sight jolts us out of our 70 mph trance. I notice Kaufmann Stadium, home of the Kansas City Royals to the side of the highway on our right. I quickly wake our cameraman Kevin out of his deep sleep in the front passenger seat. He grabs his camera, gets the shot, and falls back asleep. All within six seconds.


 Monday: No turnin&apos; back, 8:12 p.m. CST 
We have reached halfway and in NASCAR race terms that means the event can be called if weather should be a problem.


Well, not for us. The weather is fine and if we called it quits now I am sure we could not return to work without being run out of town. The joy of being 50 percent of the way home was even felt back in the No. 18 hauler. When reached for comment, Bob said, &quot;I wish we were home now but at this pace we&apos;ll be in Charlotte ahead of schedule.&quot;


The sun sets with morale in both vehicles very high.


 Monday: HELLO NEBRASKA!!, 4:14 p.m. MST 
The Cornhusker State never looked so good. With Wyoming finally in our rear-view mirror, we plow forward toward North Carolina.


 Monday: Wyomingmaybe we like it here and we&apos;ll stay, 3:33 p.m. MST 
Joe is still driving, Kevin is playing co-pilot while resting his eyes, and Jen and I are surfing the web looking for the juiciest celebrity gossip. Come to find out, info on the private lives of Hollywood&apos;s brightest is a guilty pleasure for both of us. We delight in the latest breakups, shakeups and incarcerations of celebrities.
During all this gossip searching there is a Alyssa Milano hot or not flareup.


A few minutes go by and we agree to disagree on each other&apos;s stance on the mega-talented superstar. Those last words are mine, not Jen&apos;s.


 Monday: Guess where?, 2:30 p.m. MST 
I will give you one guess which state we are in. Hint. It starts with a &quot;W&quot; and ends with &quot;yoming.&quot;


This stop is an extended one because the gas tanks of the Hauler are bone dry. It cost them $500 to fill up. So I jumped at the chance to change my clothes, the same outfit I wore at the track all day Sunday and all night in the van.


I&apos;m not the most nimble of fellows but I believe I changed my clothes in the backseat of the van in like 5 minutes.


That might be a world record for changing clothes in the backseat of a minivan at a truck stop. And if you&apos;re wondering, all the doors were closed and the windows are tinted so no one got a free show. With a fresh outfit on, I am ready for some Wendy&apos;s goodness inside the truck stop.


In line waiting for my order, some female truckers asked us where we&apos;re headed? They think the four of us (Jen, Kevin, Joe and myself) are driving the No. 18 hauler. We don&apos;t correct them and begin to exchange trucker clichés. So it only took us like 1,000 miles to be completely accepted into the trucker community and we don&apos;t even drive a truck. Man, life on the road does have its perks. See I told you this entry would be fullkind of like me after a nice meal.


 Monday: Still in Wyoming&apos;s grasp, 1:40 p.m. MST 
Hopefully we are nearing the end of the great state of Wyoming. Driving through part prairie and rock canyon has a sort of peaceful feeling. The crew is all awake but we haven&apos;t said much to each other in awhile.


It may be all the miles we&apos;ve logged but I would like to think it&apos;s the picturesque American landscape that has us in its spell as the reason our chatter is at an all-time low.



 Monday: Wyomingstill, 1:10 p.m. MST 
I know there are great drivers in the world like A.J. Foyt, Mario Andretti, Jeff Gordon and Dale Earnhardt, but I would like to nominate another for that list; our audio guy Joe.

 Chase Thompson/ESPN.com The Interstate Batteries hauler can run up a hefty fuel bill on a cross-country trek. 


He has managed to make great time all the while following a semi loaded with two racecars. We even took a side trip down an unpaved road looking for an old ghost town and Joe handled the minivan like he was born to race on dirt. So he gets my vote as all-time road-trip driver.


While Jen is not driving she is playing navigator. Her skills at that are not as sharp as say Christopher Columbus.


We were looking for the Continental Divide and she said it was about 50 miles ahead. Just as she finished that sentence we see the sign for the Divide and thanks to the quick camera work from Kevin we got the shot. Jen&apos;s navigation is OK if you like to be 50 or so miles off your target.


I have listed what others are doing on this trip and you are probably wondering what does Chase contribute to the group? Well, besides blogging I&apos;m the moral compass and morale booster.


Every trip needs a guy to say to the others, &quot;that&apos;s a good idea,&quot; or, &quot;I don&apos;t think that idea will work,&quot; or, &quot;good job everybody,&quot; and &quot;hey, when are we going to eat again?&quot;


So consider the question of what Chase is doing on the trip answered.

 Monday: STILL in the middle of Wyoming, 12:50 p.m. MST 
Geez! This is a big state to drive across. The crew is low on sleep but the job has to get doneI mean this story isn&apos;t going to get done by itselfit needs trained TV professionals to manage it to the end.


So far through Wyoming we are left with counting prairie dogs and cows to pass the time. The lack of sufficient radio stations has given way to us just listening to static with the faint hope of hearing a word or lyric we might recognize to pass the time.


Pearl of wisdom number 2. If you drive cross-country, satellite radio is a must. I would say its second behind fuel on the list of things needed for a trip this size.


 Monday: Middle of Wyoming, 10:49 a.m. MST 
We visited a truck stop called Little America in Little America, Wyo., and now we are back on the road 1,031 miles into our great journey.


The Little America truck stop did give us one of our brightest moments on the trip so farthe cleanest restrooms we&apos;ve seen.


The stop allowed us to reposition our cameras on the hauler and let Peter Rabbit get a bite to eat.


The meal looked like a mix of roasted peppers and potatoes. I am sure that&apos;s a delicacy in the hauler driver business but I am going to stick with your regular road-trip snacks.


 Monday: Bonneville Salt Flats, Utah, 5:50 a.m. PST 
What looks like the world&apos;s largest beach at first glance is really the famed Bonneville Salt Flats.

 Jennifer Chafitz/ESPN.com The No. 18 hauler rolls across the Bonneville Salt Flats. 


This setting will give us some of the best video as the green NASCAR hauler we are following is set against the flat wide-open dried-up lake bed.


The salt flats also provide a quick chance to play tourist, with picture taking and a closer look at the grains of salt that make up miles of barren Utah landscape.


Jen gathered up a handful of salt/dirt and brought it back to the minivan. I don&apos;t have any visual proof but I believe Jen might have tasted her salty dirt mix.


If the salty taste is true I think this is another sign of Jen cracking under the road trip pressure.


To be continued.


 Monday: Outside of Wendover, Utah, 5 a.m. MST 
After 594 miles, it&apos;s time to fill up again and do a little leg stretchingand maybe down a few cups of hot Pilot travel center truck stop coffee, which I&apos;ve been told by Joe (audio guru) is the best in all of Utah.


The rising of the sun brings us some great chances to get the video we need. Every couple of miles or so its like a Chinese fire drill as we pour out of the minivan, set up the tripod, set the camera and get the shot we need just as the No. 18 hauler whips by.


 Sunday: Outside Reno, Nev., 10:30 p.m. PST 
Its our first gas stop since leaving Infineon Raceway. Hauler drivers Peter Rabbit and Bob pull into a sight for sore eyes, a Pilot travel center truck stop. Peter Rabbit is greeted with shouts of &quot;hey Hollywood,&quot; from the driver of the No. 66 Jeff Green Best Buy hauler.


The two spark up a conversation about the afternoon&apos;s race. Peter Rabbit jokes about the No. 66 car, which caught fire during the race and is now sitting in the hauler stinking up the joint. After all the talking is done is time for the bad newsthe fuel bill.


The damage came to a whopping grand total $480. I asked Peter Rabbit about what kind of gas mileage the big rig gets and he said that is something he doesn&apos;t worry about. He &quot;just fills up when its empty and keeps going.&quot;


Our weary crew also got gas with a much lower total. But more importantly we got much-needed food.


We stopped at the home of the Whopper and each placed an order that would make any nutritionist shutter. Road trips this long are full of little pearls of wisdom. Well after my late-night burger fix, I had my first nugget of wisdom. I realized that cross-country jaunts are not for vegetarians.


After the stop and with full bellies, we passed the time by discussing one of the world&apos;s biggest issues. Is Alyssa Milano super-hot or not? The final vote was 3-1 for super-hot. After that meeting of the minds over Alyssa Milano, the crew started to drift off to sleepy land, except for Jen, the trusty driver for the first leg of the trip.


 Sunday: Sonoma, Calif., 6:41 p.m. PST 
So after 110 laps and 350 kilometers of stock car racing, the real race begins.

 Chase Thompson/ESPN.com Peter Rabbit may be waving from coast-to-coast. 


Our cast of characters includes (names may have been changed to protect the innocent) Peter Rabbit and Bob, hauler drivers for the No. 18 Interstate Batteries car driven by J.J. Yeley, television experts Jen and Chase, cameraman Kevin and audio guru Joe.


Next stop? Huntersville, N.C.


Stuck in race traffic and things on the road are already getting boring just one mile into the journey. Wait, did I say boring? Scratch that because 2.8 miles into the trip, Peter Rabbit shows his cat-like reflexes and speed behind the wheel by avoiding some rough-driving fans leaving Infineon Raceway.


After an afternoon at the track and in the sun sweating out all the beverages our trusty crew had the night before, the rental car is already starting to smell and I mean smell bad (possibly foot odor)so first thing on our list when we stop is to get a bunch of those taxi-cab air fresheners.


Our trip will take us 48 hours, hopefully, to complete and we will log 2,790 miles door-to-door.


So far we are winding through the hills of Sonoma. Early on, the morale of the crew is upbeat but we&apos;ve only gone 16 miles.


The feeling in the rental car is that after going through a few states, all the happy-go-lucky attitudes will change into anger and shouting.


If you like to bet on who is going to break first, then the smart money is on Jen. She is happy now, but say after 1,000 miles that will all change because cross-country trips like these have been know to turn the most wily TV veterans into weeping babies. So put money on Jen cracking first.


Jen is already starting to show cracks in the armor by whining about a little interstate traffic.


 Chase Thompson is an associate producer with ESPN&apos;s studio production group. He can be reached at chase.b.thompson@espn.com 

 Recommend 0 Tweet 0 Comments 0 Email Print 
 
ESPN TOP HEADLINES

 Report: Penn St. disregarded children&apos;s welfare Clips&apos; Griffin hurts knee at Team USA camp Source: Howard nixes Magic GM&apos;s new plea Knicks introduce veteran additions Kidd, Camby 

MOST SENT STORIES ON ESPN.COM

 MJ &apos;laughed&apos; at Kobe&apos;s Dream Team boast Report: Penn St. disregarded children&apos;s welfare China-made Team USA uniforms ignite anger Wojciechowski: Frank Beamer has staying power at Virginia Tech 
 
MORE FROM THE WEB
 
ESPN Conversations
 comments 
 + Add your comment View all comments 
 
Share the news about your favorite sports and teams! Learn more» 
 Learn more Logged into Facebook as 
 
 Facebook Share ESPN with your friends 
What is this?

 Learn about sharing your ESPN activites on Facebook» 

 Close 
 
 Social Sharing ON ▼ 
 Social Sharing ON OFF▼ Remind me every time I add an event to my Activity 
 Learn more Register on ESPN Not you? Log out of Facebook Remove this experience 
 
 My Activity▼ 
 Recently shared to your timeline: 
 
 
Share ESPN with your friends

Your friend shared this story on Facebook. Share ESPN with your friends to see everything they&apos;re reading and watching, and then share the latest news about the sports and teams you care about most!
 ESPN read an article . ESPN Like · Comment · Share · Share ESPN with your friends 
 
 
 SPORTS 
 NFL MLB NBA NHL College Football College Basketball Soccer NASCAR 
 
 
 MORE 
 Racing Golf Tennis Boxing MMA Recruiting Olympic Sports Horse Racing 
 
 
 FANTASY 
 Football Baseball Streak for the Cash 

 
 SPORTSNATION 
 Polls Chats Community 
 
 
 VIDEO 
 Most Recent Highlights 

 
 PLAYBOOK 
 Sports Passport Sports Calendar Arcade Contests 
 
 
TOOLS
 Contact Us Member Services myESPN ESPN Alerts Developer Center Corrections Daily Line RSS 
 
 
 TV LISTINGS 
 
 ESPN3 
 
 RADIO 
 
 ESPN THE MAGAZINE 
 
 SHOP 
 
 SPORTSCENTER 
 
 TEAM ESPN 
 
 ESPN FRONT ROW 
 
 
 

 MyESPN NFL MLB NBA NHL NCAA FB NCAA BB NASCAR SOCCER GOLF TENNIS BOXING MMA MORE SPORTS INSIDER SN RADIO &amp;MORE espnW &amp;PLAYBOOK FANTASY &amp;GAMES WATCH 

 
 NASCAR Home Motorsports Home Cup: Standings Results Schedule Drivers Fantasy Local Nationwide: Schedule Truck: Schedule Tickets 
 ESPN.com: Help | PR Media Kit | Advertise on ESPN.com | Sales Media Kit | Interest-Based Ads | Corrections | Contact Us | Site Map | Patents | Jobs at ESPN | Supplier Information 
©2012 ESPN Internet Ventures. Terms of Use and Privacy Policy and Safety Information/Your California Privacy Rights are applicable to you. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
