<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009097" url="http://www.eatinfrederick.com/Restaurant/389/Mediterranean_Grill/" time="2012-07-13-02:29" support="10" score="0.02310822278766244" bingtitle="Mediterranean Grill, Frederick, MD - Ratings &amp; Reviews - Eat In ..." webtitle="Mediterranean Grill, Frederick, MD - RatingsReviews - Eat In Frederick, MD">
			<query id="000353" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="001326" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000516" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000680" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="001324" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000292" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="001106" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="001138" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000523" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="001339" bing-rank="227"/>
	<description>I absolutely love the food at this restaurant. I have been eating here for over ... soup, two of the large appetizer trays ... It&apos;s not a fast food restaurant but I would ...</description>
	<body>
		Add a Restaurant Contact 
 
 Eat In Frederick 

Life&apos;s too short to eat bad food.
 
 All Restaurants Recently Reviewed Highest Rated 
 
 Loading... Search by filter: 
 
 Cuisines Locations 

 - Cusines - - Locations - 
 
Popular Cuisines

 American Chinese Coffee Houses Italian Mexican Pizza Steak Houses 
 
All Cuisines

 African American Asian Bagels Bakeries Barbeque Bars Bistro Brazilian Breakfast Burmese Cafe Cafeteria Cajun Caribbean Carry Out Catering Chicken Chinese Coffee Houses 

 Continental Convenience Stores Country Cuban Deli Desserts Diners Doughnuts Ethiopian Family Fast Food Fine Dining French German Greek Grills Grocery Stores Hamburgers Ice Cream Indian 

 International Irish Italian Jamaican Japanese Korean Kosher Latin American Malaysian Mediterranean Mexican Middle Eastern Mongolian Pakistani Pasta Pizza Portuguese Pretzels Pubs Restaurants 

 Salads Salvadoran Sandwiches Seafood South American Southwestern Spanish Steak Houses Sushi Sweets Taiwanese Tea Rooms Tex Mex Thai Vegetarian Vietnamese Waterfront Wine Bars Wineries 
 
All Locations

 Adamstown Boonsboro Braddock Heights Brunswick Buckeystown Catoctin Clarksburg Emmitsburg 

 Frederick Gaithersburg Hyattstown Ijamsville Jefferson Knoxville Lewistown Libertytown 

 Linganore Middletown Monrovia Mt. Airy Mt. Pleasant Myersville New Market Point of Rocks 

 Thurmont Union Bridge Urbana Walkersville Waynesboro Westminster Woodsboro 

 From: 
 We won&apos;t store your address on our systems. 
 Mediterranean Grill 
 
 5221A Buckeystown Pike, Frederick, MD 21704 · 301-620-1666 
 Review this Restaurant 
Post a Review
 
Ratings
 Overall: 
 Food: 
 Service: 
 Name E-mail Review * Enter the Verification Text * 
 Submit Review Verification text did not match - please try again. Add Yours 
Reviews (50)
 
Post a Review
 
Ratings
 Overall: 
 Food: 
 Service: 
 Name E-mail Review * Enter the Verification Text * 
 Submit Review Verification text did not match - please try again. 
Anonymous
 
I absolutely love the food at this restaurant. I have been eating here for over 5 years. HOWEVER, other than the pretty ambiance, the food is the only thing that is good about this place. Best hummus I have ever had, great paninis, awesome salads, awesome desserts. Portion sizes are okay. 

The bruschetta is silly because it comes with a decent sized bowl of the bruschetta salsa and one very small piece of bread. You get charged a $1 a piece for every extra piece (and I am talking really small). What are you supposed to do, spoon the tomatoes in your mouth?

They will charge you for anything extra you want. They are not at all flexible about sides. If you want a small side of hummus (that you have said you are willing to pay for) you are told no that you have to buy the whole $7 appetizer. 

The managers are always quite rude and really could care less if you don&apos;t like the food, service, or options. 

It also often can take 30-45 minutes to get your food after you order it. 
Honestly, the only reason I go back is because I like the food so much and can&apos;t get hummus that good anywhere else. But the managers are horrible and they penny pinch.

 Permalink 

 0 February 21, 2012 
Anonymous
 
This place is wonderful! The food, clean atmosphere and friendly, knowledgable staff really makes the whole experience. I would recommend to anyone...

 Permalink 

 0 March 15, 2011 
Amy
 
Love eating there, lots of choices for vegetarians.ymmmm making me hungry writing about it i might go there again tonite.

 Permalink 

 0 May 31, 2010 
Anonymous
 
AMAZING! The food is delicious and it is all served with generous portions. Everything is fresh and homemade including the pita bread. I found the service to be great and the staff to all be extremely kind. I highly recommend experiencing this restaurant for yourself. It&apos;s a very classy addition to Frederick!

 Permalink 

 0 May 23, 2010 
LTL
 
Overall, we are pleased with this restaurant, even though it&apos;s very small and seating is not that comfortable. It is difficult to find a place to dine if you are a vegetarian or have food issues, but this place offers plenty of variety for all. Some of the dishes we have tried have been outstanding, yet some have not. But that is the nature of all dining establishments. What was disappointing though was not really get a &quot;hot&quot; cup of tea. They use the water that comes out of a cappuccino machine, which is not hot enough to brew tea. We also would like to see it served in a more manageable cup. If you are going to have large and heavy cups for tea, then the cups need larger handles. Some of the dishes were too heavy on the parsley, like the fattoush, so that was all we tasted. The bruschetta was a little heavy on the garlic, which was okay with us as we love garlic, but may not be for someone else. And all you get with this dish is a small piece of bread. It costs $1 for each additional small slice, and you need more bread since you do get a nice serving of bruschetta. The service is excellent, other than the waitstaff always bumping into the ends of tables because of the small size of the restaurant. One time a bump caused a cup of tea to spill over. So a few minor changes, and this place will become our &quot;Go To&quot; restaurant from now on.

 Permalink 

 0 April 28, 2010 
Anna
 
Ate here a few times. Liked the stuffed grape leaves and the tiramisu and sandwiches. Kabobs are a healthy choice, but dry.

 Permalink 

 0 February 10, 2010 
Anonymous
 
I&apos;ve never had anything bad here and most has been delicious. Wait staff has always been prompt and attentive and the atmosphere is intimate and relaxing. For those complaining about the price: Select 6 mezza (appetizers) for $30 and share them with a friend or two. Even those with hearty appetites will find this more than enough food for 2 and it will make a full meal for many people when shared between 3. I especially love their Fattoush (chopped vegetable salad with sumac, pomegranate essence and mint), hummus and baba ghanouj.

This place is an excellent choice if you have a mixed group of carnivores and vegetarians, as there are plenty of both options.

 Permalink 

 0 September 19, 2009 
Fred
 
Expensive&amp;slow service! The first time my wife and I went the chicken was pricey , which would be fine if it wasn&apos;t overcooked and dry. The second time we went with friends and waited 45 minutes for Gyros and asked how much longer. WOW... the server came back and told us the cook didn&apos;t know how much longer. We left without dinner and will not be visiting ever again. The worst part is the manager didn&apos;t even act like she cared.

 Permalink 

 0 August 12, 2009 
Fred
 
Went to dinner with friends and waited 45 minutes for gyros.We asked the server how much longer it would be and she told us that the cook didn&apos;t know because he was busy.We asked for our check and upon leaving I explained our situation to the owner/manager and she sided with the cook without an apology saying the cook was busy even though tables that ordered 20 minutes after us were getting food.I will NEVER go back,the service was terrible.

 Permalink 

 0 January 2, 2009 
Dave
 
very very slow service,waited almost 40 minutes for a sandwich.

 Permalink 

 0 July 25, 2008 
Adam
 
Delicious food. I got the Lebanon mezza sampler- which was perfect for me. A good price, a nice variety of tabouleh, kibbeh, hummus, pita, and two things I can only describe as empanadas. We went very late, so the service was a tad slow due to us having a large group for their small staff at that hour. The waiter was very courteous and prompt as possible. I plan on going back and recommend this restaurant!

 Permalink 

 0 June 23, 2008 
David
 
I do not understand why a Gyro takes over 40 minutes to make,very very disappointed and will never waste my time or money at this restaurant again!!!

 Permalink 

 0 June 1, 2008 
Anonymous
 
We used to go there frequently (at least a few times a month) especially when they first opened. At that time, the food was excellent, the portions generous, and the service friendly.

Since that time - the portions have become smaller, the food seems - at least to us - less fresh - and the service is hit or miss.

I would say at present, the food is decent - if not a little overpriced. However, for Frederick it is not bad.

 Permalink 

 0 May 7, 2008 
Mama Hen
 
best place to eat in Frederick. They use organic ingredients, and use care in the preparation. And you can tell . . best hummus I&apos;ve ever had. We usually go in and order several appetizers and split them - we like those better than the main course selections. Wine list is also good. Love it!! Great for vegetarians and omnivores alike.

 Permalink 

 0 April 5, 2008 
Anonymous
 
It&apos;s obvious that most of the patrons have never had &quot;real&quot; Middle Eastern food. This is a fairly good copy, but lacks the lemony zest and important ingredients (bulgar) that make the dishes authentic. Tabouli is not all parsley and it does have a fair amount of lemon juice. Grape leaves are never overcooked to be considered good and are prepared, again, with an adequate amount of lemon juice. Try a real Middle Eastern restaurant outside of Frederick.

 Permalink 

 0 January 22, 2008 
Jenni O&apos;Neil
 
I love the Med Grill. Great food especially for vegetarians like me:-) I am going there this weekend. Affordable, nice atmosphere and nice waitstaff. My favorite place in frederick. 

What I do not understand is the people who go to a Med resteraunt and order chicken fingers or grilled cheese...why? Maybe you should take your children to McDonalds instead. 

PS: Alot of the portions can be split. That is what I do with my girlfriends.

I eat out alot and let me tell you...this place is well worth the visit.

Plus occasionaly they have belly dancers. So Neat!

 Permalink 

 0 August 23, 2007 
Lore
 
I have eaten at this particular spot for MONTHS and on a regular basis. No problems...food is great, service is good...I think I am a picky eater and I LOVE this place!! I always try to mix it up but seem to get the &quot;sampler&quot; mixed platter very often! YUM!!!

 Permalink 

 0 August 6, 2007 
Anonymous
 
Love this place. Owner is very nice. Food is great, fresh and well priced. An unusual find for Frederick!

 Permalink 

 0 June 17, 2007 
Paige
 
The food is amazing. The spinach sambousek appetizers is to die for. The service is very nice and friendly. They always made sure I was satisfied. I don&apos;t mind waiting for the food (and the wait is reasonable) I understand their food is fresh, unlike other franchise restaurants that pre-cook their meats the night before. I went with some friends on a Saturday night and they had a belly dancer, is was very entertaining. My server also informed me that there is wine tasting everyother friday, which i need to look into. Over all I think the food is great. Its filling and they give you nice portions, and to top it all off it&apos;s healthy for you. I deffinately recommend it

 Permalink 

 0 May 9, 2007 
Niki
 
GREAT place with amazing food. Always clean, great atmosphere and decor, WORLDS better than the chain restaurants in the same shopping center.

The outdoor tables are lovely during warmer weather and the chicken kabobs are incredible. Be sure to try the smoothies from the juice bar next door, they are incredible as well! I love this place - amazing food i dont feel guilty about afterwards.

 Permalink 

 0 April 25, 2007 
Anonymous
 
The food is delicious and fresh. The service is good overall but sometimes can take a little longer when it gets busy, but its def. worth the wait. The food is fairly priced when taking into consideration how unique the cuisine is to our area and the obvious time and care that goes into preparing such aesthetically pleasing entress and apps. Make sure to bring along you&apos;re sense of adventure, because you are certain to discover something new and delicious.

 Permalink 

 0 April 10, 2007 
Anonymous
 
awesome food! wonderful servers! the food IS obviously fresh and so healthy. I absolutely love it! take your whole family!

 Permalink 

 0 February 10, 2007 
Irene
 
In regards to the last person&apos;s comment, it is extremely false. The food is NOT pre made, hense why it takes a bit of time for the food to come out. It&apos;s not a fast food resturant. It&apos;s a small resturant, not a huge corporate business, so there are not 10 cooks and 10 servers for every individual customer. (Please note the obvious sarcasam there.) The servers who do work there are very friendly and professional. Their service is not terrible by any means! The food there is obviously cooked absolutely fresh. Unlike more large resturants, which precook all their meat, the Mediterranean Grill does not. Hence again why it does take a bit of time for the food (30 mins. is the lastest it&apos;s taken for my meals ). The food is wonderful and the atmosphere is wonderful. For anyone who wants to enjoy healthy, delicious food, I would recommend the Mediterranean Grill any given day!

 Permalink 

 0 February 10, 2007 
Justine
 
Disappointing because this restaurant had good potential. Food was dry and kabobs were burnt. Fish didn&apos;t taste fresh. However, service was very good and prompt. In the end, I had to resort to eating my kids chicken tenders and fries. I guess they couldn&apos;t go wrong with that... but who can&apos;t go wrong with that. We also noticed the people behind us who left before us left 1/2 of their food on their plate. Would not recommend this place unless they get a good chef who knows how to cook.

 Permalink 

 0 January 19, 2007 
Lanie
 
Great location at the Promenade... Food tastes good yet its a bit bland for me because I like garlic in my Hummas. Staff is very accommodating and friendly!

 Permalink 

 0 December 27, 2006 
Anonymous
 
I had no complaints with the restaurant until the last time I had lunch there. I ordered a grilled cheese sandwhich for my daughter, and the cheese was spoiled on it. I told the waitstaff, and he blew us off. I haven&apos;t been back for months since then.

 Permalink 

 0 November 27, 2006 
Anonymous
 
The food is good, but not cheap, and the service is terrible. Going there for lunch on a weekday will take at least 1-2 hours (I experienced this on several occasions). They take a very long time to prepare a simple appetizer that is obviously pre-made (ex. hummus and flatbread). During our last visit while waiting for our food for over an hour and not complaining we asked to speak with the manger. Before we could say anything to the manager he yelled and lectured us. I will not patronize this establishment again.

 Permalink 

 0 September 7, 2006 
Kapil
 
Excellent reasonably priced food. Ideal location.

 Permalink 

 0 August 13, 2006 
Anonymous
 
Wow! Fresh food, expertly prepared, and nicely displayed....This is not your run of the mill eatery-quality restaurant. It&apos;s the real thing. Not cheap, but reasonably priced.

We liked it so much that we brought friends with us the next day! Try it....

 Permalink 

 0 August 4, 2006 
Lisa Y.
 
The food is very good with huge portions, some dishes are amazing. We tried the Lentil soup, two of the large appetizer trays, several sandwiches, several of the most popular entrees and all of the desserts. The wine list is adaquate for a small place and served nicely. It&apos;s always very clean and children are welcome. The outside tables are always in demand so get there early and wait for them. The service can be another story. I went 3 times in the month of June 2006 and had service from extremely attentive to just disgusting. On visit number 2, it took more than 30 minutes to order our food and another 40 minutes to get our entrees, which were incorrect and cold. Our third visit wasn&apos;t any better. They really should train the servers better or hire experienced help, this could be one of the best places in Frederick if the service was improved. They do have a take out menu, and whatever you do don&apos;t order pastry from next door. They give you this option for dessert and it is the oldest tasting pies and pastry I have ever tasted, YUCK! Order the Grill&apos;s Baklava or lime sorbet. They are wonderful and portions are generous for sharing.

 Permalink 

 0 June 23, 2006 
Eli
 
the food is fantastic, the beautiful blends of flavors tantalizes my mouth every time I go there.

 Permalink 

 0 June 21, 2006 
Missterrys
 
Excellent! Excellent service. Excellent food. Excellent experience.

 Permalink 

 0 June 15, 2006 
Stan
 
Wonderful Treats!

 Permalink 

 0 April 23, 2006 
Anonymous
 
Great place to eat! Food is exceptional, authentic, and reasonably priced. Fast and friendly service, too!

 Permalink 

 0 April 8, 2006 
Angel
 
Best Hummus I&apos;ve ever had and the domalas are fantastic add the kabobs and I am a very happy diner!! Favorite place to eat in town!! Summer is great to dine here as you can sit outside before a movie or after and enjoy a light snack or a delicious meal! The decor is relaxing and gorgeous!

 Permalink 

 0 April 1, 2006 
Celia
 
Service is wonderful, food is great...an inexpensive treat.

 Permalink 

 0 November 9, 2005 
Anonymous
 
Wonderful place, I could eat there 2 or 3 times a week. The shwarma sandwiches are dead on perfect and I crave the Tabouleh. It is worth the trip.

 Permalink 

 0 November 8, 2005 
Rachel and Rocky
 
This is a great restaurant. The food is always fresh and delicious. I love it. It&apos;s not a fast food restaurant but I would not rate the service slow at all as other raters may have. It is good and timely and you can get it for pick up if you&apos;re in a rush.. call ahead. They are fantastic and their juice place is deeelicious too. Frederick needed both types of places. IT is key.

 Permalink 

 0 August 26, 2005 
Michael Srabian
 
Flat out one of the best places to eat in town. Clean, friendly service, fast&amp;hot. Me being Armenian, I have been looking for something like this near by. The Lebanese Mezza out of this world. Tastes like moms.

 Permalink 

 0 April 2, 2005 
Anonymous
 
This is the most unique/funky/tasty restaurant in town. Delicious shwarma sandwiches, pitas, hummas, soups and entrees. The service is homey and atmosphere takes you to &quot;another place.&quot; Great for dates and families. The juice bar next door, WildBerries, is of the same owner and has delicious juices and decadent desserts.

 Permalink 

 0 January 27, 2005 
Angela
 
This casual cafe is one of those awesome finds that you come across by accident and never want to forget. I eat out a lot and this is one of the best places that I&apos;ve been to. There were four of us and each of us got something different so that we could try a variety. All of the dishes were absolutely delicious. For dessert, try the Tiramisu. I love Tiramisu and they had one of the best that I&apos;ve ever tasted and that includes the ones from Italian restaurants. Also, the service was also very friendly and the prices were very reasonable.

 Permalink 

 0 January 13, 2005 
Anonymous
 
Expensive food and slow service???? My experiences here have been outstanding. The food is fabulous- great menu, good portions, very yummy, overall phenomenal IMHO, and we&apos;ve never had a problem w/service. This is a great place to eat if you&apos;re in the area and don&apos;t want to fight the nonsense at Friday&apos;s or Macarroni Grill. Better, more inspiring food, and a much better dining experience.

 Permalink 

 0 December 19, 2004 
Kasey Crist
 
My favorite restaurant in Frederick, yummy Mediterranean food, the service is usally prompt and friendly, and the new smoothie and bakery section next door makes it easy to take home a nice dessert.

 Permalink 

 0 November 26, 2004 
Waynesboro
 
Fabulous find! Three of us ordered various Middle Eastern combination platters--every single item on all of them were beyond delicious!

Service was amazingly friendly and fast, prices great, and the portions were very generous!

Decor is lovely&amp;relaxing, with lots of interesting items to look at. Overall, we were very impressed and will be back soon!

 Permalink 

 0 November 20, 2004 
Anonymous
 
They have the best chicken gyros and onion rings. I also had the fresh squeezed lemonade and thought it was great. Good service and great atmosphere.

 Permalink 

 0 October 25, 2004 
Anonymous
 
The Food is good and has an authentic taste close to food you would get in the middle east. I recommend the falafel or the shwarma platter

 Permalink 

 0 October 2, 2004 
Anonymous
 
OMG! I love this place! Food is authentic and delicious. Well worth the money and time.

 Permalink 

 0 September 30, 2004 
Anonymous
 
Food is good, but expensive. Ask anyone who has ever been there - don&apos;t stop unless you have a great deal of time to spare. Service is very, very slow.

 Permalink 

 0 July 14, 2004 
Anonymous
 
Excellent menu, friendly service and extremely reasonable prices!! Very unique feel inside, beautiful wall fountains. The appetizers and paninis are the only dishes I can rate, and both are very pleasing!

 Permalink 

 0 July 10, 2004 
Missterrys
 
Nice little restaurant with great food. Ideal for where it is situated. Well done!

 Permalink 

 0 June 29, 2004 Add a Location &gt;&gt; 
Other Locations

District of Columbia

 Washington, DC 

Florida

 Bonita Springs, FL Boynton Beach, FL Bradenton, FL Coconut Creek, FL Coral Gables, FL Daytona Beach, FL Deerfield Beach, FL Delray Beach, FL Fort Myers, FL 

 Fort Pierce, FL Homestead, FL Jupiter, FL Kissimmee, FL Largo, FL Lauderhill, FL Margate, FL North Lauderdale, FL North Miami, FL 

 North Miami Beach, FL North Port, FL Oakland Park, FL Ocala, FL Palm Beach Gardens, FL Palm Coast, FL Pensacola, FL Pinellas Park, FL Port Orange, FL 

 Sanford, FL Sarasota, FL Tamarac, FL Titusville, FL Wellington Village, FL West Palm Beach, FL Weston, FL 

Maryland

 Annapolis, MD Bethesda, MD 

 Frederick, MD Gaithersburg, MD 

 Hagerstown, MD Ocean City, MD 

 Rockville, MD Silver Spring, MD 

North Dakota

 Fargo, ND 

Virginia

 Chincoteague, VA 

West Virginia

 Charles Town, WV 
 Site Map &gt;&gt; 
Copyright© Forward Bounding LLC Loading...
	</body>
</document>
