<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009682" url="http://grocerycouponhelper.com/2009/08/12-pack-pepsi-products-512/" time="2012-07-13-03:04" support="2" score="0.006087323925650069" bingtitle="12 Pack Pepsi Products – 5/$12 | Grocery Coupon Helper" webtitle="12 Pack Pepsi Products5/$12 | Grocery Coupon Helper">
			<query id="000160" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000409" bing-rank="119"/>
	<description>When you Buy 2 12 Pack Pepsi Products you receive 3 12 Pack ... Condiments; Dairy/Refrigerated; Desserts; Facebook; Fast Food Restaurant Specials</description>
	<body>
		Grocery Coupon Helper 

Times are tough and saving money is important. Coupon savings with out the research.
 Aug 06 
 12 Pack Pepsi Products–5/$12 
 Posted by admin. Comment (0) . 
 Safeway has 12 Pack Pepsi Products on sale this week. When you Buy 2 12 Pack Pepsi Products you receive 3 12 Pack Pepsi Products for FREE. Plus you get one bag of selected varieties of Tostito’s Tortilla chips for FREE as well.
 
 





 
This entry was posted
 on Thursday, August 6th, 2009 at 11:53 am by admin. 
 
 Filed under: Beverage , Safeway , Weekly Sales .You can follow any responses to this entry through the RSS 2.0 feed. 
 
 You can leave a response , or trackback from your own site.
 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 XHTML: You can use these tags:&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 
 CAPTCHA Code * 
 
 
Our Coupon Savings Email
 Subscribe to our Newsletter. Get all of our postings via email every time they are updated. 
E-mail:
 

 Subscribe
 Unsubscribe

 
 
 
Pages

 Home About This Site Colorado Coupon Train Link with Us Printable Coupons Privacy Policy Suggestions/Comments Upromise Why“Clip”Coupons? 

Categories

 Albertson&apos;s Baked Goods Bakery Beverage Breakfast Candy Cleaning Products Condiments Dairy/Refrigerated Desserts Facebook Fast Food Restaurant Specials Frozen Groupon Gum/Mints Health and Beauty Holiday Sale Just a Thought King Soopers Meat MISC Out of Stock Items/Advertised Specials No Show Pantry Paper Products Pets Produce Safeway Smartco Sprouts Store Coupons Sunday Coupon Inserts Sunflower Market Thrift Stores Uncategorized Wal-Mart Walgreens Website Information Websites Weekly Sales 


Archives

 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 July 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 

Links

 Cellfire Coupons and Codes Coupons.com Denver Metro Moms Freebies, Deals, and Contests Grocery Saving Tips King Soopers Homeshop MyPoints Online Coupons Online Earning Guide P&amp;G eSaver Personal Finance Guide Ramblings of a Texas Housewife Shortcuts.com Smartsource Sunflower Market The Coupon Clippers The Coupon Master The Grocery Game Upromise WeUseCoupons.com Wow Coupons 
 
Content©Grocery Coupon Helper. Proudly powered by WordPress . For best results, please view with Firefox .
Stats: 20 queries. 0.652 seconds. Valid XHTML , Valid CSS , XFN . &quot;Red Delicious&quot; theme by Nicki Faulk .
Background courtesy of Country Clipart by Lisa. Stock image for header by Creapril
	</body>
</document>
