<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009352" url="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2305851/" time="2012-07-13-02:43" support="4" score="0.004432475952269293" bingtitle="Perceptions of Financial Payment for Research Participation among ..." webtitle="Perceptions of Financial Payment for Research Participation among African-American Drug Users in HIV Studies">
			<query id="001059" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="001044" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="001053" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="001047" bing-rank="46"/>
	<description>Payment of $20 was considered a minimum amount because less money would ... later time, but most replied that they would go immediately to a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Warning: The NCBI web site requires JavaScript to function. more... 
 We are sorry, but NCBI web applications do not support your browser, and may not function properly. More information here... 
 Resources 
 All Resources Chemicals&amp;Bioassays 
 BioSystems PubChem BioAssay PubChem Compound PubChem Structure Search PubChem Substance All Chemicals&amp;Bioassays Resources... 
 DNA&amp;RNA 
 BLAST (Basic Local Alignment Search Tool) BLAST (Stand-alone) E-Utilities GenBank GenBank: BankIt GenBank: Sequin GenBank: tbl2asn Genome Workbench Influenza Virus Nucleotide Database PopSet Primer-BLAST ProSplign Reference Sequence (RefSeq) RefSeqGene Sequence Read Archive (SRA) Splign Trace Archive UniGene UniSTS All DNA&amp;RNA Resources... 
 Data&amp;Software 
 BLAST (Basic Local Alignment Search Tool) BLAST (Stand-alone) Cn3D Conserved Domain Search Service (CD Search) E-Utilities GenBank: BankIt GenBank: Sequin GenBank: tbl2asn Genome ProtMap Genome Workbench Primer-BLAST ProSplign PubChem Structure Search SNP Submission Tool Splign Vector Alignment Search Tool (VAST) All Data&amp;Software Resources... 
 Domains&amp;Structures 
 BioSystems Cn3D Conserved Domain Database (CDD) Conserved Domain Search Service (CD Search) Structure (Molecular Modeling Database) Vector Alignment Search Tool (VAST) All Domains&amp;Structures Resources... 
 Genes&amp;Expression 
 BioSystems Database of Genotypes and Phenotypes (dbGaP) E-Utilities Gene Gene Expression Omnibus (GEO) Database Gene Expression Omnibus (GEO) Datasets Gene Expression Omnibus (GEO) Profiles Genome Workbench HomoloGene Map Viewer Online Mendelian Inheritance in Man (OMIM) RefSeqGene UniGene All Genes&amp;Expression Resources... 
 Genetics&amp;Medicine 
 Bookshelf Database of Genotypes and Phenotypes (dbGaP) Genetic Testing Registry Influenza Virus Map Viewer Online Mendelian Inheritance in Man (OMIM) PubMed PubMed Central (PMC) PubMed Clinical Queries RefSeqGene All Genetics&amp;Medicine Resources... 
 Genomes&amp;Maps 
 Database of Genomic Structural Variation (dbVar) GenBank: tbl2asn Genome Genome Project Genome ProtMap Genome Workbench Influenza Virus Map Viewer Nucleotide Database PopSet ProSplign Sequence Read Archive (SRA) Splign Trace Archive UniSTS All Genomes&amp;Maps Resources... 
 Homology 
 BLAST (Basic Local Alignment Search Tool) BLAST (Stand-alone) BLAST Link (BLink) Conserved Domain Database (CDD) Conserved Domain Search Service (CD Search) Genome ProtMap HomoloGene Protein Clusters All Homology Resources... 
 Literature 
 Bookshelf E-Utilities Journals in NCBI Databases MeSH Database NCBI Handbook NCBI Help Manual NCBI News PubMed PubMed Central (PMC) PubMed Clinical Queries All Literature Resources... 
 Proteins 
 BioSystems BLAST (Basic Local Alignment Search Tool) BLAST (Stand-alone) BLAST Link (BLink) Conserved Domain Database (CDD) Conserved Domain Search Service (CD Search) E-Utilities ProSplign Protein Clusters Protein Database Reference Sequence (RefSeq) All Proteins Resources... 
 Sequence Analysis 
 BLAST (Basic Local Alignment Search Tool) BLAST (Stand-alone) BLAST Link (BLink) Conserved Domain Search Service (CD Search) Genome ProtMap Genome Workbench Influenza Virus Primer-BLAST ProSplign Splign All Sequence Analysis Resources... 
 Taxonomy 
 Taxonomy Taxonomy Browser Taxonomy Common Tree All Taxonomy Resources... 
 Training&amp;Tutorials 
 NCBI Education Page NCBI Handbook NCBI Help Manual NCBI News Science Primer All Training&amp;Tutorials Resources... 
 Variation 
 Database of Genomic Structural Variation (dbVar) Database of Genotypes and Phenotypes (dbGaP) Database of Single Nucleotide Polymorphisms (dbSNP) SNP Submission Tool All Variation Resources... 
 
 How To 
 All How To Chemicals&amp;Bioassays DNA&amp;RNA Data&amp;Software Domains&amp;Structures Genes&amp;Expression Genetics&amp;Medicine Genomes&amp;Maps Homology Literature Proteins Sequence Analysis Taxonomy Training&amp;Tutorials Variation 
 Skip to main
 content Skip to
 navigation About NCBI Accesskeys 
 My NCBI Sign In Sign Out 
 PMC 
 US National Library of Medicine 
 National Institutes of Health Search term Search database All Databases PubMed Protein Nucleotide GSS EST Structure Genome Assembly BioProject BioSample BioSystems Books Conserved Domains Clone dbGaP dbVar Epigenomics Gene GEO DataSets GEO Profiles HomoloGene MeSH NCBI Web Site NLM Catalog OMIA OMIM PMC PopSet Probe Protein Clusters PubChem BioAssay PubChem Compound PubChem Substance PubMed Health SNP SRA Taxonomy ToolKit ToolKitAll UniGene UniSTS Search 
 Limits Advanced Journal list Help 
 
 Journal List &gt; J Gen Intern Med &gt; v.22(10); Oct 2007 &gt; PMC2305851 
 J Gen Intern Med. 2007 October; 22 (10) : 1403–1409. Published online 2007 August 1. doi: 10.1007/s11606-007-0319-9 PMCID: PMC2305851 
Perceptions of Financial Payment for Research Participation among African-American Drug Users in HIV Studies
 Jacquelyn Slomka , PhD, Sheryl McCurdy , PhD, Eric A. Ratliff , PhD, Sandra Timpson , PhD, and Mark L. Williams , PhD Division of Health Promotion and Behavioral Sciences, School of Public Health, University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston, 7000 Fannin, Houston, TX 77030 USA Jacquelyn Slomka, Phone: +713-500-9984, Fax: +713-500-9750, Email: Jacquelyn.Slomka/at/uth.tmc.edu . Corresponding author. Author information ► Article notes ► Copyright and License information ► Received November 15, 2006; Revised February 7, 2007; Accepted July 17, 2007. Copyright ©Society of General Internal Medicine 2007 This article has been cited by other articles in PMC. 
Abstract
 
BACKGROUND

Financial compensation for participating in research is controversial, especially when participants are recruited from economically disadvantaged and/or marginalized populations such as drug users. Little is known about these participants’own views regarding payment for research participation.
 
OBJECTIVE

The objective of the study was to elicit underserved minority drug users’views about monetary payments for participating in research.
 
DESIGN

Semi-structured in-depth interview study of motivations for and perceptions of participation in research was used.
 
PARTICIPANTS

Thirty-seven adult, economically disadvantaged African-American crack cocaine smokers were the participants of the study.
 
APPROACH

Participants were recruited from among those taking part in three HIV prevention studies. Interviews were conducted at one of 2 research field offices located in underserved minority neighborhoods in Houston, Texas. Interviews lasting 30–45 min were recorded, transcribed, coded, and analyzed for categories and themes using both conventional and directed qualitative content analysis. This report addresses themes under the broad category of financial motivations for participating in research.
 
RESULTS

Participants viewed monetary payment for research as essential to attract participation and desirable to provide optional income. Payment for research participation was perceived as one potential income source among others. Participants considered self-determination a prerogative for themselves and others. They rejected the notion of payment for participation as encouraging drug use or as inducing risk taking.
 
CONCLUSIONS

Research regulators should consider participants’views of their desires and capacity for autonomous decisions about financial compensation for research rather than assume participants’diminished capacity due to poverty and/or drug use. Payment for research participation appears to be part of the“informal economy”that has been observed in underserved communities.
 KEY WORDS: undue inducement, drug use, HIV/AIDS, underserved minorities, ethics of payment for research 
INTRODUCTION

The offer of financial compensation is often used to recruit individuals to participate in research studies; yet the concept, method, and amount of payment to research participants remain controversial. 1 – 11 Some writers argue that financial compensation for research should be avoided except under very limited circumstances. 4 , 9 In practice, however, payment for participating in research is widespread, although researchers and Institutional Review Boards (IRBs) have yet to agree on the process and appropriate levels of payment. 12 

Little empirical information is available about the effects of financial compensation on research participation for individuals from low-income, uninsured, or marginal populations, such as those engaging in illicit drug use and/or at risk for HIV/AIDS. Such populations have been a focus of ethical concern because of perceptions that payment for their inclusion in research may make them vulnerable to excessive risk taking and exploitation, whereas their exclusion may deprive them of the benefits of research participation. 13 , 14 This paper examines the views of economically disadvantaged African-American drug users participating in HIV prevention research. Participants’views about financial compensation for research participation can inform recruitment practices for research studies that have the potential for improving the prevention and treatment of HIV/AIDS and drug use in this population.
 
BACKGROUND

Ethical concerns about paying individuals to participate in research have focused on“undue inducement,”defined as the provision of positive incentives at levels high enough to undermine potential participants’ability to act in their own best interests, thereby resulting in a risk of serious harm to individuals. 15 Emanuel 15 argues that even very large monetary payments to research participants are not“undue inducement”because adequate administrative ethical review of studies will preclude serious harms when participants are compensated according to market value. Others 16 suggest that payment for research participation at the level of unskilled labor would obviate undue inducement by including paid research participation as one opportunity among others to obtain comparable wages. Research payment comparable to wages for unskilled labor might also increase the likelihood that individuals would choose research participation voluntarily and not simply for financial gain. 16 

Questions about the role of payment in enabling drug users’addictive and illegal behaviors have been noted, but not subjected to rigorous investigation. 17 , 18 One recent study demonstrated that different levels of cash incentives to encourage research follow-up did not affect the rate of new drug use among participants in several substance abuse treatment programs. 19 Furthermore, moderate financial incentives appear to be effective for recruiting drug users in health education projects 17 and preventive research. 20 

Research on payment to participants in other research populations has illuminated several aspects of the controversy. Money increased participants’willingness to participate in hypothetical research studies, but higher payment levels did not change perceptions of risks of harm. 21 , 22 Higher payment levels had a greater influence on wealthy participants’agreement to participate in hypothetical research than on those of poorer participants. 21 As well, increased monetary payments influenced participants to conceal low-risk information from investigators, but such concealment was considered less detrimental to the research participant than to the scientific integrity of the research. 22 

Research participants themselves vary in their opinions about financial compensation for participation. For example, in a survey examining willingness to participate in a vaccine trial, less than half of the participants desired financial compensation, believing that payment could increase costs of research and introduce bias. 23 In a study of healthy participants’responses to a hypothetical hypertension clinical trial, respondents believed that large financial compensation would not prevent their consideration of research risks and that monetary rewards would induce others more so than themselves. 24 The populations in these studies had relatively high socioeconomic and educational levels. It is unknown whether the results apply equally to economically disadvantaged or marginal populations.
 
METHODS

 Design Semi-structured in-depth interviews were conducted to elicit participants’views of research and motivations for participation. Forty-one participants were recruited from 3 concurrent studies of African-American crack cocaine users, with or at risk for HIV infection. Two parent studies tested educational interventions to prevent HIV; the third provided hepatitis vaccination as a model for an HIV vaccine study. Of 41 interviews, 4 were excluded for methodological or technical reasons, leaving 37 for analysis. This study was approved by the IRB of the University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston. To enhance confidentiality, participants were given an informational letter in lieu of a signed consent.

 Setting/Population Participants were adult African-American drug users from parent studies who had given prior consent to be contacted. Participants were drawn from two urban neighborhoods with large numbers of economically disadvantaged African-Americans. Interviews were conducted at 1 of 2 field offices designed for the parent projects. Demographic and population characteristics are listed in Table  1 .
 
 Table 1 
 Demographic and Population Characteristics a 
 Focus of Interviews Participants were questioned about their perceptions of research and attitudes and motivations for participating in research studies. Depending on time constraints, 2 or 3 hypothetical research scenarios were used to prompt specific discussion about perceptions of risks, benefits, inconveniences, appropriate levels of financial compensation, and additional information desired to inform decisions to participate. 21 , 24 , 25 Summaries of scenarios are found in Table  2 .
 
 Table 2 
 Summaries of Hypothetical Study Scenarios 
 Data Collection Interviews were conducted over a 3-mo period, between February and May 2006. To ensure consistency, all interviews were conducted by a single investigator (JS). General questions guided the interviews and“probe”questions (Can you say more about that?) were used to explore and cross-check new information and encourage participant elaboration. 28 Interviewees were paid $20 for their time and travel costs. Interviews lasted 30–45 min and were audio-recorded and transcribed.

 Analysis A single investigator (JS) coded and analyzed the data for thematic patterns using a combination of conventional content analysis, which derives categories from the data, and directed content analysis, which uses preexisting theoretical categories for analysis. 29 Individual data segments consisting of an idea or theme embedded in the text of a word, phrase, or narrative were coded and grouped under larger categories. Data segments relating to large thematic categories were further analyzed for subthemes.Quality and credibility of data were established through rigorous and continuous review of tapes and transcripts to critique and improve interview methods and interpret the interviewer’s effect on participants’responses. Trustworthiness of data was also verified through an interviewer assessment of participants’motives for providing information. Concepts and emerging data patterns were continuously cross-checked within and across interviews to confirm or negate participants’statements. 28 , 30 , 31 , 32 A second investigator (EAR) reviewed the transcripts to identify competing or alternative interpretations. 33 All investigators participated in reviewing and refining data interpretation and analysis. Differences were minor, and discrepancies were negotiated to achieve agreement.
 
RESULTS

In examining participants’perceptions of financial compensation for participating in research, four themes were identified: (1) financial compensation as a prerequisite for research participation; (2) ethics of payments to impoverished drug users; (3) research income as an aid to economic survival; and (4) poverty, drug use, and risks of everyday life.
 
Financial Compensation as a Prerequisite for Research Participation

All participants agreed in general with the provision of money for participating in research. No one declined financial compensation for participating in the study interviews. Several individuals noted that financial aspects were secondary to the educational benefits they believed they were receiving from HIV prevention studies, although they were initially attracted by the offer of money. A few also stated that research participants should not receive compensation for their participation because they were already benefiting by learning about drug use and HIV/AIDS risk. In general, money was seen by interviewees as a necessary incentive to attract research participants and as extra income for people in need (Table  3 a,b,c).
 
 Table 3 
 Examples of Theme“Financial Compensation as a Prerequisite for Research Participation” 
Interviewees were open and explicit about their expectations and need for payment for participating in research. The belief that people are motivated by economic incentives was frequently expressed. For example, one interviewee observed that“A lot of these people come in just for the money. They don’t give a damn about your research. I’m just putting it out there like it is.”Another respondent advised telling potential participants about compensation immediately“....Because a lot of people won’t even sit and listen to what you’ve got to say if you don’t give them an amount up front.”

In response to questions about monetary influences on risk assessment, some respondents said they would participate in a study if the price was right in spite of the risks, whereas others said they would decline certain risky studies no matter what amount of money was offered. Most respondents viewed the $20 payment for participation in this and other behavioral research projects as an appropriate amount, whereas some suggested higher payment, comparing the use of their time to a day’s pay at minimum wage. For the three hypothetical research scenarios, those who perceived risks tended to view higher payments as appropriate compensation for increased risk.

Payment of $20 was considered a minimum amount because less money would be a“waste of time”and compete with other income sources. Also, most interviewees believed that drug users with access to money were likely to use it to purchase street drugs. Based on this assumption, a number of participants believed that $10, the minimum needed for a drug purchase, would be necessary to attract participants. Although some participants believed that drug users would accept compensation as low as $5, payment in the amount of $20 generally was considered appropriate: even if one did buy street drugs with the money, enough would remain for the purchase of necessities or luxury items. Whether or not they used the money for street drugs, a payment as little as $5 or $10 was considered ineffective as a recruitment incentive and unfair to research participants:
 
Ethics of Payments to Impoverished Drug Users

When asked to comment about concerns some researchers and IRBs have about“exploiting”or“using”impoverished drug users by paying them for research participation, interviewees expressed several different opinions. Some felt that both parties, researchers and participants, were using each other (a and b in Table  4 ). Others believed that if they were being“used”by investigators, it was to their advantage, given the extra income and other benefits of research participation. Faced with the everyday reality of unemployment or lacking a consistent source of income, interviewees expressed views similar to one respondent who remarked,“Nowadays you got to do what you got to do to survive.”This person viewed research as a“good thing...because they’re helping you and you’re helping them.”Another participant opined that offering money for taking part in research was not exploitation because researchers also need to do their job to survive (c in Table  4 ). Other participants disagreed with the notion of exploitation, saying“I have a choice to say no,”and by noting that people cannot be exploited against their will. One participant explained,“If you feel like you’ve been taken advantage of, don’t do it. It’s just that simple, you know. If I felt like I had been taken advantage of, I wouldn’t have even came down anyway....”
 
 Table 4 
 Examples of Theme of“Ethics of Payments to Impoverished Drug Uses” 
Another issue of ethical concern for some researchers and IRBs is that monetary compensation for drug-using research participants would encourage them to use the money to purchase more illicit drugs or delay stopping drug use. While participants typically assumed that drug users with money would spend at least some of it on drugs, they disagreed with the premise that payment for research participation would encourage further drug use. Participants believed that drug users who take part in research should be paid. Money was not an incentive to use drugs because individuals could obtain drugs without money (d in Table  4 ). Respondents noted that“...you can’t tell them what to use it (the money) for...what they do with it you have no control over that...you can’t say if it’s wrong or right because you don’t know what they’re going to do with the money.”Overall, participants viewed themselves and others as free agents capable of determining for themselves the most appropriate ways to use money obtained as compensation for research participation.

To explore participants’views of“undue inducement”, participants were asked about pharmaceutical companies or others willing to pay large sums for research participation. Interviewees viewed the offer of large amounts of financial compensation in different ways. According to some respondents, large financial incentives might raise questions for potential research participants about whether all the risks of a study were being disclosed. Others believed that if a large amount of money was offered, individuals would be more likely to provide false information to investigators and“say anything”to obtain the money. However, for minimal risk public health research, participants were concerned that relatively large payments for research participation (e.g., $50 or $100 instead of the usual $20) would attract too many people, and“chaos”would ensue. One interviewee remarked that a $50 payment should be the limit“So it won’t be so hectic out there.”Others remarked,“Y’all would have a line out the door”of people willing to participate in the research. Another predicted:“Yeah, well you’ll have fights out there and everything...Or it would be big confusion out there....”Participants perceived appropriate levels of compensation as proportional to the study’s level of risk of harm or inconvenience.
 
Research Income as an Aid to Economic Survival

According to interviewees, people continuously search for money for daily living expenses. Participation in research is one venue for obtaining needed cash to ensure everyday survival (a in Table  5 ). One participant reiterated this view when asked about the sleep disturbance research scenario and whether people should be invited to participate in it without financial compensation. He replied that“...I’m trying to find not so much a hustle of some sort, but just some way to make money and keep it generating. So I’d be looking for that, and I’d overlook this (research study) if it were free.”In regard to unpaid research participation, another person noted,“Why should I? I could be doing something else to try and make some money....”
 
 Table 5 
 Examples of Theme“Research Income as an Aid to Economic Survival” 
Spending on drugs was considered secondary if a person needed food or if he or she had others depending on him or her. For example, when asked how they would spend the $20 payment for their interview, some participants said they might spend part on drugs at a later time, but most replied that they would go immediately to a fast food restaurant or grocery store. As one interviewee said,“It’s not drugs that was the first thing went in my mind. Closest thing on my mind was getting a hamburger or something.”One woman explained that necessities such as food for her children and gasoline for their car would take priority over drug use (b in Table  5 ). Another explained her decision to participate in a clinical trial for $1500 was motivated by the need to pay household bills out of concern for her children (c in Table  5 ). During the latter clinical trial, this interviewee described another woman who had also enrolled in the drug study. According to the participant, the woman was employed, but had enrolled in the clinical trial to obtain extra cash for a rental deposit (d in Table  5 ).

For those with serious and chronic financial need, monetary compensation for research participation can be an important source of income for basic necessities and used only secondarily for drugs. Higher amounts of compensation for the so-called“underemployed”could make the difference between the independence of being able to rent one’s own apartment or having to rely on others for housing. The stresses of being dependent upon relatives, the dangers of living‘on the street’, and the cultural value of independence are other risks and benefits that are likely to be weighed against risk of research harm in decisions to participate in compensated clinical trials.
 
Poverty, Drug Use, and Risks of Everyday Life

Participants often referred to the difficulty of their lives. Many perceived drug use as a reaction to the stresses of poverty and the dangers of life in their neighborhoods. Accepting financial compensation for participation in research was viewed as an honest way to obtain income (a in Table  6 ). As one person put it,“...you’re doing something honest. So you’re out there doing some all kinds of stuff. So you see something that can benefit you and keep you out of harm’s way, more power to you, right?”Another interviewee explained that for drug users desperately in need of a‘high’, payment for research can provide income that might deter illegal efforts at gaining money (b in Table  6 ).
 
 Table 6 
 Examples of Theme“Poverty, Drug Use and Risks of Everyday Life” 
In addition to helping individuals avoid the risks inherent in criminal activity, payment for research participation can affect other risks of everyday life that indigent drug users face. One such risk is the possible necessity to trade sex for drugs, an exchange that increases the risk of sexually transmitted infection. Another risk faced by drug users is incarceration related to illicit drug use. When asked if a large sum might preclude consideration of research risks, one interviewee compared participation in a clinical trial with incarceration. He perceived that an on-site clinical trial was superior to prison not only because of the food and clothing provided but because the participant received financial compensation (c in Table  6 ). These participants viewed participation in research as having both economic benefits, in the form of monetary payment, and social benefits, in the form of obviating certain antisocial behaviors.
 
DISCUSSION

Participants in our study viewed payment for participating in research as essential to attract individuals to a study. Some participants expressed values of altruism in research, but most saw paid participation simply as another means of pursuing their livelihood. This finding suggests that impoverished individuals may not share the same values of those who promote volunteerism as the foundation for research participation. Our data suggest that economically disadvantaged individuals are unlikely to participate in research for altruistic motives alone if they have an alternative way of making money.

This study has limitations. Many participants were unfamiliar with actual clinical research participation and may have based comments about higher risk clinical research scenarios on perceptions rather than actual experience. Some respondents appeared to make socially acceptable statements or to present careful responses to the interviewer who differed in ethnicity, education, and socioeconomic level. Because participants were paid and desired payment for research, we reasoned that it would be unlikely that they would speak out against payment for research participation, a potential bias in the study. On the other hand, the transcripts included numerous contrary examples in which participants expressed negative sentiments such as cynicism and mistrust of research and researchers. The occurrence of sufficient participant statements that were negative or critical suggests that most participants spoke freely and did not feel constrained. In future studies, the possibility of bias or distortion in participants’responses could be minimized with repeated interviews over time. 34 

In spite of limiting generalizability, a convenience sample was used because of difficulties in recruiting and following economically disadvantaged drug users who may have lacked a home, phone, or permanent address. We could not reach those who declined participation, nor avoid selection bias in recruiting participants who may have been favorably disposed to research participation; some who may have misconceived the research as a means of obtaining help for their drug use or health problems; and all of whom expected to obtain $20 for their participation.

Because our study proposed to examine motivations for participating in research, we recruited individuals whose perspectives would be informed by actual research participation. These kinds of studies—research on the research process itself—are becoming more widespread. Methodological problems of“piggybacking”an investigation of research processes onto ongoing research studies have been recognized. 35 , 36 While participants’favorable attitudes toward the parent programs may have been a source of bias, such attitudes may also have facilitated the scope of experiences shared by participants who entered the study with a high comfort level.

Two aspects of our study contribute new knowledge to the sparse empirical literature on financial compensation for research participation in this population. First, in spite of their drug use, many respondents had a clear vision of themselves as autonomous individuals. Rather than providing a picture of an out-of-control addiction, several drug users described their use as manageable, e.g., using drugs only on the weekends or saving money to buy food for children. Participants’use of drugs on any given day appeared to be based primarily on contextual factors rather than on monetary payment for research participation.

The notion that paying participants for research participation would encourage their drug use or take advantage of them was unacceptable to most participants. Respondents stated that other drug users enrolled in research to obtain money for drug purchases, but none stated explicitly that they themselves would not use compensation to buy drugs. Even if the purchase of drugs was a primary motive for participating in research, autonomy was a larger issue for these participants. They rejected stereotypical views of themselves as unable to exert control over their behavior because of their drug use and/or desire for money. Our study suggests that research regulators should consider impoverished drug users’own views about their desires and capacity for autonomous decisions to participate in paid research and not assume that participants have diminished capacity or vulnerability to undue inducement resulting from poverty and/or drug use. Participants described themselves both as capable of acting in their own interests and as having the prerogative for decision making in regard to paid research participation.

A second contribution is the observation that payment for research participation appears to be a part of the“informal economy”in economically disadvantaged communities. The informal economy includes a variety of economic transactions that reside outside traditional employment as a means for obtaining a livelihood. 37 It includes legal transactions (e.g., odd jobs for pay), illegal ones (e.g., drug dealing, prostitution—referred to by some 38 , 39 as the“underground economy”) and systems of barter. 38 Interviewees viewed participating in research as an alternative to other riskier ways of making money. The perception of everyday risks in this economy may provide a yardstick for assessing research risk from the perspective of economically disadvantaged drug users. When individuals in high-crime neighborhoods assess the risks and possible indignities of having to sell one’s body for drugs and/or food and the prospect of having to serve time in a degrading and dangerous prison system, they may conclude that the“risks”of participation in a clinical trial are not all that great.

This observation suggests that participants from disadvantaged populations are“rational”and assess the various trade offs involved in making economic decisions. As such, the decision to participate in research may represent a comparatively lower level of risk, as well as an accompanying benefit of financial gain. Some would argue that participants’risk-benefit assessments should not be considered in determining the risk-benefit ratio of a study. We suggest that while participants’perspectives may not be the sole determination, an understanding of participant views is an essential component of any dialogue about risk and benefit in research.
 
Acknowledgments
 
Partial support was provided by the National Institute on Drug Abuse. We are grateful to the staff at the Montrose field site for their assistance in facilitating our interviews. We thank our participants for sharing their views with us.

 Authors’Conflicts of Interest None.
 
References
 1. Macklin R. Due and undue inducements: on paying money to research subjects. IRB: A Review of Human Subjects Research. 1981;3:1–6. 2. Newton L. Inducement, due and otherwise. IRB: A Review of Human Subjects Research. 1982;4:4–6. 3. Wilkinson M, Moore A. Inducement in research. Bioethics. 1997;11:373–89. [ PubMed ] 4. McNeill P. A response to Wilkinson and Moore. Paying people to participate in research: why not? Bioethics. 1997;11:390–6. [ PubMed ] 5. Lemmens T, Elliott C. Guinea pigs on the payroll: the ethics of paying research subjects. Account Res. 1999;7:3–20. [ PubMed ] 6. Tishler CL, Bartholomae S. The recruitment of normal healthy volunteers: A review of the literature on the use of financial incentives. J Clin Pharmacol. 2002;42:365–75. [ PubMed ] 7. Grant RW, Sugarman J. Ethics in human subjects research: do incentives matter? J Med Philos. 2004;29:717–38. [ PubMed ] 8. Dunn LB, Gordon NE. Improving informed consent and enhancing recruitment for research by understanding economic behavior. JAMA. 2005;293:609–12. [ PubMed ] 9. Reiser SJ. Research compensation and the monetarization of medicine. JAMA. 2005;293:613–4. [ PubMed ] 10. Emanuel EJ. Undue inducement: nonsense on stilts? Am J Bioethics. 2005;5:9–13. 11. Grady C. Payment of clinical research subjects. J Clin Invest. 2005;115:1681–7. [ PMC free article ] [ PubMed ] 12. Dickert N, Emanuel E, Grady C. Paying research subjects: an analysis of current policies. Ann Intern Med. 2002;136:368–73. [ PubMed ] 13. Beauchamp TL, Jennings B, Kinney ED, Levine RJ. Pharmaceutical research involving the homeless. J Med Philos. 2002;27:547–64. [ PubMed ] 14. Pace C, Miller FG, Danis M. Enrolling the uninsured in clinical trials: an ethical perspective. Crit Care Med (Suppl.). 2003;31:S121–5. 15. Emanuel EJ. Ending concerns about undue inducement. J Law Med Ethics. 2004;32:100–5. [ PubMed ] 16. Dickert N, Grady C. What’s the price of a research subject? Approaches to payment for research participation. N Engl J Med. 1999;341:198–203. [ PubMed ] 17. Hughes JJ. Paying injection drug users to educate and recruit their peers: why participant-driven interventions are an ethical public health model. Qual Manag Health Care. 1999;7:4–12. [ PubMed ] 18. Buchanan D, Khoshnood K, Stopka T, Shaw S, Santelices C, Singer M. Ethical dilemmas created by the criminalization of status behaviors: Case examples from ethnographic field research with injection drug users. Health Educ Behav. 2002;29:30–42. [ PubMed ] 19. Festinger DS, Marlowe DB, Croft JR, et al. Do research payments precipitate drug use or coerce participation? Drug Alcohol Depend. 2005;78:275–81. [ PubMed ] 20. Williams ML, Timpson S, Klovdal A, Bowen AM, Ross, MW, Keel B. HIV risk among a sample of drug using male sex workers. AIDS. 2003;17:1402–4. [ PubMed ] 21. Halpern SD, Karlawish JHT, Casarett D, Berlin JA, Asch DA. Empirical assessment of whether moderate payments are undue or unjust inducements for participation in clinical trials. Arch Intern Med. 2004;164:801–3. [ PubMed ] 22. Bentley JP, Thacker PG. The influence of risk and monetary payment on the research participation decision making process. J Med Ethics. 2004;30:293–8. [ PMC free article ] [ PubMed ] 23. Russell ML, Morelejo DG, Burgess ED. Paying research subjects: participants’perspectives. J Med Ethics. 2000;26:126–30. [ PMC free article ] [ PubMed ] 24. Casarett D, Karlawish J, Asch DA. Paying hypertension research subjects. Fair compensation or undue inducement? J Gen Intern Med. 2002;17:651–3. 25. Casarett D, Karlawish J, Sankar P, Hirschman KB, Asch DA. Obtaining informed consent for clinical pain research: patients’concerns and information needs. Pain. 2001;92:71–9. [ PubMed ] 26. Vosvick M, Gore-Felton C, Ashton E, et al. Sleep disturbances among HIV-positive adults: The role of pain, stress, and social support. J Psychosom Res. 2004;57:459–63. [ PubMed ] 27. Coletti AS, Heagerty P, Sheon AR, et al. Randomized, controlled evaluation of a prototype informed consent process for HIV vaccine efficacy trials. J Acquir Immune Defic Syndr: JAIDS. 2003;32:161–9. [ PubMed ] 28. Patton MQ. Qualitative Evaluation and Research Methods 2nd ed. Newbury Park, California: Sage Publications; 1990. 29. Hsieh HF, Shannon SE. Three approaches to qualitative content analysis. Qual Health Res. 2005;15:1277–88. [ PubMed ] 30. Sandelowski M. The problem of rigor in qualitative research. Adv Nurs Sci. 1986;8:27–37. 31. Becker HS. Problems of inference and proof in participant observation. Am Sociol Rev. 1958;23:652–60. 32. Creswell JW, Miller DL. Determining validity in qualitative inquiry. Theory Pract. 2000;39:124–30. 33. Barbour RS. Checklists for improving rigour in qualitative research: a case of the tail wagging the dog? BMJ. 2001;322:1115–7. [ PMC free article ] [ PubMed ] 34. Wright S, Klee H, Reid P. Interviewing illicit drug users: observations from the field. Addict Res. 1998;6:517–35. 35. Agre P, Rapkin B, Dougherty J, Wilson R. Barriers encountered conducting informed consent research. IRB: Ethics and Human Research. 2002;24:1–5. [ PubMed ] 36. Sachs GA, Hougham GW, Sugarman J, et al. Conducting empirical research on informed consent: challenges and questions. IRB: Ethics and Human Research Supplement. 2003;25:S4–10. 37. Narotzky S. New Directions in Economic Anthropology. London: Pluto Press; 1997. 38. Anderson E. Code of the Street. New York: W.W Norton&amp;Company, Inc.; 1999. 39. Bourgois P. In search of Horatio Alger. Culture and ideology in the crack economy. In: Reinarman C, Levine HG, eds. Crack in America: Demon Drugs and Social Justice. Berkeley, CA: University of California Press; 1997;57–76. 
Articles from Journal of General Internal Medicine are provided here courtesy of Society of General Internal Medicine 
 
Formats:

 Abstract | Full Text | PDF (151K) 
 
Related citations in PubMed
 
 Decisions to participate in research: views of underserved minority drug users with or at risk for HIV. [AIDS Care. 2008] Decisions to participate in research: views of underserved minority drug users with or at risk for HIV. Slomka J, Ratliff EA, McCurdy SA, Timpson S, Williams ML. AIDS Care. 2008 Nov; 20(10):1224-32. Perceptions of risk in research participation among underserved minority drug users. [Subst Use Misuse. 2008] Perceptions of risk in research participation among underserved minority drug users. Slomka J, Ratliff EA, McCurdy S, Timpson S, Williams ML. Subst Use Misuse. 2008; 43(11):1640-52. Paying research subjects: participants&apos; perspectives. [J Med Ethics. 2000] Paying research subjects: participants&apos; perspectives. Russell ML, Moralejo DG, Burgess ED. J Med Ethics. 2000 Apr; 26(2):126-30. Financial remuneration for clinical and behavioral research participation: ethical and practical considerations. [Ann Epidemiol. 2009] Financial remuneration for clinical and behavioral research participation: ethical and practical considerations. Permuth-Wey J, Borenstein AR. Ann Epidemiol. 2009 Apr; 19(4):280-5. Epub 2009 Feb 20. Behavioral interventions to reduce risk for sexual transmission of HIV among men who have sex with men. [Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2008] Behavioral interventions to reduce risk for sexual transmission of HIV among men who have sex with men. Johnson WD, Diaz RM, Flanders WD, Goodman M, Hill AN, Holtgrave D, Malow R, McClellan WM. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2008 Jul 16; (3):CD001230. Epub 2008 Jul 16. 
 See reviews... See all... 
Cited by other articles in PMC
 
 Perceptions of Reimbursement for Clinical Trial Participation [Journal of Empirical Research on Human Rese...] Perceptions of Reimbursement for Clinical Trial Participation Breitkopf CR, Loza M, Vincent K, Moench T, Stanberry LR, Rosenthal SL. Journal of Empirical Research on Human Research Ethics. 2011 Sep; 6(3)31-38 Enhancing HIV Vaccine Trial Consent Preparedness Among Street Drug Users [Journal of empirical research on human rese...] Enhancing HIV Vaccine Trial Consent Preparedness Among Street Drug Users Fisher CB. Journal of empirical research on human research ethics : JERHRE. 2010 Jun; 5(2)65-80 Accelerated Hepatitis B Vaccine Schedule among Drug Users – A Randomized Controlled Trial [The Journal of infectious diseases. 2010] Accelerated Hepatitis B Vaccine Schedule among Drug Users – A Randomized Controlled Trial Hwang LY, Grimes CZ, Tran TQ, Clark A, Xia R, Lai D, Troisi C, Williams M. The Journal of infectious diseases. 2010 Nov 15; 202(10)1500-1509 Decisions to participate in research: views of underserved minority drug users with or at risk for HIV [AIDS care. 2008] Decisions to participate in research: views of underserved minority drug users with or at risk for HIV Slomka J, Ratliff EA, McCurdy SA, Timpson S, Williams ML. AIDS care. 2008 Nov; 20(10)1224-1232 Perceptions of Risk in Research Participation Among Underserved Minority Drug Users [Substance use&amp;misuse. 2008] Perceptions of Risk in Research Participation Among Underserved Minority Drug Users Slomka J, Ratliff EA, McCurdy S, Timpson S, Williams ML. Substance use&amp;misuse. 2008; 43(11)1640-1652 
 See all... 
Links
 
 PubMed PubMed PubMed citation for this article 
 
Recent activity
 Clear Turn Off Turn On 
 Perceptions of Financial Payment for Research Participation among African-Americ... Perceptions of Financial Payment for Research Participation among African-American Drug Users in HIV Studies Journal of General Internal Medicine. 2007 Oct; 22(10)1403-1409 PMC 

Your browsing activity is empty.

Activity recording is turned off.

 Turn recording back on 
 See more... 
 Payment of clinical research subjects. [J Clin Invest. 2005] Grady C J Clin Invest. 2005 Jul; 115(7):1681-7. Paying people to participate in research: why not? A response to Wilkinson and Moore. [Bioethics. 1997] McNeill P Bioethics. 1997 Oct; 11(5):390-6. Research compensation and the monetarization of medicine. [JAMA. 2005] Reiser SJ JAMA. 2005 Feb 2; 293(5):613-4. Paying research subjects: an analysis of current policies. [Ann Intern Med. 2002] Dickert N, Emanuel E, Grady C Ann Intern Med. 2002 Mar 5; 136(5):368-73. 
 
 Pharmaceutical research involving the homeless. [J Med Philos. 2002] Beauchamp TL, Jennings B, Kinney ED, Levine RJ J Med Philos. 2002 Oct; 27(5):547-64. 
 
 Review Ending concerns about undue inducement. [J Law Med Ethics. 2004] Emanuel EJ J Law Med Ethics. 2004 Spring; 32(1):100-5. What&apos;s the price of a research subject? Approaches to payment for research participation. [N Engl J Med. 1999] Dickert N, Grady C N Engl J Med. 1999 Jul 15; 341(3):198-203. 
 
 Paying injection drug users to educate and recruit their peers: why participant-driven interventions are an ethical public health model. [Qual Manag Health Care. 1999] Hughes JJ Qual Manag Health Care. 1999 Summer; 7(4):4-12. Ethical dilemmas created by the criminalization of status behaviors: case examples from ethnographic field research with injection drug users. [Health Educ Behav. 2002] Buchanan D, Khoshnood K, Stopka T, Shaw S, Santelices C, Singer M Health Educ Behav. 2002 Feb; 29(1):30-42. Do research payments precipitate drug use or coerce participation? [Drug Alcohol Depend. 2005] Festinger DS, Marlowe DB, Croft JR, Dugosh KL, Mastro NK, Lee PA, Dematteo DS, Patapis NS Drug Alcohol Depend. 2005 Jun 1; 78(3):275-81. HIV risk among a sample of drug using male sex workers. [AIDS. 2003] Williams ML, Timpson S, Klovdal A, Bowen AM, Ross MW, Keel KB AIDS. 2003 Jun 13; 17(9):1402-4. 
 
 Empirical assessment of whether moderate payments are undue or unjust inducements for participation in clinical trials. [Arch Intern Med. 2004] Halpern SD, Karlawish JH, Casarett D, Berlin JA, Asch DA Arch Intern Med. 2004 Apr 12; 164(7):801-3. The influence of risk and monetary payment on the research participation decision making process. [J Med Ethics. 2004] Bentley JP, Thacker PG J Med Ethics. 2004 Jun; 30(3):293-8. 
 
 Paying research subjects: participants&apos; perspectives. [J Med Ethics. 2000] Russell ML, Moralejo DG, Burgess ED J Med Ethics. 2000 Apr; 26(2):126-30. 
 
 Empirical assessment of whether moderate payments are undue or unjust inducements for participation in clinical trials. [Arch Intern Med. 2004] Halpern SD, Karlawish JH, Casarett D, Berlin JA, Asch DA Arch Intern Med. 2004 Apr 12; 164(7):801-3. Obtaining informed consent for clinical pain research: patients&apos; concerns and information needs. [Pain. 2001] Casarett D, Karlawish J, Sankar P, Hirschman KB, Asch DA Pain. 2001 May; 92(1-2):71-9. Sleep disturbances among HIV-positive adults: the role of pain, stress, and social support. [J Psychosom Res. 2004] Vosvick M, Gore-Felton C, Ashton E, Koopman C, Fluery T, Israelski D, Spiegel D J Psychosom Res. 2004 Nov; 57(5):459-63. Randomized, controlled evaluation of a prototype informed consent process for HIV vaccine efficacy trials. [J Acquir Immune Defic Syndr. 2003] Coletti AS, Heagerty P, Sheon AR, Gross M, Koblin BA, Metzger DS, Seage GR 3rd, HIV Network for Prevention Trials Vaccine Preparedness Study J Acquir Immune Defic Syndr. 2003 Feb 1; 32(2):161-9. 
 
 Three approaches to qualitative content analysis. [Qual Health Res. 2005] Hsieh HF, Shannon SE Qual Health Res. 2005 Nov; 15(9):1277-88. Review Checklists for improving rigour in qualitative research: a case of the tail wagging the dog? [BMJ. 2001] Barbour RS BMJ. 2001 May 5; 322(7294):1115-7. 
 
 Barriers encountered conducting informed consent research. [IRB. 2002] Agre P, Rapkin B, Dougherty J, Wilson R IRB. 2002 Jul-Aug; 24(4):1-5. 
 You are here: NCBI &gt; Literature &gt;PubMed Central (PMC) Write to the Help
 Desk 
Simple NCBI Directory

 
Getting Started
 NCBI Education NCBI Help Manual NCBI Handbook Training&amp;Tutorials 

 
Resources
 Chemicals&amp;Bioassays Data&amp;Software DNA&amp;RNA Domains&amp;Structures Genes&amp;Expression Genetics&amp;Medicine Genomes&amp;Maps Homology Literature Proteins Sequence Analysis Taxonomy Training&amp;Tutorials Variation 

 
Popular
 PubMed Nucleotide BLAST PubMed Central Gene Bookshelf Protein OMIM Genome SNP Structure 

 
Featured
 Genetic Testing Registry PubMed Health GenBank Reference Sequences Map Viewer Human Genome Mouse Genome Influenza Virus Primer-BLAST Sequence Read Archive 

 
NCBI Information
 About NCBI Research at NCBI NCBI Newsletter NCBI FTP Site NCBI on Facebook NCBI on Twitter NCBI on YouTube 
 External link. Please review our privacy policy . NLM NIH DHHS USA.gov Copyright | Disclaimer | Privacy | Accessibility | Contact 
 National Center for
 Biotechnology Information , U.S. National Library of Medicine 8600 Rockville Pike , Bethesda MD , 20894 USA
	</body>
</document>
