<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009001" url="http://www.recentnigerianjobs.com/2012/01/latest-jobs-in-nigeria-today-january.html" time="2012-07-13-02:24" support="1" score="0.0020469214436644556" bingtitle="Latest Jobs in Nigeria today January 30th - February 2012 at Box ..." webtitle="Latest Jobs in Nigeria today January 30th - February 2012 at Box&amp;Cedar">
			<query id="000257" bing-rank="114"/>
	<description>Fast Food/Restaurant Jobs (6) GCE/SSCE Jobs (10) Government Jobs (63) ... all marketing programmes and activities in order ... Prompt premium confirmation for the Claims Unit</description>
	<body>
		skip to main | skip to sidebar 
 Recent Nigerian Jobs 
 
 The fastest growing Job Site in Nigeria today, keeping you updated with the latest job vacancies in Nigeria! 
 
 Home Contact us Privacy Policy Our Lounge 
 For Latest Job Updates 
Follow Me on Pinterest
 
 
Subscribe via RSS
 
Job Archive
 
 July 2012 (71) June 2012 (168) May 2012 (200) April 2012 (222) March 2012 (247) February 2012 (224) January 2012 (184) December 2011 (144) November 2011 (149) October 2011 (116) September 2011 (102) August 2011 (99) 
 
Job Categories
 
 Abuja Jobs (191) Accounting Jobs (242) Administrative Jobs (147) Agricultural Jobs (10) Architectural Jobs (19) Artist Jobs (3) Auditing Jobs (53) Aviation Jobs (24) Awards (4) Banking Jobs (55) Building and Construction Jobs (20) Bursary Jobs (3) Business and Finance Jobs (62) Career Advice and Self Help (6) Career Humor (2) Cargo/Courier Jobs (4) Cashier Jobs (6) Cleric Jobs (8) Computer Jobs (83) Consultancy Jobs (9) Customer Care Jobs (31) Dispatch rider Jobs (1) Driving Jobs (75) Education and Training (90) Engineering Jobs (290) Entertainment (8) Estate Surveying Jobs (15) Fast Food/Restaurant Jobs (8) GCE/SSCE Jobs (12) Government Jobs (83) Graduate Trainee (96) Guardian Newspaper Jobs (11) Gym Jobs (1) Health Jobs (71) Hotel Jobs (32) HSE Jobs (16) Human Resource Jobs (60) Industrial Jobs (82) Insurance Jobs (27) International Jobs (63) Internship (6) Interviews and Results (7) IT and Telecoms Jobs (185) Lagos Jobs (538) Lecturing Jobs (15) Legal Jobs (32) Logistics Jobs (32) Lounge (19) Managerial Jobs (363) Manufacturing Jobs (57) Maritime Jobs (11) Marketing Jobs (192) Media and Publishing Jobs (29) Medical Jobs (75) Multinational Jobs (20) News (1) NGO Jobs (170) Nursing Jobs (24) NYSC (2) O level Jobs (4) Oil and Gas Jobs (154) OND/HND/BSC Jobs (88) OnShore/OffShore Jobs (3) oth (1) Other Jobs (116) Pharmaceutical Jobs (48) por (1) Port Harcourt Jobs (116) Punch Newspaper Jobs (6) Quantity Surveying Jobs (13) Real Estate Jobs (20) Receptionist (15) Religion Jobs (2) Sales Jobs (208) Scholarships (31) Secretarial Jobs (89) Security Jobs (33) Sports Jobs (1) Teaching Jobs (57) Veterinary Jobs (1) 
 
 Latest Jobs in Nigeria today January 30th - February 2012 at Box&amp;Cedar 
 on Monday, 30 January 2012 Labels: Accounting Jobs , Managerial Jobs , Marketing Jobs , Sales Jobs Latest Jobs in Nigeria today January 30th - February 2012 at Box&amp;Cedar 
Box&amp;Cedar - Do you thrive in a creative environment; know how to meet and exceed customer expectations, motivate your team and drive sales on every level?
 Then join the Insurance business of a rapidly expanding pan-African financial institution that operates in 12 countries and has extensive interests in insurance and banking. Their philosophy is to make a meaning ful difference in the lives of those associated with them.

 1.) Head, Internal Control Unit

Reports To: CEO

 Job Description 
Serve as Chief Compliance Officer with oversight responsibility for the audit unit, ensuring compliance with internal processes and procedures

 Role&amp;Responsibilities 

 Provide leadership, strategic direction and guidelines in the development of internal control framework and ensure that the framework addresses all risk areas and location Coordinate external audit activities and ensure agreement with findings and points
Analyze financial status ratios, formulate projections for revenue and expenditure.  Ensure compliance with all the regulatory bodies governing the industry Ensure operation of policies in line with documented control Ensure the maintenance of Asset Security 
 Specifications 

 First degree in Accounting, Finance or related discipline. A post graduate degree is an added advantage. Professional qualification such as ACA or ACCA and ISACA At least eight years relevant experience with at least three years managerial capacity experience in an Audit, Insurance firm or Bank.  
 Apply To: ins1@boxandcedar.net


 2.) Head, Marketing

Reports To: COO
 
Job Description 
Drive the organizational growth agenda towards a larger market share, through massive business development and retention of existing business

 Role&amp;Responsibilities 

 Develop strategy, coordinate all marketing programmes and activities in order to surpass set target. Develop and facilitate marketing communication plans and activities. Increase the company’s market share in all sectors. Drive customer satisfaction. Source for and manage new distribution channels for the company’s products Develop and enhance existing products.  Negotiate premium rates with brokers, clients and reinsurers 
 Specifications 

 First degree and a postgraduate degree in Marketing or related discipline is an added advantage. Professional qualification such as CII or CIIN and CIM Minimum of ten years relevant experience with at least five years managerial experience in an Insurance firm Good knowledge of insurance regulatory policies and claims required 
 Apply To: ins2@boxandcedar.net
 

3.) Head, Life Marketer

Reports To: Head, Life Operations

 Job Description 
Design and drive a new business development plan, retain existing business and effectively coordinate the marketing activities of the life arm
 
Role&amp;Responsibilities 

 Develop marketing strategy and manage marketing programs and activities with the aim of exceeding set target. Generate revenue by ensuring increase in Group and Individual life portfolio. Periodic review of market and competitor activities Drive customer satisfaction. Negotiate premium rates with brokers, clients, re-insurers etc. Increase the company’s market share in all sectors Develop new products and enhance existing products 
 Specifications 

 First degree in Insurance, Actuarial Science or related discipline. A postgraduate degree is an added advantage. Minimum of ten years relevant experience with at least five years managerial experience at an Insurance firm Professional qualification such as CII or CIIN Good knowledge of insurance regulatory policies and claims required 
 Apply To: ins3@boxandcedar.net

 
4.) Marketer (PH and Onitsha)

Reports To: The Branch Manager

 Job Description 
Manage existing and new relationships with clients, and ensure that annual personal and branch targets are met and premium collected

 Role&amp;Responsibilities 

 Effectively manage all existing clients and generate new insurance business. Support the branch manager in achieving targets. 
 Specifications 

 First degree Knowledge of insurance regulatory policies and claims required Professional qualification such as CII or CIIN Minimum of five years insurance marketing experience in the stated geographical territories. 
 Apply To: ins4@boxandcedar.net
 

5.) Life Underwiter

Reports To: Head, Life underwriting

 Job Description 
Evaluate degree of risk involved in policy and take decision of acceptability of the risks involved.

 Role&amp;Responsibilities 

 Review individual applications and company records Provide technical support to the head Life Underwriting Advice on excessive or substandard risk Ensure that technical processes, procedures, and documentation are carried out effectively.  
 Specification 

 First degree in Insurance and Actuarial Science or related discipline Knowledge of insurance regulatory policies and claims is necessary. Minimum of 5 years life underwriting experience. Professional qualification such as CIIn/CII 
 Apply To: ins5@boxandcedar.net


 6.) Technical Analyst

Reports To: Head, Technical Operations

 Job Description 
Work in a team that ensures efficient technical operations in the Underwriting unit and provides excellent service to all clients.

 Role&amp;Responsibilities 

 Prepare policy documents promptly and accurately Negotiate rates, terms and conditions for various insurance businesses Keep track of renewals and follow up on premium from brokers and clients. 
 Specifications 

 First degree in Insurance or related discipline. Professional qualification such as CIIn/CII Minimum of 5 years life underwriting experience. 
 Apply To: ins6@boxandcedar.net


 7.) Credit Control Analyst

Reports To: Head, Operations
 
Job Description 
Work cohesively within the Credit Control team
 
Role&amp;Responsibilities 

 Premium collection. Prompt premium confirmation for the Claims Unit Preparation of reports/schedules needed by external auditors or surveyors 
 Specifications 

 First degree in Accounting, Finance or related discipline, postgraduate degree(s) such as an MBA will be an added advantage. Minimum of 5 years relevant experience in a similar role in an insurance firm. Professional qualification such as ACCA, ICAN 
 Apply To: ins7@boxandcedar.net
 

8.) Team Lead Marketing

Reports To: Head, Marketing

 Job Description 
Head the different units in the Marketing department.

 Role&amp;Responsibilities 

 Lead a strategic drive for premium generation through effective coordination of team. Negotiate premium rates with brokers, clients and reinsurers. Substantial increase and management of Client Base in the designated marketing zone. 
 Specification 

 First degree in Insurance, Actuarial Science or related discipline, post graduate degree is an advantage. Minimum of 7 years relevant experience in general business marketing role. Professional qualification such as CIIN or CII 
 Apply To: ins8@boxandcedar.net


 9.) Senior Financial Analyst

Reports To: The Branch Manager

 Job Description 
Manage existing and new relationships with clients, and ensure that annual personal and branch targets are met and premium is collected.

 Role&amp;Responsibilities 

 Effectively manage all existing clients and generate new insurance business. Support the branch manager in achieving targets.  
 Specification 

 First degree. Professional qualification such as CIIN/CII Minimum of 5 years insurance marketing experience in the stated geographical territories. Knowledge of insurance regulatory policies and claims is necessary 
 Apply To: ins9@boxandcedar.net


 10.) Head Claims

Reports To: Chief Operating Officer

 Job Description 
The successful candidate will head the Claims Operation team.

 Role&amp;Responsibilities 

 Consult business partners on issues requiring analysis of Claim processes and impact on result. Analyze claims information inorder to provide insight into the business. Enforce and efficient system of adjustments and claims recovery. Determine the value of cutting edge claim processes to help drive the next level of organizational improvements. 
 Specification 

 First degree in Insurance or related discipline. Minimum of 10 years diverse technical experience, and a minimum of 5 years in claims handling at a supervisory level. CIIN/CII associate membership 
 Apply To: ins10@boxandcedar.net


 Application Deadline 
8th February 2012

 How to apply 
Send resume to the email address listed below the Job Title you are interested in.
Please note that all communication will be by email. Please constantly check your email box.

Only shortlisted candidates will be contacted.ke a meaning ful difference in the lives of those associated with them.
 Someone might need this,why not share or tweet it! 
 Tweet 

 Subscribe To Us Via Email and always be the first to know about the Latest Job Updates! 
 
0
comments:
 
 
Post a Comment


 
 Newer Post Older Post Home 
Latest Job Posts
 
Get Notified by Email
 Subscribe via email to get the latest job updates in your mailbox.Be the first to know and apply!!
 
 
Delivered by FeedBurner
 
Like Us and Get The Latest Job Updates via Facebook!
 
Advertisement
 
Popular Jobs
 
 Novotel Hotels Massive Recruitment,June 2012 GlaxoSmithKline Graduate and Professional Jobs in Nigeria,June 2012 Visafone Nigeria recruitment,July 4th 2012(recruitment@visafone.com.ng) PZ Cussons Nigeria Jobs,June - July 2012 US Embassy Jobs in Nigeria,June 23rd 2012 Mobil Nigeria Apprenticeship Program 2012 FirstNation Airline recruitment in Nigeria, July 2012 British Council Nigeria is recruiting! July 2nd 2012 United Nations Office for Project Services NGO Jobs in Abuja,July 2012 Radio Talk Nigeria (TrendNET) recruitment for Graduates in Nigeria(http://radiotalkng.com/) 
 
Our Visitors
   ©2012 Recent Nigerian Jobs
	</body>
</document>
