<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009063" url="http://shanebertou.wordpress.com/2012/02/19/a-place-at-the-table-chapter-2-miracle-bread/" time="2012-07-13-02:27" support="6" score="0.010568158045068818" bingtitle="A Place at the Table: Chapter 2 – Miracle Bread « ShaneBertou.com" webtitle="A Place at the Table: Chapter 2Miracle BreadShaneBertou.com">
			<query id="000676" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000681" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="001026" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="001021" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000670" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000657" bing-rank="203"/>
	<description>A Place at the Table: Chapter 2 – Miracle Bread ... also realized that one (small) meal at a fast food restaurant ... I still have money, and a car and stores, so ...</description>
	<body>
		RSS  Subscribe:  RSS feed ShaneBertou.com Part saint and part sinner. Skeptical dreamer. 
A Place at the Table: Chapter 2–Miracle Bread
 
 Posted on February 19, 2012 

 6 
 
 
 We have some great conversation going on right now based on the first chapter of the book. Thanks to everyone who has taken part so far.

Now it’s time to move on to the second chapter, titled“Miracle Bread.”In it Chris Seay discusses the time the Israelites spent wandering the desert and how God provided“manna”for them to eat. But they soon grew tired eating the same thing every day and began to complain.

Here are a couple of discussion questions based on chapter two of the book:
 
1)“Certainly, our relationship with food is a unique window into our soul.”

How would you describe your relationship with food? Are you a foodie who prefers the finer things? Are you over-indulgent and subject to your desires? Does your relationship to food affect other areas of your life?

2) Chris talks about the convenience of food in America. Not only is there an abundance of choice, but everything is delivered to us packaged and ready for consumption. Do these conveniences hurt your ability to appreciate God’s provision?
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print 
 
Like this:
 Like One blogger likes this. 
 
 Tagged: A Place at the Table , Chris Seay , christianity , Lent Posted in: Faith , Social Action ←A Place at the Table: Chapter 1–From Consuming to Sharing A Place at the Table: Chapters 3 + 4–Tools, Fasting and Feasting→ 6 Responses“A Place at the Table: Chapter 2–Miracle Bread”→ 
 

joyfullyblessed


 February 19, 2012 
 
The questions today, especially about convinence, make me think about my year on internship. While I definitely was FAR from starving, there were plenty of times I had to get creative with my cooking. It would have been SO much easier at times to grab a quick meal from Wendy’s when working late some evening, but I also realized that one (small) meal at a fast food restaurant was the equivalent of almost half my weekly grocery budget. As I think about it, some of the random kitchen concoctions that came out of figuring what in the world to do with the random items left in my pantry at the end of a month ended up being some of my favorite meals. I realize now that they were probably my favorite simply because it was SO obvious that the food was provision straight from God. Sometimes I really didn’t know where the money came from for all that I needed, nor how I was able to eat so well on such a small grocery budget, but not once did I go hungry. God provides…but sometimes it takes a little effort on our part.

(I think I’m going to like having this place each day to come and reflect with some questions to help that process along with others who are joining on this journey. Thank you for doing this!)
 Reply 
 

 Shane Bertou 


 February 21, 2012 
 
Thanks for sharing. I’ve personally never really had a time in my life when I had to think about eating“bare bones”as a cost saving measure. I’ve always been able to eat whatever I want, whenever I want. I did spend some time in Africa, where food choices were of course limited, but other than that I’ve never had to think about it.

I think one of the reasons this exercise will be good for me is that it will force me into the mundane. I still have money, and a car and stores, so everything the world has to offer with regard to food is accessible to me. But by committing to this“fast”(I’m still struggling with that term) I will be forced to live as if I had no choice. I’m fascinated by the prospects.
 Reply 
 

 brunswickchurchlent2012 


 February 20, 2012 
 
After Hurricane Katrina, I traveled several times with teams, to Pearlington, MS–considered Ground Zero after the storm. Even years after the storm, there were no stores, no restaurants in town. Each day at lunch, all the volunteers, and some weeks there were many, would convene at the fellowship hall of the First Missionary Baptist Church. At 11:30am, we would hold hands in a circle and prayed…Presbyterians, Lutherans, Methodists, and more all together. We even stood with members of a local prison work team, and we prayed with thanksgiving. The ladies of the church treated us to amazing homemade bayou fare. We were there to help them and we were the ones being blessed. This ideal of a community, prayerfully eating and lifting it all up to the Lord has never left me. I want to recapture this in my everyday life. This devotional reminds me of this time. I look forward to beginning this journey.
 Reply 
 

 Shane Bertou 


 February 21, 2012 
 
Mmmm. Bayou fare. Oh gosh, I’m never going to make it 40 days. 
 Reply 
 

 brunswickchurchlent2012 


 February 21, 2012 
 
I am trying to imagine how delicious a big steaming bowl of jambalaya will be 40 days from now when I really have learned to appreciate it. Food for thought…pun intended!!!! 
 Reply 
 
 

 Jaime 


 February 20, 2012 
 
I like food. And I like convenience, too! Before we had kids, my husband and I would go out to eat–or get fast food–fairly frequently. Now we are more disciplined (we have half the income and twice the people), and we find that we don’t even like a lot of the foods we used to ingest. It’s greasy, heavy, and not very filling. And when we go out somewhere with good food, we enjoy it so much more because it’s a rarity. We are definitely more appreciative.

What joyfullyblessed said above resonates with me too–the idea that, when we have less, it’s easier to see God’s provision. That concept and the themes in this book make me dream about the ideal–where *all* of us are able to see our blessings as provisions from God, not works of our own hands.
 Reply 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 

 Notify me of new posts via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 Search for: 
Connect
 
 Recent Tweets 

 If you&apos;re going to Party on the Park tonight, don&apos;t skip the opening act. I love @ apacherelay ! 3 hours ago RT @ sistersofmurphy : Busy weekend for The Sisters! East End Fest tomorrow at 9, Monroe County Fair Sun at 4. Come see #Rochester &apos;s talle ... 3 hours ago It&apos;s gotta be tough being a Penn State fan and a Catholic these days. That&apos;s a lot to renounce. 4 hours ago 
 
Comments

 Jaime on Highly Unimpressed Shane Bertou on Highly Unimpressed cit2012n on Genesee Beer Jaime on A few words on Joseph Kony and the people of Uganda Shane Bertou on A Place at the Table: Days 11-16 Shane Bertou on A Place at the Table: Days 11-16 Shane Bertou on A Place at the Table: Days 1-10 Shane Bertou on A Place at the Table: Days 1-10 Shane Bertou on A Place at the Table: Days 1-10 Shane Bertou on A Place at the Table: Days 1-10 
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 (1) May 2012 (1) March 2012 (2) February 2012 (8) January 2012 (3) December 2011 (15) November 2011 (3) September 2011 (6) July 2011 (1) June 2011 (2) March 2011 (8) February 2011 (6) December 2010 (8) November 2010 (4) October 2010 (3) September 2010 (1) August 2010 (3) July 2010 (3) April 2010 (3) March 2010 (5) February 2010 (4) January 2010 (12) December 2009 (15) November 2009 (8) October 2009 (15) September 2009 (19) August 2009 (6) July 2009 (13) June 2009 (24) May 2009 (18) April 2009 (13) February 2009 (20) January 2009 (25) December 2008 (39) November 2008 (31) October 2008 (36) September 2008 (34) August 2008 (34) July 2008 (35) June 2008 (47) May 2008 (45) April 2008 (43) March 2008 (45) February 2008 (47) January 2008 (34) December 2007 (48) November 2007 (44) October 2007 (52) September 2007 (36) August 2007 (34) July 2007 (28) June 2007 (21) May 2007 (19) April 2007 (26) March 2007 (27) February 2007 (10) January 2007 (22) December 2006 (8) November 2006 (6) October 2006 (21) September 2006 (20) August 2006 (16) July 2006 (10) June 2006 (1) May 2006 (1) March 2006 (1) February 2006 (8) January 2006 (17) August 2005 (14) July 2005 (7) June 2005 (5) May 2005 (8) April 2005 (10) March 2005 (12) September 2004 (1) 
Blog Stats

 239,359 hits 
 Blog at WordPress.com . Theme: Inuit Types by BizzArtic . Send to Email Address Your Name Your Email Address Cancel Post was not sent - check your email addresses! Email check failed, please try again Sorry, your blog cannot share posts by email.
	</body>
</document>
