<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009140" url="http://www.fox59.com/news/wxin-fast-food-indianapolis-gets-poor-rating-for-number-of-fast-food-restaurants-per-capita-20120329,0,5610689.column" time="2012-07-13-02:32" support="1" score="0.0013357228121103155" bingtitle="Indianapolis gets poor rating for high number of fast food ..." webtitle="Indianapolis gets poor rating for high number of fast food restaurants - fox59.com">
			<query id="000167" bing-rank="204"/>
	<description>Indy gets poor rating for high number of fast food restaurants ... The &apos;monster burger&apos; at one fast food restaurant has ... Sign-up to Receive School Closing &amp; Delays Text ...</description>
	<body>
		Indianapolis Yellow Pages Classifieds Place an Ad Employment Community Events 
   
 

90°F
 Jul 12 
 Home 
 Indy Urban Acres Fan Rewards Contests Video Pictures Viral Links Gas Prices Facebook Twitter FOX59 Mobile Staff Contact Us 
 News 
 Taking Action Wants to Know Business Bottom Line Crime Indiana&apos;s Missing Education US/World Politics Technology Offbeat RSS 
 Weather 
 Forecast 7-Day Live Guardian iMap Radar Tower Cam Regional Radar National Radar Watches&amp;Warnings Closings&amp;Delays More Weather 
 Crime 
   
 Traffic 
 Indianapolis Area Traffic Gas Prices Traffic Cams 
 Sports 
 High School College Professional Big Nasty Hit of the Week About FOX59 Sports 
 Entertainment 
 TV Schedule Shows THIS TV Antenna TV TMZ NUVO Lou Harry Events Contests Movie Showtimes Video Cityo 
 Health 
 Your Kids Health Ask Dr. Steve Living Well Straight Talk Product Recalls 
 Morning News 
 Consumer Reports Does It Work Female Focus Mommy Magic Paying It Forward Straight Talk Stretching Your Dollar More Below 
 Fox59 
 Fan Rewards Contests Staff Bios Closed Captioning Jobs Fox Shows Fox59 TV Schedules THIS TV Schedule Antenna TV Indiana Proud 
 Add 1 Job 
   
 Indianapolis Yellow Pages Classifieds Place an Ad Employment Community Events 
 
 WHAT&apos;S ON FOX59 Schedule Indiana&apos;s 4 Schedule THIS TV Schedule Antenna TV Schedule Fox Shows NUVO TMZ CNN Fox News 
 
 
 
 
 Advanced Search 
Advanced Search
 X 
 include all of these words: include any of these words: include this exact phrase: exclude: Select a date range this week past 30 days past 3 months past year Create a custom date range From: To: 
 Home  &gt;  News 
Indy gets poor rating for high number of fast food restaurants

Indianapolis has the third most fast food restaurants among the largest cities in the nation. The survey also reveals that only a small percentage of people eat fresh fruit and vegetables everyday.
 
 Comments 0 

 
 
 Ann Keil Bio | E-mail | Recent columns Topics Restaurants Dining and Drinking Foods and Beverages See more topics» 
 X Physical Fitness and Exercise Hamburgers Obesity 
 
 By Ann Keil 
 9:39 p.m. EDT , March 29, 2012 
 
Indianapolis
 
A new nationwide survey reveals Indianapolis has a high number of fast food restaurants in operation across the city.

According to a a Ziploc Fresh Eating Survey, there are 76 fast food restaurants per 100,000 people in Indianapolis, which means Naptown has the third most fast food restaurants among the 50 most populated cities nationwide.

&quot;I got the big, hot ham and cheese,&quot; said Ethan Robinson, a fast food patron.

&quot;I get a triple steak burger, and I get a side-by-side chocolate, vanilla milkshake,&quot; said MalcoLm Mattingoi, another fast food patron.

On a half mile stretch on West 86th Street, there are six fast food restaurants on one side of the road.

The &apos;monster burger&apos; at one fast food restaurant has 1,290 calories. A restaurant employee also said the healthiest item on the menu in terms of calories was an ice cream sandwhich.

&quot;What I am concerned about is that you and I learn to be savvy selectors when we go to those (places) because they&apos;re here to stay,&quot; said Kim Galeaz, a registered dietician.

She said Indianapolis residents should not play the blame game because it is about making the right choices.

While 90 percent of the people surveyed in Indianapolis are trying to include fresh fruit and vegetables in their families&apos; meals, only 37 percent overall eat the nutritious foods every day.

&quot;It&apos;s a lot cheaper to go to the fast food restuaurants that have a lot of fried foods,&quot; said Dave Chandler, Indianapolis resident.

For the people who agree with Chandler, Galeaz said there are other convenient and less expensive options.

&quot;You can stock your freezers with vegetables and fruits like crazy.&quot;

According to the 2011 American College of Sport Medicine&apos;s American Fitness Index, Indianapolis has a nearly 30 percent obesity rate.
 Don&apos;t Wait for School Closings! Sign-up to Receive School Closing&amp;Delays Text Alerts 
 
Copyright©2012, WXIN-TV
 wxin-fast-food-indianapolis-gets-poor-rating-for-number-of-fast-food-restaurants-per-capita-20120329 Sign-up for Breaking News Alerts from Fox59 
 Comments 0 

 
 
Featured Stories
 
Comments (0)
 Add comments | Discussion FAQ 
Currently there are no comments. Be the first to comment! 
 
Video gallery
 
 
 
 
VIRAL VIDEOS
 
 Man busted by mom during robbery 
 
 Stunt racing on the streets of San Francisco 
 
 Blake Griffin dunks during practice for Olympic basketball team 
 
 Baby boy and baby chimp 
 
 Kitten born with two legs and no pelvis 
 
 Mother bear rescues cub trapped in garage 
 
 Smartphone Apps 

Don&apos;t wait to get the latest Indiana news. Stay on it with news, weather, sports&amp;entertainment for...
 
 Newsletters 

 Mobile 

 Twitter 

 Facebook 

 Contact Us 

 Site Map 
 
 
 NEWS GATHERING PARTNERS Indianapolis Business Journal NUVO Newsweekly Indianapolis Woman Magazine 1070 The Fan The Times of Noblesville The Paper of Montgomery County Hendricks County Flyer 

 Privacy Policy Terms of Service Contact Us About Our Ads Fox59 WXIN-TV, 6910 Network Place, Indianapolis, IN 46278 
 
 A Tribune Broadcasting website
	</body>
</document>
