<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009660" url="http://gettinfitfabflirty4forty.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-13-03:03" support="2" score="0.003614951736452595" bingtitle="Fit, Fabulous and Flirty...for Forty" webtitle="Fit, Fabulous and Flirty...for Forty">
			<query id="001130" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001412" bing-rank="239"/>
	<description>... mean go down and get a burger at the closest fast food restaurant. ... Calories posted below are based on 1/2 cup. 1/4 ... calories before I do and I write it down in my food ...</description>
	<body>
		Fit, Fabulous and Flirty...for Forty
 
 This is my blog to track my progress in my quest for a healthy life. 
 
 Sunday, January 29, 2012 
 
 Sometimes it Ain&apos;t so Easy 
 This past week has been a struggle for me. 

I traveled to Birmingham, AL for business which normally isn&apos;t such a challenge. However, I was traveling with others and felt I did not have as much control over where and what I ate. I did go to whole foods and get snacks (apple, peanut butter, pop corn) and my breakfast (cereal and rice milk). 

My trip to whole foods helped me avoid the conference room cookies, sodas and other naughty foods. And, the one morning I did eat breakfast with my coworkers, I had eggs and fruit. But, I could not avoid the temptation of one piece of bacon!

My biggest derail on the road was eating out. I forgot my own lessons of sauce on the side, grilled when possible, etc. It&apos;s one thing to have a cheat meal, but I feel like I had several this week.

In addition to the traveling this week, I have suffered from Migraines off and on all week, hormone issues, social engagements...it&apos;s been a healthy eating recipe for disaster.

But, I have a choice. I can give up and go down the path I have gone in the past. I can just keep putting garbage in and give up. OR, I CAN GET BACK ON TRACK. I choose health. 

I started this morning on a date with my husband. I had eggs Benedict. I had crab instead of canadian bacon, the Benedict on the side, and only ate half the English muffin. 7 WW points vs 14 WW points. 

Smart decisions make BIG differences! Posted by 40yearoldhipster at 3:02 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Friday, January 20, 2012 
 
 I&apos;m addicted to... 
 Juice. Yes, I know the first step is to admit you have a problem. And, I am admitting, owning and embracing. I spent the week in LA (as in Hollywood, not lower Alabama) with my sister last week while working. She introduced me to this wonderful thing called juice. 

Now, erase all your preconceived ideas of juice. You know the carton of processed, pasteurized, preservative filled &quot;juice&quot; you have in your fridge. Even many of the &quot;claimed&quot; natural juices contain ingredients we are unaware of. For years I was unable to drink juice (apple, orange, etc) because it caused such extreme acid reflux. I assumed it was the acid in the juices. I was so wrong! It was the additives!

A few months ago, I purchased an unpasteurized juice. And, surprise, surprise, surprise! I had no acid reflux. This was a pure Orange Juice with nothing added, with an expiration date within a few weeks.

So, let&apos;s go a step farther...or a few miles. Welcome to juice bars in LA. I had so many different interesting, FRESH concoctions. Some where true juices where the fruit/veges where put through a juicer. Then I was introduced to cold pressed juices. And, there are juice smoothies which are blended in a blender and full of wonderful fiber. So many options!

I am back in the ATL now and I was very sad to leave behind my fresh juice options. Then, I remembered this fancy thing called the Internet. After a bit of research, I found Ardens Garden. A cold press juice store and smoothie shop. I purchased a few juices to take home and for lunch had a fresh blended juice smoothie with spinach, mango, apple and ginger. Yummy!

Why the juice? It is a great meal replacement IF it has the fiber. The juice I ordered today had several different properties that I specifically wanted:

 Ginger: Ginger is known to have healing properties. It is used to aide in digestion and to help with gastrointestinal issues such as acid reflux and nausea. In addition, it has been used to help with allergies, itchy throat and mucus reduction. It is also an anti-inflammatory which aides with migraines and other headaches. And...much much more. Spinach: Spinach is an anti-cancer, anti-oxidant, anti-inflammatory. AND, it is amazingly high in vitamin K which is great for your bones! Mango: Helps improve digestion, lowers cholesterol, regulates sex hormones and boosts drive, improves concentration and memory, Is high in Iron, prevents cancer and heart decease. Apples: The apple is rich in anti-oxidants and has many cardiovascular benefits. In addition, it helps to regulate blood sugar.It has anti-cancer and anti-asthma benefits. And, although the research is young, some studies indicate it may help prevent Alzheimer&apos;s. 
So, in one 22 oz glass at lunch, I accomplished all of these things! Amazing powers of juice!

This is just another step in my quest for health. I also walked more last week in LA then I ever have. I reintroduced my feet to my Brooks. And, they quite enjoyed themselves. As a result of healthy eating, juicing and walking, i am down another 1.4lbs. I am at a grand total of 14.6lbs since November 8th. 

Every week I continue to lose, discover new healthy habits and feel better. I encourage all of you to continue on this quest with me. This is not just a weight loss quest, this is a quest for health! Posted by 40yearoldhipster at 2:23 PM 2 comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Thursday, January 12, 2012 
 
 5% Lighter! 
 I am 5% Lighter!

I have lost 13.2 lbs which is 5% of my starting body weight. And, 2.2 lbs was during my last week! YAY!

I am trying something new, which I tried during the Holidays. I am trying the Weight Watchers simply filling technique. I feel confident with my ability to STOP eating when I am full. So, I am eating from a select list of foods until I am full. And, other foods I am counting and taking off my &quot;bonus&quot; points for the week. So far, it is working very well!!! And, it is very easy to do in LA. So many HEALTHY options!

LA is a smorgasbord of healthy eating options. I have had tuna tartar, veges, braised chicken with olives and artichokes. And, for a treat, amazing healthy juices, freshly juiced. Today I had a juice with apple, parsley, kale, hot pepper, ginger, lemon...amazing!!!! And then, for dinner, I left my hotel with my walking shoes on and walked to a fresh restaurant, had a bite and walked back. I walked a total of half a mile. Quite lovely!

The sad thing is that the farther outside of the Hollywood/Beverly Hills area I got today: more and more fast food restaurants; bigger and bigger people. So sad.

I will continue to strive to eat healthy, clean and to my benefit. I will continue to turn my back on processed food. I will continue to drive up my whole food intake and green foods. I will eat clean proteins and when I eat meat, they will be properly fed and not fast grown. 

Eat clean folks! It has helped me and it will help you!!!!!!!!!!!! Posted by 40yearoldhipster at 1:38 AM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Monday, January 9, 2012 
 
 Happy New Year! I love Seat Belts! 
 Good afternoon all! And a Happy New Year to you!

I hope you all are continuing your journey for health, as I am. My quest is still to lose a total of sixty by forty and I lose every week. I even lost between Christmas and New Years by sticking to the Weight Watchers simply filling principles and pumping up the fruits and veges. I am still eating Vegan/Vegetarian part time as I feel it helps with increasing the fruits and veges in my diet. And, quite honestly, I feel better. I have discovered, sadly, pig does not like me. And, this includes my all time favorite BACON. I will probably still eat my friend the pig, just not as frequently, nor as large a portion. So sad!!!

I am discovering that listening to my body is the secret. It tells me what it wants, when it is full, how to eat. The key is not to listen to signals. We are so used to putting processed, chemically laden foods in our body, sometimes we get false indicators. The more clean you eat, the more clear you will be. This doesn&apos;t mean you have to be vegan, but eat grass fed meats, not processed foods, steroid free and organic.

Now. I&apos;m sure you are wondering about my love for seat belts! I am a frequent flyer for work. And, I can tell you there is nothing more humiliating than asking for a seat belt extender. That is the equivalent to me of standing up on the plane with a bull horn screaming: I AM FAT!!!! Well, I have progressed from needing an extender. But, today, is a special day. Today I had to TIGHTEN my seat belt. And, I had to tighten it by a couple of inches. This tells me I am making progress. I am slimming down. It&apos;s not just about the number on the scale, but it is all those other indicators we encounter in our every day life. It&apos;s tightening the set belt. It is putting on a smaller size. It is feeling better about ourselves! I will be fit, fabulous and flirty! And my journey continues in 2012!!! - Posted using BlogPress from my iPad

Location: An AirTran Flight 
 Posted by 40yearoldhipster at 1:17 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Wednesday, November 30, 2011 
 
 Gobble Gobble 
 Happy Belated Thanksgiving to everyone! As we kick off the annual season of greed and gluttony, I think it&apos;s important to find perspective.

WHY NOW? This is a question I have heard several times recently in reference to why I started Weight Watchers and an exercise plan in November instead of waiting until January like the rest of the world population. Well, let me tell you, I refuse to ignore my problem any longer. And, I refuse to compound the problem by eating my way through another holiday season.

Because of this attitude, and because I plan my meals, stay conscious of what goes from plate to mouth:
-I lost 4.4lbs last week
-I have lost a total of 7.2lbs in 3weeks.
-I received my first 5lb sticker at Weight Watchers today!

Just because we are in the holiday season, it does not mean we need to eat like it&apos;s our job. The holiday season does not give us a free ride on the large caboose train! Instead, research the food before you eat it. Make smart choices. And, if there is something you just MUST have, take a smaller portion.

OTHER NEWS

This week has also introduced me to a new food group: VEGAN! Brian and I have decided to go meatless several meals/days per week. This is to help increase our vegetable and fruit consumption as well as increase the fiber in our diet. I am also adding different types of fats and oils (coconut oil, walnut oil)to help vary flavor and add additional Omega 3 to our diet.

We kicked this off by attending a dinner at the home of great friends B&amp;A.;We had a lovely tomato bisque with cashew cream, chickpea patty with lemon aioli and roasted Brussels sprouts. It was AMAZING.

I have experimented with several recipes the last couple of days, including converting my own tomato sauce vegan and serving it over the chickpea patties and Spaghetti Squash. This was a win!

As we go into January, I will begin posting pictures of some of the foods I prepare, the recipes, and how they are helping me stay on track.

I will check in again soon! Stay focused, keep moving, and please do not eat your way through December!


- Posted using BlogPress from my iPad

Location:
	</body>
</document>
