<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009225" url="http://www.usatoday.com/money/covers/2002-04-03-drive-thru.htm" time="2012-07-13-02:37" support="26" score="0.10456024439024003" bingtitle="USATODAY.com - Fast-food world says drive-thru is the way to go" webtitle="USATODAY.com - Fast-food world says drive-thru is the way to go">
			<query id="000099" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000724" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000161" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000902" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="000612" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000410" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000976" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000050" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000536" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000945" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000941" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="001479" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000441" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000895" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000455" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="001038" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000424" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000598" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="001512" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="000881" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000224" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000609" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000175" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="001509" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000887" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000896" bing-rank="94"/>
	<description>There&apos;s just one place that Victoria Vollaire stops every ... New feature: Boards that tally up a customer&apos;s order as it&apos;s given. Best menu board: A&amp;W</description>
	<body>
		Home News Money Money 
 briefs Markets Markets 
 Report Most 
 active stocks World 
 stocks Commodities Currencies Key 
 interest rates Investor 
 Research Stock 
 Screener Mutual 
 funds screener Get 
 a Quote Managing 
 Money Columns 
 and tips Financial 
 calculators CD 
 and loan rates Calendars Economic Company Special 
 Sections Autos Small 
 Business Careers 
 Network USA 
 TODAY Travel Interactive Money 
 eXchange Talk 
 Today Sports Life Tech Weather 
 
 
 
Click here to get the Daily Briefing in your inbox 
 
 
 
 
 
 04/03/2002 - Updated 12:18 PM ET 
 
 
Fast-food world says drive-thru is the way to go

By Bruce Horovitz, USA TODAY

 
 7-Eleven Cynthia Bloomer serves a Slurpee at 7-Eleven&apos;s only 
 drive-thru, in Plano, Texas. 
 
 Quick 
 question 
 Quick question 

 What is your preferred fast food option? 
 The drive-thru
 Going inside




 
 Latest 
 results 
 

There&apos;s just one place that Victoria Vollaire stops every 
 day. It&apos;s not the supermarket. It&apos;s not the ATM. It&apos;s not even to visit her 
 mom. It&apos;s the drive-thru. The single, working mother straps her 2-year-old son, 
 Lukas, into his car seat and typically steers over to the nearby In-N-Out Burger 
 stand. There, she gets a burger, fries and root beer combousually splitting 
 the burger with Lukas. This costs her $400 a monthright out the drive-thru 
 window. &quot;I don&apos;t like getting out of the car,&quot; explains Vollaire, who lives 
 in Ontario, Calif., and works as a hotel guest service aide. &quot;Who does?&quot; The 
 $129 billion fast-food industry already knows the answer to that question: fewer 
 and fewer of us. More than half the money spent on fast food rolls in through 
 the drive-thru lane. That&apos;s why the fast-food giants are falling all over themselves 
 to plaster new drive-thru lanes anywhere they can.

 Read more below Video 
 Drive 
 through or walk in? USATODAY.com tests the speed of both Drive 
 through popularity catching on with businesses 
 Related 
 Drive-thru rankings and average service times McDonald&apos;s is 
 testing imported beef 
 
 
That&apos;s why Starbucksthe company that sells coffee 
 as cosmic experienceis testing drive-thrus from Washington state to 
 Washington, D.C. It&apos;s why 7-Eleven has such serious drive-thru envy that it 
 wants to erect thousands.

It&apos;s why one busy Good To Go fast-food location in Houston 
 has 14that&apos;s right, 14drive-thru lanes. It&apos;s why several chains 
 are quietly shrinking the size of new restaurants to make room for extra drive-thru 
 lanes.

It&apos;s why each chain spies on the other, testing and retesting 
 whose drive-thrus are like expresswaysand whose are more like parking 
 lots. And it&apos;s why the number of drive-thru windows at fast-food stands has 
 doubled in five years. (The industry cooks better than it spells: It&apos;s drive-through 
 in English class, but it&apos;s drive-thru at every major chain.)

In 1975, McDonald&apos;s didn&apos;t have a single drive-thru. Today, 
 more than 90% of its 13,000 U.S. restaurants do. Industrywide, 80% of fast food&apos;s 
 growth over the past five years has been at the drive-thru.

 What 
 makes a good drive-thru 
 Menu board 
Menu items must be easy to read and understand. Combo meals are a time-saving 
 element. New feature: Boards that tally up a customer&apos;s order as 
 it&apos;s given.
 Best menu board: A&amp;W
 Worst menu board: Church&apos;s Chicken 
 Speaker clarity 
Quality speakers make it unnecessary for customers to reorder at window. New feature: System that compensates for high- and low-activity periods.
 Best speaker: Chick-fil-A
 Worst speaker: Church&apos;s Chicken 
 What&apos;s in the bag 
Orders must be accurate; mistakes cancel out efforts of fast drive-thrus. New feature: Outside workers wearing wireless headsets team up 
 to take orders and payment.
 Most accurate: Taco John&apos;s
 Least accurate: Krystal 


 Drive-thru rankings 
 

&quot;Most drive-thru customers are just stopping to fill their 
 guts,&quot; says Bob Sandelman, a fast-food consultant. The industry&apos;s bread and 
 butterfolks who buy fast food 25 to 30 times monthlyare the 
 biggest drive-thru fans, he says. They want their food fast. Or they&apos;ll bolt.

Drive-thru mania has everyone scrambling for an edge, especially 
 with the summer approaching, when more than 30% of all fast food is sold:

 McDonald&apos;s is consulting with Disney about its drive-thru lanes because 
 Disney is viewed as the world&apos;s expert at keeping folks movingand 
 entertainedwhile in line. 7-Eleven is testing its first fast-food drive-thru window in Plano, Texaswith plans to eventually make them as common as Slurpees. Starbucks has drive-thrus at 205 locations. It&apos;s even converted former Burger 
 King and McDonald&apos;s buildings into Starbucks drive-thrus. Some Starbucks drive-thrus 
 have strategically placed cameras right at the order boards so that when regular 
 customers pull up, baristas can start making the order even before it&apos;s placed. Arby&apos;s last year delivered a new Ford Mustang to the store manager who posted 
 the best drive-thru times. Dunkin&apos; Donuts executives decided five years ago that every new, stand-alone 
 unit will be built with a drive-thru. Taco Bell makes 65% of its money at the drive-thru window. And it thinks 
 it can do better. Wendy&apos;s profits have outpaced the rest of the fast foodies for one key reason: 
 Its drive-thru windows consistently rank among the fastest and most accurate 
 in the industry. Bolstering those numbers are hidden timers that measure how 
 long every single car spends in line. Little Caesars pizza has plopped drive-thrus in some units, hoping to attract 
 new business. 

&quot;Right now,&quot; says Chris Clouser, president of Burger King 
 brands, &quot;there is nothing more important to us than our drive-thrus.&quot;

 The drive to be fastest 

Burger King takes this so seriously that it is revamping 
 its drive-thrus with new sound systems and simpler menu boards. It is testing 
 see-through food bags to help keep orders accurate. And every time a Burger 
 King store sets a drive-thru record for the number of cars serviced in a single 
 hour, it is announced in a systemwide voice-mail call.

One Burger King owner in Minneapolis offers a free Whopper 
 to anyone stuck at the drive-thru window for more than 30 seconds.

Perhaps no one knows drive-thrus better than Lea Davis.

She&apos;s editor of QSR , a trade magazine targeted at 
 fast-food executives. Four years ago, she got a big idea: publishing an annual 
 survey tracking whose drive-thru windows are bestand worst.

A fellow named Jack Sparagowski already was quietly, but 
 meticulously, doing the survey.

Publishing the survey in QSR annually has turned 
 the entire industry on its head. Everyone wants to win. Badly. Industry CEOs 
 phone Davis ahead of time, begging for an early peek at results.

And the politics of the survey run thicker than cola syrup. 
 Coca-Cola co-sponsored the first survey five years ago. That was fine and dandy 
 because its fast-food partner, McDonald&apos;s, finished first that year. But when 
 McDonald&apos;s subsequently slid further and further in the rankings, Coca-Cola 
 bailed, Sparagowski says.

It isn&apos;t just about pride, either. It&apos;s about profits. 
 Industry analyst Mark Kalinowski of Salomon Smith Barney says he factors in 
 the QSR drive-thru survey results before recommending a stock.

 Make 
 the most of your drive-thru experience 
 Don&apos;t be fooled by short lines. A long drive-thru line at lunch 
 hour is often a good sign that the line will move quickly. Short lines 
 usually indicate lousy service.

 Don&apos;t order substitutions. Drive-thrus make mistakes on about 
 one in five special orders.

 Don&apos;t use your credit card. It will slow your trip down far more 
 than fumbling for correct change in your pocket.

 Don&apos;t procrastinate. If you don&apos;t know your order once you reach 
 the menu board, you&apos;re holding up the show. Plan your menu in advance.

 Don&apos;t panic. Driver indecision at the drive-thru contributes to 
 longer wait times and botched orders. If you feel rushed, bag the drive-thru 
 and walk inside.
 

McDonald&apos;s CEO Jack Greenberg has told industry analysts 
 that unit sales increase 1% for every 6 seconds saved at the drive-thru. And 
 sales at a single Burger King restaurant grow $15,000 a year for each second 
 it shaves off drive-thru time, a 1999 study says.

When Arby&apos;s CEO Michael Howe saw how poorly Arby&apos;s scored 
 in QSR &apos;s 1998 surveyranking a distant 13thhe went ballistic. 
 &quot;We decided we had no choice but to focus on the drive-thru,&quot; he says.

Everything was changed. Preview menu boards were added 
 to help customers make faster decisions. Soft-drink machines were placed closer 
 to order-takers, so they could take orders and pour drinks at the same time. 
 Toasters were tweaked to toast buns in 9 seconds instead of 12.

Arby&apos;s also installed clearer speaker systems. It ordered 
 wireless headsets for order-takers. It added digital screens that show customers 
 what they ordered. And it promised big prizesfrom new cars to vacationsto store managers with the fastest drive-thrus.

Result: Arby&apos;s leaped to second place in QSR &apos;s survey 
 last year.

Perhaps no one is testing more whiz-bang drive-thru technology 
 than McDonald&apos;s. It is installing double drive-thru lanes at 100 West Coast 
 restaurants. It has installed new, wireless headsets in about 12,000 units.

More than 400 McDonald&apos;s drive-thrus in the Chicago area 
 have begun to accept payment by Speedpassa transponder used for payment 
 nationally at ExxonMobil gasoline stations and markets. Waving the tiny, Speedpass 
 wand, which fits on a key ring, over a sensor exchanges the payment information 
 and automatically debits a credit card.

To promote its use, McDonald&apos;s occasionally offers freebies 
 to its Speedpass customers.

McDonald&apos;s will do just about anything to boost drive-thru 
 traffic. At two locations in Cheyenne, Wyo., a franchisee has installed drive-thru-lane 
 conveyor beltsone to handle food and the other to handle money. Never 
 mind that it looks weird.

&quot;The customer only wants it fast,&quot; insists Jack Preiss, 
 who owns the stores. &quot;If you can be fastnothing is too weird.&quot;

 Drive-thrus of the future 

Someday, says Bob Marshall, assistant vice president of 
 U.S. operations for McDonald&apos;s, there will be voice-recognition systemsand vehicle-recognition systemsthat will let customers pre-order and 
 pick up their meals at the drive-thru hassle-free.

No one knows who opened the first drive-thru. But by most 
 accounts, it was Royce Hailey, who in 1928 promoted drive-thru service at his 
 Pig Stand restaurant in Los Angeles. Of course, back then, the drive-thru was 
 different. There was no drive-thru window. Folks would drive by the back door, 
 and the cook would come out and deliver the chain&apos;s &quot;Barbequed Pig&quot; sandwiches, 
 says Richard Hailey, CEO of Pig Stand.

Drive-thrus didn&apos;t catch on until the mid-1970s when Wendy&apos;s, 
 under the prodding of founder Dave Thomas, built drive-thrus with virtually 
 every new unit.

Thomas, who died earlier this year, also believed that 
 friendliness could boost drive-thru business.

When visiting Wendy&apos;s stores, Thomas loved to quietly trade 
 places with the drive-thru order-taker. When the customer pulled up to the window, 
 Thomas would flash his classic smile and hand the food bag to the stunned driver.

Wendy&apos;s is the real drive-thru stickler. It recently repositioned 
 the way the refrigerator doors open by its drive-thru windows to shave off a 
 second or two. &quot;This is an art as well as a science,&quot; says Tom Mueller, Wendy&apos;s 
 president.

7-Eleven is arriving late to the drive-thru party. While 
 just one 7-Eleven store is testing a drive-thru window, if the system works, 
 &quot;You&apos;ll eventually see 50% of our new stores with drive-thrus,&quot; CEO Jim Keyes 
 says.

Instead of burgers and fries, 7-Elevens will feature sandwiches 
 and chips. &quot;Stuff you can toss in a briefcase and go,&quot; Keyes says.

Technology is taking over.

Some Wendy&apos;s, McDonald&apos;s and Taco Bells use underground 
 devices that track time in line to the tenth of a second. When a lousy window 
 time is recorded, a warning bell or buzzer goes off.

The fear among some store managers is that no matter how 
 good the time, &quot;It&apos;s still too long,&quot; says John Ludutsky, CEO of Phase Research, 
 a consulting firm.

Some drive-thrus even have video cameras fixed on the drive-thru 
 window to capture bad habits of workers that slow things down.

Some folks don&apos;t like drive-thrus. Cities from Sierra Madre, 
 Calif., to Carrboro, N.C., have banned new drive-thrus. And several years ago, 
 an Atlanta city councilman tried to outlaw new ones from opening in the city.

&quot;The American public is getting lazier and lazier,&quot; says 
 Lee Morris, the former Atlanta councilman whose proposed legislation went down 
 in defeat.

&quot;People should be able to walk to lunchnot drive,&quot; 
 Morris says.

But without drive-thrus, Jodie Joyce wouldn&apos;t have her 
 Mustang. The Arby&apos;s store manager from Syracuse, N.Y., won the new car for posting 
 the fastest drive-thru times of any Arby&apos;s in the country.

Sheand her crewdid this without a double 
 lane. Without wireless headphones. And without digital readout boards. &quot;We didn&apos;t 
 need all that stuff,&quot; she says. &quot;We just all listen to each other.&quot;

Perhaps the biggest drive-thru fan is Sharon Turnier.

She&apos;s got the morning shift at the drive-thru window at 
 Dunkin&apos; Donuts in West Simsbury, Conn.

Every weekday morning, around 6 a.m., the manager of the 
 nearby electronics store would zip through and order a large hazelnut coffee 
 with cream and sugar.

Four months ago, he drove through, placed his order and 
 handed her an engagement ring.

&quot;I ran outside screaming,&quot; recalls Turnier, who jumped 
 into the customer&apos;s car and embraced him.

Folks in line didn&apos;t mind the wait.

 Final 
 overall rankings Top five   Restaurant Speed Order Accuracy Menu appearance Speaker clarity Total 1 Wendy&apos;s 10.0 6.4 1.9 2.1 20.4 2 Arby&apos;s 8.4 8.4 1.0 2.0 19.8 3 Chich-fil-A 9.2 5.2 2.4 2.5 19.3 4 A&amp;W 5.2 9.6 2.5 1.3 18.6 5 Taco Bell 7.6 8.0 1.3 1.4 18.3 Bottom five 1 Krystal 4.4 0.4 0.8 1.7 7.3 2 Popeyes 3.2 2.4 0.7 0.7 7.0 3 Captain D&apos;s 1.2 3.6 0.6 1.1 6.5 4 Church&apos;s 3.6 0.8 0.1 0.1 4.6 5 White Castle 0.8 2.8 0.2 0.2 4.0 Importance 
 of speed and accuracy means those rankings are more heavily weighed and 
 comprise 40% of total score. Average 
 service times Top five   Restaurant 2001 average time of service 1 Wendy&apos;s 2 min., 14.7 sec. 2 Burger King 2 min., 42.2 sec. 3 Chick-fil-A 2 min., 47.2 sec. 4 McDonald&apos;s 2 min., 50.9 sec. 5 Arby&apos;s 2 min., 53.9 sec. Bottom five 1 Jack in the Box 3 min., 37.5 sec. 2 Whataburger 4 min., 16.1 sec. 3 Captain D&apos;s 4 min., 17.1 sec. 4 White Castle 5 min., 18.1 sec. 5 Steak-n-Shake 5 min., 23.1 sec. National 
 Average: 3 min., 8.4 seconds. Source: 
 QSR, Sparagowski&amp;Associates 
 
 
 
 USATODAY.com partners: USA WEEKEND Sports Weekly Education Space.com 
 Home Travel News Money Sports Life Tech Weather 
Resources: Mobile news Site map FAQ Contact us E-mail news 
 Jobs with us Internships Terms of service Privacy policy/Your California Privacy Right 
 Advertise Press Room Media Lounge Electronic print edition Reprints and Permissions 
 
 Add USATODAY.com RSS feeds   
 
The Nation&apos;s Homepage

 
 Copyright 2008 USA TODAY, a division of Gannett Co. Inc.
	</body>
</document>
