<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009386" url="http://www.activediner.com/keystone-corner-inc/restaurant/odessa/fl/us/reviews/628541" time="2012-07-13-02:45" support="1" score="0.0005917403278215162" bingtitle="Keystone Corner Inc Restaurant Reviews, 18515 Crawley Rd, Odessa ..." webtitle="Keystone Corner Inc Restaurant Reviews, 18515 Crawley Rd, Odessa, FL, 33556, (813) 920-5158 - ActiveDiner">
			<query id="000667" bing-rank="198"/>
	<description>Brian&apos;s Place - Italian, Spanish, Deli/Sandwich/Subs, Fast Food Restaurant in ... Avg Rating: Number of ... Select one of their old time sodas ...</description>
	<body>
		CUISINE OR RESTAURANT   CITY/STATE OR ZIP     
 
 
 Destinations 

 Atlanta Austin Boca Raton Boston Charleston Charlotte Chicago Dallas Denver Detroit Fort Worth Ft. Lauderdale Greensboro (Triad) Hartford Houston Indianapolis Kansas City Las Vegas Los Angeles Louisville Miami Minneapolis Nashville New Orleans New York Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Pittsburgh Portland Raleigh San Diego San Francisco Seattle Washington DC  -------------------------- Browse by Map   
 

 
 Sign Up for Specials 
 

 
 Add Your Restaurant 
 

 
 ActiveDiner Blog 
 
 
Cuisine
 All Restaurants 
 American 



Nearby Cities
 Tampa 
 Clearwater 
 Brandon 
 New Port Richey 
 Palm Harbor 
 
 more... 
 Clearwater Beach Dade City Dover Dunedin Gibsonton Gulfport Hernando Beach Holiday Hudson Indian Rocks Beach Land O Lakes Largo Lutz Madeira Beach Oldsmar Pinellas Park Riverview Ruskin Safety Harbor San Antonio Seffner Seminole South Pasadena St. Petersburg Sun City Center Thonotosassa Treasure Island Valrico Weeki Wachee Zephyrhills 
 
 



 
Dining Specials
 Brian&apos;s Place 
 - Italian, Spanish, Deli/Sandwich/Subs, Fast Food Restaurant in
Hernando Beach 
 
5.0|I had the best prepared butter fish in my entire life last night. The food was excellent, Jason ... Costas Restaurant 
 - Greek, Seafood, Children&apos;s Menu, Kids Friendly Restaurant in
Tarpon Springs 
 
5.0|This place is awesome! Love the place, food and service. Whenever we have company, we always ta... 
 
 


 
 United States &gt; Florida &gt; Odessa Restaurant Guide (3 ratings) 
Keystone Corner Inc
 (813) 920-5158 
 18515 Crawley Rd, Odessa, FL 33556 | MAP 
   | Share | Features 
 Deli/Sandwich/Subs 

 
 Overview 
   
 Reviews (3) 
   
 Map 
   
 



 UPDATE THIS LISTING 

Keystone Corner Inc Reviews
 
Avg Rating:     Number of Reviews: 3
 A diner 
 from Odessa,FL gave an overall rating of on May 12, 2011 @ 4:02 PM

  I love that funny jewish kid! A diner 
 from Trinity, FL gave an overall rating of on April 20, 2010 @ 5:18 PM

  Excellent food! A group of four co-workers went for lunch. All four of us enjoyed our lunches: chicken parm sandwich, Reuben, tuna melt, gyros all great! A diner 
 from Odessa, FL gave an overall rating of on March 31, 2010 @ 6:17 PM

  BEST PIZZA and CUBAN SANDWICHES in Odessa! Christine Branigan and her friendly crew serve up tasty food quickly with a cheerful smile in this cozy neighborhood deli. Select one of their old time sodas that you never thought you would see again or have a scoop of their home-made ice cream with real fruit. 

   »  Read More:   Odessa Restaurant Reviews Copyright 1996-2012 ActiveDiner.com All rights reserved.      About Us  |  Contact Us  |  Disclaimer  | Privacy Policy  | Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
