<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009650" url="http://www.pe.com/local-news/columns/bob-pratte-headlines/20120105-hemet-new-panera-bread-busy.ece" time="2012-07-13-03:02" support="1" score="0.002456396206771437" bingtitle="HEMET: New Panera Bread busy | Breaking News | PE.com - Press ..." webtitle="HEMET: New Panera Bread busy | Breaking News | PE.com - Press-Enterprise">
			<query id="000789" bing-rank="18"/>
	<description>It’s kind of a fast-food restaurant and bakery in disguise. ... Despite the line, the wait to place my order for a $5.99 ... Check the &quot;Delete browsing history on exit&quot; box.</description>
	<body>
		pe.com Web Search Story Archive Business Directory Member Submitted Events Calendar 
 Home 
 Video Photos Twitter Facebook About Us Contact Us Advertise With Us 
 Local News 
 Riverside County 
 Corona-Norco Hemet-San Jacinto Lake Elsinore Menifee Moreno Valley Murrieta Perris Riverside Temecula The Pass Wildomar 
 Southwest San Bernardino County Archives Columns Obituaries Politics Special Reports Traffic Weather 
 Other News 
 California Nation World Lottery Noticias En Español 
 Sports 
 MLB 
 Angels Dodgers Padres Cal League Headlines 
 NBA 
 Lakers Clippers 
 Boxing College 
 UCLA Football USC Football 
 NFL Golf HS GameTime NHL 
 Ducks Kings Reign 
 Motor Sports Other Outdoors Soccer 
 Business 
 National Local Profiles Real Estate News Stock Market Business Wire Marketwire PR Newswire 
 Opinion 
 Editorials Letters to the Editor Local Views Write Your Legislator 
 iGuide 
 Arts Attractions Casinos Celebrities Dining Events Family Movies&amp;TV Music Puzzles Theater TV Listings Video 
 About You 
 Readers&apos; Choice Horoscopes Your Photos Girl Scouts 
 Tools 
 E-mail Newsletters Mobile Sites&amp;Apps RSS Feeds 
 Cars 
 Buy a Car Sell a Car Browse Newspaper Ads 
 Real Estate 
 Search Homes for Sale Search Rentals Search Foreclosures Inland Home Sales Listings 
 Jobs 
 Search for a Job Post Your Resume Post a Job Opening 
 Marketplace 
 Business Directory Deal of the Day Search Classifieds Place Classified Ad Legal Guide Legal Notices Browse Print Ads Shopping 
 
 Home &gt; Local News &gt; Columns &gt; Bob Pratte Headlines January 05, 2012 04:49 PM PST January 05, 2012 04:49 PM PST HEMET: New Panera Bread busy 
HEMET: New Panera Bread busy
 
 
  BOB PRATTE/STAFF PHOTO People continued to crowd into the new Panera Bread in Hemet this week.  
 
 1 of 2 
 
 
BY BOB PRATTE
 BY BOB PRATTE The Press Enterprise 
COLUMNIST

 bpratte@pe.com 

 Published: 05 January 2012 04:49 PM
 A Text Size 
Hemet’s new Panera Bread — which should slightly placate Hemet residents who dream of a Trader Joe’s market or an Olive Garden restaurant — continued to have lines out the door this week.

The restaurant’s Dec. 27 opening was a pretty big deal in out-of-the way, down-home Hemet. The establishment — located east of the intersection of Florida and Sanderson avenues near Vons — offers wholesome, healthful food served fairly quickly. It’s kind of a fast-food restaurant and bakery in disguise.

I visited Wednesday about 20 minutes before the noon rush. The line of more than a dozen people nearly reached the entrance door. Outside, three cars waited in the drive-through lane.

My wait was not too bad. Two cashiers were taking orders for the St. Louis-based, bread-baking chain’s sandwiches, salads and soups. Loaves of bread in a glass case looked tasty, as did an assortment of fresh bagels, a rarity in Hemet. By the time I reached the head of the line, a third cash register opened.

Despite the line, the wait to place my order for a $5.99 smoked turkey breast sandwich on rye and a $1.99 iced tea only took about 10 minutes. I was handed a GPS locating device to place on a table. It was used to help a waitress deliver my sandwich.

There were plenty of empty tables inside and outside the former Guarantee Bank building that became a Panera location.

I found a table next to Lori Van Arsdale and Myrna Rohr, two busy women uncharacteristically dawdling the morning away. Van Arsdale, a former member of the Hemet City Council, and Rohr, a retired San Jacinto Valley educator, were joyfully chatting and working on Ramona Bowl biz. They laughed about their long talk over coffee. They appreciated not being pressured by Panera workers to depart.

My sandwich, which was accompanied by a hunk of baguette, arrived in about 10 minutes. I liked it. The iced tea was quite good, too.

I refilled my clear plastic to-go cup before I departed.

“See you at dinner,” joked Rohr about the possibility of continuing her conversation with Van Arsdale for the entire afternoon.

When I left, the line had doubled in length and extended out the entrance door.

Panera Bread has been busy from late morning into the afternoon since its opening. The place figures to remain busy longer than the traditional Hemet rush to a new restaurant. Panera has the recipe for success in Hemet: moderate prices, quick service and good food.

If the quick-moving line appears to be too long, a mobile phone could be handy. Just call the Panera takeout number to place an order right away.

Reach Bob Pratte at 951-763-3452, bpratte@PE.com, or 3400 Wentworth Drive, Hemet, CA 92545. And follow Bob on Facebook at www.facebook.com/PE.BobPratte and Twitter at @bpratte

Bob Pratte
 Comments PE.com is now using Facebook Comments. Comments are subject to Facebook&apos;s Privacy Policy and Terms of Service on data use. If you don&apos;t want your comment to appear on Facebook, uncheck the &apos;Post to Facebook&apos; box. To find out more, read the FAQ . Copyright 2011 The Press Enterprise. All rights reserve. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. Bob Pratte Headlines 
 HEMET: Roosting vultures photographed 
 
 HEMET: Laughter set for church Sunday 
 
 HEMET: Anti-panhandling cards working 
 
 HEMET: Lousy In-N-Out burger settles Hemet Theatre wager 
 Photos 
 FULLERTON: USA Swim Team&apos;s Tyler Clary Trains 
   
 WEST HOLLYWOOD: IE roots, Artist Ramiro Gomez Jr. 
   
 READER PHOTOS: Waterman Canyon fire 
 Your Photos 
Want to contribute?

 View photos | Submit photos 
 Follow Us Search Events Events Restaurants Movies Venues 
 
   What When Where Within Miles   
 
   What Price Range Any $0-$14 $15-$30 $30-$50 $50+ Where Within Miles   
 
   Movies When Where Within Miles   
 
   What Where Within Miles   
 
 Most Popular 
 Most Read 
 
 MORENO VALLEY: Motorcyclist killed in crash with unlicensed driver 
 Fontana teacher pleads not-guilty in classroom sex case 
 LOS ANGELES: Riverside county girl rescued in sex trafficking 
 S.B. BANKRUPTCY: Police and Fire chiefs vow to protect city 
 SAN BERNARDINO: New officials discovered financial mess 
 Most Commented 
 
 Most Recommended 
 
 View More Jobs 
 If you see this, your Javascript is off. 
MAINTENANCE MECHANIC

Galassos Bakery

Has an opening for a maintenance mechanic. Knowledge of PLC preferred. Qualified candidates please send resume: 10820 San Sevaine Way, Mira Loma, 91752 - EOE - Fax: (951) 685-9586
 
ADVERTISING MANAGER

ICSN, Inc.

Responsible for all aspects of co&apos;s advertising, etc. REQ: BA in Communications (Advertising);&amp;must have taken &quot;Ad&amp;Brand Comm Mgmt&quot;&amp;&quot;Internet Ad&amp;Promotion Comm&quot; courses.
SUBMIT RESUME TO:
ICSN, Inc.
Attn: Mr. Kenny Kim
1826 Pomona Road
Corona, CA 92880
 
GENERAL

Company Confidential

F/T AR CLERK W/STRONG DATA ENTRY AND MS OFFICE, INT. EXCEL EXP. DUTIES BILLING/COLLECTIONS/RECON./MAINT. CUST ACCTS. EMAIL RESUMES TO CLERKRESUME2012
@GMAIL.COM
 
LEAD GROUNDS PERSON

Plymouth Village

FT benefitted position to direct and work beside team on 37 acre retirement campus. Must have extensive knowledge of plants, landscaping, cultivating lawns, pruning trees and shrubs. Prefer 3-5 yrs exp with grounds inc. supervisory knowledge. Plymouth Village 900 Salem Dr, Redlands CA 92373 909-793-1233, fax 909- 255-7520
 
RN

Plymouth Village

2 full-time positions, to work in a skilled nursing environment. Must have current CA license, prefer 1-2 yrs exp. in long-term care, strong in med.administration and customer service. Some weekends required. Benefits include med/dental/vision/ annually receive 2 week vac and 11 pd holidays. Plymouth Village 900 Salem Dr, Redlands CA 92373 909-793-1233, fax 909- 255-7520
 
 ELECTRICAL PROJECT MANAGER 

Stronghold Engineering

Are you an experienced Electrical Project Manager looking for an opportunity to reach a new level of success?
 
RESTAURANT

Lone Star Steakhouse

Become a LEGEND with us!
We are looking for the very best&amp;talented people to staff our new restaurant.
If you are passionate about food&amp;great customer service, we would like to invite you to apply for an exciting opportunity in a fast paced environment.
Now Interviewing Servers, Hosts/Hostesses, Line Cooks&amp;Bartenders.
If you are interested in these great opportunities, please
APPLY IN PERSON!
On-site interviews
Wed. - Fri. 9am-5pm
Lone Star Steakhouse
18601 Dexter Ave.
Lake Elsinore, CA 92532
EOE
 
ALL POSITIONS

New American Funding

Mortgage Banker Opening 80,000 square foot facility next to MetroLink Station.
Now Hiring All Positions!
Loan Officers • Processors • Underwriters • Funders • Production Assistants • Post Closing • Wholesale Account Managers • Wholesale Jr. Account Managers • Wholesale Account Executives • Wholesale Set Up Coordinators • Wholesale Doc Drawers • QC Auditors • Compliance Managers • Sales Trainer • Executive Assistants • Administrative Assistants • Marketing Coordinator • Graphics Designer • HR Assistant • Programmers
Call 877-478-5476 for more information or email your resume to: resumes@nafinc.com 
 
CONSTRUCTION

Company Confidential

Temecula Valley area Construction Mgr/GC looking for Architectural Construction Administrator. Duties include working w/Precon Dept. interacting w/owner and owners reps, maintain and/or build detailed project schedules, QC of drawings&amp;specs, estimating; scopes of work, etc. Some training provided, however solid Construction Mgmt or Arch. Admin. background req’d. Field experience a plus! Excellent salary and benefits. Send resumes w/history&amp;references to: recruitingad30@gmail.com 
 
Featured Business
 
 Riverside Yellow Pages 
 
 Home About Us Site Map Contact Us Privacy Policy Terms Advertising Solutions PE Careers 
 ©2012, Enterprise Media. All Rights Reserved •3450 Fourteenth Street, Riverside, California 92501 Powered by the Parse.ly Publisher Platform (P3).
	</body>
</document>
