<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009807" url="http://emsigogreenteam.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-13-03:12" support="3" score="0.002647469965189187" bingtitle="EMSI&apos;s Go Green Blog" webtitle="EMSI&apos;s Go Green Blog">
			<query id="001232" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="001247" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="001251" bing-rank="218"/>
	<description>She used a drink carrier from a fast food restaurant and made a ... We wouldn&apos;t throw candy wrappers, soda cans, or ... Instead of bottled water get a reusable container to ...</description>
	<body>
		EMSI&apos;s Go Green Blog
 
 As part of the corporate community, EMSI recognizes our duty to conduct business in an environmentally conscious manner. This means using resources in an earth-friendly way, conserving energy and other resources whenever possible, and working to foster ecological responsibility and active participation among employees, customers and partners. To achieve these goals, EMSI will strive to develop high-impact“green”initiative to positively influence the environment, EMSI employees and customers. 
 
 Tuesday, November 15, 2011 
 
 Happy ARD (America Recycled Day)!!!! 
 ARD is an annual day set aside to encourage Americans to recycle&amp;purchase recycled products. Go to Earth911.com for recycling idea. Posted by EMSI Go Green Team at 10:07 AM No comments: Links to this post 
 Monday, June 6, 2011 
 
 Summer Go Green Contest 
 The next Go Green contest has been announced,“Create a Container Garden”. In keeping with the organic theme of the contest I thought I would start by providing some information on organic soils. Organic soils help the plant by: 
 
 
 
 •Supplying nutrients 
 
 
 •Facilitating better drainage 
 
 
 •Storing more water 
 
 
 •Increasing microorganisms 
 
 
 To increase the organic content, add mulch from organic materials such as compost or shredded leaves. Working organic matter into the soil before planting will also help. BUT DON’T OVERDUE IT!! Too much of a good thing can also be harmful. Five to six percent organic matter is a good average. Posted by EMSI Go Green Team at 5:14 PM 1 comment: Links to this post 
 Wednesday, February 16, 2011 
 
 repurpose 
 repurpose: to take an item and change its use. To use something in a different way than it was originally intended. 

 The Go Green Committee recently held a repurposing contest to see the most creative ways people take items that have lost their original purpose but are still able to be used in other ways. 

 Boy, were we surprised at the responses and the creativity we got! From bird houses to tote bags, purses to pillows, nightstands to ornament holders. 

 So, with that in mind, here are the winners: 

 
 1st place goes to Tammy Farris. She won a $50 American Express Gift Card for using old fence posts to make furniture for their hom. The built end tables, coffee tables, shelves, picture frames and an entertainment center! 

 

 2nd prize, Christine Bryant. She made a waterproof tote bag from plastic shopping bags and combined them with crochet to make colorful tote bags. The colors in the bag come from different colored bags. She won a $25 American Express Gift Card. 

 
 
 3rd prize was won by Kambria Johnson. She used a drink carrier from a fast food restaurant and made a decorative napkin holder/storage holder for her home. She won a $10 Starbuck Gift Card. 
 (I will update with a picture when I can get one. I apologize.) 
 Other entries included: 
 Lisa Taylor--ornament holders 
 
 Audrie Goff--a jeans purse. Audrie also made a bird house from a large peanut butter jar and a door draft guard. 

 

 
   Jenna Dion-- decorative pillow from a roman shade 

 






 
 
 Sandra Kanaski--cord holders made from Crystal Light containers and a curling iron holder 

.
 
 Posted by EMSI Go Green Team at 4:23 PM No comments: Links to this post Labels: recycling , repurposing 
 Tuesday, November 10, 2009 
 
 What&apos;s the most littered item in America??? 
 Try to guess before you scroll down for the answer.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.Do you think you know?
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
Did you guess correctly?

Cigarette butts are everywhere. This is a problem across the country and around the world. If we do our part in our corner of the world, we can make a big difference.

For example, our company (or our landlord in some offices) pays our cleaning crews to pick up cigarette butts. We wouldn&apos;t throw candy wrappers, soda cans, or other trash on the ground or on the floor for the crew to pick up.

Here are some pics I took right outside the door of the CP building in Waco.


 
 
 
 
 
 It seems harmless enough, but a quick internet search will prove otherwise.

 
 Here are a few facts from Cigarettelitter.org.

 Cigarettes are the number one source of litter in the world, with an estimated several trillion littered annually. Cigarette butts are NOT biodegradable -- they are made of plastic fibers. Littered cigarette filters contain toxic chemicals which are released into the environment. Cigarette litter causes numerous fires every year, many of which are fatal. 

 
 LINKS 

 Cigarettelitter.org 
 
 Email Wal-Mart
 http://www.cigarettelitter.org/index.asp?PageName=Walmart 

Anonymous email page
 http://www.cigarettelitter.org/index.asp?pagename=Email 

 
 10 Things You Should Know about Cigarette Litter
 http://www.blisstree.com/healthbolt/10-things-you-should-know-about-cigarette-butt-litter/ 

 
 Another good site:
 http://whyquit.com/whyquit/A_Butts.html 

 
 There are TONS of articles out there. For more information, go to Google or Bing or any search engine and search for &quot;cigarette butts.&quot;

 
 
 ACTION ITEMS 

 
 Here are some things you can do to reduce cigarette butt litter:

1. If you are a smoker, dispose of your butts properly
2. Encourage others to dispose of butts properly
3. Buy (and use!) a personal (or pocket) ashtray - buy one for a smoking friend
4. Use ashtrays when provided
5. Encourage retailers to put up signs reminding smokers to dispose of the butts wisely
6. Ask retailers to sell pocket ashtrays
7. Pick up cigarette butts
8. Learn more about the cigarette butt litter problem Posted by EMSI Go Green Team at 11:56 AM 3 comments: Links to this post 
 Tuesday, November 3, 2009 
 
 Tips from Muhammad Shah 
 Muhammad Shah, Branch Manager in Oakland, CA submitted the following tips to letstalktrash@emsinet.com 

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Change to Fluorescent Bulbs - If every house in the United States changed all of the light bulbs in their house, that would be equivalent to taking one million cars off the streets.


Don&apos;t Rinse - Skip rinsing your plates before putting them into the dishwasher. In average you will save 15 gallons of water per load. Plus, you will save time.

Hang Outside to Dry - Get a cloths line or rack to dry your cloths. Your cloths will last longer and you will save money

Turn off computers at night - don&apos;t just put them to sleep. You will save an average of 4 cents a day which ads up to $14.60 a year.

Use Both Sides of Paper - if you have a printer with a double sided print option use it. You will save half of the amount of paper you would have normally used. Then when your done bring it to the recycle bin.

Get rid of baths - Don&apos;t take baths, take showers. You will in average save about half the amount of water that you would if you were taking a bath.

Don&apos;t get bottled water - Instead of bottled water get a reusable container to carry water. Also you can get a filter to make your home tap taste more like bottled water. It is definitely more cost efficient.

Turn the water off when you brush - Your parents have said this before, now I say it. You will save 4 gallons of water doing this alone.

Shorten your shower - Every minute you cut from your shower is roughly 5 gallons of water. The less time your shower takes, the lower your impact on the environment.

Recycle Glass - If you do not recycle this, it will take a million years to decompose.

Don&apos;t Pre-Heat the Oven - unless needed, just turn the oven on after you put the dish in it. Also, to see if it&apos;s finished just look through the glass instead of opening it.

Use Warm or Cold Setting on Washer - instead of the hot cycle use the warm or cold setting. This will save a lot of energy a year.

Turn Down your Thermostat - Every degree lower in the winter or higher in the summer you put it is a 10% decrease on your energy bill.

Turn off your lights - An easy one. Turn off your lights when you are not using them. The benefits are obvious.

Get rid of junk mail - There are many services that can help you get rid of junk mail. That will lead to a lot less trees being cut down to take up room in your mailbox.

Use Matches instead of lighters - Lighters are usually considered disposable so they will most likely end up in land fills. You can use the cardboard matches which are much more eco-friendly because they are made of recycled material.

Don&apos;t get a paper phone book - Instead of getting a paper phone book. Use a online directory instead.

Give things away - Take things that you are not going to wear or use and give it to a charity or someone who will use it.

Go to a car wash - Going to a car wash is a lot more water efficient then washing your car at home.

Stop paper bank statements - Why waste paper getting your bank statement mailed to you when you can just check it out online.

Buy Rechargeable Batteries - Even though it will take a good investment to buy these you will find yourself gaining it back in no time.

Pay your Bills Online - If every house in the US did this then we would save 18 million trees every year.

Get a reusable bag - You can&apos;t recycle plastic bags, instead get yourself a reusable bag so that you won&apos;t have to worry about carrying your necessities.

Do Errands in Bulk - Make a list of the things you have to do, and see if you can fit a couple of those things together in one ride.

Inflate your Tires - If your tires are inflated at all times your car will run more miles on less gas.

Wrap Presents Creatively - Without going out to get wrapping paper you can use newspaper, an old map, or anything else. It would look a whole lot more creative.

Plant a Tree - It&apos;s good for the air, can keep you cool, and can increase your property value.

Buy Local Produce - Consider how much energy it takes for produce from china or any other country to come here. If you have the option to buy local, do it.

Walk or Ride Your Bike When you can - If you have to go somewhere close consider riding your bike or walking there instead of your car. It&apos;s better on the environment and healthier. Posted by EMSI Go Green Team at 4:54 PM 3 comments: Links to this post 
 Making comments Part II - Identifying yourself 
 An observant reader noticed that it will ask you to login when you attempt to add a comment. The graphic below gives some information about that.

 
 
 After you have entered your comment, click the down arrow next to &quot;Comment As:&quot;
 
 If you have one of the accounts listed in the green box (the top box), you can use that ID to login here. AIM also includes AOL email addresses.
 
 If you don&apos;t have one of those logins and you don&apos;t wish to sign up for one of them, you can select &quot;Name/URL&quot;. This box has a place to type your name (and location). Optionally, you could type a URL, but for our purposes a name will be better.
 
 
 
 
 Don&apos;t choose anonymous - if you choose that we won&apos;t be able to find you when it&apos;s time to give you your prize!
 
 Happy commenting!!!
 Posted by EMSI Go Green Team at 2:21 PM 1 comment: Links to this post 
 Thursday, October 29, 2009 
 
 Instructions on how to comment 
 If you are new to blogging and commenting on blogs, you might not know how to comment.

This illustration will help.

 
 There are two ways.

1 - Click the title (see red arrow) of the blog entry you wish to comment to open it&apos;s own page. The comments area will be at the bottom.

2 - Click the &quot; n comments&quot; link (see green arrow). This is another way to the blog entry&apos;s page.

Check back often and comment even more often!

If you have further questions, send email to letstalktrash@emsinet.com .

Thanks!

The EMSI Go Green Team Posted by EMSI Go Green Team at 3:54 PM No comments: Links to this post Older Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 
Helpful Link
 
 What is &quot;Following&quot;? 
 
 
About Me
 EMSI Go Green Team View my complete profile 
Blog Archive
 
 ▼  2011 (3) 
 ▼  November (1) 
 Happy ARD (America Recycled Day)!!!! 
 

 ►  June (1) 
 Summer Go Green Contest 
 

 ►  February (1) 
 repurpose 
 
 

 ►  2009 (12) 
 ►  November (3) 
 What&apos;s the most littered item in America??? Tips from Muhammad Shah Making comments Part II - Identifying yourself 
 

 ►  October (4) 
 Instructions on how to comment How will you GREEN your HALLOWEEN??? Composting: Getting Started How do YOU recycle??? 
 

 ►  September (2) 
 Take the Energy Star Pledge!!! WATCH THIS SPACE!!! 
 

 ►  April (1) 
 Brush up on your Green Vocabulary!! 
 

 ►  March (2) 
 New Green Products at Target! Greening Your Spring Cleaning!! 
 
 
 
 
Followers
 
 
 Picture Window template. Powered by Blogger .
	</body>
</document>
