<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009383" url="http://archisaur.us/" time="2012-07-13-02:45" support="27" score="0.04092266038198927" bingtitle="A Blog about the practice of Restaurant Architecture - Restaurant ..." webtitle="A Blog about the practice of Restaurant Architecture - Restaurant Ideas and Restaurant Architecture">
			<query id="001459" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000590" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000986" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="001270" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000670" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000937" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="001272" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="000579" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001175" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000987" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="001050" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="001145" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000673" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000999" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000685" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="001302" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000924" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000578" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000968" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="001280" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="001187" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="001156" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="000956" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="001144" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="001049" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="001269" bing-rank="105"/>
	<description>Hard ceilings are made of drywall and give a high end elegant look to a restaurant. ... You probably want your customers to sit down even in fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		All About the Hospitality Industry 
 
 Home About Privacy Policy Consulting 
 
 Architect Rant Architect Tip Green Design Restaurant Architecture Restaurant Design Ideas Uncategorized 
 Comments Posts Your Ad Here 
 What Makes Good Restaurant Furniture? 
 Your Ad Here 
 Restaurant furniture is certainly one of the key components to your restaurant design.  Assuming you have a site down restaurant and not a carry out only restaurant.  Every customer that comes in must directly interact with your restaurant’s furniture.  Customers must bout see and touch your table, chairs and booths, hopefully not smell.  So selection the right restaurant furniture will have an enormous impact on the ultimate success and failure of your restaurant and it is a critical part of any restaurant design.

Types of Restaurant Furniture

First of all I am not going to discuss atypical restaurant furniture like picnic tables and benches.  We can leave that conversation for another time.  Today I will focus on the main stays for restaurant furniture, Tables, Chairs, Booths and Banquettes.  One thing you need to understand is that restaurant furniture is not like what you have in your house, it is sturdier commercial grade furniture.  Also it should be designed for easy cleaning.  Never forget restaurant furniture is not only used far more that residential furniture it is abused more.  Is is human nature to treat what you own better that what some one else owns.

Restaurant furniture construction is an art and science.  Selecting the right restaurant furniture for your restaurant design is a balance between comfort with clean-ability.  Your restaurant design will determine if you upholstery or not.  What materials make good furniture?  Restaurant furniture can be build out of metal, wood or plastic your over all restaurant design will drive what materials are used for construction.  You should only buy restaurant furniture from a commercial furniture suppler who understand the furniture for restaurants.

Tables

Restaurant Table Tops and Bases come in 2 broad types regular dining table to be used with chairs and high top tables used for standing and bar stools.  When selecting regular tables your have to choose shape round or square and capacity 2 people, 4 people, 6 people or more.  You can see my previous post of selecting the mix required.  Another thing to select is the legs, you often select the table tops and table base separately.  Most restaurateurs opt for a pedestal to avoid the leg banging issue we all seem to have at banquets.  Rectangular table tops for 6 get 2 pedestals.  One funny thing about selecting tables is that expensive restaurants with table cloths buy cheap table tops often just raw plywood and cheap restaurant with out table cloths have to buy expensive top because they are seen take a lot of abuse.

Chairs

Restaurant Chairs are the most important piece of restaurant furniture to select.  They have the biggest impact on the restaurant design and on the customer experience.  Things to look for in selecting a chair are of course the durability but conversely you also want a chair that is light so people can get up and down easily.  A heavy institutional steel chair that weighs a ton is OK in schools or hospitals where customer satisfaction is unheard of, but in the competitive environment all restaurants are in you have to balance strength and weight.  Clean-ability is also most critical with chairs.  Chairs will get spilled on and staff has to be able to wipe a chair down and turn over the table or you loose business.  Make sure any fabric you select sheds liquid and is stain resistant to the drinks you serve, red wine, coffee, or whatever.  Check you chairs for stability also, sit in them lean back twist side to side and see if they tip over.  And get a few kids to do the same chair are less stable when your feet don’t reach the ground.

Booths

Booths come is 2 styles the straight bench variety and the circular bench type.  As a rule only higher end restaurants opt for the circular booths.  Booths have many of the same issues as chairs when is comes to clean ability, but since they are firmly anchored to the ground they don’t have the stability issues.  The main reason to use booths in your restaurant design is that they are space efficient.  The back to back of booths is around 6 feet 6 inches where tables and chairs will require about 8 feet minimum.  Booths let you get more seating in less floor space, the trade off being loosing flexibility to seat larger groups.

Banquettes

Banquettes are basically booth bench seats that run along a wall and have tables and chairs in form of them to form a seating arrangement.  Banquettes are a good way to protect walls from chairs.  If you put chairs near a wall you have to then protect the walls with chair rail or wainscotting. Banquettes also save space like booths.

I hope this brief summary of what furniture goes into a good restaurant design helps clarify the uses and terminology of restaurant furniture for you.

 
 Your Ad Here 
 Be the first to comment - What do you think?   Posted by
 - 
 February 17, 2012 at 5:21 pm

Categories: Architect Tip , Restaurant Architecture , Restaurant Design Ideas   Tags:


 
 The Mr. Potato Head School of Restaurant Design 

 For most of us Mr. Potato Head is a beloved childhood toy, and let’s keep it that way. The problem is many people use Mr. Potato Head as a model on how to design restaurants. Let me recap the metaphor so we are all on the same page.

Mr. Potato Head consisted of a hollow plastic potato shaped body with a few holes in it along with a hatch. The hatch opened to let out all the other body parts stored inside the potato body. You had a few different eyes, ears, noses and mouths. You also had a mustache, eyebrows, glasses, a pipe and hats. The fun was in putting different combinations of body parts and accessories on the potato body to get funny results.

This combining different things to get a variety of results is great fun in a kids toy and we should leave it there. The problem is some adults use this Mr. Potato Head technique when it comes to restaurant design. They take pieces of different restaurants that they like and respect and combined them together and call it restaurant design.

Part of being a restaurant architect is getting everything to be part of one design. A restaurant can not have its own identity, its own brand with out a consistent design. If you are going for a slick contemporary look and feel you can not use restaurant furniture that looks colonial. If you are going for a traditional look sleek stainless steel track light does not fit.

There are some restaurant designs out there that are described as “eclectic” and if you want to go that route that’s fine. However, to successfully be eclectic you have to make a conscious choice to seek out variety so you avoid the Mr. Potato Head look and feel of a few mismatched body parts.

I have had this happen to me many times, on restaurant design jobs and other project types as well. The owner comes in with a stack of photos clipped from different magazines or a list of their favorites restaurants and they want a little bit from each. We then have to have a discussion about what it is they really like in each photo and does it really go with everything else they brought in. And yes I invoke the name of Mr. Potato Head to explain why.
 
 Be the first to comment - What do you think?   Posted by
 - 
 February 1, 2012 at 2:53 pm

Categories: Architect Rant , Restaurant Architecture , Restaurant Design Ideas   Tags:


 
 How Do I Get What I Want For a Price I Can Afford? 

In the previous post I wrote about what factors influence the final cost of your restaurant design. In this post I want to apply those ideas. Once you have accepted the fact that you are not going to get some super special deal where everything will cost you a lot less than your competitors, you can start to:

 Think realistically about how to get the biggest bang for your buck. Think strategically about what is important and what is not. 

With a blank page your restaurant design can be anything. You need to find constraints to define what the final restaurant design will be. So before you even start the restaurant design you should have a financial proforma as part of your business plan. The proforma should define how much you expect to make in total revenue, what your operating expenses are what your projected profit will be. Part of the operating expenses will be rent and debt. With this information you can back into how much you have to spend on building your restaurant. Going back to the last post again, you should check to make sure this is a realistic number.

Now, that you have a financial model to guide the restaurant design you can start the design process. There are 2 ways to use the financial constraint when working on your restaurant design. Design to a price or price a design.

 Design to a Price 

Designing to a price is efficient, in terms of time spent by the restaurant architect working of the restaurant design. It is also less stressful for the restaurateur, because you don’t have to give things up when you can’t afford it. In this method you take your budget and break it down into parts on a spread sheet. There are line items stating how much will be spent of the kitchen, toilets, floors, ceilings, furnishings, etc. After you have these sub-budgets only components that fall within the price range are incorporated into the restaurant design. Working this way takes discipline but in the end everyone should be happy. People tend not to use this method because they don’t et to dream about what could be.

 Price a Design 

This is by far the more common method of restaurant design. It involves creating a design with the final budget in mind but not detailed and not enforced as in the previous method. The restaurant architect will rely on experience to try to hit the budget. If the design comes in over budget, then the restaurant architect and restaurateur will have go back to the design and decide what comes out. When I talked about stress for the restaurateur above, this is what I was talking about. You put something in the design because you want it, but then have to give it up.

One technique often used in this method is the “Bid Alternate”. A Bid Alternate is when part of the restaurant is designed but may or may not be built depending on where the prices come in when the construction bids are received from the contractors bidding on the restaurant. This can be less stressful, because you get less attached to the restaurant design elements tagged as alternates. But, taking things out is always a bummer.

One word of warning about the Price a Design method, is that it creates the temptation to “find more money” for the design once the prices come in. Do this at your risk. Having a bigger monthly nut to pay because you fell love with a design and weren’t willing to compromise, is how many restaurants fail.

As always I hope this is usefully information for you and helps your work go more smoothly.

To the right you can sign up for our newsletter, this is not a spammy sales letter, it is information I consider interesting and relevant to retail and restaurant design.
 
 Be the first to comment - What do you think?   Posted by
 - 
 January 20, 2012 at 4:50 pm

Categories: Architect Tip , Restaurant Architecture , Restaurant Design Ideas   Tags:


 
 How Much is This Restaurant Going to Cost to Build? 

 In any design and construction project weather it is a restaurant design or not “how much is this going to cost” if it is not the very first question it is certainly in the team photo of early questions. The problem is you don’t exactly know how much it will cost until the built. That is not to say you can not very close with an estimate early than that. This post will talk about pricing for restaurant construction, but will be applicable to all construction not just restaurants.

Everyone thinks they are special and can get better pricing than everyone else, but you’re not. Get over it. Assuming you are honest, live up to your commitments, pay your bills and do business with similar design and construction professionals, your restaurant project will be priced fairly and in line with the industry standard for restaurant construction. If you want to know what the standards are you can have your restaurant architect give you guidance from published documents like RS Means . RS Means publishes books every showing what typical construction costs, this data is what most cost estimates are based on. An initial estimate, if done honestly with be within about 10% of the final cost. This estimate is useful for an early go-no-go decision and it is also becomes a self-fulling prophecy for the final price.

 What control’s pricing? 

Now when you first start looking at cost, you are not totally helpless in controlling where the price ends up, but you are not in complete control either. The main thing you can control is the restaurant design. The main thing you can’t control is the market you are building in, that is controlled by supply and demand in the market. The last main factor in your pricing is your volume discount, some times you control it, but if you are not careful it will control you.

 The Design 

This is pretty straight forward to understand. If your restaurant design calls for a lot of expensive finishes, fancy light fixtures and high end furniture, then expect to pay a lot. If your restaurant design calls for bare concrete floors, painted walls and picnic-tables you can expect to get buy pretty cheap. That being said there are some tricks and pitfalls your restaurant architect needs to be aware of. Below is a brief list of things to be aware of.

 Some finishes that look cheap can actually be expensive. Exposed structure open ceilings is one example that comes to mind. One might think no ceiling equals no cost, wrong. If you leave out the ceiling then everything above where the ceiling might be has to look better than it would with the ceiling and therefor it costs more. It really cost the same or more to leave a ceiling out. Some finishes that look expensive are actually cheap. Porcelain tile is a good example of this, wears like iron for a flooring, doesn’t cost that much. People only focus on certain things and this is where you should send your money. An example of this would be light fixtures. You use light fixtures for 2 reasons, lighting and decoration. If you try to get all of your lighting out of expensive decorative fixture you will have an expensive design. You can and probably should only use a few decorative fixtures and then fill in the lightning with unobtrusive less expensive fixtures. 

 Supply and Demand 

Not much you can control here but like a surfer that doesn’t control waves you can still take advantage of the ups and downs in the market. From 2005 through the middle of 2008 prices for construction were going up fast, because the market was over heated and everyone was demanding building materials. There was new construction everywhere. Today in 2012 prices are way down. A buyers market. It’s OK to build in a market going up and down. The waring sign to look for is shortages in materials that indicate an overheated market. In 2007 the demand for drywall in North America exceeded the production capacity, so drywall was actually imported.

 Volume discount 

This also seems straight forward, but can be tricky. The more you buy of something the less each unit will cost. You can take advantage of this in your selection of products to use. Where this really comes into play is in the size of the restaurant itself. A 4,000 square foot restaurant is 20% smaller that a 5,000 square foot restaurant, but will cost only 10% or so less. In other words the bigger the restaurant the smaller the cost per square foot of the restaurant. Now, this is where you have to be careful and not over buy just because of the volume discount. You have to have a reasonable chance to fill up your restaurant, before you build.

That is my primer on restaurant design pricing. In the next post we will cover on how to get the restaurant you want for the price you can afford.

To the right you can sign up for our newsletter, this is not a spammy sales letter, it is information I consider interesting and relevant retail and restaurant design.
 
 Be the first to comment - What do you think?   Posted by
 - 
 January 11, 2012 at 10:23 am

Categories: Architect Tip , Restaurant Architecture , Restaurant Design Ideas   Tags:


 
 The Disintegration of Restaurant Design 

 What do I mean by Disintegration? 

I am using the word in the most literal sense meaning it was integrated and now it is not. This is not a totally original idea. I first started to think about business this way after reading The Innovator’s Dilemma book series by Clayton M. Christensen. These books are mostly about high tech business and their supply chains but the ideas apply to all business including the restaurant industry.

Let me recap the idea using an example from the books. Way back when IBM was the only computer company in the world. They were the innovators of computers, and as such they had to do everything themselves. In the original mainframe computers IBM made everything and did everything that went into the computer. They needed to design the chips and make the chips. They needed to design and build the memory and storage. They need to create the operating system and programming languages. Everything they needed they had to design and build themselves and after that they had to market, sell and support the computers. In other words IBM was an integrated computer company, in that all aspects of design, production, sales and support were all in one organization, nothing was outsourced. Accordingly IBM received a huge profit margin on each computer they sold.

 Now seeing these huge profits and a growing market other business jumped into the game. Some of these new competitors were integrated like IBM and designed and built everything themselves, but others focused on just certain parts of the computer. Intel came along and just made chips. Seagate came along just made hard drives. Microsoft just made the software. These companies that made just parts of a computer allowed the industry to dis-integrate into these pieces. Companies like Apple and Dell rely on this pool of component manufactures to do most of the work. Most of what computer manufactures do today is integrate all the pieces from other companies.

One interesting thing to note is that as the computer industry went through this process of dis-integration the profit margins went down at each step. On the bright side as the margins deteriorated the cost of starting a new computer company went down also. IBM was already a huge company making typewriters and punch card machines when they got into computers so they could afford the cost, to innovate and they reaped huge profits for quite a while. Compare that to Michael Dell starting his company in his college dorm room financed on a credit card.

One case does not make a general rule. Does this case study represent a general rule or just a quirk of the computer industry. In the books, the same process of companies starting out doing everything and slow becoming broken up into specialty companies is tracked in several industries. For example Ford at one time started with iron ore to make cars and now they have a large network of suppliers. The books make a compelling case that the dis-integration of a business over time is a natural cycle of any successful industry.

 Is this a good thing? 

Yes, it is a good thing as long as you are not IBM. The original innovators have their day in the sun reaping large profits but it is those profits that attract the attention of competitors that eventually dis-integrate the original business. The important thing to take away about this process is that as the industry is divided into smaller chunks it becomes more efficient so the cost to start a new business goes down. Also, the required expertise to start a new business goes down as well. Dell did not have to learn how to make hard drives or chips. All Dell had to learn to do was assemble computes and then sell them, much simpler that what IBM had to do years earlier.

 Does this apply to restaurants? 

Yes, this does apply to restaurants. There are 2 different phases of creation in the restaurant industry. First there is the creation of the restaurant itself and second is the ongoing creation of meals every day. Both parts are separate industries in themselves and both have dis-integrated over time just as described above. In the restaurant creation phase it used to be that a prospective restauranteur had to do most everything themselves now there is a large industry of consultants to take on specialized tasks and suppliers to provide specialized furnishing and equipment.

 What Types of Consultants Are There? 

As a restaurant architect I am one of the consultants that bring specialized knowledge to restauranteurs so they don’t have to spend their time learning what I already know. Restaurant owners and people thinking about opening restaurants should not only accept the fact the industry is dis-integrated but they should embrace it and use it to their best advantage.

Creating a new restaurant requires a lot of specialized knowledge required to brand, design and build, but once that work is done that is it, you don’t have to do it again. Having extensive knowledge about branding, design and construction doesn’t help run the place. So why should someone interested in running a restaurant spend the time to own all that knowledge when they can just rent it from consultants?

The main consultants involved in restaurant creation would be:

 Real Estate. There are brokers that specialize in real estate for restaurants. You should definitely work with someone who understands restaurants and their requirements. Such as parking, black iron grease ducts, exhaust fans and grease traps. Not all building are set up for this and you shouldn’t waste time looking at spaces that can’t accommodate a restaurant. Also, a good broker will do a “gap analysis”. This is a study of the local competition looking for areas that are not covered by your type of restaurant. In other word that can help you avoid competing restaurants. Restaurant Architects and Designers. I am not going to recap this here since most of the blog is devoted to restaurant design. Kitchen Designers. A good kitchen designer will be up to date on the latest equipment, be able to help get the best pricing and work through any installation issues. One caveat here is don’t use cheep or free design services from an equipment supplier. They will at least be tempted to select equipment that has the best profit margin for them and not the best value for you. 

The main consultants involved is running a restaurant are:

 Marketing. Even thought I have Marketing as an ongoing consultant this should be the first consultant you hire when starting a restaurant. This is because knowing your target market and understanding your brand should be done first before you even select a site. The entire creation of your restaurant should revolve around your brand. Once you select a location or a name you start to limit your marketing choices. You have to work around what you have already done. Menus Consultants. When you do your branding you will select the type of food to be served. You probably have some key recipes in mind. A menu consultant can advise on the balance of the menu. They will provide information on where to source ingredients and how to maximize the profits on each dish. Operations Consultants. These consultants design or re-design the processes within a given restaurant. Operations consultants help restauranteurs work smart so they don’t have to work hard. Operations consultants should be people that have run successful restaurants in the past and want to share their knowledge now. 

 What Can’t be outsourced and why? 

Your Passion can’t be outsourced. I don’t want to give anyone the idea that you just outsource everything and the restaurant business is easy. Nothing could be farther from the truth, but it is easier with consultants than without. There is still a lot of knowledge that a restaurant owner must possess to run the business on a daily basis, but far more important than knowledge is passion.

The word passion is really over used. It seems that everyone is throwing it out as the cure all to fix whatever is wrong with an organization. I think I am using it correctly in this case. It is the only word I have that explains the inner drive that will let you keep going in the face of adversity. Most restaurants fail and succeed or not they are hard work and require long hours. So you have to have that something that causes you to try in face of bad odds and keep you going when thing get rough.
 
 Be the first to comment - What do you think?   Posted by
 - 
 June 30, 2011 at 3:16 pm

Categories: Restaurant Architecture , Restaurant Design Ideas   Tags:


 
 Do You Get Your Old Building? 

The fact is buildings once built are hard to change.  Ironically if a building is well designed and built it can achieve historic status and then it becomes impossible to change.  So buildings don’t change but people do, then what do we do with our old buildings? 

People have changed a lot over the last century, both physically and socially.  Everyone knows that the height and weight of Americans has increased steadily for the last 100 years.  The seating capacity of old churches have gone down.  You used to figure 1 person took up 18 inches of pew space and now to have to figure 2 feet per person.   Old stadiums and theater seats have to be replace with wider seats to accommodate us.  This widening reduces the capacity the venue was originally designed for.

Less well understood by the public are the social changes that have gone on that change the way we use buildings.  The biggest impact has been the Americans with Disabilities Act.  It is very common to find older buildings with door that are 30 or 32 inches wide.  Under the ADA doors must be 36 inches wide to accommodate wheel chairs.  Older buildings often used level changes of a step or two between rooms to create some interest and visual drama.  Can’t do that anymore.  The classic example is the court house steps.  Almost every historic county courthouse in American has a grand stair case leading to the entrance.  Some office buildings built in the early 20th century didn’t have women’s toilets or only had them on one floor.

So what are we to do with the older building stock we have?  There is no one answer to the question, in fact each building will have its own unique answer.  One person that has found his answer is Ron Onesti owner or the Arcada Theater is St. Charles Illinois.  I sat down and talked to Mr. Onesti about his theater and the vision he has for a historic building.

The Arcada theater was opened in 1926 by a local millionaire to bring theater to a town of only 5,000 people at the time.  The theater became a popular stop on the Vaudeville circuit.  In the 1940′s it evolved into a movie theater and was operated as such by Plitt and Cineplex Odeon until 1993 when it was sold to Classic Cinemas.  Classic Cinemas restore the building to its original appearance and operated it until 2001 when the sold it.  The single screen theater no matter how nice has gone the way of the buffalo and the theater struggled until 2005 when Ron Onesti took over management.  The solution of what to do with the building was to go back to the original intent for the building and have live performances.

Modern movie theaters set the bar for what we expect in the movie going experience.  Wide cushioned seats with cup holders.  Large concession stands with hot dogs and nachos in addition the the standards of popcorn and candy.  And, most importantly a lot of screens with many chooses of film and starting time.  Historic theaters with only one screen and limited concession stands can’t compete with these modern facilities for the same customer.  The solution is to tap into a different customer base.

The customer base for live concerts expects one act to perform at one time so this fits perfectly with what the Arcada Theater already has a stage.  The theater also fills a niche in the market for live acts.  It fills the gap between bars and stadiums.  At 900 seats the venue is large enough to draw national acts but remains within reach of local and regional shows.

While speaking with Ron Onesti the one thing that was very clear is his passion to provide entertainment to people.  He combined his passion with a great historic venue to provide a terrific asset to the community and the region.  The current incarnation of the Arcada Theater simultaneously preserves a local landmark while elevating the quality of life for the local residence, by providing a unique entertainment opportunity.

This example should serve as a template on how to understand older building and find new uses for them.  Learn the history of you building, inventory what you have and look for gaps in the markets that can be filled by your building.  Don’t try to compete with modern buildings that define what customers expect but instead look for areas where your building can add value that newer buildings can’t.
 
 
 Be the first to comment - What do you think?   Posted by
 - 
 May 2, 2011 at 3:41 pm

Categories: Architect Tip   Tags:


 
 Restaurant Ideas – What About the Sign 

This post is not just for restaurants but for all businesses that depend on signs to attract customers. The oldest form of marketing there is put up a sign to announce who your are and what you have to sell. Advertisement in the newspaper, on radio and on television are all nice to have if you can afford it but every business that seek to serve the public needs a sign. You might think my restaurant has a name and a logo I just slap them up as big as I can and customer will come in. I am here to tell you otherwise there is a science to a good sign. 

If you study the signs of successful restaurants and stores you will see what I am talking about. The most successful restaurant and retail signs have the same two elements, a strong silhouette and a dominate color. Below I will explain what each of these is. The fun thing about working with restaurants and stores is that they are all around and you can test what I am talking about for yourself. Next time you go out see what signs catch your eye and ask why. 

Silhouette – During World War II spotting planes and identifying them was a matter of life and death. When something is at a distance and first becomes visible what you see is the silhouette. It makes sense that you can pick out the outline shape of something long before detailed markings become visible. Now understanding that the military was face with the problem of educating a huge number of people on what plane had what silhouette. The solution was not to have classes with a lot on monotonous drill. Instead the military printed up and gave away decks of playing cards with different airplane silhouette’s on them. As you gambled away your pay you learned how to identify enemy planes.

The best signs use this ability people have to identify things at a great distance by the silhouette. Even with the sign turned off in moonlight can’t you pick out McDonald’s golden arches from a mile away. Blockbuster is going the way of the buffalo but it its time the torn-ticket sign was a strong sign identifiable from far off. Wendy’s, Lowes, Chevy all have a unique outline. Can your potential patrons identify your sign as easily?

Dominant Color – The next thing people see on your sign after the outline is the dominant, think John Deere Green. Starbucks and Target both use the same shape, a simple circle, but each owns their color, Target red and Starbucks green. If you see a round sign at a distance and can not read the text yet, you can probably tell if it is a Starbucks or Target. Along the same lines Home Depot uses a simple square sign but owns the color orange. The important thing to remember is you don’t have to choose color or shape, it is best to use both, like McDonald’s “Golden Arches”. 

Educating the Public – Remember the deck of card from above? It is not enough to carefully design the silhouette of your sign and select a good color to call your own. Once you have done those thing you have to educate the public, so they know your sign at a distance. How do you do this? Just like the deck of cards, make your sign common to your potential patrons and the let the message sink in. This is a process of repetition and time.

Let’s compare 2 stores everyone knows Staples and Office Depot. Both stores compete in the office supply category they have similar store plans, their stores are similar sizes and they sell the same stuff. Looking at their signs neither has a distinct silhouette, but Staples has white letter on a big red background. Staples is clearly the more successful of the 2 companies. Now I am not giving all the credit to the red background, but that clearly is a factor in the public’s awareness of where stores are located.

Let’s compare restaurants. What restaurants have signs with both a unique silhouette and a dominate color. There is McDonald’s and … well you don’t have to like a big mac to respect their success. Why not take a page from their play book when it comes to designing your sign.

Design your Logo so it has both a Silhouette and Dominant Color and your sign design will fall into place. Covering these 2 fundamentals will give you a leg up on your competition. Think what Now go out and make better signs.
 
 Be the first to comment - What do you think?   Posted by
 - 
 February 4, 2011 at 12:45 pm

Categories: Uncategorized   Tags:


 
 Taxes and Architecture? 
 
Get paid to stop this
 
2010 is behind us except for the tax returns.  Traditionally architects and engineers have had little to do with taxes except for paying them like everyone else, but since the“ Energy Tax Incentives Act of 2005 ”that has changed.  What I am talking about is the“ Energy-Efficient Commercial Building Property Deduction “.  The reason is that building owners and their accountants need Architects and Engineers to do some calculations and sign off so the deduction can be claimed.  In a nut shell if a commercial building is built or remodeled to be more energy efficient it may qualify for a text deduction.  Here is the government synopsis on the energy efficient commercial building property deduction. “A deduction is allowed for all or part of the cost of energy efficient commercial building property (i.e., certain major energy-savings improvements made to domestic commercial buildings) placed in service after December 31, 2005 and before January 1, 2014 Code Sec. 179D, as added by the Energy Tax Incentives Act of 2005, and amended by the Tax Relief and Health Care Act of 2006 and the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008″. A short summary of the deduction is that you can deduct a maximum of $1.80 per square foot of building or the cost of the energy efficient improvement whichever is less.  To qualify your building must be 50% more energy efficient than the base line established by the law.  The base line is the American Society of Heating, Refrigerating, and Air Conditioning Engineers [ASHRAE for short] and the Illuminating Engineering Society of North America. 90.1-2001 Energy Standard for Buildings Except Low-Rise Residential Buildings .

I am not going to go into detail on what does and doesn’t qualify because there is a lot of good information about that on the web already.  Best to go to the source and visit the IRS website .  What I am going to cover is how the calculate and determine if you are qualified, I think this is not well explained by the IRS and this is a place where I can add some value.  The procedure described by the IRS is generic and explains the concept but if far from a how to on claiming the deduction.  The process described by the IRS is simple use a software program approved by the Department of Energy [DOE for short] input your building and run the program once with the minimum base line mentioned and a second time as designed to see if it meets the requirements.  The list of approved software can be found here .

Now pay attention here is the big secret.  Of all the programs listed on the page use HAP“Hourly Analysis Program”.  Why because you probably already did use HAP.  HAP is distributed by Carrier and most mechanical engineers use this program to do the energy modeling to design the heating ventilating and air-conditioning system [HVAC for short] to start with.  Its just that simple.  Use a qualifying program to do the design and then nothing has to be redone for make the IRS happy.  Don’t get sidetracked with the programs written by DOE use the program you already are using.

I hope this helps everyone.  Claiming the deduction isn’t hard and it is there to be used.  Being eligible for the deduction is something to be proud of not in a“I am sticking it to the man”sort of way but in a“I am helping the environment”sort of way.  If you are a building owner and think you may qualify for this contact your architect and engineer and ask them.  If you are an architect and you have a client that may qualify please contact them and help them get the deduction.  Also, if you are an architect and the client was a governmental body then you can claim the deduction for yourself.
 
 Be the first to comment - What do you think?   Posted by
 - 
 January 14, 2011 at 4:51 pm

Categories: Architect Tip , Green Design   Tags:


 
 Why Payback is Wrong 

 

When contemplating an energy saving or green project people have been trained to ask“how long is the payback”but this absolutely the wrong question to ask.  Depending on how a project is paid for the correct questions to ask is“what is the effect on cash flow”or“what in the return on investment”.  When contemplating any project what you really want to know is will this have a good economic impact.  Knowing the time it takes to recoup the money spent doesn’t tell you this directly.  People have some arbitrary number in their heads 2 years, 5 years, 7 years or something else, the fact is the appropriate length of time to recoup the money expended on the project varies based on the nature of the project.  In this post I will explain why the is wrong and how you should approach analyzing if a project has a positive of negative economic impact.

Don’t ask about payback.  First of all nothing else is ever quoted in terms of“time to payback”so it makes comparing the project is question to another use of your capitol impossible.  This should be reason enough but there is more.  Second,“time to payback”is an absolute scale and doesn’t take into account the ultimate life span or the project.  If you are contemplation insulation as your project, insulation last indefinitely with no maintenance or up keep so longer pay back would be acceptable.  A windmill on the other hand may need to be rebuilt in 5 years so a shorter pay back is in order.  We need to have an idea of the life span of the project and make that part of the economic equation.  Third, the money spent on your project is most likely borrowed so you are going to be paying it off over time and this time scale doesn’t match up“time to payback”.  Lastly, if the money spent on your project isn’t borrowed, but actually taken from savings then“time to payback”can’t be compared to other places the money could be invested.

Ask about cash flow.  Any energy saving or green project should have a cash flow so looking at the effect on cash flow should be natural and helpful.  For example imagine you are considering adding solar panels to your home.  Determine how much the panels are and how long the panels will last, let us say 20 years and $20,000.  Next how long will you finance these panels for, let us say 10 years at 6% APR.  That is $222 a month for 120 months.  Now the question is will the energy savings going to exceed $222 a month, yes or no?  If yes then do the project.  The method of looking at cash flow work on all project types where the money is borrowed and also yields a simple yes or no out come.  The project is cash flow positive or it isn’t.

Ask about return on investment.  Not all projects borrow money some are actually paid for out of savings.  Many churches collect all or most of the cost of building before construction starts, also buildings donated to schools are often paid for up front.  In this case cash flow many not work for you so instead you can look at return on investment.  Again back to the solar panel question, imagine your house is paid for and you have a $20,000 certificated of deposit come due.  Should you renew the CD or buy solar panels?  Lets say that the the solar panels will save you $100.00 a month of electricity. That is $1,200.00 or 6% return on your money in the first year.  Remember this isn’t compounding interest so it is comparable to living off interest or principal and interest if the project is wearing out.  Go back to the life span question.  If the panels last 20 years and are then a complete loss you saved $24,000 over 20 years and that is only a 1.9% return on investment.  In other words you could have left the original $20,000 in an account that pays 1.9% interest and just take out $100 a month for 20 years to pay for electricity and had the same economic effect.  If you have something that doesn’t wear out like insulation the $20,000 would be preserved unlike the solar panels.

I hope you find this helpful in making decision on how to best invest money in green projects.  Please leave your feed back.  I would be interested to know if other are using these methods or something else.
 
 Be the first to comment - What do you think?   Posted by
 - 
 December 10, 2010 at 4:12 pm

Categories: Architect Rant , Architect Tip , Green Design   Tags:


 
 Restaurant Ideas–10 Tips for Interior Finishes 

This post continues my series on restaurant design ideas .  This list is intended as a professionals guide to restaurant ideas, design and architecture.   It is aimed at architects and designers but hopefully the public can enjoy it too.  Previously I wrote about restaurant exteriors , floor plans and lighting .  This post is about interior finishes.  This is a collection of ideas for restaurant design that are universal and should be applied to all restaurants regardless of restaurant type.  Whether you are designing for fast food, a bare-bones restaurant, a plain sit down diner or a full-service restaurant, these 10 design ideas will be actions to take.  This is not a list of restaurant trends for designer and architects.  I have tried to stay away from matters of taste and focus on unchanging truths of design and architecture.  This list is intended for the food service professionals, restaurant architects and restaurant designers.  Both the entrepreneur intending to start a restaurant or the operator of an existing restaurant looking into a re-branding effort should find these restaurant design ideas useful.   Good design ideas are the best type of marketing.

 Harden the walls tastefully .  Look into any successful restaurant and you will see that the walls take a lot of abuse from the restaurant customers.  The walls of the waiting area get dirty the dining area gets dented from chairs, the hallways get scratched from mop buckets and service carts.  Any wall exposed to traffic will take a beating, so they must be tough.  It is the restaurant designers job to harden these walls and make it look good.  Any wall in a restaurant that is just painted will get dented and scratched.  The ways to harden wall are limited only by your creativity.  Some ways I have used with success are; traffic coatings which are just heavy duty paints pricey but they leave a clean look, wainscoting a very traditional solution and alternate wall material like wood paneling or tile.  Remember the food service professional who has to clean the restaurant, hardening the walls is not just about scratch and dent but is also about being easily cleanable. Everything in a restaurant has to be cleaned .  Talented architects and designers always envision a restaurant as new and clean, but starting with the first customers the place starts to get dirty.  During the time you are open to the restaurant public the tables will get wiped a little sweeping and that’s it until the place closes down for the night and the public goes home.  Cleaning a restaurant is tough, it requires a lot of effort.  As the architect don’t be part of the problem.  The design challenge is to make a restaurant free of places that are hard to clean.  Avoid small nooks that can’t be moped.  Avoid shelves that can’t be dusted. Dust is gray not black .  This restaurant idea is a special case of the idea above.  Not everything is going to get dusted everyday some place won’t get dusted until the scheduled deep cleaning of your restaurant.  If you have a place like this in your design plan for it to hide dust.  Don’t let the public see the build-up.  You have a restaurant architecture with exposed structure, dust is going to accumulate on the ducts and structure.  If these are painted black they will acquire a grey halo outlining them against the black deck.  Next time you go into a restaurant with an black exposed structure look into the ceiling and check for the dust.  Go through your design and identify these places where dust will collect and make sure the dust is camouflaged.  Grey paint works well but don’t limit your creativity. Tile last forever don’t be trendy. In the life of a restaurant ceramic tile will last a long time, so plan on living with it a long time.  If you pick a fashionable tile it will go out of style before it wears out.  Many restaurateurs start a restaurant in an old restaurant.  The design work will be to do some re-branding of the space with fresh ideas to keep the owners costs down.  Remember restaurants are a business.  If the tile was the hot and trendy thing 5 years ago you will want to rip it out if today’s restaurant.  It is not wrong to follow the restaurant trends, the challenge for the talented design professional is to do it wisely with finishes that can be easily changed like paint and fabric. You don’t have to decorate all at once. First, let me clarify what I mean by restaurant decoration.  Decoration is not the restaurant design and it is not picking the finishes and furniture.  Decoration is all the stuff in your restaurant that goes on top of the finishes like artwork.  I would make this statement even stronger and say you should not decorate your restaurant all at once.  When you open a restaurant it becomes part of the community and that community your customers the restaurant public will want to see it become more a part of the community over time.  Adding decoration over time that is relevant to the neighborhood is a great type of marketing that creates a bond with your customers.  A lot of owners just jamb the walls with pictures the day the restaurant opens.  Does having that Marilyn Monroe poster endear you to your customers?  Why not wait and have a picture of local significance?  Build your collection of decoration over time, let your regular restaurant customers know you are looking for decoration and bring the community to action.  What better way to build loyal customers and make your place someone’s favorite restaurant.  This will be one of your best forms of marketing. Use walk off mats and other types of dirt control in your restaurant. Hopefully you have a lot of foot traffic into your restaurant and feet bring dirt.  Good dirt control is integrated into the design.  Start at the front door before it gets in your restaurant have a mat outside that will help to strip dirt and water off  of shoes.  These walk off mats will need to be cleaned and changed so make them a manageable size.  If your in a snowy climate the mats may need to be changed quickly during business hours to avoid a slippery situation.  Where a door swings over a walk of mat as in a vestibule if the mat and door are not designed to go together the door will damage the mat.  This is a tough restaurant problem and ignoring it won’t make it go away, incorporate it in the restaurant architecture. Hard ceilings in restaurants need access panels. When it comes to restaurant ceilings you have 3 options, exposed structure, access ceilings and hard ceilings.  Exposed structure is just what it sound like the buildings structure is exposed to view allowing you to see all the beams and ducts.  This can be fun and fitting for some restaurants like bare-bones restaurant or a sports bar.  Access ceilings are modular tiles they hide everything above them but allow access.  This is common in family style restaurants.  Hard ceilings are made of drywall and give a high end elegant look to a restaurant.  The problem is that there is no access above them.  A hard ceiling will need panels located to allow access above them.  Make sure these panels are located in unobtrusive places.  A competent design professional and food service professional should locate the required panels of the design drawings and not leave it to chance during construction. When designing start by selecting finishes with the least options to the most options. Restaurant design always starts from the given’s and builds for there.  Selecting finishes should proceed in the same fashion.  Start by selecting the materials that offer the least variety first.  If you do this backwards and pick a paint color first finding a wood and tile to match will be difficult.  Tile ranges are limited to a few dozen and wood is similar but some paint manufactures have 1500 standard colors. Chairs and Booths need crumb control. You probably want your customers to sit down even in fast food restaurant.  If restaurant idea includes people eating on premises (a real restaurant) you will have crumbs.  Examine the furniture your restaurant architect is showing you for clean ability.  On a bench the gap between the cushions will collect crumbs.  How easily can you clean them out?  Smarter diners look at the cleanliness of a restaurant as an indicator of quality.  Take specific action by selecting easily cleanable restaurant furniture.  This does not mean you have to throughout your restaurant ideas and use institutional furnishings.  An upholstered booth can have a space between the back and seat cushions that can be vacuumed and wiped, or the bottom can come up easily for a nightly wipe down. Floor finishes should hide dirt, not trap it. At the start of the business day your restaurant is clean but as soon as the first customer walks in the place starts to get dirty.  The floor takes most of the abuse.  Look at these finishes with a tough eye.  Pick something that won’t look instantly dirty and will clean up easily.  Hard patterned surfaces work great for this but can be loud.  Carpet is unavoidable because it helps control noise.  So be smarter with your restaurant ideas when selecting flooring and look beyond price and color to the wear and clean-ability data. 

I hope you find this collection of ideas useful and it helps you design smarter when you start a restaurant or your re-branding effort.  This list is not intended to be specific actions but a check list of fundamental restaurant ideas.  I believe that all restaurants share some unchangeable truths no matter what type of restaurant you are designing full-service sit down to fast food.  I also hope that these design ideas would act as a check list of basics to give you confidence in your restaurant ideas which lead to freedom and creativity.  New restaurants ideas are being tried all time, I love checking out the new restaurant model.  Please leave a comment describing the new variations you have tried on the ideas expressed here, or let me know how your favorite restaurant approaches these design ideas.  Thank you.
 
 224 comments - What do you think?   Posted by
 - 
 November 17, 2010 at 3:32 pm

Categories: Architect Tip , Restaurant Design Ideas   Tags:


 
 Next Page» 
 
 
Sign up for Our Retail Newletter
 Email Address * First Name Last Name * = required field Preferred Format 
 HTML Text Mobile 
 
 powered by MailChimp ! 
 
 Your Ad Here 
Recent Posts

 What Makes Good Restaurant Furniture? The Mr. Potato Head School of Restaurant Design How Do I Get What I Want For a Price I Can Afford? How Much is This Restaurant Going to Cost to Build? The Disintegration of Restaurant Design 
 
Archives

 February 2012 January 2012 June 2011 May 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 
 
Hospitality Industry Favorites
 Do You Get Your Old Building? 
 
 Your Ad Here 
 
 Your Ad Here 
 
WordPress Theme by HeatMapTheme.com
	</body>
</document>
