<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009740" url="http://www.43things.com/things/view/1942153/stop-drinking-pepsi-for-30-consecutive-days" time="2012-07-13-03:08" support="1" score="0.0005539039383628894" bingtitle="Stop drinking pepsi for 30 consecutive days." webtitle="Stop drinking pepsi for 30 consecutive days.">
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="219"/>
	<description>Get advice and support on how to Stop drinking pepsi ... that I enjoyed, like coffee, the occational glass ... then I had to park in the parking lot of a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Zeitgeist Login with
Facebook    Log in  or  Sign up 
 

 2 people want to do this. 
 Stop drinking pepsi for 30 consecutive days. 
 Share this goal with others Invite 
 
 
 Sponsored Links 
 Stop Drinking 

 www. drink lessnow.com/    A New Way To Help Alcoholics. Stop Drinking In Just 8 Weeks!
 
 Schick Shadel Hospital 

 www.schickshadel.com/    Alcohol Treatment Hospital Get your life back in ten days !
 
 Treatment for Alcoholism 

 www.bettyfordcenter.org/    Inpatient, Outpatient, Residential, 90 day programs. Contact us now.
 
People doing this

 

 Sponsored Links 
 Kick the habit 

 www.alcolim.org/    Quit drinking , quick, easy and Natural, 3 for 2 offer
 
Recent activity
 
 jaasssoooonnnnn wrote thanks for the motivation 
 
i’m quitting this too 2 years ago 
 1 cheer . 1 comment . Comment 
 
 cassolete completed this goal 
 It took me 30 days It made me proud 

 How I did it: I chose a period of time that was reasonable to me. I also provided myself with other beverages that I enjoyed, like coffee, the occational glass of pinapple juice, tea, and good water. I drank enough water to prevent being thirsty, but not so much that I felt punished for trying to set a good goal. Finally, knowing that I could have pepsi after my trial period was up helped me get through my cravings. Read how I did it… 3 years ago 

 Comment 
 cassolete wrote Untitled 
 
Tomorrow (Today?? It’s 12:31 AM) is my last day of requred pepsi-less-ness. I’m thinking I might say I’ve conquored this goal and then start a new goal for 60 days, and see if I can tag another 30 days onto the last 30 days. Then again, I might really want a pepsi tomorrow. :D 3 years ago 
 1 cheer . Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote I&apos;m really close to the end 
 
I’m thinking about extending this goal to 60 days, see how it goes. Think I could make it to 60 days? I guess I’m starting day 28 now. 3 years ago 
 Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote Untitled 
 
I’m almost there! :D Almost! 3 years ago 
 Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote stress makes it harder 
 
I wanted to drink pepsi badly today. I did drink several glasses of chocolate milk, and I’ve eaten way too much today, probably because I was so stressed out about grad school. I’m getting thirsty, so maybe I’ll go drink a bottle of water now to help avoid that whole pepsi craving. I’m finding that when I don’t have access to the pepsi, it’s easier than relyin’on Will Power. Will Power gets me past the pepsi in the checkout line at Walmart, but not all the way through a month spent in an apartment stocked with pepsi! Y’know? I can’t wait until the 31st, though, no questions there. I plan on having a bottle of pepsi then. (Just a small one!) 3 years ago 
 Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote Untitled 
 
Still goin’strong. I’ve actually been wanting to drink water today. That’s exciting, eh? 3 years ago 
 1 cheer . Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote Untitled 
 
Today I repaid a person’s kindness by driving through Taco John’s and buying them supper food. Of course, they sell pepsi there. I bought a sprite. It’s not technically pepsi, so it doesn’t count. ;) Nah, the real aim of this goal was to break the habit of pepsi, and I think I have done that. Sprite isn’t something I do on a regular basis. Plus, they didn’t sell anything juice-like and I didn’t want water. :P So, so far so good but NO MORE SODA AT ALL for me. 3 years ago 
 Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote No pepsi today! 
 
10 days to go! 3 years ago 
 Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote Untitled 
 
Today I went to Denny’s and I drank a fizzy drink. It was…uh…mango and strawberry, I think, with a little bit of orange juice, and Sprite. I’m not counting it as cheating because I was working on something I really didn’t want to do and needed a treat as motivation, because it wasn’t pepsi, because it’s not something I am in the habit of drinking, and because I don’t feel guilty about it. ;) So, no pepsi for me, and onward we go! 3 years ago 
 Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote Untitled 
 
Y’know, staying home is a good strategy for this goal. I spent today doing homework, cleaning, and exercising in my apartment, so I didn’t run into Pepsi or Pepsi advertisements at all. I did drink Chai tea, though. :) I like that stuff.

Eighteen days down! Twelve to go! Today I didn’t have as many cravings, either, so maybe I’ll be able to continue to stick with it. I’ve noticed it’s been a lot easier to keep my weight on the lower side of average, even though it’s just been about a pound or two lower than usual. I haven’t noticed many gains in the way of how I think/feel, though, and those are the results that would motivate me the most. It’s a lot cheeper to drink water and tea and coffee and juice, though! I’ve noticed that. :) 3 years ago 
 Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote More water 
 
Today was another successful day. Not having pepsi in the house and not leaving the house helps. :P I have noticed that things like juiceboxes taste much sweeter now. I haven’t stopped having these crazy cravings, though. This trial has been good for my pocketbook, since I spend less pocketmoney on impulse pepsi from vending machines. It’s also been good for my weight. I’ve been just slightly under my usual weight all month, with less fluctuating. If that is a continuous benefit, I might be more likely to continue with this habit after my self-imposed date. 3 years ago 
 Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote Untitled 
 
I wonder when I’ll stop wanting pepsi so much? Today I seriously considered drinking a pepsi and then starting my 30 days over again! :P That would be a ton of work. Heh. But I drank water today instead, which is probably the very best. :) 3 years ago 
 Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote 2 weeks in! 
 
So far so good…I am sort of noticing a slight change in how I taste things. Water tastes better, for example. Also, the grapes I’ve been eating seem to taste sweeter than they might have otherwise. I still have crazy-ass cravings, though. I’m halvway there! 3 years ago 
 Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote Untitled 
 
I went on a Dennys run with friends last night…I ordered a BLT plate with fries and water. Water is kind of boring, but I am getting used to it as a substitute. I used to always try to drink juice or coffee if I was in a situation I used to drink Pepsi in, but I am thinking that water is probably the best choice. I mean, not all the time—chocolate milk is a good choice, too. ;)

I am on day 14! After today I will have abstained for two whole weeks! Go me! ;)

“When in doubt, act boldly, as if it were impossible to fail”.

—Crystal 3 years ago 
 1 cheer . Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote Untitled 
 
I nearly broke today!! I went grocery shopping while hungry, which is always a bad idea, but the thing about grocery shopping is that I tend to put it off until there’s no more food in the house. Hah. Anyway. Here is the point: I had to push my cart past the pepsi aisle. I just didn’t give myself any time to linger on it. AND THEN there was pepsi in the checkout line!! I was like, is there no mercy? But at that point my stubborn nature kicked in and my brain said NO, NO WAY .

And then I had to park in the parking lot of a fast food restaurant that sells pepsi before running an errand, while I was still hungry. But I KNEW that if I went inside and ordered food there, I wouldn’t be able to resist my carbonated boghole! So I was a good girl.

As a reward for sticking with it, I am going to make myself corn on the cob for supper. Yum, right? Yes, yum.

Good luck on your goals, everyone! 3 years ago 
 Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote Untitled 
 
I made it another day, although today I stayed home and there’s no Pepsi in my house, so victory was the defalt setting. :) I drank hot chocolate and juice instead. Oh, and a bit of water. I think it’s getting easier? It will be harder when I go back to campus, I bet, because I have more pepsi drinking habits engraved there. Heh, I guess I’ll just have to walk through the buildings singing something like WE ARE THE CHAMPIONS MY FRIENDS …or somesuch. One day at a time! Technically, 19 more days to go! I may have to do this challenge again and add another couple weeks to it, or something. 3 years ago 
 Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote Untitled 
 
I’ve made it another day! I was in a hurry to travel 6 hours today, and I bought a McDonald’s extra value meal (a big mac…not something I do often, but it sure tastes good)! I almost forgot about my resolution but just at the last moment remembered to ask for OJ instead of pop. It wasn’t as hard of a desision to make, since McDonalds only sells Coke and that’s a last resort sort of beverage to me. ;)

It’s too bad that it costs a little extra to choose OJ instead. I wish they would reward my good choice by catching a little of the extra expense, you know? But that’s okay.

I also drank chocolate milk and pinapple juice. I am getting creative in my no-pepsi lifestyle! I have made it through day 10 of my abstenance. Yay. 3 years ago 
 1 cheer . Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote Another day! 
 
We went to a restaraunt again. No pepsi for me! Coffee, though. I’m getting good at this. ;) 3 years ago 
 Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote Made it another day! 
 
I went to a restaraunt today with a friend and wanted a bottomless pop, but instead I…drank water. Go me! Also, two nights ago I dreamed I was drinking the BEST PEPSI EVER . Good thing dream pepsi doesn’t count. ;) 3 years ago 
 Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote Untitled 
 
I am eating Canadian macaroni and cheese, and I want a pepsi sooooo bad! So I am compromising. Instead of my fizzy drink, I will pull out the wine. HAH .

Uh. Just to let you know. I didn’t pull out the wine. Empty threat. BUT STILL . ;) 3 years ago 
 Comment 
 
 cassolete wrote Untitled 
 
I made this my resolution for this year! I’m only making myself do it as a 30 day trial though. I started January 1st, and it’s the 4th now. (Actually, I started a little before Christmas but didn’t officially commit until the new year). A month isn’t that long, right? Right? I’ve been drinking coffee and juice instead. 3 years ago 
 Comment 
 See more:     Entries   |   How I Did It Entries 
 
 Report a very similar goal 
 
Report a very similar goal
The current goal: Stop drinking pepsi for 30 consecutive days. 
Very similar goal: (or Cancel )
Meaning is slippery, but try to only add goals that have nearly identical meanings. For example, &quot;Be fluent in Italian&quot; and &quot;Speak fluent Italian&quot;.
 On average: This goal takes 4 weeks to complete 
Worth Doing

1 person thinks this is worth it.
 
 “ For one human being to love another -- that is perhaps the most difficult of our tasks; the ultimate, the last test and proof, the work for which all other work is but preparation. ” - Rainer Maria Rilke 
 ( What is RSS? ) 
 First added to cassolete &apos;s list 
 
 I want to: 
The world wants to...
 find the most peaceful place on Earth improve my public speaking skills confused101 wants to Beat my depression get up on time learn to play the harmonica cast a spell on someone. go to the oscars watch southpark Strength train paint my kitchen Learn to cook create a non-profit organization make a collage shoemaker wants to have more self control find at least one thing each day that makes me happy and record it everyday for a year Sing figure out what clothes suit me and fit me Watch a Joan of Arcadia Episode i want to live in the wild embrace Upgrade my PC Become Financially Independent house ATLfemme wants to meet like minded people dream lucidly bellydance build an online portfolio read 12 books in 2010 
 City Hall 
 FAQ Guidelines Contact Us Tools 
 iPhone App RSS API About Us 
 Our blog Press coverage Terms of Use Follow @43things Copyright©2004 - 2012 Robot Co-op 
 
 43 Things Login 
 Username: Password: Remember me   Forgot username or password? 
 or Join 43 Things
	</body>
</document>
