<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0009605" url="http://www.usedicemachine.info/city/dallas/1" time="2012-07-13-03:00" support="1" score="0.0008331692010741522" bingtitle="Used Ice Machines Dallas" webtitle="Used Ice Machines Dallas">
			<query id="000588" bing-rank="46"/>
	<description>Here is the deal on this ice machine... It was donated to us last year from a fast food restaurant that was going ... If you want to pay with a credit card we ask you pay ...</description>
	<body>
		Used Ice Machines Dallas 


 
 Used Ice Machines 1808 

 dallas 114 
 
 albuquerque 11 anchorage 11 atlanta 63 austin 34 bakersfield 9 baltimore 32 boston 41 buffalo 12 charlotte 35 chicago 94 cincinnati 24 cleveland 28 columbus 28 corpuschristi 5 dallas 114 denver 36 detroit 60 elpaso 18 fresno 22 honolulu 25 houston 92 indianapolis 21 jacksonville 33 kansascity 30 lasvegas 24 lincoln 5 losangeles 135 memphis 3 miami 107 milwaukee 20 minneapolis 34 nashville 32 neworleans 23 newyork 52 oklahomacity 30 omaha 9 philadelphia 28 phoenix 60 pittsburgh 25 portland 58 raleigh 28 sacramento 39 sanantonio 29 seattle 49 stlouis 24 stockton 3 tampa 44 tucson 9 tulsa 26 washingtondc 34 
 
 Search: Used Ice Machines Dallas 

 


 subscribe to used ice machines in dallas 


114 used ice machines in dallas


 


 U Line Ice Machine New New New N Dallas 1800   details   visit 
07/11/2012
 NEW ! 
U LINE ICE MACHINE 
NEW ! 
All of our appliances come with a nice warranty! 
We can deliver and install too! 
Call JOY: 972-516-2277 
OR 
Come by our store: 
APPLIANCES OF PLANO 
2508 14TH ST 
PLANO, 75074 
THANK YOU! 
 

 dallas 

 
 New Ice 21 Cuisinart Frozen Yogurt Sorbet Ice Cream Maker Machine Box Mckinney Tx 30   details   visit 
07/11/2012
 HTF Rare and Hard to Find Great Condition Brand New in Box Never Used Cuisinart Frozen Yogurt-Ice Cream&amp;Sorbet Maker not in box. Ice Cream, Sorbets Sherbets&amp;more ! Purchased for a family reunion get-together and never used time. We have another o [... 
 

 dallas 

 
 Scotsman Ice Machine Corinth Tx 1250   details   visit 
07/11/2012
 Scotsman Ice Machine CM500 with Ice bin holds 300lbs of ice. Works great and being use at this time. 
 

 dallas 

 
 Ice Cream Machine Dallas 1500   details   visit 
07/10/2012
 I HAVE THE REAL DEAL TAYLOR SOFT SERVED ICE CREAM MACHINE. THIS MACHINE WORKS GREAT JUST POUR IN THE MIX PULL THE HANDLE AND SOFT SERVED ICE CREAM ON A CONE OR IN A CUP IS SERVED, IF INTERESTED PLEASE CALL CHRIS AT 214-989-5621 SERIOUS BUYER ONLY THA [... 
 

 dallas 

 
 Manitowoc Ice Machine Triple Filtration System Incl Model Qd0452a Arlington 1800   details   visit 
07/10/2012
 Manitowoc is the Cadillac of commercial ice machines. I have had it for a few years and it has been lightly used. It works like a champ and I have used my own personal refrigeration specialist for regular maintenance. I am also throwing in a Manitowo [... 
 

 dallas 

 
 Ice Machine Arlington 1500   details   visit 
07/10/2012
 Scotsman Ice machine model CME 256 I am selling my ice machine because we are no longer needing these go for $2700 to $3000 
 

 dallas 

 
 Ice Maker Ice Machine Commercial 95pounds Daily Dfdubww 1   details   visit 
07/09/2012
 THIS IS A COMMERCIAL ICE MAKER WILL 95 POUNDS DAILY--ITS NEW AS YOU CAN SEE ALL THE WHITE WRAPPING ALL AROUND THE ICE MAKER SO ITS STILL UNDER WARRANTY--BRANDNEW ITS RUNNING 3,0000 DOLLARS AT THE MANUFACTURE--HERE ITS ONLY 695.00 ONLY 695.00 ONLY 695 [... 
 

 dallas 

 
 Ice Machine 65lbs Day Dfw 500   details   visit 
07/09/2012
 HAVE A FRANKLIN CHEF FIM70 FOR SALE PLEASE EMAIL IF INTERESTED 
 

 dallas 

 
 Ice Machine Equipment Dallas Fort Worth   details   visit 
07/09/2012
 Risk Free! The Easy Ice subscription plan for commercial ice makers is the new, better alternative to buying or leasing! Our 30-day cancellation policy gives you the flexibility you need. NO long term contracts. An Easy Ice subscription includes: 
 [... 
 

 dallas 

 
 Ice Machine Brandnew Dfw 695   details   visit 
07/09/2012
 MAKES 95 POUNDS OF ICE PER DAY---still under warranty--still fully wrapped all around--will make about 10 -10pound bags in a day-------at the store it cost 2,000 dollars buy here for a fraction of the price it was only used for a couple of weeks--onl [... 
 

 dallas 

 
 Ice Machine Sherman 25   details   visit 
07/08/2012
 I have a Emerson ice machine ( like sold at target for $100.) used one summer, selling as I recently bought a refrigerator with ice maker. Call 903-267-5997. Can send pictures upon request thank you 
 

 dallas 

 
 Scotsman Ice Machine Corinth Tx 1850   details   visit 
07/08/2012
 Scotsman Ice Machine CM500 with Ice bin holds 300lbs of ice. Works great and being use at this time. 
 

 dallas 

 
 Marvel Ice Machine In Stainless Steel New New N Dallas 1800   details   visit 
07/07/2012
 Super Nice MARVEL Ice Machine NEW! 
All of our appliances come with a nice warranty! 
We can deliver and install too! 
Call JOY: 972-516-2277 
OR 
Come by our store: 
APPLIANCES OF PLANO 
2508 14TH ST 
PLANO, 75074 
THANK YOU! 
 

 dallas 

 
 Ice Vending Machine For Sale Dallas Area   details   visit 
07/07/2012
 For Sale &quot;ICE BUCKET&quot; brand ice vending machine $40,000 DOWN PAYMENT We will deliver and set up. This machine can produce more than 300 16lb. bags of ice a day that sell for $2.00 each!! In a good location, and managed by a good owner, this machine c [... 
 

 dallas 

 
 Ice Machine Wylie 300   details   visit 
07/06/2012
 110v Ice machine in good shape and puts out allot of ice.call kurt2143844844 
 

 dallas 

 
 Ice Machine Dfw 700   details   visit 
07/06/2012
 FRANKLIN CHEF FIN70 
OPEN TO ANYTHING JUST EMAIL ME. WHAT DO U GOT? 
 

 dallas 

 
 Hoshizaki Ice Machine Bins Dallas Ft Worth   details   visit 
07/06/2012
 Hoshizaki commercial ice machines, bins and dispensers up to 600 lbs/day for as little as $129/month! Larger machines available -- call for pricing. 
All Maintenance Included! Your monthly subscription covers installation, preventive maintenance, fil [... 
 

 dallas 

 
 Follet W Hoshizaki Ice Machine Sg1475s 60 Wylie Tx 2500   details   visit 
07/06/2012
 I have alot of commercial appliances for sale i have one of these please contact kenny 214-909-9252 1490lb bin with hoshizaki machine F-1500mah i don&apos;t have a picture of the hoshizaki top motor it was to big and heavy this is a picture of the follet [... 
 

 dallas 

 
 Ice Machine 65lbs Day Dfw 500   details   visit 
07/05/2012
 HAVE A FRANKLIN CHEF ICE MACHINE MODEL FIN70. MAKES ROUND ICE. MAKES 65 LBS IN A DAY. BIN HOLDS 25 LBS AND HAS DRAIN FOR BIN. MAKE ME AN OFFER 
 

 dallas 

 
 Hoshizaki Ice Machine Bins Dallas Ft Worth   details   visit 
07/04/2012
 Hoshizaki commercial ice machines, bins and dispensers up to 600 lbs/day for as little as $129/month! Larger machines available -- call for pricing. 
All Maintenance Included! Your monthly subscription covers installation, preventive maintenance, fil [... 
 

 dallas 

 
 Kitchenaid 18in Stainless Steel Clear Cube Ice Machine South Ftw Crowley Burleson 600   details   visit 
07/03/2012
 KitchenAid Clear Cube Ice Machine: 
Makes up to 50lbs. in 24 hours. 
35lb. storage capacity great for a ready supply of ice at all times. 
Electronic controls concealed behind the door. 
Lighted bin with ice scoop. 
Great ice supply when entertaining [... 
 

 dallas 

 
 Manitowoc Ice Machine With Remote Ice Bin And Water Filtration Rowlett   details   visit 
07/03/2012
 SE HABLA ESPANOL! MANITOWOC ICE MACHINE WITH REMOTE, ICE BIN AND WATER FILTRATION. 
restaurant equipment, bakery equipment, used restaurant equipment, janitorial equipment, automotive equipment, furniture, commercial, auction, kitchen, BBQ, stainless [... 
 

 dallas 

 
 Ice Machine Almost New Mainauctionservicescom   details   visit 
07/03/2012
 Ice machine model 2011, Manitowoc and dozens of major appliances for restaurant / barCall us today !!! Se habla espanol !!!
restaurant equipment, bar, bakery, coffee, donut, hotel, country club, commercial appliances, stainless steel, furniture, pizz [... 
 

 dallas 

 
 Stoelting Ice Cream Smoothie Machine Texas Restaurant Equipment   details   visit 
07/03/2012
 STOELTING ICE CREAM SMOOTHIE MACHINE Call Us Today ! Se Habla Espanol !!!
restaurant equipment, bar, bakery, coffee, donut, hotel, country club, commercial appliances, stainless steel, furniture, pizzeria, taqueria, torteria, catering companies, lonc [... 
 

 dallas 

 
 Self Vending Ice Machine To Be Moved Bryan College Station 100000   details   visit 
07/03/2012
 Vending machine to be bought and MOVED to YOUR location. I can help arrange the move and set-up. 
Need to sell due to marginal traffic count as well as my property lease expired in May 2012. Machine was manufactured in April of 2010 by The Ice Bucket [... 
 

 dallas 

 
 1 2 3 4 5 
 


 Terms of Service | Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
